<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 02:33:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 波兰标准化气候水平衡（1951-2023）支持林业和干旱监测</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06178-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Standardized Climatic Water Balance for Poland (1951–2023) Supporting Forestry and Drought Monitoring&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Paweł Netzel; Dominika Cywicka&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;该数据描述符提供了波兰标准化气候水平衡的高分辨率 (100 × 100 m) 网格数据集，时间跨度为 1951 年至 2023 年 72 年。该数据集是作为一项研究计划的一部分而开发的，该计划的重点是评估不断变化的气候状况下的长期水可用性和干旱条件。输入数据集包括来自 2,000 多个气象站的每月温度和降水记录，以及来自航天飞机雷达地形任务的海拔数据。我们描述了完整的方法，包括使用混合回归样条模型进行空间插值，通过 Thornthwaite 方法计算潜在蒸散量，以及气候水平衡的标准化，以产生跨空间和时间可比较的波兰标准化气候水平衡值。生成的数据集包含波兰标准化气候水平衡的每月栅格图层以及气温和降水的插值图层。所有文件都是公开的，适用于区域和地方尺度的环境监测、干旱风险评估、森林生态系统分析以及气候适应规划。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This Data Descriptor presents a high-resolution (100 × 100 m) gridded dataset of the Standardized Climatic Water Balance for Poland, spanning 72 years from 1951 to 2023. The dataset was developed as part of a research initiative focused on assessing long-term water availability and drought conditions under changing climate regimes. Input data set includes monthly temperature and precipitation records from over 2,000 meteorological stations, as well as elevation data from the Shuttle Radar Topography Mission. We describe the full methodology, including spatial interpolation using a hybrid regression-spline model, calculation of potential evapotranspiration via the Thornthwaite method, and standardization of the climatic water balance to produce Standardized Climatic Water Balance for Poland values that are comparable across space and time. The resulting dataset comprises monthly raster layers of the Standardized Climatic Water Balance for Poland, along with interpolated layers of air temperature and precipitation. All files are publicly available and suitable for use in environmental monitoring, drought risk assessment, forest ecosystem analysis, and climate adaptation planning at regional and local scales.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-27225-0/MediaObjects/41598_2025_27225_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 对日本富士山地质复杂的火山流域进行综合水资源管理建模</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06380-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Modeling a geologically complex volcanic watershed for integrated water resources management in Mt. Fuji, Japan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Stephanie L. Musy; Horst Dresmann; Yama Tomonaga; Yuji Sano; Oliver S. Schilling&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;该数据集提供了日本富士山流域的高分辨率 3D 地质和综合水文模型。该流域复杂的火山和构造环境、广阔的空间范围和有限的地下数据给综合水文建模带来了重大挑战。收集、处理各种地质数据集（钻孔日志、地质图和水相表面），并用于构建和验证适合综合水文模拟的 3D 地质模型。在此基础上，构建了综合水文模拟的 3D 数值模型。该存储库包括栅格格式的 3D 水相表面、数值网格文件以及使用集成的地表-地下水文模拟器 HydroGeoSphere 运行模拟所需的输入配置。异质地质数据的准备、水相表面的构建、数值网格的生成以及综合水文模型的设置均在适合火山环境的简化、可重复的工作流程中进行描述，并且可转移到其他地质复杂或数据有限的区域。这些资源旨在减少反复试验，并支持地下水评估、模型校准、气候影响研究和减灾方面的进一步研究。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This dataset provides high-resolution 3D geological and integrated hydrological models of Mt. Fuji watershed in Japan. The watershed’s complex volcanic and tectonic setting, large spatial extent, and limited subsurface data present significant challenges for integrated hydrological modeling. Diverse geological datasets – borehole logs, geological maps, and hydrofacies surfaces – were collected, processed, and used to construct and validate a 3D geological model suitable for integrated hydrological simulations. Building on this, a 3D numerical model for integrated hydrological simulations was constructed. The repository includes 3D hydrofacies surfaces in raster format, numerical mesh files, and input configurations necessary to run simulations with the integrated surface-subsurface hydrological simulator HydroGeoSphere. The preparation of heterogeneous geological data, construction of hydrofacies surfaces, generation of the numerical mesh, and setup of the integrated hydrological model are described in a streamlined, reproducible workflow suited for volcanic contexts and transferable to other geologically complex or data-limited regions. These resources are intended to reduce trial-and-error iterations and support further research in groundwater assessment, model calibration, climate impact studies, and hazard mitigation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06178-z/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6178_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 集中地下水补给受景观和气候控制</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-03063-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Focused groundwater recharge is controlled by landscape and climate&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Stephen Lee; Dylan J. Irvine; Gabriel C. Rau; Matthew Currell; Carol V. Tadros; Clément Duvert&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;集中地下水补给，即水通过溪流、洼地或裂缝等地表特征集中渗透到地下水位，被认为是干旱气候下的主要补给机制。随着气候变得越来越干旱，地下水补给预计将转向集中机制。然而，在大陆尺度上，集中补给的规模、其空间分布和跨气候区的控制仍然很少被描述。在这里，我们将历史降雨量氚与超过 1700 个地下水氚测量值进行比较，以评估整个澳大利亚大陆集中补给的可能性，为水资源管理提供重要背景，并具有全球影响。 46% 的评估钻孔显示出集中补给的证据，这表明基于扩散机制的传统补给估计可能大大低估了总补给。我们表明，裂隙岩石和常年水道是强烈影响集中补给可能性的主要景观特征。虽然集中补给在干旱地区最常见，但它也发生在潮湿的气候中，那里的裂隙岩石增强了地下的连通性。随着干旱和气候变化的加剧，了解能够实现集中补给的景观与气候相互作用，以及能源和水供应的变化如何改变地下水在水循环中的作用，对于维持地下水资源至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Focused groundwater recharge, the concentrated infiltration of water through surface features including streams, depressions, or fractures to the water table, is accepted as the dominant recharge mechanism in arid climates. As climates become increasingly arid, groundwater recharge is expected to shift towards focused mechanisms. Yet the magnitude of focused recharge, its spatial distribution and controls across climate zones remain poorly characterised at the continental scale. Here, we compare historical rainfall tritium with &amp;gt;1700 groundwater tritium measurements to assess the likelihood of focused recharge across the Australian continent, providing important context for water resources management, with global implications. 46% of bores assessed show evidence of focused recharge, suggesting that conventional recharge estimates based on diffuse mechanisms may substantially underestimate total recharge. We show that fractured rock and perennial watercourses are the main landscape features that strongly influence the likelihood of focused recharge. While focused recharge is most common in arid regions, it also occurs in wetter climates where fractured rock enhances subsurface connectivity. As aridity and climate variability intensify, understanding the landscape-climate interactions that enable focused recharge, and how shifts in energy and water availability alter the role of groundwater in the water cycle, will be critical to sustaining groundwater resources.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-27331-z/MediaObjects/41598_2025_27331_Fig1a_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>