<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 02:16:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 孟加拉国的高分辨率网格流量数据（1951– 2023年）</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05014-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;High-resolution gridded streamflow data for Ganges-Brahmaputra-Meghna River Basins in Bangladesh (1951–2023)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Byeong-Hee Kim; Sazzad Hossain; Jonghun Kam&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;使用1951年至2023年的恒河 -  brahmaputra-meghna河流跨恒河 -  brahmaputra-meghna河流跨越1951  -  2023年，使用可变的浸润能力转速路由模型（VIC-RRM）生成9公里的每日电网流量数据集，该数据集在1951  -  2023年间，由ERA5-LAND REANALALIS REALALASIS DATA（用于天然化流量）强迫。 ECMWF S2S预测还会生成物理一致的流量预测数据。使用来自恒河，婆罗门河和梅格纳河流的孟加拉国三个轨距站的观测流量数据进行评估数据集的性能，计算365天气候学的修改后的Kling-Gupta效率（MKGE）度量。对于恒河，婆罗门河和梅格纳河，重建流量数据的MKGE值分别为0.50、0.75和0.25。与重建的流量数据相比，流量预测在三个量规站的MKGE值分别与1.00、0.97和0.91的MKGE值达成了良好的一致性。该数据集以高分辨率提供了物理一致的重建和预测的流量数据，为评估气候变化和变化以及曼格拉德郡恒河河流河流的河流盆地特异性水管理策略的发展提供了宝贵的资源。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A 9-km daily gridded streamflow dataset is generated using the Variable Infiltration Capacity-River Routing Model (VIC-RRM) across the Ganges-Brahmaputra-Meghna River basins over 1951–2023, forced by the ERA5-Land reanalysis data for naturalized streamflow. Physically consistent streamflow forecast data is also generated forced by the ECMWF S2S forecasts. The performance of the dataset is evaluated using observed streamflow data from three gauge stations in Bangladesh along the streams of Ganges, Brahmaputra, and Meghna Rivers, calculating the modified Kling-Gupta Efficiency (mKGE) metric for the 365-day climatology. For Ganges, Brahmaputra, and Meghna Rivers, the mKGE values of reconstructed streamflow data are 0.50, 0.75, and 0.25, respectively. Comparing with the reconstructed streamflow data, the streamflow forecasts show a good agreement with mKGE values of 1.00, 0.97, and 0.91 at three gauge stations, respectively. This dataset provides physically consistent reconstructed and forecasted streamflow data at high resolution, offering a valuable resource for the assessment of climate variability and change and the development of river basin-specific water management strategies in the Ganges-Brahmaputra-Meghna Rivers in Bangladesh.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05014-8/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5014_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>