<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 02:26:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 突发干旱加剧了全球植被损失并延迟了恢复</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-67173-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Flash droughts exacerbate global vegetation loss and delay recovery&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yuanfang Chai; Chiyuan Miao; Amir AghaKouchak; Yadu Pokhrel; Yongshuo Fu; Xiaoyan Li; Jiachen Ji; Qi Zhang; Josep Peñuelas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球突发干旱的发生率不断增加，对农业部门、生态系统复原力和水资源系统提出了巨大挑战。在这里，我们介绍一种方法，可以提高量化干旱引起的全球植被损失的准确性（使用归一化植被指数（NDVI）导出的指标）。我们的结果显示，突发干旱期间的 NDVI 损失 (9.0%) 大约是常规干旱期间 (5.3%) 的 1.5 倍，这凸显了突发干旱作为全球干旱引起的 NDVI 损失的主要驱动因素的作用日益增强。此外，我们发现，由于突发干旱导致的全球 NDVI 损失呈显着上升趋势（每十年 1.8%），这主要是由于此类事件发生频率的增加所致，占总体趋势的 81.2%。尽管在突发干旱后，全球陆地表面超过 9256.3 × 10 &lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;的 NDVI 通常会在 36 候内恢复，但从 1982 年到 2020 年，NDVI 恢复时间显着增加（每年 0.4 候），特别是在热带雨林和温带森林。这些发现凸显了日益频繁和严重的突发干旱所带来的令人震惊的生态后果，预计未来影响将会加剧。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The increasing incidence of flash droughts globally presents a great challenge to the agriculture sector, ecosystem resilience and water resource systems. Here we introduce a methodology that improves the accuracy of quantifying drought-induced global vegetation loss (using Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI)-derived metric). Our results reveal that NDVI loss during flash droughts (9.0%) is approximately 1.5 times higher than that during conventional droughts (5.3%), highlighting the increasing role of flash droughts as the key driver of drought-induced NDVI loss worldwide. Furthermore, we identify a significant upward trend (1.8% per decade) in global NDVI loss due to flash droughts, primarily driven by the increasing frequency of such events, which account for 81.2% of the overall trend. Although NDVI typically recovers within 36 pentads across more than 9256.3 × 10&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; of the global land surface after flash droughts, there is a notable increase (0.4 pentads per year) in NDVI recovery time from 1982 to 2020, particularly in tropical rainforests and temperate forests. These findings highlight the alarming ecological consequences of increasingly frequent and intense flash droughts, with impacts expected to intensify in the future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06178-z/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6178_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 根系平衡土壤水流行为的双重功能</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-03062-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Dual function of root systems in balancing soil water flow behavior&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zhiying Tang; He Ba; Wenqi Zhang; Yinghu Zhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;从染料染色图像中表征三维 (3D) 土壤水流的局限性阻碍了对 3D 根系作用的进一步深入了解。在这里，我们使用 X 射线计算机显微断层扫描、染料示踪实验和 3D 土壤水流建模软件来暗示 3D 根系的双重功能。我们的结果表明，在壤土混交林中，土壤水流特征表现出与深度相关的变化。我们还得出结论，壤土条件下的根系可以促进优先流和土壤基质流行为。当根系性状关键指标小于临界值时，优先流将主导土壤水流行为；否则，土壤基质流将占主导地位。不同土壤水流特征导致土壤水流行为传递的指标临界值不同。我们的研究从 3D 角度深入了解根系统的双重功能。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A limitation in characterizing three-dimensional (3D) soil water flow from dye-stained images hinders further insights into the role of 3D root systems. Here we used X-ray computed microtomography, dye-tracing experiments, and 3D soil water flow modeling software to imply the dual function of 3D root systems. Our results revealed that soil water flow traits exhibited depth-dependent changes at the mixed forest stands with loam soils. We also concluded that root systems under loam soil conditions could promote both preferential flow- and soil matrix flow behavior. Preferential flow will dominate soil water flow behavior when the key indicators of root systems traits were less than a critical value; otherwise, soil matrix flow will dominate. Critical values of the indicators inducing the transfer of soil water flow behavior varied for different soil water flow traits. Our study provides an insight into the dual function of root systems from a 3D perspective.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-27331-z/MediaObjects/41598_2025_27331_Fig1a_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>