<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 01:56:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Climate Change | 忽视土地 - 大气反馈高估了气候驱动的蒸散量增加</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-025-02428-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Neglecting land–atmosphere feedbacks overestimates climate-driven increases in evapotranspiration&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Sha Zhou; Bofu Yu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;蒸散液（ET）的准确投影对于理解对气候变暖的水文反应至关重要，由于复杂的土地 - 大气相互作用，它们仍然高度不确定。在这里，我们开发了一个理论框架来消除这些相互作用，从而实现了离线模型和耦合模型之间高度一致的ET预测。我们的发现表明，以前对气候驱动的ET增加的估计已被夸大，这主要是由于大气蒸发需求的高估。值得注意的是，实际上，通常假定驱动ET的大气条件对土壤水分和植被动态引起的ET变化的反应。忽略这些大气反馈的忽视导致气候驱动的全球ET增加了25-39％的高估，而土地表面变化的负贡献的夸大了77-121％。这些偏见在离线和耦合模型之间的水文预测和归因方面造成了巨大差异，强调了准确代表土地 - 大气相互作用以提高未来水文预测的可靠性和一致性的重要性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Accurate projections of evapotranspiration (ET) are crucial for understanding hydrological responses to climate warming, which remain highly uncertain because of complex land–atmosphere interactions. Here we develop a theoretical framework to disentangle these interactions, achieving highly consistent ET projections between offline and coupled models. Our findings show that previous estimates of climate-driven ET increases have been exaggerated, primarily due to a substantial overestimation of atmospheric evaporative demand. Notably, the atmospheric conditions often assumed to drive ET are, in fact, responses to ET changes induced by soil moisture and vegetation dynamics. Neglecting these land–atmosphere feedbacks has led to a 25–39% overestimation of climate-driven global ET increases and a 77–121% exaggeration of the negative contribution from land surface changes. These biases have caused large discrepancies in hydrological projections and attributions between offline and coupled models, underscoring the importance of accurately representing land–atmosphere interactions to improve the reliability and consistency of future hydrological projections.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41558-025-02428-5/MediaObjects/41558_2025_2428_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 格陵兰冰片径流通过淡水在裸冰中降低</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-62281-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Greenland ice sheet runoff reduced by meltwater refreezing in bare ice&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Matthew G. Cooper; Laurence C. Smith; Åsa K. Rennermalm; Jonathan C. Ryan; Lincoln H. Pitcher; Glen E. Liston; Clément Miège; Sarah W. Cooley; Dirk van As&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;格陵兰冰层融合水径流对全球海平面上升的贡献正在加速，这是由于其裸露的消融区的融化增加。然而，越来越多的证据表明，气候模型从冰盖的关键区域高估了径流。传统上，气候模型认为，与多孔Firn不同，所有裸露的径流都进入了海洋，其中一些熔融水被保留和/或重新旋转。我们使用现场测量和数值建模来揭示在裸露的冰川冰中也发生了广泛的保留和重新冻结。我们发现，从2009年到2018年，仅在西南格陵兰岛，裸露的多孔冰川冰层融化了据估计，估计减少了11-17 GT A -1 &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ，相当于该行业的9-15％的年度融化融合，这是气候模型模拟的。这种质量保留解释了当前一代气候模型对裸露冰上径流高估的先前研究的证据，并且可能代表预计径流增加的缓冲区。因此，在气候模型中包含裸露的保留和重新冻结过程具有立即的潜力，可以改善对冰原径流的预测及其对海平面上升的贡献。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The contribution of Greenland Ice Sheet meltwater runoff to global sea-level rise is accelerating due to increased melting of its bare-ice ablation zone. There is growing evidence, however, that climate models overestimate runoff from this critical area of the ice sheet. Climate models traditionally assume that all bare-ice runoff enters the ocean, unlike porous firn, in which some meltwater is retained and/or refrozen. We used field measurements and numerical modeling to reveal that extensive retention and refreezing also occurs in bare glacier ice. We found that, from 2009 to 2018, meltwater refreezing in bare, porous glacier ice reduced runoff by an estimated 11–17 Gt a&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; in southwest Greenland alone, equivalent to 9–15% of this sector’s annual meltwater runoff simulated by climate models. This mass retention explains evidence from prior studies of runoff overestimation on bare ice by current generation climate models and may represent an overlooked buffer on projected runoff increases. Inclusion of bare-ice retention and refreezing processes in climate models therefore has immediate potential to improve forecasts of ice sheet runoff and its contribution to sea-level rise.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-62281-0/MediaObjects/41467_2025_62281_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 融合水块对格陵兰冰盖表面的辐射效应低估</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-62503-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Meltwater ponding has an underestimated radiative effect on the surface of the Greenland Ice Sheet&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jonathan C. Ryan; Matthew G. Cooper; Sarah W. Cooley; Åsa K. Rennermalm; Laurence C. Smith&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在格陵兰冰盖表面上的融合水块有可能减少冰盖反照率并扩大质量损失。但是，这个过程仍然受到限制，并且没有投射冰盖质量平衡的模型。在这里，我们证明融化池塘大大增加了用于融化格陵兰冰盖的能量量。我们首先使用卫星衍生的产品来表明熔融水池对空间反照率模式有重大影响，尤其是在较低的渗滤区。然后，我们使用无人机图像来证明，在上层消融区中，有成千上万的狭窄溪流和小型池（&amp;lt;100平方米），占融水总面积的50％。这些小的融水特征无法通过中等分辨率卫星图像得出的地表水图解决，这表明融合水块的辐射效应比基于卫星的方法强的三到四倍。因此，我们的发现将融合池辐射效应的辐射效应放在了下限，该融合物可用于主张将此过程纳入预测格陵兰冰盖对海平面上升的贡献的模型。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ponding of meltwater on the surface of the Greenland Ice Sheet has the potential to reduce ice sheet albedo and amplify mass loss. However, this process remains poorly constrained and is absent from models that project ice sheet mass balance. Here we demonstrate that meltwater ponding considerably increases the amount of energy available for melting the Greenland Ice Sheet. We first use satellite-derived products to show that meltwater ponding has a significant impact on spatial albedo patterns, particularly in the lower percolation zone. We then use drone imagery to demonstrate that, in the upper ablation zone, there are thousands of narrow streams and small pools (&amp;lt;100 m²) that collectively account for &amp;gt;50% of the total meltwater area. These small meltwater features are not resolved by surface water maps derived from medium-resolution satellite imagery, signifying that the radiative effect of meltwater ponding is three to four times stronger than predicted by satellite-based approaches. Our findings therefore place lower bounds on the radiative effect of meltwater ponding that could be used to advocate for the inclusion of this process into models that forecast Greenland Ice Sheet’s contribution to sea-level rise.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-62503-5/MediaObjects/41467_2025_62503_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>