<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 02:11:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 伊朗河流综合水化学数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05932-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A Comprehensive Water Chemistry Dataset for Iranian Rivers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Erfan Zarei; Roohollah Noori; Changhyun Jun; Sayed M. Bateni; Peiman Kianmehr; Senlin Zhu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流水质数据对于管理地表水资源和保护陆地水生生态系统至关重要。尽管编制的全球河流水质数据集的数量不断增加，但亚洲国家（尤其是伊朗）的可用数据明显缺乏。为了解决这一差距，本研究编制了涵盖 1964 年至 2020 年伊朗河流的综合水化学数据集。该数据集包括14种化学成分和11个水质指标，从全国1,591个河流监测站获得总计5,968,568条记录（即不同测量点×变量×时间步长）。我们可用的化合物包括总溶解固体、pH、电导率、碳酸盐、氯化物、碳酸氢盐、硫酸盐、钙、钾、镁、钠、硝酸盐、Σ阳离子和Σ阴离子。我们数据集中计算的水质指标包括钠吸附比、拉森指数、钠百分比、凯利比、总硬度、残留碳酸钠、镁危害、氯碱指数、腐蚀性比、渗透性指数和饱和度指数。该数据集可以支持国家层面的大规模河流水质评估研究，并对现有的全球河流水质数据库进行补充。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;River water quality data are essential for managing surface water resources and protecting terrestrial-aquatic ecosystems. While the number of compiled global river water quality datasets is growing, there is a notable lack of available data in Asian countries, especially Iran. To address this gap, this study compiled a comprehensive water chemistry dataset for Iranian rivers covering 1964–2020. The dataset includes 14 chemical compounds and 11 water quality indices, totaling 5,968,568 records (i.e., distinct measurement points × variables × time steps) obtained from 1,591 monitoring stations across the country’s rivers. Our avialable chemical compounds include total dissolved solids, pH, electrical conductivity, carbonate, chloride, bicarbonate, sulfate, calcium, potassium, magnesium, sodium, nitrate, ΣCations, and ΣAnions. The calculated water quality indices in our dataset were sodium adsorption ratio, Larson index, sodium percentage, Kelly’s ratio, total hardness, residual sodium carbonates, magnesium hazard, chloro-alkaline index, corrosivity ratio, permeability index, and saturation index. This dataset can support large-scale river water quality assessment studies at the national level and complement the available global river water quality databases.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05932-7/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5932_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 物理嵌入式学习揭示了全球独特的水文响应模式和趋势</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-64367-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Distinct hydrologic response patterns and trends worldwide revealed by physics-embedded learning&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Haoyu Ji; Yalan Song; Tadd Bindas; Chaopeng Shen; Yuan Yang; Ming Pan; Jiangtao Liu; Farshid Rahmani; Ather Abbas; Hylke Beck; Kathryn Lawson; Yoshihide Wada&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;为了跟踪水部门的快速变化，全球水模型 (GWM) 需要真实地表示水文系统的响应模式（例如水流的基流部分），但其从数据中学习的能力有限，从而受到阻碍。在这里，我们引入了一种高分辨率、物理嵌入式、大数据训练的模型，可以可靠地捕获特征水文响应模式（特征）及其变化。通过真实地反映长期水平衡，该模型揭示了全球基本绿蓝水分配和基流比率的广泛变化（在某些情况下，20 年来变化超过 20%）。这些先前假定的静态响应模式的变化导致北部中纬度地区洪水风险增加，南部亚热带地区供水压力加大，许多欧洲河口淡水输入减少，所有这些都会产生生态影响。与当前操作系统相比，该下一代模型在月度和日尺度上进行了更加准确的模拟，解决了半干旱和干旱地区对降雨（弹性）和水流闪度的大型非线性季节性径流响应。我们的结果突出显示了由于供水变化大和气候敏感性高而面临管理挑战的地区，并展示了预测季节性可用水量的先进工具。这一功能使全球规模的模型能够为水管理提供可靠且与当地相关的见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To track rapid changes within our water sector, Global Water Models (GWMs) need to realistically represent hydrologic systems’ response patterns — such as the baseflow fraction of streamflow — but are hindered by their limited ability to learn from data. Here we introduce a high-resolution, physics-embedded, big-data-trained model to reliably capture characteristic hydrologic response patterns (signatures) and their shifts. By realistically representing the long-term water balance, the model revealed widespread shifts — in some cases, more than 20% over 20 years — in fundamental green-blue-water partitioning and baseflow ratios worldwide. Shifts in these previously-assumed-static response patterns contributed to increasing flood risks in northern mid-latitudes, heightening water supply stresses in southern subtropical regions, and declining freshwater inputs to many European estuaries, all with ecological implications. With substantially more accurate simulations at monthly and daily scales than current operational systems, this next-generation model resolves large, nonlinear, seasonal runoff responses to rainfall (elasticity) and streamflow flashiness in semi-arid and arid regions. Our results highlight regions with management challenges due to large water supply variability and high climate sensitivity, and demonstrate an advanced tool to forecast seasonal water availability. This capability enables global-scale models to deliver reliable and locally-relevant insights for water management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-64367-1/MediaObjects/41467_2025_64367_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>