<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:17:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 近全球农业气候干旱监测数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06316-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Near-global Agro-climatological Drought Monitoring Dataset&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Sneha Kulkarni; Yohei Sawada&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球干旱日益频繁和严重，给农业和气候资源管理带来了严峻挑战，凸显了对全面干旱数据的需求。为了解决这个问题，我们引入了近全球农业气候干旱监测（NEC-DROMO）数据集，该数据集集成了关键的农业气候变量以提供可靠的干旱见解。 NEC-DROMO 跨越 2002 年至 2021 年，以 0.25 度的空间分辨率和月度尺度，结合土壤湿度 (SM) 和植被含水量 (VWC) 来捕捉农业压力，并结合降雨量和温度来捕捉气候背景。 NEC-DROMO 每月为近乎全球的地区提供干旱数据，延迟时间取决于输入数据集的可用性。 NEC-DROMO 通过主成分分析构建，客观地对每个变量进行加权，确保历史监控和潜在的近实时应用的稳健性。针对独立卫星和现场方法（包括 SPI、NDVI 和地理编码灾害数据集）的验证证实了 NEC-DROMO 在准确捕捉全球干旱模式方面的可靠性。 NEC-DROMO 以生态水文土地再分析数据集为基础，并使用其 VWC、SM 和温度数据，代表了全球干旱监测、支持政策制定和灾害风险评估方面的重大进步。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The increasing frequency and severity of global droughts present critical challenges to agriculture and climate resource management, highlighting the need for comprehensive drought data. To address this, we introduce the Near-global Agro-Climatological Drought Monitoring (NEC-DROMO) dataset, which integrates key agro-climatological variables to provide robust drought insights. Spanning 2002–2021 at a 0.25-degree spatial resolution and monthly scale, NEC-DROMO combines soil moisture (SM) and vegetation water content (VWC) to capture agricultural stress, with rainfall and temperature for climatological context. NEC-DROMO delivers monthly drought data for near-global regions, with latency depending on the availability of input datasets. NEC-DROMO is built through Principal Component Analysis, which objectively weights each variable, ensuring robustness for historical monitoring and potential near-real-time applications. Validation against independent satellite-based and in-situ methods, including the SPI, NDVI, and Geocoded Disaster dataset, confirms NEC-DROMO’s reliability in accurately capturing global drought patterns. Building upon the ECoHydrological Land Reanalysis dataset and using its VWC, SM, and temperature data, NEC-DROMO represents a significant advancement in global drought monitoring, supporting policymaking and disaster risk assessment.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-25715-9/MediaObjects/41598_2025_25715_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>