<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 02:19:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 侧碳运输的干旱收缩</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01807-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Drought constrictions on lateral carbon transport&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jinyu Wang; Julien Bouchez; Matthew J. Winnick; Allison E. Goodwell; Ashlee Dere; Praveen Kumar; Jennifer L. Druhan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;由于水流的减少，干旱阻碍了碳沿大陆河网络沿大陆网络的横向通量。在这里，我们表明，除了较低的流量外，干旱还加剧了次级碳酸盐形成和大气CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;排放。我们报告了北美上桑加蒙河上主要离子化学的次数田间测量，这表明干旱在分水岭量表上加速了碳酸盐矿物质形成的特征快速速度。在连续195天的中度水文干旱中，我们观察到由于次要碳酸盐形成而导致的河流横向通量减少了17％，除了低流速所施加的限制外，这表明对河流的无机碳承载能力有自然的限制。我们使用历史数据集并对全球河流地球化学测量结果进行汇编，以表明这种现象在干旱期间是可重现和广泛的。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Drought impedes the lateral flux of carbon along continental river networks to the oceans due to reduction in water flow. Here we show that, in addition to lower flow, drought also exacerbates secondary carbonate formation and atmospheric CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions. We report sub-hourly field measurements of major ion chemistry in the upper Sangamon River in North America, revealing that drought accelerates the characteristically rapid pace of carbonate mineral formation at the watershed scale. Over 195 consecutive days of moderate hydrologic drought, we observe a 17% decrease in annual riverine lateral carbon flux due to secondary carbonate formation, in addition to the restrictions imposed by low flow rates, indicating a natural limit to the inorganic carbon carrying capacity of rivers. We use historical datasets and a compilation of global river geochemistry measurements to show that this phenomenon is reproducible and widespread during periods of drought.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01807-z/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1807_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Sustainability | 制定可再生能源过渡以保持沉积物运输完整性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-025-01626-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Strategizing renewable energy transitions to preserve sediment transport integrity&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Bo Xu; Zhanwei Liu; Shuyue Yan; Rafael J. P. Schmitt; Xiaogang He&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水力发电对于通过启用低碳能量系统来缓解气候至关重要，但是水电坝也诱使沉积物，这是生态系统的关键资源和下游海岸线沿线的气候适应。在这里，我们提出了一个多部门综合水 - 代码 - 能源规划框架，该框架完全内化了水力机扩展的影响，无论是对能源系统成本以及对湄公河盆地沉积物供应减少的预期生态系统服务的影响。我们的分析表明，大型水力发电的全部发育可以将湄公河三角洲的沉积物流量减少41.2±6.6 megatonnes（75±9％）。但是，用太阳能，风能储能替代品策略性地代替了19个高层捕捞水电厂，最多可以保留98％的沉积物供应量，而能源系统成本仅为4-6％（15.7-260亿美元），而能源系统成本增加了2020- 2050年。至关重要的是，当考虑到与沉积物有关的福利（每年每年兆雄的价值为12-28亿美元）时，保存沉积物供应的额外费用几乎被抵消了。拟议的框架提供了一种可转移的方法，以支持可持续的低碳能量转变，同时保护全球依赖沉积物的生态系统。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hydropower is vital for climate mitigation by enabling low-carbon energy systems, but hydropower dams also trap sediment, a crucial resource for ecosystems and climate adaptation along downstream coastlines. Here we present a multisectoral integrated water–sediment–energy planning framework that fully internalizes the impacts of hydropower expansion, both on energy system costs and on foregone ecosystem services from reduced sediment supply for the Mekong River Basin. Our analysis indicates that full development of large hydropower could reduce sediment flows to the Mekong Delta by 41.2 ± 6.6 megatonnes per year (75 ± 9%). However, strategically replacing 19 high-sediment-trapping hydropower plants with solar, wind and energy storage alternatives could preserve up to 98% of sediment supply, with only a 4–6% (US$15.7–26.0 billion) increase in energy system costs over 2020–2050. Crucially, when sediment-related benefits—valued at US$12–28 million per megatonne per year—are considered, the additional costs of preserving sediment supply are nearly offset. The proposed framework offers a transferable approach to support sustainable low-carbon energy transitions while safeguarding sediment-dependent ecosystems worldwide.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41893-025-01626-5/MediaObjects/41893_2025_1626_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>