<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 02:08:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 极端干旱的波动事件威胁着长江生态系统中水生浮游生物社区的生物多样性和稳定性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02143-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Extreme drought-heatwave events threaten the biodiversity and stability of aquatic plankton communities in the Yangtze River ecosystems&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jixuan Lyu; Yong Shi; Tao Liu; Xiaomei Xu; Shengjing Liu; Guang Yang; Dong Peng; Yubing Qu; Shuo Zhang; Chonghao Chen; Yanxu Zhang; Jianhua Gao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流对生物地球化学周期至关重要，连接陆地，海洋和大气系统。但是，他们的生态系统越来越受到极端天气事件的威胁。在这里，我们使用了环境DNA方法来评估极端干旱的事件对长江河水群社区的影响。我们表明，极端干旱的事件减少了社区的α多样性，增加了其β多样性，并同时简化了不稳定的社区网络结构。该事件还将主要的藻类分类单元从芽孢杆菌转移到蓝细菌，并伴随着有机碳和不稳定有机碳含量的增加。在全球范围内，在高纬度地区，在极端干旱的波动事件中，温度升高更为明显，可能会增加对河流生态系统生物多样性和稳定性的影响。我们的发现突出了河流生态系统对极端事件的脆弱性，并强调了减轻气候变化对河流生态系统的影响的必要性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Rivers are crucial to biogeochemical cycles, connecting terrestrial, oceanic, and atmospheric systems. However, their ecosystems are increasingly threatened by extreme weather events. Here we used the environmental DNA approach to assess the impact of extreme drought-heatwave events on the aquatic plankton communities of the Yangtze River. We showed that an extreme drought-heatwave event reduced the α diversity of communities, increased their β diversity, and simultaneously simplified and destabilized community network structure. This event also shifted the dominant algae taxa from Bacillariophyta to Cyanobacteria, accompanied by increases in organic carbon and labile organic carbon contents. Globally, temperature rises during this extreme drought-heatwave event are more pronounced in high-latitude regions, likely amplifying impacts on river ecosystem biodiversity and stability. Our findings highlight the vulnerability of river ecosystems to extreme events and underscore the need to mitigate climate change’s effects on river ecosystems.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02143-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2143_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 30年（1991-2021）意大利PO河区的雪水量数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04633-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;30-years (1991-2021) Snow Water Equivalent Dataset in the Po River District, Italy&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Matteo Dall’Amico; Stefano Tasin; Federico Di Paolo; Marco Brian; Paolo Leoni; Francesco Tornatore; Giuseppe Formetta; John Mohd Wani; Riccardo Rigon; Gaia Roati&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文介绍了意大利PO河区的长期雪水同等数据集，该数据集跨越1991年至2021年，每天的时间步骤和500 m的空间分辨率部分覆盖了阿尔卑斯山和阿彭宁的山脉。该数据是使用混合建模方法生成的，该方法将与基于物理的Geotop模型进行的水文建模，对气象数据的预处理以及对原位雪测量值和地球观测雪产物的同化，以提高模型估计的质量。基于可靠性，质量和领土分布选择的不同控制点，对数据集进行了严格的质量评估。整个控制点模拟和观察到的积雪之间的点验证表明，数据集分别模拟正常和相对较高的积雪条件的准确性。此外，将卫星雪地图与模拟的积雪深度图进行了比较，这是高程和方面的函数。 2D验证显示了随时间和空间的准确值，该值以沿着基本方向的雪线表示。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This paper presents a long-term snow water equivalent dataset in the Po River District, Italy, spanning from 1991 to 2021 at daily time step and 500 m spatial resolution partially covering the mountain ranges of Alps and Apennines. The data has been generated using a hybrid modelling approach integrating the hydrological modelling conducted with the physically-based GEOtop model, preprocessing of the meteorological data, and assimilation of in-situ snow measurements and Earth Observation snow products to enhance the quality of the model estimates. A rigorous quality assessment of the dataset has been performed at different control points selected based on reliability, quality, and territorial distribution. The point validation between simulated and observed snow depth across control points shows the accuracy of the dataset in simulating the normal and relatively high snow conditions, respectively. Additionally, satellite snow cover maps have been compared with simulated snow depth maps, as a function of elevation and aspect. 2D Validation shows accurate values over time and space, expressed in terms of snowline along the cardinal directions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04633-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4633_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature | 亚马逊森林砍伐对季节之间降水逆转的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08570-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Impact of Amazonian deforestation on precipitation reverses between seasons&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yingzuo Qin; Dashan Wang; Alan D. Ziegler; Bojie Fu; Zhenzhong Zeng&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;发现，使用一系列基于观测的数据集&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; ，发现热带森林砍伐会导致降水量大量减少。但是，基于卫星的空间统计分析的局限性阻碍了人们对重塑中尺度大气环流和区域降水回收在不同尺度上的作用的理解。这些作用被认为是非局部效应，这些作用与森林砍伐引起的蒸散量减少（ET）的局部效应不同。在这里，我们显示了整个潮湿和干旱季节对亚马逊森林砍伐的降水反应。在潮湿的季节，森林砍伐的网格值得注意的是降水量增加（0.96 mm月&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;个每百分比森林损失），主要归因于中尺度大气循环的增强（即非局部效应）。这些非局部性随着距离森林砍伐的网格的距离而增加，导致60公里以上的缓冲液的降水量显着减少。相反，在干旱季节，降水量减少，在所有分析缓冲液中都会减少，并且局部效果减少了ET的主导作用。我们的发现突出了局部效应与非局部效应之间的复杂平衡，以推动不同季节和尺度的森林砍伐 - 预测反应，并强调迫切需要解决亚马逊地区森林的快速而广泛的损失。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tropical deforestation was found to cause large reductions in precipitation using a range of observation-based datasets&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;. However, the limitations of satellite-based space-for-time statistical analysis have hindered understanding of the roles of reshaped mesoscale atmospheric circulation and regional precipitation recycling at different scales. These effects are considered nonlocal effects, which are distinct from the local effects governed by deforestation-induced reductions in evapotranspiration (ET). Here we show reversed precipitation responses to Amazon deforestation across wet and dry seasons. During the wet season, deforested grids experienced a noteworthy increase in precipitation (0.96 mm month&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; per percentage point forest loss), primarily attributed to enhanced mesoscale atmospheric circulation (that is, nonlocal effect). These nonlocal increases weaken with distance from deforested grids, leading to significant precipitation reductions in buffers beyond 60 km. Conversely, during the dry season, precipitation decreases in deforested grids and throughout all analysis buffers, with local effects from reduced ET dominating. Our findings highlight the intricate balance between local effects and nonlocal effects in driving deforestation–precipitation responses across different seasons and scales and emphasize the urgent need to address the rapid and extensive loss of forest in the Amazon region.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-024-08570-y/MediaObjects/41586_2024_8570_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 离散断裂网络建模重建裂缝阵列的演化和相关的岩石物理特性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02146-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Discrete fracture network modelling reconstructs fracture array evolution and related petrophysical properties over geological time&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Matthew S. Hodge; Mark Cottrell; Jochen Knies; Giulio Viola&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;破裂的岩石物理研究很少使用时间限制，从而阻碍了与骨折相关的渗透性和过去地理流体迁移期间的连通性估计。在这里，我们提出了一种概念方法，使用一种随机方法，该方法结合了绝对年龄，以重建地质时期的断裂阵列。生成“成年”离散裂缝网络模型，我们通过渐进的裂缝后折射模拟了从晚白垩纪/古代到泥盆纪的断裂岩量的液压行为。我们透露，对于所检查的岩体，最大主渗透率从9.47e-14 m &lt;sup&gt;2 2&lt;/sup&gt;增加到4.44e-13 m &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; （〜3个数量级），以及最大的水平渗透率方向从NEE-SW转移到NW-SE。同样，连通性度量随断裂饱和度增加，在白垩纪中部峰值。为了进行比较，日期的海上烃二次迁移可能与我们的结果相吻合。因此，对时间约束的裂缝集的后置是一种强大的方法，可以通过地质时代研究和量化岩石物理特性的动态演化。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Fractured rock petrophysical studies rarely use temporal constraints, thus hindering fracture-related permeability and connectivity estimation during past geofluid migration. Here we present a conceptual approach, using a stochastic method incorporating absolute ages to reconstruct fracture arrays back in geological time. Generating ‘grown’ discrete fracture network models, we simulate the hydraulic behaviour of fractured rock volumes from the late-Cretaceous/Palaeocene to the Devonian, via progressive fracture back-stripping. We reveal that for the examined rock mass, maximum principal permeability increased through time from 9.47e-14 m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; to 4.44e-13 m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; (~3 orders of magnitude) along with the maximum horizontal permeability orientation shifting from NE-SW to NW-SE. Similarly, the connectivity metric increased with fracture saturation, peaking in the mid-Cretaceous. For comparison, dated offshore hydrocarbon secondary migration potentially coincides with our results. Back-stripping of time-constrained fracture sets is therefore a powerful method to investigate and quantify the dynamic evolution of petrophysical properties through geological time.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02146-y/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2146_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 带注释的数据集和基准测试，用于检测内陆水域的浮动碎片</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04594-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;An annotated Dataset and Benchmark for Detecting Floating Debris in Inland Waters&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Guangchao Qiao; Mingxiang Yang; Hao Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;海洋垃圾是对海洋生态系统的严重威胁，及时清除内陆水域的浮动废物可有效防止漂浮的碎片进入大海。准确的对象检测系统是有效清除浮子的先决条件。但是，水中的复杂光条件，小尺寸的物体和其他因素对浮动物体检测构成了巨大挑战。为了促进浮动物体污染问题的解决方案，并促进了AI技术在水行业中的应用，我们提出了基于基于海岸的拍摄设备的iWHR_AI_LABLE_FLOATER_V1从真实水景中收集的第一个浮点数据集。该数据集由3000张图像组成，其中包含准确的注释信息，以支持基于视觉的水面浮点检测任务。我们进行了许多基线实验，以评估该数据集主流对象检测算法的性能。结果表明，包括最先进的模型Yolov9在内的模型的检测准确性都很低，这也表明浮动对象检测是一项具有挑战性的任务。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Marine litter is a serious threat to marine ecosystems, and the timely removal of floating waste from inland waters is effective in preventing floating debris from entering the sea. An accurate object detection system is a prerequisite for efficiently clearing floaters. However, complex light conditions in the water, small size objects and other factors pose a huge challenge for floating object detection. In order to facilitate the solution of the floating object pollution problem and promote the application of AI technology in the water industry, we proposed the first floater dataset of waters collected from real water scenarios based on shore-based filming equipment, IWHR_AI_Lable_Floater_V1. The dataset consists of 3000 images containing accurate annotation information to support vision-based water surface floater detection tasks. We conducted a number of baseline experiments to evaluate the performance of mainstream object detection algorithms on this dataset. The results show that the detection accuracies of the models, including the state-of-the-art model YOLOv9, are all low, which also indicates that floating object detection is a challenging task.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04594-9/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4594_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 干旱指数对历史土地使用和土地覆盖变化的不同反应</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00978-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Divergent response of aridity index to historical land use and land cover change&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Tao Tang; Jun Ge; Haiyun Shi; Junji Cao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;通过使用模型模拟，我们显示自1850年以来的历史土地使用和土地覆盖变化影响了全球的干旱指数（AI），从而在不同地区引起了不同的反应。在本地，AI倾向于在造林区域和大多数潮湿区域中增加（潮湿）。由于这些变化，潮湿区域的面积不足以占全球土地面积的0.22％，牺牲了旱地。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;By using model simulations, we show that historical land use and land cover change since 1850 has impacted aridity index (AI) worldwide, causing divergent responses in different regions. Locally, AI tends to increase (getting humid) in reforestation regions and most humid regions. Owing to these changes, the area of the humid zone expanded insignificantly by 0.22% of the global land area at the expense of drylands.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00978-1/MediaObjects/41612_2025_978_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 跨越1940  -  2023年的地表水质的全面数据集用于经验和ML采用的研究</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04715-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A Comprehensive Dataset of Surface Water Quality Spanning 1940-2023 for Empirical and ML Adopted Research&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Md. Rajaul Karim; M. M. Mahbubul Syeed; Ashifur Rahman; Khondkar Ayaz Rabbani; Kaniz Fatema; Razib Hayat Khan; Md Shakhawat Hossain; Mohammad Faisal Uddin&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;对地表水质的评估和监测对于粮食安全，公共卫生和生态系统保护至关重要。尽管水质监测是一种已知现象，但在全球范围内为地表水提供了全面且协调的数据集的努力。这项研究提出了一个全面的地表水质数据集，可保留数据的时空变异性，完整性，一致性和数据深度，以促进经验和数据驱动的评估，预测和预测。该数据集由来自世界五个著名国家，例如美国，美国，加拿大，爱尔兰，英国和中国的各种来源组装，包括区域和全球水质数据库，水管理组织以及个人研究项目。最终的数据集由跨越1940年至2023年的八个水质参数的282万个测量值组成。该数据集可以支持水质模型的荟萃分析，并可以促进基于机器的数据（ML）数据以及基于模型的空间和时间驱动器研究的研究，并促进了空间和时间驱动因素的调查，以及在整体规模的交叉范围的地表水质的模式。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Assessment and monitoring of surface water quality are essential for food security, public health, and ecosystem protection. Although water quality monitoring is a known phenomenon, little effort has been made to offer a comprehensive and harmonized dataset for surface water at the global scale. This study presents a comprehensive surface water quality dataset that preserves spatio-temporal variability, integrity, consistency, and depth of the data to facilitate empirical and data-driven evaluation, prediction, and forecasting. The dataset is assembled from a range of sources, including regional and global water quality databases, water management organizations, and individual research projects from five prominent countries in the world, e.g., the USA, Canada, Ireland, England, and China. The resulting dataset consists of 2.82 million measurements of eight water quality parameters that span 1940 - 2023. This dataset can support meta-analysis of water quality models and can facilitate Machine Learning (ML) based data and model-driven investigation of the spatial and temporal drivers and patterns of surface water quality at a cross-regional to global scale.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04715-4/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4715_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | Bedmap3更新了南极洲的冰床，表面和厚度网格数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04672-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Bedmap3 updated ice bed, surface and thickness gridded datasets for Antarctica&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hamish D. Pritchard; Peter T. Fretwell; Alice C. Fremand; Julien A. Bodart; James D. Kirkham; Alan Aitken; Jonathan Bamber; Robin Bell; Cesidio Bianchi; Robert G. Bingham; Donald D. Blankenship; Gino Casassa; Knut Christianson; Howard Conway; Hugh F. J. Corr; Xiangbin Cui; Detlef Damaske; Volkmar Damm; Boris Dorschel; Reinhard Drews; Graeme Eagles; Olaf Eisen; Hannes Eisermann; Fausto Ferraccioli; Elena Field; René Forsberg; Steven Franke; Vikram Goel; Siva Prasad Gogineni; Jamin Greenbaum; Benjamin Hills; Richard C. A. Hindmarsh; Andrew O. Hoffman; Nicholas Holschuh; John W. Holt; Angelika Humbert; Robert W. Jacobel; Daniela Jansen; Adrian Jenkins; Wilfried Jokat; Lenneke Jong; Tom A. Jordan; Edward C. King; Jack Kohler; William Krabill; Joséphine Maton; Mette Kusk Gillespie; Kirsty Langley; Joohan Lee; German Leitchenkov; Cartlon Leuschen; Bruce Luyendyk; Joseph A. MacGregor; Emma MacKie; Geir Moholdt; Kenichi Matsuoka; Mathieu Morlighem; Jérémie Mouginot; Frank O. Nitsche; Ole A. Nost; John Paden; Frank Pattyn; Sergey Popov; Eric Rignot; David M. Rippin; Andrés Rivera; Jason L. Roberts; Neil Ross; Antonia Ruppel; Dustin M. Schroeder; Martin J. Siegert; Andrew M. Smith; Daniel Steinhage; Michael Studinger; Bo Sun; Ignazio Tabacco; Kirsty J. Tinto; Stefano Urbini; David G. Vaughan; Douglas S. Wilson; Duncan A. Young; Achille Zirizzotti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;我们提出了Bedmap3，这是最新的网格产品套件，描述了60°S南极南极南极的地面高度，冰厚度以及海底和冰川床升高。 BedMap3均包含并增加了先前用于BedMap2的所有后1950年后数据集，其中包括15个数据提供商的84次新的Aero-Geophysical Surveys，另外5200万个数据点和190万行的测量线。这些努力填补了包括主要山脉和南极洲东部，南极海岸线和南极半岛的显着空白。我们的新Bedmap3/Rings接地线类似地将最近的多个映射整合到一个单一的，空间连贯的功能中。结合更新的表面地貌，冰架厚度，岩石露头和测深的图，Bedmap3揭示了南极冰的冰山下景观和分布，提供了解释大陆规模景观演化的新机会，并为南极冰板的过去和未来的进化提供了新的机会。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We present Bedmap3, the latest suite of gridded products describing surface elevation, ice-thickness and the seafloor and subglacial bed elevation of the Antarctic south of 60 °S. Bedmap3 incorporates and adds to all post-1950s datasets previously used for Bedmap2, including 84 new aero-geophysical surveys by 15 data providers, an additional 52 million data points and 1.9 million line-kilometres of measurement. These efforts have filled notable gaps including in major mountain ranges and the deep interior of East Antarctica, along West Antarctic coastlines and on the Antarctic Peninsula. Our new Bedmap3/RINGS grounding line similarly consolidates multiple recent mappings into a single, spatially coherent feature. Combined with updated maps of surface topography, ice shelf thickness, rock outcrops and bathymetry, Bedmap3 reveals in much greater detail the subglacial landscape and distribution of Antarctica’s ice, providing new opportunities to interpret continental-scale landscape evolution and to model the past and future evolution of the Antarctic ice sheets.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04672-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4672_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | GLEAM4：从1980年到现在为0.1分辨率的全球土地蒸发和土壤水分数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04610-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;GLEAM4: global land evaporation and soil moisture dataset at 0.1 resolution from 1980 to near present&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Diego G. Miralles; Olivier Bonte; Akash Koppa; Oscar M. Baez-Villanueva; Emma Tronquo; Feng Zhong; Hylke E. Beck; Petra Hulsman; Wouter Dorigo; Niko E. C. Verhoest; Shekoofeh Haghdoost&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;陆地蒸发在调节气候和水资源中起着至关重要的作用。在这里，我们提供了一个连续的，每日的数据集，涵盖了1980  -  2023年，其空间分辨率为0.1°，该数据集使用第四代Amsterdam模型（GLEAM）产生。 GLEAM4包含混合建模中的发展，从涡流和SAPFLOW数据中学习蒸发应力。它具有改进的关键因素的代表，例如拦截，大气水需求，土壤水分和植物进入地下水。估计值与现有的全局蒸发产品相互比较，并针对原位测量值进行了验证，包括来自473个涡流协调位点的数据，显示中位相关性为0.73，根平方误差为0.95 mm d- &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;和kling-Gling-Gupta效率为0.49。全球土地蒸发估计为68.5×10 &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;年&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ，归因于蒸腾作用62％。除了实际的蒸发及其成分（蒸腾，截距损失，土壤蒸发等）之外，数据集还提供土壤水分，潜在的蒸发，明智的热通量和蒸发压力，从而促进了广泛的水文，气候和生态研究。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Terrestrial evaporation plays a crucial role in modulating climate and water resources. Here, we present a continuous, daily dataset covering 1980–2023 with a 0.1°spatial resolution, produced using the fourth generation of the Global Land Evaporation Amsterdam Model (GLEAM). GLEAM4 embraces developments in hybrid modelling, learning evaporative stress from eddy-covariance and sapflow data. It features improved representation of key factors such as interception, atmospheric water demand, soil moisture, and plant access to groundwater. Estimates are inter-compared with existing global evaporation products and validated against in situ measurements, including data from 473 eddy-covariance sites, showing a median correlation of 0.73, root-mean-square error of 0.95 mm d&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;, and Kling–Gupta efficiency of 0.49. Global land evaporation is estimated at 68.5 × 10&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;, with 62% attributed to transpiration. Beyond actual evaporation and its components (transpiration, interception loss, soil evaporation, etc.), the dataset also provides soil moisture, potential evaporation, sensible heat flux, and evaporative stress, facilitating a wide range of hydrological, climatic, and ecological studies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04610-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4610_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 驱动旋风，温暖的传送带和大气河的运动学分析</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00942-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A kinematic analysis of extratropical cyclones, warm conveyor belts and atmospheric rivers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Helen F. Dacre; Peter A. Clark&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;中纬度天气系统在造成洪水，风损和相关的社会影响方面起着重要作用。数值建模和观察方法的进步导致了中纬度概要和动态研究的众多概念模型的发展。随着这些模型扩散，将新的见解纳入凝聚力的理解可能是具有挑战性的。本文使用运动学观点来解释中纬度研究，以综合各种概念并创建大气河生命周期的示意图。我们的分析表明，尽管有不同的方法，定义和术语来描述驱动旋风旋风，温暖的输送带气流和大气河流，但推动其形成和发育的基本机制还是一致的。因此，在独立研究这些功能的同时，重要的是要认识到它们都是更大的大气流程模式的一部分。我们希望这种运动学方法将成为联系这些现象研究的桥梁。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mid-latitude weather systems play a significant role in causing floods, wind damage, and related societal impacts. Advances in numerical modeling and observational methods have led to the development of numerous conceptual models in mid-latitude synoptic and dynamical research. As these models proliferate, integrating new insights into a cohesive understanding can be challenging. This paper uses a kinematic perspective to interpret mid-latitude research in a way that synthesises various concepts and create a schematic diagram of an atmospheric river lifecycle. Our analysis demonstrates that, despite varying methods, definitions, and terminology used to describe extratropical cyclones, warm conveyor belt airflows, and atmospheric rivers, the underlying mechanisms driving their formation and development are consistent. Thus, while studying these features independently is valuable, it is important to recognise that they are all part of a larger atmospheric flow pattern. We hope this kinematic approach will serve as a bridge to link research on these phenomena.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00942-z/MediaObjects/41612_2025_942_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>