<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 02:23:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 加剧大坝引起的中国河流系统的破裂</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02416-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Exacerbating dam-induced fragmentation in China’s river systems&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Fan Chenyu; Linghong Ke; Jida Wang; Jim Best; Yunlin Zhang; Yongwei Sheng; Kai Liu; Tan Chen; Fanxuan Zeng; Pengfei Zhan; Jingying Zhu; Jian Cheng; Chunqiao Song&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;堵塞引起的碎片化可以说是全球河流系统中最明显的人为障碍，但由于大坝信息的限制，其时空进化仍然很糟糕，尤其是在诸如中国等迅速发展的地区。在这里，我们在空间和时间上建立了中国河流水库的清单，并评估了1970  -  2020年期间对河流破裂的长期轨迹。我们发现，大坝数量从1019升至17,414，促进了总容量的近增加。因此，约62％的主要河流占中国河流总流量的90％，已经分散了。特别是，在1980年代和21世纪初的大坝建设加剧大大改变了中国主要河流的自由流动条件，包括长江和黄河。在五十年的时间里，中国自由流动的主要河流降低了38.9％，削弱了河流生态系统并威胁到长距离迁移鱼类。值得注意的是，我们的精细分辨率结果表明，小河流的长度比先前报道的长3-16倍，揭示了正在进行的河流破碎化扩散到脆弱的高空源水中。这强调了迫切需要考虑这种严重零散的河流系统的社会和生态环境影响，并与联合国可持续发展目标促进可持续实践相吻合。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Damming-induced fragmentation is arguably the most pronounced anthropogenic disturbance of global river systems, yet its spatio-temporal evolution remains poorly understood due to constraints in dam information, particularly in rapidly developing regions like China. Here we establish a spatially and temporally explicit inventory of Chinese riverine reservoirs and assess the long-term trajectory of damming impacts on river fragmentation during 1970–2020. We find that the number of dams rocketed from 1019 to 17,414, promoting a nearly-fourfold rise in total capacity. Consequently, ~62% of the main rivers, accounting for 90% of the total river discharge in China, have become fragmented. In particular, intensified dam construction in the 1980s and early-21st century substantially altered the free-flowing conditions of main rivers in China, including the Yangtze and Yellow rivers. Over five decades, free-flowing main rivers in China decreased by 38.9%, weakening fluvial ecosystems and threatening long-distance migratory fish species. Notably, our fine-resolution results show that small rivers are fragmented at lengths 3-16 times greater than previously reported, revealing the ongoing river fragmentation spreading to fragile high-altitude headwaters. This underscores the urgent need to consider the societal and eco-environmental effects of such a severely fragmented river system, and aligns with the UN SDGs in promoting sustainable practices.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02416-9/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2416_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>