<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 02:24:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 水源和陆地电容器效应刺激观测到的夏季北极湿润和变暖</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-03000-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Water sources and land capacitor effects stimulate observed summer Arctic moistening and warming&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ian Baxter; Qinghua Ding; Thomas Ballinger; Hailong Wang; Marika Holland; Hailan Wang; Zhe Li; Yutian Wu; Nicole Feldl; Jennifer E. Kay; Bin Guan; Jiang Zhu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;再分析中最近夏季北极湿润趋势的主要来源尚不确定，这阻碍了对观测到的北极变暖归因于水蒸气变化的辐射影响的归因。在这里，我们在社区地球系统模型中使用组合的在线数值水示踪剂和循环助推方法来跟踪初始来源之外的水蒸气来源。近几十年来，北半球夏季大范围环流的趋势推动了北极的湿润，对北极的辐射收支产生了巨大影响，占加强水汽辐射反馈的94%。我们确定了提供北极水蒸气反馈的两个关键区域：北美东北部和欧亚大陆西部/中部。在这两个地区，西南大西洋和东欧的反气旋环流通过冬季和春季的降水将水分从热带海洋向极地转移到高纬度陆地。在夏季，陆地上的蒸散释放出这些水蒸气，并通过风输送到北极。我们将陆地水分储存和释放的这种序列称为陆地电容器效应。因此，环流变化对高纬度地区水汽输送和陆地-大气相互作用的影响代表了北极近期湿润和变暖的潜在机制。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The primary sources of recent summer Arctic moistening trends in reanalysis are uncertain, hindering attribution of observed Arctic warming due to radiative effects from water vapor changes. Here, we use a combined online numerical water tracer and circulation nudging approach in the Community Earth System Model to track the sources of water vapor beyond its initial sources. Trends in boreal summer large-scale circulation have driven moistening of the Arctic over recent decades, having a large impact on the Arctic radiative budget, accounting for 94% of the strengthening water vapor radiative feedback. We identify two key regions supplying the Arctic water vapor feedback: Northeast North America and western/central Eurasia. In both regions, anticyclonic circulations over the southwest Atlantic and eastern Europe move moisture from the tropical oceans poleward to high latitude land through precipitation in winter and spring. During summer, evapotranspiration over land releases this water vapor, and it is transported by winds into the Arctic. We refer to this sequence of terrestrial moisture storage and release as the land capacitor effect. Thus, the impacts of circulation changes on poleward moisture transport and land-atmosphere interactions over high latitudes represent the underlying mechanisms of the recent moistening and warming in the Arctic.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-27066-x/MediaObjects/41598_2025_27066_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 节水措施降低灌溉降温效果</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-03030-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Irrigation cooling effect reduced by water-saving practices&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Chao Zhang; Quansheng Ge; Wim Thiery; Yan Li; Shushi Peng; Guoyong Leng; Guosong Zhao; Zhenong Jin; Wei Li; Kun Zhang; Xuezhen Zhang; Songjun Han; Geli Zhang; Xiangming Xiao; Jinwei Dong&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;灌溉改变了陆地与大气的相互作用，冷却了地表并缓解了极端高温。然而，全球向节水灌溉技术的转变引发了关于用水受限下灌溉的气候调节能力的新问题。通过对中国二十年的高分辨率卫星观测，我们发现节水的广泛采用大大削弱了灌溉的生物物理冷却效果，特别是在夏末和早春。全国白天地表降温下降 0.05 K/十年 (15%)，干旱地区高达 0.20 K/十年 (9%)，这主要是由于土壤蒸发减少和感热通量增加。由于作物蒸腾作用增强，半干旱和半湿润地区不存在这种趋势。相反，夜间降温每十年增加 0.04 K，这可能是由于土壤热容量降低和辐射反馈所致。这些发现揭示了用水效率和气候缓解之间正在出现的权衡，呼吁考虑地球系统模型和气候变化预测中不断变化的灌溉实践。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Irrigation modifies land-atmosphere interactions, cooling land surface and mitigating heat extremes. However, the global shift toward water-saving irrigation technologies raises new questions about the climate regulation capacity of irrigation under constrained water use. Using two decades of high-resolution satellite observations across China, we show that widespread water-saving adoption has substantially weakened irrigation’s biophysical cooling effects, particularly in late summer and early spring. Daytime land surface cooling declined by 0.05 K/decade (15%) nationally and up to 0.20 K/decade (9%) in arid regions, primarily due to reduced soil evaporation and increased sensible heat flux. This trend was absent in semi-arid and semi-humid regions because of enhanced crop transpiration. Conversely, nighttime cooling intensified by 0.04 K per decade, likely driven by lower soil thermal capacity and radiative feedbacks. These findings reveal an emerging trade-off between water-use efficiency and climate mitigation, calling for considering evolving irrigation practices in Earth system models and climate change projections.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-27163-x/MediaObjects/41598_2025_27163_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>