<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 02:13:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Water | 跟踪网格水平的淡水边界超过全球供应链，从消费到影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00420-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Tracking grid-level freshwater boundary exceedance along global supply chains from consumption to impact&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Siyu Hou; Jingwen Huo; Xu Zhao; Xiaoxi Wang; Xinxin Zhang; Dandan Zhao; Martin R. Tillotson; Yuli Shan; Martina Flörke; Wei Guo; Jing Meng; Klaus Hubacek&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;消费行为通过相互联系的供应链在本地和全球施加压力，阻碍了可持续发展目标6（清洁水和卫生）和12（负责消费和生产）的实现。但是，将空间尺度的水耗尽热点与最终消耗联系起来，同时反映了水间竞争，这是一项挑战。在这项研究中，我们使用2015年的数据估计了由于人类水的戒断而导致的区域淡水边界（RFB）的全球超出性，从而使跨不同空间尺度的热点鉴定了热点。为了减少不确定性，我们使用了15个全球水文模型和5种环境流量要求方法的平均估计。我们通过多区域输入 - 输出模型的出现，进一步将超出的热点归因于245个经济体和134个部门的最终消费。我们精致的框架揭示了以前的区域热点与通过国际贸易消费之间未知的联系。 Notably, we found that 24% of grid-level RFB exceedance (718 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr &lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; ; 95% confidence interval of 659–776 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr &lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; ) was outsourced through trade, with the largest flows (52 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr &lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; ; 95% confidence interval of 47–56 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr &lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; ) from water-stressed South and Central Asia to arid West Asia.对谷物和其他农产品的需求占据了基于全球消费的RFB的超出性（29％），而纺织品，机械和设备的出口加剧了新兴经济体内部制造中心的领土超出领土。我们的方法促进了沿供应链沿供应链的全球水稀缺热点的追踪，以及在较小规模的责任分配。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Consumption behaviours exert pressure on water resources both locally and globally through interconnected supply chains, hindering the achievement of Sustainable Development Goals 6 (Clean water and sanitation) and 12 (Responsible consumption and production). However, it is challenging to link hotspots of water depletion across spatial scales to final consumption while reflecting intersectoral competition for water. In this study, we estimated the global exceedance of regional freshwater boundaries (RFBs) due to human water withdrawal at a 5-arcmin grid scale using 2015 data, enabling the identification of hotspots across different spatial scales. To reduce uncertainty, we used average estimates from 15 global hydrological models and 5 environmental flow requirement methods. We further attributed the hotspots of exceedance to final consumption across 245 economies and 134 sectors via the multi-region input–output model EMERGING. Our refined framework revealed previously unknown connections between regional hotspots and consumption through international trade. Notably, we found that 24% of grid-level RFB exceedance (718 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;; 95% confidence interval of 659–776 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;) was outsourced through trade, with the largest flows (52 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;; 95% confidence interval of 47–56 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;) from water-stressed South and Central Asia to arid West Asia. The demand for cereals and other agricultural products dominated global consumption-based RFB exceedance (29%), while the exports of textiles and machinery and equipment exacerbated territorial exceedance in manufacturing hubs within emerging economies. Our methodology facilitates the tracing of global hotspots of water scarcity along supply chains and the assignment of responsibilities at finer scales.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00420-z/MediaObjects/44221_2025_420_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 冰山下水放大南极对海平面上升的贡献</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-58375-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Subglacial water amplifies Antarctic contributions to sea-level rise&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Chen Zhao; Rupert Gladstone; Thomas Zwinger; Fabien Gillet-Chaulet; Yu Wang; Justine Caillet; Pierre Mathiot; Leopekka Saraste; Eliot Jager; Benjamin K. Galton-Fenzi; Poul Christoffersen; Matt A. King&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;南极对全球海平面上升的贡献是深刻的不确定性，怀疑是冰山的水下水，但其影响尚不清楚。我们证明，冰盖底部的水会影响滑动行为，并且其排除在模型中可以低估海平面上升的投影并延迟预测的倾斜点的发作。在这里，我们使用南极冰盖模型（Elmer/Ice）来探索对冰基水压的不同假设如何影响2015年至2300年的海平面上升预测。我们的结果表明，融合冰山下水可以在整个南极冰层上纳入冰排放，而在标准级别上最多三倍的速度，可以使2.2级别的高级升级为2300级别的效果，从而稳定了2.2级的效果，并效果2300级别的效果。相对于将有效压力简化为空间恒定系数的情况，接地线附近的接地线通量超过2300。特定于盆地的反应差异很大，有些情况将临界点提高了40年。这些发现强调了将不断发展的冰川水文学整合到冰盖模型中的关键需求。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Antarctica’s contribution to global sea-level rise is deeply uncertain, with subglacial water suspected to play a critical role, yet its impact remains unclear. We demonstrate that water at the base of ice sheets influences sliding behaviour and that its exclusion from models can underestimate sea-level rise projections and delay the predicted onset of tipping points. Here we use an Antarctic Ice Sheet model (Elmer/Ice) to explore how different assumptions about water pressure at the ice base affect sea-level rise projections from 2015 to 2300. Our results indicate that incorporating subglacial water can amplify ice discharge across the Antarctic Ice Sheet by up to threefold above the standard approach, potentially contributing an additional 2.2 metres to sea-level rise by 2300. Notably, a smoothly decreasing basal drag near the grounding line more than doubles grounding line flux by 2300 relative to scenarios where effective pressure is simplified into a spatially constant coefficient. Basin-specific responses vary significantly, with some scenarios advancing tipping points by up to 40 years. These findings underscore the critical need to integrate evolving subglacial hydrology into ice sheet models.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-58375-4/MediaObjects/41467_2025_58375_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | Fanyun-3卫星的微波集成干旱指数的全球近实时数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04935-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A global near real-time dataset of Microwave Integrated Drought Index from the Fengyun-3 satellites&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Anzhi Zhang; Hao Gao; Ronghan Xu; Xiaoqing Li; Huichen Zhao; Gensuo Jia&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;随着气候变暖的增加，对生态系统，农业和水资源构成广泛的风险，干旱变得越来越频繁和激烈，因此有效且及时的干旱监测对于干旱评估，管理和缓解至关重要。在这里，我们通过整合了不一致的纠正范围的3B/C/D衍生的微波降水，土壤湿度，土壤湿度和土地表面温度，从2014年6月到现在，我们介​​绍了Fengyun-3微波集成干旱指数（FY-3 MIDI）的全球每月和为期10天的干旱数据集（FY-3 MIDI）。对数据集进行了评估和验证，并针对标准化的降水蒸散指数，自校准的帕尔默干旱严重程度指数和0.25°的非财产MIDI进行了验证。 FY-3 MIDI可以有效地观察参考数据集捕获的干旱状况和特征，并且在监测气象干旱的能力中可靠地监测气象干旱。基于运营Fengyun-3系列卫星，它以每月和十天的时间尺度实时提供了宝贵的运营服务，保证了当前和未来的连续申请，以支持全球和地区干旱监测和评估。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Droughts have become more frequent and intense with increasing climate warming, posing widespread risks on ecosystem, agricultural, and water resources, therefore effective and timely drought monitoring is critical to drought assessment, management, and mitigation. Here, we presented a global monthly and ten-day drought dataset of the Fengyun-3 Microwave Integrated Drought Index (FY-3 MIDI) by integrating the inconsistency corrected FY-3B/C/D derived microwave precipitation, soil moisture, and land surface temperature with optimal weights from June 2014 to present. The dataset was evaluated and validated against the Standardized Precipitation Evapotranspiration Index, the Self-calibrating Palmer Drought Severity Index, and the non-FY MIDI at 0.25°. The FY-3 MIDI can effectively observe drought condition and characteristics as captured by the reference datasets, and it was reliable in monitoring meteorological drought with the ability to work in all-weather condition. Based on the operational Fengyun-3 series satellite, it provided valuable operational service in near real-time on a monthly and ten-day time scale, guaranteeing present and future continuous applications to support global and regional drought monitoring and assessment.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04935-8/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4935_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>