<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:30:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 大气水分升高升级了大气河在南极气候系统中的未来影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02333-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Rising atmospheric moisture escalates the future impact of atmospheric rivers in the Antarctic climate system&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Michelle L. Maclennan; Andrew C. Winters; Christine A. Shields; Rudradutt Thaker; Léonard Barthelemy; Francis Codron; Jonathan D. Wille&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;尽管它们相对罕见，但大气河还是南极表面质量平衡的关键因素。但是，大气河流在调节南极海平面贡献中的未来作用是不确定性的主要领域。在这里，我们利用高分辨率的气候模拟表明，南极大气河对大气水分的未来增加非常敏感，从而导致大气河频率增加了一倍，从2066-2100的降水量增加了2.5倍，从2066  -  2100年下降，在当今的阈值中，大气阈值对大气河流的检测。但是，未来的降水影响至关重要取决于检测阈值：考虑到阈值的水分增加会导致大气河频率的较小，区域变化，这主要是由于极性喷射最大风速的向东转移。我们的结果强调了使用大型集合来量化南极大气河对预计水分变异性的反应的重要性，这在仅使用少数合奏成员时可能不会被捕获。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Despite their relative rarity, atmospheric rivers are key contributors to the surface mass balance of Antarctica. However, the future role of atmospheric rivers in modulating Antarctic sea-level contributions is a major area of uncertainty. Here, we leverage high-resolution climate simulations to show that Antarctic atmospheric rivers are highly sensitive to future increases in atmospheric moisture, leading to a doubling of atmospheric river frequencies and 2.5 × increase in precipitation from 2066–2100 under present-day thresholds for atmospheric river detection. However, future precipitation impacts are critically dependent on the detection threshold: accounting for moisture increases in the threshold produces smaller, regional changes in atmospheric river frequency, primarily resulting from an eastward shift in the polar jet maximum wind speeds. Our results underscore the importance of using large ensembles to quantify Antarctic atmospheric river responses to variability in projected moisture, which may not be captured when using only a few ensemble members.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02333-x/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2333_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 2022年2月如何重新定义澳大利亚的极端洪水</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02307-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;How February 2022 redefines extreme floods in Australia&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Julien Lerat; Jai Vaze&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2022年2月，由于强烈的降雨和接近饱和的初始土壤水状况，澳大利亚东部遭受了极端的洪水。这导致了创纪录的水位和洪水量，导致澳大利亚对一次洪水事件的总保险总索赔。在这里，我们分析了该事件的物理因素，并将其与澳大利亚的大量洪水进行比较，其历史可以追溯到1950年。我们的发现表明，2022年2月对设计洪水量的影响最大，年度超高概率为1％，预计该地区的平均地区将增加16％。此外，这种洪水促使国家洪水风险管理的重大变化，包括升级洪水警告网络以及对洪水保险部门的全面审查。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In February 2022, eastern Australia experienced an extreme flood due to a combination of intense rainfall and close to saturation initial soil water conditions. It resulted in record-breaking water levels and flood volumes, leading to Australia’s largest total insurance claim for a single flood event. Here we analyse the physical factors underlying this event and compare them with a large dataset of floods in Australia dating back to 1950. Our findings show that February 2022 had the largest impact on design flood volumes with a 1% annual exceedance probability, which are expected to increase by 16% on average across the affected region. Additionally, this flood prompted major changes in national flood risk management, including upgrades to flood warning networks and a comprehensive review of the flood insurance sector.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02307-z/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2307_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Sustainability | 由不可持续的地下水灌溉驱动的三角洲淡水短缺</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-025-01566-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Deltaic freshwater scarcity driven by unsustainable groundwater-fed irrigation&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Augusto Getirana; Nishan Kumar Biswas; Sujay Kumar; Wanshu Nie; Shahryar Ahmad; Fadji Maina; Nazmus Sakib; Md Sazzad Hossain; Robin Kumar Biswas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;南亚通过提高该地区农作物生产率和季风含水层补给率，从地下水抽水中受益于旱季灌溉。根据数据驱动的集成建模系统，我们提供了数值证据，表明不可持续的地下水灌溉对地表淡水的可用性的影响远远超出了以前的理解。我们的结果证实了先前研究的发现表明，在2002  -  2021年间潮湿季节期间的地下水充电率提高，但是这些速率不足以使含水层恢复，逐渐耗尽了恒河 - 恒河 - 布拉赫马普拉 - 梅格纳三角洲的地下水。主要发现是，这种增加的充值会导致季风期间的地表径流和碱流产生下降，从而导致洪水危险降低（有益的结果），但可用于耕种的地表淡水较少，这可能会触发额外的地下水需求。内陆地下水喂养的灌溉引起的沿海洪水风险下降超过了海平面上升约五到十倍。减少的径流也可能会增加海水的侵入，这是由于淡水较少以推动海水驱动的驱动，从而进一步增加了淡水稀缺性。这尤其令人担忧，因为该地区一直处于海平面上升和沉没土地的下降。我们对这一三角洲的发现具有全球影响，因为人类和气候在全球范围内越来越压力沿海和三角洲生态系统。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Southern Asia benefits from groundwater pumping for dry-season irrigation by increasing both crop productivity and monsoon aquifer recharge rates in the region. On the basis of a data-driven integrated modelling system, we provide numerical evidence that the impacts of unsustainable groundwater-fed irrigation on surface freshwater availability go beyond what was previously understood. Our results confirm findings from previous studies showing increased groundwater recharge rates during wet seasons over 2002–2021, but these rates are insufficient for aquifers to recover, gradually depleting groundwater across the Ganges–Brahmaputra–Meghna delta. The main findings are that this increased recharge causes a drop in surface runoff and baseflow generation during the monsoons, resulting in lower flood risk (a beneficial outcome), but also less surface freshwater available for farming, which may trigger additional groundwater demand. The drop in coastal flood risk induced by inland groundwater-fed irrigation exceeds the increase caused by sea level rise by about five- to tenfold. Reduced runoff may also increase seawater intrusion, driven by less freshwater to push ocean water away, further increasing freshwater scarcity. This is particularly concerning, since the region has been under rising sea levels and sinking lands. Our findings over this delta have global implications, as humans and climate are increasingly pressuring coastal and deltaic ecosystems worldwide.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41893-025-01566-0/MediaObjects/41893_2025_1566_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 火星斜坡上的条纹干燥</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-59395-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Streaks on martian slopes are dry&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Valentin Tertius Bickel; Adomas Valantinas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;斜坡条纹是火星斜率上的深色反照率特征，它们会自发地形成，并逐渐消失了数十年。与季节性重复的斜坡线条一起，条纹形成还归因于水过程，这意味着在火星表面上存在瞬时但大量的液态水或盐水，对当今的火星的可居住性具有重要意义。在这里，我们使用一种深厚的学习方法来创建第一个一致的全球目录，为半百万个单独的斜率连续。我们表明，坡度的变形可修改不到火星表面的0.1％，但每年火星年的几种全球风暴等效物都可能在火星尘埃周期中发挥重要作用。我们的全球地球统计分析挑战了潮湿的形成模型，而是支持季节性灰尘递送和诸如风能和气象撞击之类的充满活力的触发因素。我们进一步确定了重复的斜坡形成，季节性灰尘沉积和尘埃魔鬼活动之间的定性时空关系。我们的发现表明，现代火星的斜坡通常不会体验到水或盐水的短暂流动，这意味着可以探索轴承痕迹地形而不会引起行星保护的问题。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Slope streaks are dark albedo features on martian slopes that form spontaneously and fade over years to decades. Along with seasonally recurring slope lineae, streak formation has been attributed to aqueous processes, implying the presence of transient yet substantial amounts of liquid water or brines on Mars’ surface, with important implications for present-day Mars’ habitability. Here, we use a deep learning-enabled approach to create the first consistent, global catalog of half a million individual slope streaks. We show that slope streaks modify less than 0.1% of the martian surface, but transport several global storm equivalents of dust per Mars year, potentially playing a major role in the martian dust cycle. Our global geostatistical analysis challenges wet streak formation models and instead supports dry streak formation, driven by seasonal dust delivery and energetic triggers like wind and meteoritic impacts. We further identify a qualitative, spatiotemporal relation between recurring slope lineae formation, seasonal dust deposition, and dust devil activity. Our findings suggest that modern Mars’ slopes do not commonly experience transient flows of water or brines, implying that streak bearing terrain can be explored without raising planetary protection concerns.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-59395-w/MediaObjects/41467_2025_59395_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Climate Change | 超过1.5°C后，不可逆的冰川变化和槽水数百年</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-025-02318-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Irreversible glacier change and trough water for centuries after overshooting 1.5 °C&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lilian Schuster; Fabien Maussion; David R. Rounce; Lizz Ultee; Patrick Schmitt; Fabrice Lacroix; Thomas L. Frölicher; Carl-Friedrich Schleussner&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;超过前工业水平以上的全球变暖超过1.5°C已成为一种明显的可能性，但是这种过冲对山地冰川的后果及其对提高海平面和影响水分的贡献的后果尚不清楚。在这里，我们表明超过并返回到1.5°C以下将对冰川质量和几个世纪的径流产生不可逆转的后果。全球气候和冰川模拟计划，即3.0°C的峰值和排列情况将导致全球冰川质量损失增加2500，而不是将变暖限制在1.5°C而不会过度冲击的情况下。在峰值温度后冰川再生的盆地中，冰川径流比冰川稳定的情况更降低，这是我们称为“槽水”的现象。一半研究的冰川盆地显示出冰川径流减少，而峰值变暖后几十年没有几个世纪。这些发现强调了近期排放降低和限制温度过冲的紧迫性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Exceeding 1.5 °C of global warming above pre-industrial levels has become a distinct possibility, yet the consequences of such an overshoot for mountain glaciers and their contribution to raising sea levels and impacting water availability are not well understood. Here we show that exceeding and then returning to below 1.5 °C will have irreversible consequences for glacier mass and runoff over centuries. Global climate and glacier simulations project that a 3.0 °C peak-and-decline scenario will lead to 11% more global glacier mass loss by 2500 compared with limiting warming to 1.5 °C without overshooting. In basins where glaciers regrow after peak temperature, glacier runoff reduces further than if the glaciers stabilize, a phenomenon we call ‘trough water’. Half the studied glaciated basins show reduced glacier runoff with overshoot compared with without for decades to centuries after peak warming. These findings underscore the urgency of near-term emissions reductions and limiting temperature overshoot.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41558-025-02318-w/MediaObjects/41558_2025_2318_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Water | 密集的灌溉缓冲区地下水在关键的欧洲面包板中下降</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00445-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Intensive irrigation buffers groundwater declines in key European breadbasket&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Grace Carlson; Christian Massari; Marco Rotiroti; Tullia Bonomi; Elisabetta Preziosi; Andrew Wilder; Destinee Whitaker; Manuela Girotto&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;意大利北部的PO平原是一个关键的农业地区，也是欧盟最大的水使用者之一。最近的干燥条件使未来的水资源可用性受到质疑。这项研究检查了由重力恢复和气候实验卫星观察到的地下水储存的时空变化以及2002年至2022年的1000多个地下水井。与2002-2022-2022-222的费率相比，从2015年到2022年，从2015年到2022年，地下水储存率下降了一倍以上。我们还表明，季节性和长期地下水的可用性受灌溉活动的强烈影响。灌溉区域的地下水储存与阿尔卑斯山的积雪高度相关，并且与非灌溉区域相比显示出更高的稳定性，而这些地区在干旱年份的下降幅度急剧下降。这表明，使用融雪的主要提供的水，在地下含水层中充实并帮助维持高水位桌，这使灌溉农田的基础含水剂富含蓄水量，使灌溉效率低下，使灌溉效率低下，这使灌溉农田具有抗干旱的负面影响。这些发现可以帮助指导气候驱动的对灌溉系​​统的适应，以解释对地下水充电的影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Po Plain in northern Italy is a critical agricultural region and one of the largest water users in the European Union. Recent dry conditions have put future water resource availability into question. This study examines spatio-temporal variations in groundwater storage observed by the Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment satellites and more than 1,000 groundwater wells from 2002 to 2022. We find that the rate of groundwater storage decline more than doubled from 2015 to 2022 as compared to the 2002–2022 rate. We also show that seasonal and long-term groundwater availability is strongly influenced by irrigation activities. Groundwater storage in irrigated areas is highly correlated to snow accumulation in the Alps and shows more stability as compared to non-irrigated areas, which experience dramatic declines during drought years. This indicates that inefficient irrigation practice, using water largely supplied by snowmelt, recharges underground aquifers and helps maintain high water tables, making aquifers underlying irrigated farmland resilient to the negative consequences of drought. These findings can help guide climate-driven adaptations to irrigation systems that account for the impact on groundwater recharge.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00445-4/MediaObjects/44221_2025_445_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 全球雨水的模式及其对从过去到未来预测的径流的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-59855-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Global patterns of rain-on-snow and its impacts on runoff from past to future projections&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Fadji Z. Maina; Sujay V. Kumar&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球变暖引起了寒冷地区的雨水（ROS），从而对生态系统和社会经济发展产生重大影响。但是，目前缺乏在不同排放场景之后对ROS和未来预测的全球分析，目前缺乏对管理策略必不可少的。在这里，我们研究了ROS的变化及其对可用于径流的水的影响，分析自1950年以来的历史状况，并在SSP245和SSP585之前预测未来的趋势。到本世纪末，ROS将主要发生在高纬度和海拔地区，例如高山，高山，北部，北部，北部的欧洲高度，以及三倍的历史范围。尽管如此，尽管降雨量增加，但降雨量的增加将减少ROS对径流的贡献的一半以上。尽管像美国西部这样的地区历史上经历了重要的ROS，但由于降低了积雪和降雨量的降低，变暖会减少ROS的影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Global warming has induced rain-on-snow (ROS) in cold regions leading to significant consequences on ecosystems and socioeconomic development. However, a global analysis of ROS under historical conditions and future projections following different emissions scenarios, essential for management strategies, is currently lacking. Here, we examine ROS changes and their impacts on the water available for runoff, analyzing historical conditions since 1950 and projecting future trends under SSP245 and SSP585 until 2100. By the end of the century, ROS will predominantly occur in high-latitude and altitude regions such as High Mountain Asia, the Alps, Northern Eurasia, and America with rates up to three times higher than those of the historical conditions. Nonetheless, the increasing rainfall will reduce by more than half the contribution of ROS to the water available for runoff despite its rise. Although regions like the Western United States have historically experienced significant ROS, warming will diminish ROS impacts as they become twice lower due to decreasing snowpack and intensified rainfall.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-59855-3/MediaObjects/41467_2025_59855_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 干旱频率，强度和暴露因历史土地使用和土地覆盖变化而增加</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02392-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Drought frequency, intensity, and exposure have increased due to historical land use and land cover changes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Tao Tang; Jun Ge; Haiyun Shi; Lin Wang; Junji Cao; Xuhui Lee&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;干旱是地表水的明显缺乏，对环境，农业和社会经济产生了广泛的不利影响。然而，土地利用变化对干旱特征的全球影响以及对干旱的相关暴露仍然很少知道。在这项研究中，通过使用有或没有土地使用变化的模型模拟来估算干旱特征的变化。我们表明，自1850年以来的历史土地使用变化，主要是森林砍伐和农作物的扩张，增加了全球土地面积一半以上的干旱频率，持续时间和严重性。活动更大的地区往往会经历更强烈的干旱事件加剧。由于它们的频率不断增加，持续时间延长，种群，农田和森林越来越多地暴露于干旱事件，这对人类健康，农业和森林生态系统产生了严重的潜在影响。潜在的造林活动可以大大减轻干旱事件的增强事件。我们的结果为与土地管理相关的决策提供了有用的信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Drought, a marked deficiency of surface water, has a wide adverse impact on the environment, agriculture, and the socio-economy. The global impact of land use changes on drought features and associated exposures to droughts, however, remains largely unknown. In this study, the changes of drought features are estimated by using the model simulations with and without land use change. We show that historical land use changes since 1850, mainly deforestation and crop expansion, has increased the drought frequency, duration, and severity over half of the global land area. Regions with greater activity tend to experience stronger exacerbation of drought events. Owing to their increasing frequency and prolonged duration, populations, croplands and forests are increasingly exposed to drought events, which poses serious potential impacts on human health, agriculture, and forest ecosystems. The enhanced drought events could be substantially alleviated by potential reforestation activity. Our results provide useful information for land-management-related policy-making.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02392-0/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2392_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 河流流入在西藏高原上地表水温的湖内异质性中的重要性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01083-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Importance of fluvial inflows in the intra-lake heterogeneity of surface water temperatures on the Tibetan Plateau&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Bingqing Du; Jing Zhou; Deliang Chen; Hu Liu; Baoyan Liu; Ruishun Liu; Lei Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;藏族高原（TP）上的湖泊对环境变化高度敏感。湖面水温（LSWT）的时空变化显着影响区域生态系统稳定性，碳循环和区域气候。但是，由于观察到有限的观察结果，LSWT及其驱动力的湖泊内异质性尚不清楚。通过使用多源数据集，尤其是观察到的LSWT和湖泊流入数据，以及随机森林方法，我们在2001年至2019年期间分析了三个TP湖（Nam Co，Siling Co和Paiku CO）。未检测到明显的LSWT变化。湖水流入（贡献最高40％）是7月至11月LSWT变化的主要驱动力，随后是空气温度。在空间上，LSWT湖内异质性在湖泊之间有所不同，锡灵CO在秋天显示最大的差异（接近4°C），主要是由河流流入地点和湖泊测深的湖泊引起的。这项研究提高了我们对LWST高山湖泊的LWST时空变化的理解，为气候变化适应和水资源管理提供了见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lakes on the Tibetan Plateau (TP) are highly responsive to environmental change. Spatiotemporal variations in the lake surface water temperature (LSWT) significantly impact regional ecosystem stability, carbon cycling, and regional climate. However, due to limited observations, the intra-lake heterogeneity of LSWT and its driving forces remain unclear. By employing multi-source datasets, especially observation-constrained LSWT and lake inflow data, along with the random forest method, we analyzed three TP lakes (Nam Co, Siling Co, and Paiku Co) during 2001‒2019. No evident inter-annual LSWT changes were detected. Lake inflow (up to 40% contribution) was the main driver of LSWT variations from July to November, followed by air temperature. Spatially, LSWT intra-lake heterogeneity varied among lakes, with Siling Co showing the largest difference (nearly 4 °C) in autumn, mainly caused by river inflow locations and lake bathymetry. This study improves our understanding of the spatiotemporal variations of LWST for high-mountain lakes, providing insights for climate-change adaptation and water resources management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01083-z/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1083_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 历史雨林洪水极端对温暖气候的不同反应</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02354-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Divergent responses of historic rain-on-snow flood extremes to a warmer climate&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Dalei Hao; Gautam Bisht; Donghui Xu; Mukesh Kumar; L. Ruby Leung&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球变暖正在改变雨水事件引起的洪水风险。但是，决策者缺乏有关如何随着变暖而改变的雨水引起的极端洪水的指导。在这里，使用公里尺度的陆地表面模型进行故事情节分析表明，由于水预算的改变，这四个具有历史性影响的，与决策的雨水相关的雨水引起了连续的洪水事件。对于2017-FEB加利福尼亚州的洪水，径流首先增加，然后随着变暖而减小，在+3 K场景下达到峰值，而2017年 - 加利福尼亚州洪水的径流单调地增加了〜53％/k。相反，1996年 -  1月中大西洋洪水的径流随着变暖而逐渐减少。尽管存在这些差异，但变暖通常会沿着海拔概况转移生成洪水的体制。高海拔高度可能会出现明显增加的径流，而低海拔则遇到了从阵阵驱动到以降雨为主的径流的转变。这些发现强调了洪水控制计划的需求，以量化温暖气候下的雨水抢断事件的区域和高程特定变化。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Global warming is altering flood risks induced by rain-on-snow events. However, decision-makers lack guidance on how rain-on-snow induced extreme floods could be altered with warming. Here, storyline analyses using a kilometer-scale land surface model reveal diverse responses of four historically-impactful, decision-relevant rain-on-snow induced extreme flood events over the contiguous U.S. to warming, due to alterations in their water budgets. For the 2017-Feb California floods, runoff first increases and then decreases with warming, peaking under the +3 K scenario, while runoff of the 2017-Jan California floods increases monotonically by ~53%/K. Contrastingly, runoff of the 1996-Jan Mid-Atlantic floods decreases gradually with warming. Despite these differences, warming generally shifts flood-generating regimes along elevation profiles. High elevations could experience notably increased runoff, while low elevations encounter a shift from rain-on-snow-driven to rainfall-dominated runoff. These findings underscore the need for flood control planning to quantify region- and elevation-specific changes in rain-on-snow events in a warmer climate.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02354-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2354_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>