<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 02:16:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Water | 湿地保护和恢复在整个欧洲河流域清除氮中的重要作用</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00465-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;The important role of wetland conservation and restoration in nitrogen removal across European river basins&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; L. E. Bertassello; N. B. Basu; J. Maes; B. Grizzetti; A. La Notte; L. Feyen&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在欧洲，氮的过多投入威胁生态系统和公共卫生。湿地充当天然过滤器，去除多余的养分并保护下游水域。使用有关氮盈余和湿地分布的高分辨率数据，我们估计现有的欧洲湿地每年消除1,092±95 kt的氮。恢复历史上有27％的湿地用于农业（占土地面积的3％），旨在用于高氮输入区域，可能会将当前的氮负荷降低到海上的36％，但可能会给农业生产力带来潜在的成本。一项更有效的策略是针对预计将在2040年放弃的农田的湿地恢复，从而减少了22％的负载，并使莱茵河，埃尔伯和维斯提拉等主要河流能够满足农业影响最小的水质目标。我们的发现凸显了湿地恢复是一种具有成本效益的，与政策相关的解决方案，如果以空间为目标，可以提供重大的水质改进，同时支持欧盟在气候，生物多样性和农业可持续性方面的广泛目标。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In Europe, excessive inputs of nitrogen threaten ecosystems and public health. Wetlands act as natural filters, removing excess nutrients and protecting downstream waters. Using high-resolution data on nitrogen surplus and wetland distribution, we estimate that existing European wetlands remove 1,092 ± 95 kt of nitrogen per year. Restoring 27% of wetlands historically drained for agriculture (3% of land area), targeted in high nitrogen input areas, could reduce current nitrogen loads to the sea by 36%, but with potential costs to agricultural productivity. A more efficient strategy targets wetland restoration on farmlands projected to be abandoned by 2040, yielding a 22% load reduction and enabling major rivers such as the Rhine, Elbe and Vistula to meet water quality targets with minimal agricultural impact. Our findings highlight wetland restoration as a cost-effective, policy-relevant solution that, if spatially targeted, can deliver major water quality improvements while supporting the European Union’s broader goals on climate, biodiversity and agricultural sustainability.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00465-0/MediaObjects/44221_2025_465_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>