<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 02:17:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 气候变化加速青藏高原河湖系统重组演化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02865-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Climate change accelerates the evolution of reorganized river-lake systems on the Tibetan Plateau&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xinya Kuang; Shanlong Lu; Liping Zhu; Jiahua Wei; Yuxiang Cui; Alice C. Hughes; Guoqiang Shi; Xidong Chen; Xinru Li&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候变化日益破坏寒冷地区水文系统的稳定性，推动湖泊和河流流域重组，对生态和社会经济产生深远影响。在这里，我们调查了位于联合国教科文组织世界自然遗产地青藏高原可可西里地区的佐乃流域和盐湖流域的剧烈水文变化。利用实地观测、卫星遥感和气候数据，我们表明，自 2019 年以来，这些以前的内流湖泊已与长江源头相连，扩大了流域。该地区的极端降水事件增加了湖泊溃决的风险，而湖岸的退缩引发了自2011年以来更频繁的沙尘暴，导致藏羚羊的栖息地退化。气候预测表明，到 2035 年，水文和生态将持续不稳定。我们的研究结果强调，迫切需要适应性水管理，以减轻与潜在湖泊溃决相关的洪水风险，并应对持续沙化导致的生态退化。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate change is increasingly destabilizing hydrological systems in cold regions, driving lake and river drainage reorganization with profound ecological and socio-economic impacts. Here we investigate intensified hydrological changes in the Zonag and Yanhu Lake drainage basins, located in the Hoh Xil region of the Tibetan Plateau, a UNESCO World Natural Heritage site. Using field observations, satellite remote sensing, and climate data, we show that since 2019 these previously endorheic lakes have connected to the headwaters of the Yangtze River, expanding its basin. The region’s extreme precipitation events have heightened lake outburst risks, while the retreating lake shores, which have triggered more frequent sandstorms since 2011, degrading habitats for Tibetan antelope. Climate projections indicate persistent hydrological and ecological instability through 2035. Our findings highlight urgent needs for adaptive water management to mitigate flood risks associated with potential lake outbursts and to combat ecological degradation driven by ongoing sandification.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02865-2/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2865_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>