<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 02:09:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | rub&amp;#39;al khali沙漠的第四纪晚期景观上的季风烙印</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02224-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Monsoonal imprint on late Quaternary landscapes of the Rub’ al Khali Desert&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Abdallah S. Zaki; Antoine Delaunay; Guillaume Baby; Negar Haghipour; Cécile Blanchet; Anne Dallmeyer; Pietro Sternai; Sam Woor; Omar Wani; Hany Khalil; Mathieu Schuster; Michael Petraglia; Florence Sylvestre; Giovan Peyrotty; Mohamed Ali; Frans Van Buchem; Abdulkader M. Afifi; Sébastien Castelltort&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;大量的地貌，生物学和同位素记录表明，在第四纪潮湿时期，阿拉伯反复发生了重大气候驱动的环境变化。精确地绘制了在这些潮湿时期，非洲季风的增强和扩张如何影响了阿拉伯的景观演变和人类职业动态仍然是一项科学挑战。在这里，我们重建了一个古老的水雕像景观，该景观由湖泊和河流矿床组成，并在沙特阿拉伯的鲁鲁（Rub&amp;#39;Al Khali）沙漠中加上一个大型出口谷。在全新世潮湿时期或之前的高峰期，强烈的降雨重新激活了冲积洪泛区，并填补了约1100公里的地形凹陷，最终违反了大约150公里的山谷。将地质重建与瞬态接地系统模型模拟耦合表明，这种水文活性与较高的季节性降水有关，季节性沉淀被反复的重型事件对立。分析湖泊和河流沉积沉积物意味着距离阿西尔山（Asir Mountains）距离高达1000公里的距离的沉积物路由。我们的结果表明，这种强烈的洪水挑战了阿拉伯降雨增加后，简单，弱和线性景观稳定的常规观点。我们的发现突出了增强的非洲季风在推动阿拉伯沙漠快速景观转变中的关键作用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Abundant geomorphological, biological, and isotopic records show that Arabia repeatedly underwent significant climate-driven environmental changes during late Quaternary humid periods. Precisely mapping how the enhancement and expansion of the African Monsoon during these humid periods have affected landscape evolution and human occupation dynamics in Arabia remains a scientific challenge. Here we reconstruct an ancient water-sculpted landscape consisting of lake and river deposits, coupled with a large outlet valley in the Rub’ al Khali Desert of Saudi Arabia. During the peak of the Holocene Humid Period or before, intense rainfall reactivated alluvial floodplains and filled a ~1100 km² topographic depression, which eventually breached, carving a deep ~150 km-long valley. Coupling geologic reconstructions with transient Earth system model simulations shows that this hydrological activity was linked to higher seasonal precipitation punctuated by repeated heavy events. Analysis of lacustrine and fluvial sedimentary deposits implies sediment routing across distances of up to 1000 km from the Asir Mountains. Our results indicate that such intense flooding challenges the conventional view of simple, weak, and linear landscape stabilization following increased rainfall in Arabia. Our findings highlight the crucial role of an enhanced African Monsoon in driving rapid landscape transformations in the Arabian Desert.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02224-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2224_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>