<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 02:32:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | SMRFR：使用来自多源数据的随机森林生成的全球多层土壤水分数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05511-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;SMRFR: A global multilayer soil moisture dataset generated using Random Forest from multi-source data&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yuhan Liu; Yuanyuan Zha; Gulin Ran; Yonggen Zhang; Liangsheng Shi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;对土壤水分（SM）的准确和连续监测对于在农业，水文学和气候建模中的广泛应用至关重要。在这项研究中，我们提出了一个新型机器学习（ML）框架，用于生成连续更新的多层全局SM数据集：SMRFR（通过随机森林回归的土壤水分）。 Leveraging publicly available reanalysis and remote sensing data, SMRFR provides daily SM estimates at five soil layers (0–5, 5–10, 10–30, 30–50 and 50–100 cm) with a spatial resolution of 9 km, covering the period from 2000 to 2023. Evaluation results demonstrate that SMRFR effectively captures both spatial and temporal SM variability.它还表现出强大的概括能力，成功地转移了大陆的知识，并在降雨事件发生后准确捕获了短暂和季节性的SM动态。 SMRFR在验证集上达到了无偏的根平方误差为0.0339 m &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; /m &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; 。我们的小说SM数据集为农业，水文和生态研究提供了基础和宝贵的参考，从而可以改进区域与全球量表的SM动力学的分析和建模。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Accurate and continuous monitoring of soil moisture (SM) is crucial for a wide range of applications in agriculture, hydrology, and climate modelling. In this study, we present a novel machine learning (ML) based framework for generating a continuously updated, multilayer global SM dataset: SMRFR (Soil Moisture via Random Forest Regression). Leveraging publicly available reanalysis and remote sensing data, SMRFR provides daily SM estimates at five soil layers (0–5, 5–10, 10–30, 30–50 and 50–100 cm) with a spatial resolution of 9 km, covering the period from 2000 to 2023. Evaluation results demonstrate that SMRFR effectively captures both spatial and temporal SM variability. It also exhibits strong generalization capacity, successfully transferring knowledge across continents and accurately capturing transient and seasonal SM dynamics following rainfall events. SMRFR achieved an unbiased root mean square error of 0.0339 m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; on the validation set. Our novel SM dataset offers a basis and valuable reference for agricultural, hydrological, and ecological research, enabling improved analysis and modelling of SM dynamics at regional to global scales.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05511-w/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5511_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>