<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 02:17:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 在全球变暖下湖泊的加热效果增强</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-59291-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Enhanced heating effect of lakes under global warming&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yuanlin Qiu; Jie Chen; Deliang Chen; Wim Thiery; Daniel Mercado-Bettín; Lihua Xiong; Jun Xia; R. Iestyn Woolway&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;湖泊在通过与大气的热量交换中塑造本地和区域气候方面起着至关重要的作用。在全球气候变化中，这些相互作用发生了重大变化。但是，我们对从湖泊到大气的全球热量释放及其未来轨迹的理解仍然有限。在这项研究中，我们研究了全球湖水释放模式的变化，并确定了热量释放的扩增增加，尤其是在高纬度地区（&amp;gt; 45°N）。这种放大与反馈机制有关，其中湖冰覆盖的减少不仅降低了较温暖的湖水和较冷的气氛之间的绝缘作用，而且还会导致湖泊吸收热量。结果，与较低纬度的湖泊相比，湖泊中高纬度地区的湖泊的相对释放相对增加，主要是通过向上的热辐射增加。此外，与较冷的季节相比，潜在热通量的季节性变化会加剧季节中的热量释放。未来的预测表明，与历史趋势相比，热量释放要大得多。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lakes play a crucial role in shaping both local and regional climates through heat exchange with the atmosphere. Amid global climate change, these interactions have undergone significant shifts. However, our understanding of the global heat release from lakes to the atmosphere, and its future trajectory, remains limited. In this study, we investigate changes in global lake heat release patterns and identify an amplified increase in heat release, particularly in mid to high latitudes (&amp;gt;45°N). This amplification is linked with a feedback mechanism, where the reduction in lake ice cover not only reduces the insulating effect between the warmer lake water and the colder atmosphere but also leads to increased heat absorption by lakes. As a result, lakes in mid-high latitudes experience a greater relative increase in heat release, primarily through upward thermal radiation, compared to lakes at lower latitudes with comparable surface water temperature increases. Additionally, seasonal variations in latent heat flux intensify the heat release during warmer seasons compared to colder ones. Future projections suggest substantially greater heat release compared to historical trends.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-59291-3/MediaObjects/41467_2025_59291_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>