<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 02:32:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 从2003年到2018年的全球每日平均无间隙地表温度数据集的合成</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05498-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Synthesis of a global daily average gapless land surface temperature dataset from 2003 to 2018&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xin Pan; Xu Ding; Kevin Tansey; Rufat Guluzade; Penghua Hu; Zi Yang; Suyi Liu; Jie Yuan; Zhanchuan Wang; Ziyu Lv; Wenyi Duan; Yingbao Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;土地表面温度（LST）在能量平衡，水文，气象，地理和生态学领域的研究中起着至关重要的作用，它是广泛关注的重要输入指标。遥感LST是使用最广泛和应用的方法之一。但是，由于诸如云之类的因素，遥感LST数据通常会显示出大量缺失值，这可能会对其应用构成挑战。这项研究提出了一种无质量的LST产品，其空间分辨率为1公里，时间分辨率为一天，通过整合了两个遥感数据集（每天1 km每天平均地表温度（DMLST）数据集，由Zhan等人和1 km DMLST数据集和Liu等人的1 km DMLST Dataset由Liu等人。验证结果表明，合成产品的均方根误差（RMSE）约为2 K，比其他四种产品好，RMSE的准确性增加了0.4-0.6 K，并且在干旱和冷区域显示出显着改善。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Land Surface Temperature (LST) plays a crucial role in research in the fields of energy balance, hydrology, meteorology, geography, and ecology, serving as a significant input indicator of widespread interest. Remote sensing LST is one of the most widely used and applied methods. However, due to factors such as cloud, remote sensing LST data often exhibit a significant number of missing values, which can pose challenges to its application. This study proposes a gapless LST product with a spatial resolution of one kilometer and a temporal resolution of one day, generated by integrating two remote sensing datasets (1 km daily mean land surface temperature (DMLST) dataset by Zhan et al. and 1 km DMLST dataset by Liu et al.) and two reanalysis datasets (GLDAS and ERA5-Land). The validation results show that the Root Mean Square Error (RMSE) of the synthesized product is about 2 K, which is better than the other four products, the accuracy of RMSE has increased by 0.4–0.6 K, and it have shown significant improvements in arid and cold regions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05498-4/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5498_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>