<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 02:21:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 东北亚气候引起的地表水和总储水量损失</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02449-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Climate-induced losses of surface water and total water storage in Northeast Asia&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Chenchen Zhang; Xiangming Xiao; Xinxin Wang; Shuang Yi; Cheng Meng; Yuanwei Qin; Yuan Yao; Leikun Yin; Jorge Celis; Li Pan; Baihong Pan; Xuebin Yang; Jinwei Dong&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;由于气候变化和人类活动，水短缺正在加剧全球。东北亚具有多种生态系统和跨界水系统，对这些压力特别敏感。然而，该地区的水资源变化，驱动因素在很大程度上仍然未知。在这里，我们整合了Landsat和Sentinel-2图像，重力恢复和气候实验及其随后的观察，气候和人为数据，发现在2000-2023的遥远俄罗斯的净地表水面积损失为16×10 &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ，主要是由温度升高以及净地表水域驱动的，以及净地表水域的驱动，以及净地表水域的驱动，以及净地表水域的增长，以及&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; KM 2 KM 2 KM 2 KM 2 KM 2 KM 2 KM 2 KM 2 KM 2 KM 2 &lt;sup&gt;KM&lt;/sup&gt; 2 KM灌溉基础设施。大约1004 0.5°的网格（1.4×10 &lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ）同时损失地表水面积和总水存储。大约1.85亿人居住在具有地表水面积或储水量损失的流域，强调了在加剧气候变化和人类活动的增强下对可持续水管理的需求。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water shortages are intensifying globally due to climate change and human activities. Northeast Asia, with diverse ecosystems and transboundary water systems, is particularly sensitive to these pressures. Yet, the region’s water resource changes and drivers remain largely unknown. Here, we integrate Landsat and Sentinel-2 images, Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment and its Follow-On observations, climate and anthropogenic data, finding a net surface water area loss of 16 × 10&lt;sup&gt;3 &lt;/sup&gt;km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; in Far East Russia over 2000−2023, primarily driven by rising temperature and evaporative demand, and a net surface water area gain of 3 × 10&lt;sup&gt;3 &lt;/sup&gt;km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; in Northeast China, primarily driven by increasing precipitation and irrigation infrastructure. Approximately 1004 0.5° gridcells (1.4 × 10&lt;sup&gt;6 &lt;/sup&gt;km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;) have concurrent losses of surface water area and total water storage. Approximately 185 million people reside in watersheds with surface water area or total water storage loss, underscoring the need for sustainable water management under intensifying climate change and human activities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02449-0/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2449_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 2°C的变暖可以使阿尔卑斯山极端倾盆大雨的频率增加一倍</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01081-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A 2°C warming can double the frequency of extreme summer downpours in the Alps&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Nadav Peleg; Marika Koukoula; Francesco Marra&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;山区的强烈短期夏季降雨可能会引发各种自然危害，包括山洪，碎屑流和城市洪水。预计变暖会加剧极端的降雨事件，以响应大气中的水蒸气含量和激动人心的风暴动态。在这里，我们采用了一种新的基于物理的统计模型来估算法国，德国，瑞士，意大利和奥地利的299个高山高山站的次时间和小时极端降雨的预计强化。分析在变暖1至3°C下的10分钟降雨量的预计强化证实，在高山区域，以9％°C -1的速率以9％°C &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;的速度进行一般强化，在较高海拔时的强化更强。相对于1991  -  2020年期间的平均区域温度升高2°C，阿尔卑斯山的极端降雨统计数据可能会发生重大变化，从而导致出现用于基础设施设计和风险管理的极端降雨水平的可能性增加了两倍。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Intense short-duration summer rainfall in mountainous areas can trigger a variety of natural hazards, including flash floods, debris flows, and urban floods. Warming is expected to intensify extreme sub-hourly rainfall events in response to an increased atmospheric water vapor content and invigorated storm dynamics. Here, we employ a new physically-based statistical model to estimate the projected intensification of sub-hourly and hourly extreme rainfall across 299 high-mountain Alpine stations in France, Germany, Switzerland, Italy, and Austria. Analyzing the projected intensification for 10-min rainfall at 1 to 3 °C of warming confirms a general intensification at a rate of 9% °C&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; over the Alpine region, with a stronger intensification at higher elevations. With a 2 °C increase in average regional temperature relative to the 1991–2020 period, extreme rainfall statistics over the Alps are likely to undergo significant changes, resulting in a two-fold increase in the probability of occurrence of the extreme rainfall levels used for infrastructure design and risk management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01081-1/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1081_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 美国疾病的四十年水力发电重新分析</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05323-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Forty-year hydropower generation reanalysis for Conterminous United States&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Sean W. D. Turner; Debjani Singh; Carly Hansen; Shih-Chieh Kao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Rectifhyd数据集于2022年首次发布，为美国约有1,500家水力发电厂的每月净产生估算值估计，该净生成量在美国的工业调查中遇到了差距，这些差距从2003年后仅收集了约10％的工厂的每月生成数据。在这里，我们提出了整流的数据集，这是一个扩展和增强的数据集，可改善替代信息和直接缩小方法的直接数据集。除了为从1980年至2019年提供&amp;gt; 10 MW铭牌容量的590台植物的历史每月发电的更新估计值外，Rectifhydplus还增加了一个水文控制数据集，该数据集隔离了历史水的影响对生成的影响。新的水文控制数据集适用于寻求代表当代舰队能力的应用程序，但由于气候中的历史际变化。整流性Plus还包括每个大坝的40年，每日分辨率调整后的水释放时间序列，使用户可以将生成估算值汇总到所需的时间分辨率。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;First published in 2022, the RectifHyd dataset provides hydrologically consistent estimates of monthly net generation for approximately 1,500 hydropower plants in the United States, addressing a gap in industrial surveys that have collected monthly generation data from only ~10% of plants post-2003. Here we present RectifHydPlus—an extended and enhanced dataset that improves on both the proxy information and temporal downscaling methodology adopted in RectifHyd. In addition to providing updated estimates of historical monthly generation for 590 plants with &amp;gt;10 MW nameplate capacity from 1980 through 2019, RectifHydPlus adds a hydrological control dataset that isolates the influence of historical water availability on generation. The new hydrological control dataset is suited to applications seeking to represent the capabilities of the contemporary fleet subject to historical interannual variability in climate. RectifHydPlus also includes a forty-year, daily-resolution, spill-adjusted water release time series for each dam, allowing users to aggregate generation estimates to the desired temporal resolution.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05323-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5323_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | CNSW 1.0：使用机器学习方法对中国地表水资源进行县重建</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05389-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;CNSW 1.0: Prefectural Reconstruction of China’s Surface Water Resources Using Machine Learning Methods&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Qichen Wang; Fubo Zhao; Xi Wang; Wenbo Shi; Yinuo Shan; Qiang Li; Dengfeng Liu; Yiping Wu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;县地表水资源的全面和长期数据集对于中国有效的水资源管理至关重要。但是，此类数据集的可用性存在很大的差距，没有现有数据集提供全面的长期覆盖范围。为了解决这一差距，我们已经开发了CNSW 1.0，这是中国的第一个长期（2000- 2020年）数据集。利用官方水资源公告中的地表水资源数据，我们采用了14个高级机器学习模型来重建CNSW 1.0数据集。最终的数据集表现出很高的精度，总地表水资源的R &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;为0.98，并且在整个中国可接受的偏见水平。 CNSW 1.0不仅优于CNRD V1.0，Grun和Isimip等现有数据集就模拟准确性和空间分配而言，而且还填补了中国水资源数据的关键空白。预计该数据集将是在中国行政层面，特别是在气候变化的背景下制定更知情的水资源管理策略的宝贵工具。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A comprehensive and long-term dataset of prefectural surface water resources is crucial for effective water resources management in China. However, there has been a significant gap in the availability of such datasets, with no existing datasets providing comprehensive long-term coverage. To address this gap, we have developed CNSW 1.0, the first long-term (2000–2020) dataset of prefectural surface water resources in China. Utilizing surface water resources data from official water resources bulletins, we employed 14 advanced machine learning models to reconstruct the CNSW 1.0 dataset. The resulting dataset exhibits high accuracy, with an R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; of 0.98 for total surface water resources and acceptable level of bias across China. CNSW 1.0 not only outperforms existing datasets like CNRD v1.0, GRUN, and ISIMIP in terms of simulation accuracy and spatial distribution but also fills a critical gap in water resources data for China. This dataset is expected to be an invaluable tool for developing more informed water resources management strategies at the administrative level in China, particularly in the context of climate change.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05389-8/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5389_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 动态受限的降雨预测表明，中国南部平原的人口暴露于前所未有的洪水</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02457-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Dynamics-constrained rainfall projection reveals substantial increase in population exposure to unprecedented floods in the North China Plain&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Long Yang; Jinghan Zhang; Fang Zhao; Daniel Wright; Chao Li; Dai Yamazaki; Xuezhi Tan; Miao Yu; Quan J. Wang; Fuqiang Tian&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;了解不断变化的洪水幅度和频率对于管理洪水风险至关重要。目前的洪水预测受到不确定的降雨变化和全球气候模型的时空降雨特征的不足表示。在这里，我们开发了一个框架，用于整合大型集合气候模型输出和动态缩减模拟。通过揭示大气循环和水蒸气变化与降雨量极端变化的重要性，得出的缩放比例可限制受热力学扰动实验的降雨投影。将此框架应用于中国南部平原，我们揭示了大幅度降雨的增加，部分原因归因于更有利的天气条件。这导致人口暴露于中等和高洪水深度（即0.5〜2 m）的近五倍。随着降雨量的增加，洪水风险增加的地区在空间上被抵消。这些发现突出了人口稠密地区改善洪水风险管理的紧迫性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understanding the changing flood magnitude and frequency is crucial for managing flood risks. Current flood projections are hindered by uncertain rainfall changes and inadequate representation of spatial-temporal rainfall characteristics from global climate models. Here we develop a framework for flood projection integrating large ensemble climate model outputs and dynamic downscaling simulations. By unveiling the shifting importance of changes in atmospheric circulation and water vapor to rainfall extremes of varying magnitudes, a scaling ratio is derived to constrain rainfall projections from thermodynamics-perturbed experiments. Applying this framework to the North China Plain, we reveal substantial rainfall increases partially attributed to more favorable synoptic conditions. This leads to a nearly fivefold rise in population exposure to moderate and high flood depths (i.e., 0.5 ~ 2 m). The region with heightened flood risk is spatially offset from that with rainfall increases. These findings highlight an urgency for improved flood risk management in the densely populated region.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02457-0/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2457_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>