<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 02:18:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 来自CMIP6模拟的阿拉伯半岛上极端降水事件的强化动力学</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01016-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Dynamics of intensification of extreme precipitation events over the Arabian Peninsula derived from CMIP6 simulations&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Raju Pathak; Hari Prasad Dasari; Karumuri Ashok; Ibrahim Hoteit&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;这项研究使用CMIP6模型的数据来得出整个阿拉伯半岛（AP）极端降水事件（AP）的历史和未来变化。与观察相比，历史CMIP6数据中，EPES的频率和强度都较低。尽管存在这种偏见，但CMIP6模型为未来的气候预测提供了宝贵的见解。在所有发射阶段中，AP的EPES频率和强度的显着增加。在高排放方案（SSP5-8.5）下，某些地区可能会在21世纪末的EPES上增加一倍。这种上升归因于几个气候变化驱动的因素，包括向南移动和亚热带 - 战利品的增强，瞬态活性增加，动力提升增强以及从附近海洋的水分传输增加。这些因素表明，未来的氛围将比今天更具动态和水分。尽管这些CMIP6洞察力对于指导适应和缓解策略至关重要，但增强的EPE建模对于在未来风险增加的情况下对精确决策至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This study derives historical and future changes in extreme precipitation events (EPEs) across the Arabian Peninsula (AP) using data from CMIP6 models. Both the frequency and intensity of EPEs are lower in historical CMIP6 data compared to observations. Despite this bias, CMIP6 models offer valuable insights into future climate projections. Across all emission-scenarios, significant increases in EPEs frequency and intensity are expected over the AP. Under the high-emission scenario (SSP5-8.5), some regions may experience a doubling of EPEs by the end-of-the-21st-century. This rise is attributed to several climate change-driven factors, including the southward-shift and intensification of subtropical-westerly-jet, increased transient activity, enhanced dynamical lifting, and increased moisture transport from nearby seas. These factors suggest a future atmosphere that will be more dynamic and moisture-rich than today. While these CMIP6 insights are crucial for guiding adaptation and mitigation strategies, enhanced EPE modeling is essential for precise decision-making amid rising future risks.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01016-w/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1016_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>