<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 02:12:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 土壤侵蚀研究的公平符合数据库：Marganai Forest实验</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04797-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;FAIR-Compliant Database for Soil Erosion Studies: The Marganai Forest Experiment&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Filippo Giadrossich; Ilenia Murgia; Enrico Guastini; Antonio Ganga; Simone Di Prima; Laura Chessa; Raffaella Lovreglio; Roberto Scotti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“ 2018年Marganai森林土壤侵蚀实验数据库”是一项全面的措施，旨在研究森林冠层覆盖范围对森林冠层覆盖范围对强烈人工降雨的影响，这是在强烈的人造降雨中，在培养后四年。调查涉及建立八个配对地块，具有和没有森林冠层覆盖范围，并经过人工降雨模拟，旨在测量径流运输的沉积物量。这项工作是有兴趣了解森林管理实践对土壤侵蚀的复杂含义的研究人员的宝贵资源。该论文在基于GitLab的RSTUDIO项目中使用四分之一生产的论文是“可重复的研究”记录的一个示例，即数据库提供了有关实验设置以及已收集的不同测量范围的详细信息。使用NFS-DataDocumentationProcedure生成的数据库存储在SQLite文件中，广泛利用引擎的关系属性，增强了数据可访问性，互操作性和可重复性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The ‘2018 Marganai Forest Soil Erosion Experiment Database’ is a comprehensive collection of measures taken during scientific experiment trials designed to investigate the effects of forest canopy coverage on soil erosion under intense artificial rainfall, four years after coppicing. The investigation involved the establishment of eight paired plots with and without forest canopy coverage, subjected to artificial rainfall simulation aimed to measure the amount of sediment transported by runoff. The work represents a valuable resource for researchers interested in understanding the complex implications of forest management practices on soil erosion. The paper, produced using Quarto in a Gitlab-based RStudio project, is an example of ‘reproducible research’ documenting that the database provides detailed information on the experimental setup as well as on the range of different measurements that have been collected. The database, produced using NFS-DataDocumentationProcedure, is stored in an SQLite file, extensively exploiting the relational properties of the engine, enhancing data accessibility, interoperability and reusability.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04797-0/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4797_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 亚马逊洪泛区中沉积物沉积的驱动因素和影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-57495-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Drivers and impacts of sediment deposition in Amazonian floodplains&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Dongyu Feng; Zeli Tan; Sebastien Pinel; Donghui Xu; João Henrique Fernandes Amaral; Alice César Fassoni-Andrade; Marie-Paule Bonnet; Gautam Bisht&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;亚马逊河从安第斯山脉的山脉中载着大量的沉积物，其中大部分沉积在其洪泛区中。然而，在良好的时空尺度上对沉积物汇的准确定量仍然具有挑战性。在这里，我们提出了一个高分辨率的流体动力学模型，以模拟代表性的亚马逊/Solimīes洪泛区中的沉积物沉积。发现该过程是由淹没，亚马逊河中的悬浮沉积物浓度以及洪泛区流体动力学的共同驱动的，并且仅与淹没水平无关。通过提高沉积物沉积速率（1.33±0.24 kg m &lt;sup&gt;-2&lt;/sup&gt; yr &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ），我们估计每年亚马逊/索利米斯洪泛区捕获亚马逊河沉积物的77.3±13.9吨（或6.1±1％）。广泛的森林砍伐将随着时间的流逝而降低洪泛区的陷阱效率，从而加剧下游河流的繁荣。此外，我们表明，与沉积物相关的有机碳的沉积在加油亚马逊的二氧化碳和甲烷排放方面起着较小的作用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Amazon River carries enormous amounts of sediment from the Andes mountains, much of which is deposited in its floodplains. However, accurate quantification of the sediment sink at fine spatiotemporal scales is still challenging. Here, we present a high-resolution hydrodynamic-sediment model to simulate sediment deposition in a representative Amazon/Solimões floodplain. The process is found to be jointly driven by inundation, suspended sediment concentration in the Amazon River, and floodplain hydrodynamics and only weakly correlated with inundation level. By upscaling the sediment deposition rate (1.33 ± 0.24 kg m&lt;sup&gt;−2&lt;/sup&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;), we estimate the trapping of 77.3 ± 13.9 Mt (or 6.1 ± 1%) of the Amazon River sediment by the Amazon/Solimões floodplains every year. Widespread deforestation would reduce the trapping efficiency of the floodplains over time, exacerbating downstream river aggradation. Additionally, we show that the deposition of sediment-associated organic carbon plays a minor role in fueling carbon dioxide and methane emissions in the Amazon.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-57495-1/MediaObjects/41467_2025_57495_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>