<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 02:28:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | Landsat-8和Sentinel-2卫星测量的全球多传感器数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05562-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A Global Multi-Sensor Dataset of Surface Water Indices from Landsat-8 and Sentinel-2 Satellite Measurements&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yohei Miura; Mohammad Shamsudduha; Anawat Suppasri; Daisuke Sano&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;地表水范围的时空映射构成了用于管理水资源，监测洪水和干旱影响区域以及湿地和淡水生态系统的宝贵数据集。地表水指数，源自光学卫星数据，是估计地表水覆盖率的有效指标。然而，使用多个水指数的高分辨率地表水图的全球尺度数据集仍然稀缺，并且在时间范围和空间范围内受到限制。在这里，我们介绍了从三个水指数（标准化差异指数（NDWI），修改的NDWI（MNDWI）和水指数2015（WI2015）得出的每月地表水图，利用高分辨率的地球观测卫星数据在2019年1月9日至12月20日的时间为202年1月9日。这些水指数映射为投射地表水资源的分配提供了基准，并在全球气候变化带来的挑战下为地表水资源的可持续管理提供关键信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Spatiotemporal mapping of surface water extent constitutes a valuable dataset for the management of water resources, the monitoring of flood- and drought-affected areas, and the conservation of wetlands and freshwater ecosystems. Surface water indices, derived from optical satellite data, serve as effective indicators for estimating surface water coverage. However, global-scale datasets featuring high-resolution surface water mapping using multiple water indices remain scarce and constrained in temporal and spatial scope. Here, we present monthly surface-water maps derived from three water indices, Normalized Difference Water Index (NDWI), Modified NDWI (MNDWI), and Water Index 2015 (WI2015), utilizing high-resolution earth observation satellite data from Landsat-8 and Sentinel-2 for the period January 2019 to December 2021. These maps will be regularly updated as new satellite data become available. These water index mappings provide a baseline for projecting the distribution of surface-water resources and deliver critical information for the sustainable management of surface water resources under the challenges posed by the global climate change.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05562-z/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5562_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 机器学习的河流排放，温度和热通量的数据集进入北极海洋</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05582-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A Machine Learning-Reconstructed Dataset of River Discharge, Temperature, and Heat Flux into the Arctic Ocean&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zihan Wang; Fengming Hui; Xiao Cheng&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;北极河流将全球河流排放量的11％带入北极海洋，影响海洋循环，海冰和沿海生态系统。我们对这些模式的理解受到大量数据差距的限制。为了解决这个问题，我们介绍了重建的北极排放的河流排放和温度（RADIT）数据集，这是1950年至2023年25个主要北极河流重建的每日排放，温度和热通量的全面记录。基于机器学习回归方法和ERA5-LOND重新分析数据，我们设计了不同的重新构造框架，以进行分配和温度，以考虑不同的形式。我们实现了高重建精度，纳什– utcliffe效率（NSE）值为0.861，温度为0.906。径向数据集具有广泛的空间和时间覆盖范围，是理解北极水文学及其对气候变化的反应的宝贵资源。它将改善北极淡水预算量化，气候模型校准以及对河流对北极海洋影响的评估，从而增强我们对北极海洋在全球气候系统中作用的理解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Arctic rivers deliver 11% of the global river discharge volume into the Arctic Ocean, influencing ocean circulation, sea ice, and coastal ecosystems. Our understanding of these patterns is limited by substantial data gaps. To address this, we present the Reconstructed Arctic-draining river DIscharge and Temperature (RADIT) dataset, a comprehensive record of reconstructed daily discharge, temperature, and heat flux for 25 major Arctic rivers from 1950 to 2023. Based on machine learning regression methods and ERA5-Land reanalysis data, we designed distinct reconstruction frameworks for discharge and temperature, considering the different characteristics of the observational data. We achieved high reconstruction accuracy, with median Nash–Sutcliffe efficiency (NSE) values of 0.861 for discharge and 0.906 for temperature. The RADIT dataset, with extensive spatial and temporal coverage, is a valuable resource for understanding Arctic hydrology and its response to climate change. It will improve Arctic freshwater budget quantification, climate model calibrations, and assessments of river impacts on the Arctic Ocean, enhancing our understanding of the role of the Arctic Ocean in the global climate system.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05582-9/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5582_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>