<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 02:27:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 全球三角洲对河流沉积物供应变化的响应时间</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-60531-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Response time of global deltas to changes in fluvial sediment supply&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jie Wang; Zhijun Dai; Xuefei Mei; Huan-Feng Duan; Jaap H. Nienhuis&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流沉积物供应支持全球三角洲的增长，但是这两个关键变量之间的关系仍然很难验证现代河三角洲。并发症的一部分可能是，增量适应河流沉积物供应的变化缓慢。为了检验这一假设，我们在这里分析了河流沉积物供应的年度时间序列，并在1990  -  2020年间分析了60个主要三角洲的三角洲土地面积变化。互相关表明，全球平均，三角洲生长速率的变化落后于河流沉积物供应的波动6年。对于增加沉积物供应增加的24个三角洲，土地变化率的滞后时间降至1年；而36个三角洲的河流沉积物量延迟了6年。河流为主导的三角洲的高沉积物可用性导致三角洲土地面积更快地响应上游供应变化，而潮汐优势较强的三角洲则具有较长的滞后时间的柔和响应。我们在这里的发现突出了三角洲及其生态系统对不断变化的外部驱动因素的高脆弱性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Fluvial sediment supply supports global delta growth, yet the relationship between these two key variables remains difficult to verify for modern river deltas. Part of the complication might be that deltas are slow to adjust to changes in fluvial sediment supply. To test this hypothesis, here we analyze yearly time series of fluvial sediment supply and delta land area changes for 60 major deltas through 1990–2020. Cross-correlations show that, globally averaged, changes in delta growth rate lag 6 years behind fluctuations in fluvial sediment supply. For the 24 deltas with increased sediment supply, the lag time of land change rates was reduced to 1 year; while the 36 deltas supplied with lower fluvial sediment loads lagged by 6 years. High sediment availability in river-dominated deltas leads to a quicker response of delta land area to upstream supply changes, and deltas with stronger tidal dominance have a subdued response with long lag times. Our findings here highlight the high vulnerability of deltas and their ecosystems to changing external drivers.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-60531-9/MediaObjects/41467_2025_60531_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 海洋在海底附近下坡，并在上方循环</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-61027-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;The ocean flows downhill near the seafloor and recirculates upward above&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; René Schubert; Jonathan Gula; Esther Capó; Pierre Damien; M. Jeroen Molemaker; Clément Vic; James C. McWilliams&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;海洋的循环将地球上的热量，盐，生物群，溶解气体，微塑料和沉积物重新分布。在海底上方最低1000 m处的深色海洋平均在北半球的左下角和南半球的左侧移动。这一发现很少受到关注，其对深渊垂直循环的后果在很大程度上尚未得到探索。 Here, we show, using current-meter measurements and numerical simulations, that the interior flow, \({{{\mathcal{O}}}}\)(100 m) - \({{{\mathcal{O}}}}\)(1000 m) above the seafloor, is deflected within the bottom boundary layer, the lowest \（{{{\ Mathcal {O}}}} \）（10 m），进入广泛的下坡流。这种流与海底的陡峭程度加剧。我们进一步揭示了海底陡度的典型局部变化导致这种下坡流动的较浅差异和深层收敛。这些通过上覆的向上再循环形成封闭的倾覆细胞，平均在海洋的最低1000 m上延伸。我们的研究提高了对海洋深渊循环的理解和与气候相关的倾覆。未来的研究应集中于量化与这些深渊斜率倾覆细胞相关的热，颗粒和溶解的化学物质的运输。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The ocean’s circulation redistributes heat, salt, biota, dissolved gases, microplastics, and sediments on Earth. The abyssal ocean, in the lowest 1000 m above the seafloor, moves on average with the deeper seafloor to its left in the Northern Hemisphere and to its right in the Southern Hemisphere. This finding has received little attention and its consequences for the abyssal vertical circulation have remained largely unexplored. Here, we show, using current-meter measurements and numerical simulations, that the interior flow, \({{{\mathcal{O}}}}\)(100 m) - \({{{\mathcal{O}}}}\)(1000 m) above the seafloor, is deflected within the bottom boundary layer, the lowest \({{{\mathcal{O}}}}\)(10 m), into a widespread downhill flow. This flow intensifies with the steepness of the seafloor. We further reveal that typical local changes in seafloor steepness lead to a shallow divergence and a deep convergence of this downhill flow. These are connected by an overlying upward recirculation forming closed overturning cells that extend on average over the lowest 1000 m of the ocean. Our study improves the understanding of the oceanic abyssal circulation and the climate-relevant overturning. Future research should focus on quantifying the transports of heat, particles, and dissolved chemicals associated with these abyssal slope overturning cells.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-61027-2/MediaObjects/41467_2025_61027_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 不同的地貌过程控制悬挂的沉积物和冰川从冰川出口</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-60776-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Different geomorphic processes control suspended sediment and bedload export from glaciers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ian Delaney; Frédéric Lardet; Matt Jenkin; Davide Mancini; Stuart N. Lane&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;正在进行的冰圈变化已大大改变了冰川化集水区的导出，对生态系统和下游用户（尤其是水电公司）产生了重大影响。沉积物在悬浮液中以更细的沉积物出口，或者是较粗的床，在沉积物和床之间间歇接触。迄今为止，与悬挂载荷相比，观察下冰层床的运输的困难限制了对撤离床负荷相关的物理过程的理解。我们通过将基于物理的基于物理的数值模型的数值模型和悬浮沉积物的悬浮沉积物和连续的床上载排放记录从高山冰川产生，从而阐明了控制沉积物出口的因素。出口大量的悬浮沉积物和床上负载，模型结果表明两者都依赖于沉积物的可用性进行运输。然而，冰川下通道中的床载出口也取决于特定的液压条件，特别是通道形状和液压粗糙度。与细粒沉积物相比，这使出口床尺寸的颗粒效率低下。结果，在检查床负荷进出过程时，应明确考虑亚冰液压，并应分别考虑悬挂和床负载的运输。熔融水的效率低下疏散疏散表明，只有在非易流动机制撤离沉积物（例如沉积物夹带到冰中）时，冰川侵蚀才能持续下去。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ongoing cryospheric change has modified sediment export from glacierized catchments substantially, with significant implications for ecosystems and downstream users, notably hydropower companies. Sediment is exported either as finer sediment in suspension or as coarser bedload with intermittent contact between sediment and the bed. To date, the difficulty in observing subglacial bedload transport limits the understanding of the physical processes associated with evacuating bedload compared with suspended load. We elucidate the factors controlling sediment export by inverting a physically-based numerical model of subglacial sediment production and sediment transport with suspended sediment and continuous bedload discharge records from an Alpine glacier. Comparable quantities of suspended sediment and bedload are exported, and model results suggest that both rely on the availability of sediment for transport. Yet, bedload export in subglacial channels also depends on particular hydraulic conditions, notably channel shape and hydraulic roughness. This makes exporting bedload-sized particles inefficient compared to fine-grained sediment. As a result, subglacial hydraulics should be explicitly considered when examining bedload export processes, and suspended and bedload transport should be considered separately. Inefficient bedload evacuation by melt water implies that glacial erosion may only continue when non-fluvial mechanisms evacuate sediment, such as sediment entrainment into the ice.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-60776-4/MediaObjects/41467_2025_60776_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 地球系统模型中的更精细的决议和目标过程表示改善水文投影和氢化气候影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01134-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Finer resolutions and targeted process representations in earth system models improve hydrologic projections and hydroclimate impacts&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Puja Das; Auroop R. Ganguly&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;地球系统模型为水政策和干预提供了信息，但是水文表示的知识差距限制了预测的可信度和影响评估。文献没有提供结论性的证据，表明将更高的决议，全面的过程模型和最新的参数化方案纳入将导致改进。我们比较了两代耦合建模对比项目（CMIP）模型，特别是CMIP5和CMIP6的氢气气候表示和径流预测，以及全球径流重建（Grun）和ECMWF Reanalysis Reanalysis v5（ERA5）的栅格径流（ECMWF）。我们的结果表明，最佳可用过程模型和参数化的系统嵌入方式以及更精细的分辨率，以机械上可以解释的方式改善了全球30条最大河流中30条最大河流中的不确定性特征。更熟练的CMIP6型号表明，在中端SSP370排放方案之后，40％的河流将显示出2100年的径流减少，影响了8.5亿人。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Earth system models inform water policy and interventions, but knowledge gaps in hydrologic representations limit the credibility of projections and impacts assessments. The literature does not provide conclusive evidence that incorporating higher resolutions, comprehensive process models, and latest parameterization schemes, will result in improvements. We compare hydroclimate representations and runoff projections across two generations of Coupled Modeling Intercomparison Project (CMIP) models, specifically, CMIP5 and CMIP6, with gridded runoff from Global Runoff Reconstruction (GRUN) and ECMWF Reanalysis V5 (ERA5) as benchmarks. Our results show that systematic embedding of the best available process models and parameterizations, together with finer resolutions, improve runoff projections with uncertainty characterizations in 30 of the largest rivers worldwide in a mechanistically explainable manner. The more skillful CMIP6 models suggest that, following the mid-range SSP370 emissions scenario, 40% of the rivers will exhibit decreased runoff by 2100, impacting 850 million people.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01134-5/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1134_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 全球城市城市化引起的降水不对称变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-61053-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Asymmetric shifts in precipitation due to urbanization across global cities&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jinghua Xiong; Yuting Yang; Long Yang; Dawen Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;城市化通过修改大气中的热，动态和化学过程来改变降水模式。但是，它对降水制度的影响，尤其是在每日量表下，对降水状态的影响很少。在这项工作中，我们使用高分辨率的，空间连续的卫星降水数据集来检查城市化引起的在全球城市的降水强度的转移。我们表明，城市化通常会导致不对称的偏移，增加较低强度的事件并降低更高强度的事件，在热带季风区域中具有不同的模式。这些转变主要是由于事件频率的变化而驱动的，导致城市地区的降水差异降低，尤其是在温带城市和表现出较高城市化水平的城市。每日分析表明，较低强度的降水最明显在清晨增加，而下午晚些时候较高的强度事件减少，减轻了昼夜降水的可变性。这些发现提供了重要的观察证据，表明城市化如何改变降水制度并强调对自适应城市水管理策略的需求。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Urbanization alters precipitation patterns by modifying thermal, dynamic, and chemical processes in the atmosphere. However, its effect on precipitation regimes, particularly at the sub-daily scale, is poorly understood. In this work, we use a high-resolution, spatially continuous satellite precipitation dataset to examine urbanization-induced shifts across precipitation intensities over global cities. We show that urbanization generally causes asymmetric shifts, increasing lower-intensity events and decreasing higher-intensity ones, with distinct patterns in tropical monsoon regions. These shifts, primarily driven by changes in event frequency, lead to reduced precipitation variability in urban areas, particularly in temperate cities and those exhibiting higher urbanization levels. Sub-daily analysis reveals that lower-intensity precipitation most notably increases in the early morning, while higher-intensity events decrease in the late afternoon, dampening diurnal precipitation variability. These findings offer important observational evidence of how urbanization alters precipitation regimes and highlight the need for adaptive urban water management strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-61053-0/MediaObjects/41467_2025_61053_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 用10年的卫星雷达数据绘制全球洪水</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-60973-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Mapping global floods with 10 years of satellite radar data&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Amit Misra; Kevin White; Simone Fobi Nsutezo; William Straka III; Juan Lavista&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;洪水每年造成广泛的全球损失，从而使有效的监视至关重要。尽管事实证明，卫星观测对于洪水检测和跟踪是无价的，但跨越时间段的全球全球洪水数据集仍然很少。在这项研究中，我们介绍了一个深度学习洪水检测模型，该模型利用了Sentinel-1合成孔径雷达（SAR）卫星图像的云渗透能力，从而使一贯的洪水范围通过云覆盖物以及白天和夜间条件进行映射。通过将该模型应用于10年的SAR数据，我们创建了一个独特的，纵向的全球洪水范围数据集，并没有受到云覆盖范围影响的预测，从而在过去十年中对历史上容易发生洪水的地区提供了全面和一致的见解。我们使用模型预测来确定埃塞俄比亚历史上容易发生洪水的地区，并在2024年5月在肯尼亚的洪水中证明了实时灾难反应能力。此外，我们的纵向分析揭示了随着时间的流逝，全球洪水范围的潜在趋势可能增加，尽管需要进一步验证才能探索与气候变化的联系。为了最大程度地发挥影响力，我们为我们的模型预测和代码存储库提供了公众的访问权限，赋予全球研究人员和从业人员的能力，以推动洪水监测并增强灾难响应策略。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Floods cause extensive global damage annually, making effective monitoring essential. While satellite observations have proven invaluable for flood detection and tracking, comprehensive global flood datasets spanning extended time periods remain scarce. In this study, we introduce a deep learning flood detection model that leverages the cloud-penetrating capabilities of Sentinel-1 Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) satellite imagery, enabling consistent flood extent mapping through cloud cover and in both day and night conditions. By applying this model to 10 years of SAR data, we create a unique, longitudinal global flood extent dataset with predictions unaffected by cloud coverage, offering comprehensive and consistent insights into historically flood-prone areas over the past decade. We use our model predictions to identify historically flood-prone areas in Ethiopia and demonstrate real-time disaster response capabilities during the May 2024 floods in Kenya. Additionally, our longitudinal analysis reveals potential increasing trends in global flood extent over time, although further validation is required to explore links to climate change. To maximize impact, we provide public access to both our model predictions and a code repository, empowering researchers and practitioners worldwide to advance flood monitoring and enhance disaster response strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-60973-1/MediaObjects/41467_2025_60973_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>