<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 02:18:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Water | 与美国洪水相关的财务损失随着频繁的低回归周期降水而发生</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00506-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Financial losses associated with US floods occur with frequent low-return-period precipitation&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Adam Nayak; Pierre Gentine; Upmanu Lall&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;美国的洪灾每年导致数十亿美元的财务损失，预计由于降水，人口增长和恶化洪水基础设施而增加。联邦法规要求在100年沿海和河流洪泛区内购买洪水保险。然而，我们对数百万个联邦保险索赔的分析表明，大多数洪水损失与相对于区域气候学的频繁，低强度的降水事件有关，平均地区降水返回期为5年。同样，与灾难援助和房地产收购有关的降水的平均返回期限不到20年。使用无监督的学习，我们确定与主要风暴相关的时空降水集群占主导地位，强调了对洪水风险评估和缓解策略的需求，这些策略涉及反复出现的时空化合物事件。这些发现强调了洪水风险管理的重要性，洪水风险管理范围超出了沿海和河流的影响，并带来了洪水的准备和评估。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Flooding in the USA leads to billions of dollars in financial losses annually, with projected increases due to escalating extreme precipitation, population growth and deteriorating flood infrastructure. Federal regulation mandates flood insurance purchase within 100-year coastal and fluvial floodplains. Yet our analysis of millions of federal insurance claims reveals that most flood losses are associated with frequent, low-intensity precipitation events relative to regional climatology, with average regional precipitation return periods of under 5 years. Likewise, precipitation linked to disaster aid and property buyouts has return periods averaging less than 20 years. Using unsupervised learning, we identify that space-time precipitation clusters associated with major storms dominate losses, emphasizing the need for flood risk assessments and mitigation strategies that account for recurrent spatiotemporal compound events. The findings underscore the importance of flood risk management that extends beyond solely coastal and fluvial impacts into pluvial flood preparedness and assessment.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00506-8/MediaObjects/44221_2025_506_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Climate Change | 使用观察结果来限制海平面预测的不确定性的进展和未来方向</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-025-02437-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Progress and future directions in constraining uncertainties in sea-level projections using observations&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Denis Felikson; David R. Rounce; John Fasullo; Angelica Rodriguez; Surendra Adhikari; Brett Buzzanga; Sönke Dangendorf; Robert E. Kopp; Richard B. Lammers; J. T. Reager; Doug Brinkerhoff; Beata Csatho; Manuela Girotto; Benjamin Hamlington; Erik R. Ivins; Praveen Kumar; Eric Larour; R. Steven Nerem; Sophie Nowicki; Nicole-Jeanne Schlegel; Jan-Erik Tesdal; Matthew Weathers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;沿海计划，缓解和适应工作取决于物理模型产生的可靠海平面预测。但是，这些预测中的巨大不确定性对决策者构成了挑战。在这里，我们概述了多年代到百年纪念时间尺度的海平面变化模型预测的主要不确定性来源，我们提供了关于使用观察值来狭窄不确定性的观点。我们为未来的研究提出了几个方向，包括改进新兴的仿真技术，对观察和模型内的不确定性结构进行更系统的量化，延长过程的观察记录以及在物理和社会科学之间扩大合作。由于气候变化评估周期的下一阶段正在进行中，因此迫切需要这些领域的进步。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Coastal planning, mitigation and adaptation efforts rely on credible sea-level projections generated by physical models. However, the large uncertainties in these projections pose a challenge for policymakers. Here we provide an overview of the main sources of uncertainty in model projections of sea-level change on multi-decadal to centennial timescales and we offer perspectives on the use of observations to narrow uncertainties. We propose several directions for future research, including improvements in emerging emulation techniques, more systematic quantification of uncertainty structure within both observations and models, lengthening observational records of processes, and expanding collaborations across physical and social sciences. Advancements in these areas are urgently needed, as the next phase of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change assessment cycle gets underway.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41558-025-02437-4/MediaObjects/41558_2025_2437_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 卫星雷达高度测定揭示了玻利维亚salar de uyuni的水表面光滑度的空间和时间变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02715-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Satellite radar altimetry reveals spatial and temporal changes in water surface smoothness in the Salar de Uyuni, Bolivia&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Stefano Vignudelli; Ron Abileah; Paula Pacheco Mollinedo; Francesco De Biasio&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Salar de Uyuni是由盐制成的沙漠，当它被薄薄的水覆盖时，它被称为世界上最大的天然镜子。但是，这一说法从未通过研究得到科学证明。唯一的证据来自沿边界拍摄的智能手机照片，因为在潮湿季节内不容易进入内部区域。在这里，我们提出了一种基于雷达横截面的方法，以使用Sentinel-3卫星的雷达高度计观测值测量表面平滑度。该方法使用在其内部进行的独特现场调查中收集的地面实际测量值进行了验证，并在其被水覆盖并与卫星立交桥一致的同时进行了验证。我们表明，整个salar de uyuni不是反映雷达波的均匀镜子，因为可见光波长处的平滑度会引起人们的信仰。取而代之的是，水表面的平滑度在空间和时间上演变。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Salar de Uyuni is a desert made of salt and is called the world’s largest natural mirror when it is covered with a thin layer of water. However, that statement has never been scientifically proven through research. The only evidence is from smartphone photographs taken along the border, as the interior area is not easily accessible during the wet season. Here, we present a methodology based on Radar Cross Section to measure surface smoothness using radar altimeter observations from Sentinel-3 satellites. The methodology was validated using ground-truth measurements collected during a unique field survey conducted in its interior while it was water-covered and coinciding with a satellite overpass. We show that the whole Salar de Uyuni is not a uniform mirror reflecting radar waves, as the smoothness at visible light wavelength would induce one to believe. Instead, the smoothness of the water surface evolves spatially and temporally.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02715-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2715_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 从十年的CryoSat-2数据中检测到南极洲的85个新的活性亚冰川湖泊</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-63773-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Detection of 85 new active subglacial lakes in Antarctica from a decade of CryoSat-2 data&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Sally F. Wilson; Anna E. Hogg; Richard Rigby; Noel Gourmelen; Isabel Nias; Thomas Slater&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;冰川下湖活动会影响冰盖流，地面线排放和冰架基础熔化。尽管在南极通过与其活性相关的冰表面高度变化发现了146个活跃的冰川湖泊，但在全球范围内仅观察到36个填充循环，并且对这些机制的了解受到限制。在这里，我们使用十年的冷冻-2雷达高度测定法来检测南极洲的85个活跃的冰川湖泊，分别记录了37和34完整的排水和填充事件。我们描述了冰川下湖活动的时变边界，并研究了它们随时间的变化。我们的观察结果将南极洲已知的活性亚冰湖湖的数量增加了58％，其中6个位于接地区8公里以内。我们观察到五个亚冰山湖网络，并同时上游排水和下游填充物以及25个湖泊，从而提高了我们对相互连接的亚冰分水文途径的了解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Subglacial lake activity influences ice sheet flow, grounding line discharge and ice shelf basal melting. Although 146 active subglacial lakes have been detected in Antarctica via ice surface elevation change associated with their activity, only 36 fill-drain cycles have been observed worldwide, and knowledge of these mechanisms is limited. Here, we use a decade of CryoSat-2 radar altimetry to detect 85 active subglacial lakes in Antarctica, documenting 37 and 34 complete draining and filling events respectively. We delineate time-varying boundaries of subglacial lake activity and investigate their variability over time. Our observations increase the number of known active subglacial lakes in Antarctica by 58%, with six of these located within 8 km of the grounding zone. We observe five subglacial lake networks, with concurrent upstream drainage and downstream filling, and 25 clusters of lakes, improving our knowledge of interconnected subglacial hydrological pathways.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-63773-9/MediaObjects/41467_2025_63773_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>