<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 02:35:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature | 全球河流系统从陆地到大气的旧碳</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09023-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Old carbon routed from land to the atmosphere by global river systems&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Joshua F. Dean; Gemma Coxon; Yanchen Zheng; Jack Bishop; Mark H. Garnett; David Bastviken; Valier Galy; Robert G. M. Spencer; Suzanne E. Tank; Edward T. Tipper; Jorien E. Vonk; Marcus B. Wallin; Liwei Zhang; Chris D. Evans; Robert G. Hilton&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流和溪流是全球碳循环中的重要途径，从水面释放二氧化碳（CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; ）和甲烷（CH &lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; ）到大气上的&lt;sup&gt;1,2&lt;/sup&gt; 。到目前为止，从河流中排放的CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;和CH &lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;被认为主要源自最近（亚少年生物量的生物量），因此，生态系统呼吸的一部分&lt;sup&gt;3,4,5,6&lt;/sup&gt; 。在这里，我们结合了新的和已发布的测量结果，以创建河流溶解的无机碳（DIC），CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;和CH &lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;的放射性碳含量的全球数据库。我们数据库的同位素质量平衡表明，59±17％的全球河流CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;排放来自旧碳（千禧一代或以上），其释放与河流集水岩石学和生物群落有关。以前无法识别的旧的，工业化的碳从长期的土壤，沉积物和地质碳储存到大气中通过侧向水文路由的释放相当于1.2±0.3 pg c年&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ，大小与地际生态系统交换相似。这种通量的结果比陆地上老化有机物商店的碳净损失的净损失要大。这需要重新评估陆地系统以及全球碳循环预算和模型中人为碳的命运。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Rivers and streams are an important pathway in the global carbon cycle, releasing carbon dioxide (CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) and methane (CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;) from their water surfaces to the atmosphere&lt;sup&gt;1,2&lt;/sup&gt;. Until now, CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; emitted from rivers were thought to be predominantly derived from recent (sub-decadal) biomass production and, thus, part of ecosystem respiration&lt;sup&gt;3,4,5,6&lt;/sup&gt;. Here we combine new and published measurements to create a global database of the radiocarbon content of river dissolved inorganic carbon (DIC), CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;. Isotopic mass balance of our database suggests that 59 ± 17% of global river CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions are derived from old carbon (millennial or older), the release of which is linked to river catchment lithology and biome. This previously unrecognized release of old, pre-industrial-aged carbon to the atmosphere from long-term soil, sediment and geologic carbon stores through lateral hydrological routing equates to 1.2 ± 0.3 Pg C year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;, similar in magnitude to terrestrial net ecosystem exchange. A consequence of this flux is a greater than expected net loss of carbon from aged organic matter stores on land. This requires a reassessment of the fate of anthropogenic carbon in terrestrial systems and in global carbon cycle budgets and models.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-025-09023-w/MediaObjects/41586_2025_9023_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature | 变暖会加速全球干旱严重性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09047-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Warming accelerates global drought severity&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Solomon H. Gebrechorkos; Justin Sheffield; Sergio M. Vicente-Serrano; Chris Funk; Diego G. Miralles; Jian Peng; Ellen Dyer; Joshua Talib; Hylke E. Beck; Michael B. Singer; Simon J. Dadson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;干旱是影响环境，经济和人口最常见，最复杂的自然危害之一，全球&lt;sup&gt;1,2,3,4&lt;/sup&gt; 。然而，全球干旱趋势&lt;sup&gt;4,5,6&lt;/sup&gt;存在明显的不确定性，并且对关键驱动因素，大气蒸发需求（AED）的程度有限，影响了干旱的幅度，频率，持续时间和面积范围的最新演变。在这里，通过开发1901  -  2022年的高分辨率全球干旱数据集的合奏，我们发现全球干旱严重程度的趋势日益增加。我们的发现表明，AED在全球范围内平均增加了40％的干旱严重程度。不仅干燥区域变得更干燥，而且潮湿的区域正在经历干燥趋势。在过去的5年（2018  -  2022年）中，与1981  -  2017年相比，干旱地区平均增长了74％，AED占此增长的58％。 2022年是创纪录的，其中30％的全球土地面积受中度和极端干旱影响，其中42％归因于AED增加。我们的发现表明，AED在驾驶严重的干旱方面起着越来越重要的作用，这种趋势可能会在未来的变暖场景下继续进行。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Drought is one of the most common and complex natural hazards affecting the environment, economies and populations globally&lt;sup&gt;1,2,3,4&lt;/sup&gt;. However, there are significant uncertainties in global drought trends&lt;sup&gt;4,5,6&lt;/sup&gt;, and a limited understanding of the extent to which a key driver, atmospheric evaporative demand (AED), impacts the recent evolution of the magnitude, frequency, duration and areal extent of droughts. Here, by developing an ensemble of high-resolution global drought datasets for 1901–2022, we find an increasing trend in drought severity worldwide. Our findings suggest that AED has increased drought severity by an average of 40% globally. Not only are typically dry regions becoming drier but also wet areas are experiencing drying trends. During the past 5 years (2018–2022), the areas in drought have expanded by 74% on average compared with 1981–2017, with AED contributing to 58% of this increase. The year 2022 was record-breaking, with 30% of the global land area affected by moderate and extreme droughts, 42% of which was attributed to increased AED. Our findings indicate that AED has an increasingly important role in driving severe droughts and that this tendency will likely continue under future warming scenarios.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-025-09047-2/MediaObjects/41586_2025_9047_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 秘鲁安第斯山脉中的薄雪形融化和径流动态</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02379-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Thin and ephemeral snow shapes melt and runoff dynamics in the Peruvian Andes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Catriona L. Fyffe; Emily Potter; Evan Miles; Thomas E. Shaw; Michael McCarthy; Andrew Orr; Edwin Loarte; Katy Medina; Simone Fatichi; Rob Hellström; Michel Baraer; Emilio Mateo; Alejo Cochachin; Matthew Westoby; Francesca Pellicciotti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;秘鲁安第斯山脉的雪和冰川在面临缺水和大量冰川变化的地区提供重要的水供应。但是，仍然缺乏对雪过程的了解和对熔体对径流的贡献的量化。在这里，我们将分布式的冰川流学模型在里奥圣诞老人上使用，以解开冰冻圈在安第斯水周期中的作用。只有在最高海拔（&amp;gt; 5000 m ASL）下进行积雪连续。在较低的海拔时，积雪稀薄且短暂，降雪和融化的速度快速。由于较大的集水区受到短暂的降雪的影响，其对集水区投入的贡献是很大的（在潮湿和干旱季节分别为23％和38％）。冰融化在干旱季节至关重要（最多占投入的44％）。我们的结果改善了水通量的估计，并呼吁在安第斯山脉进行进一步的基于过程的建模。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The snow and glaciers of the Peruvian Andes provide vital water supplies in a region facing water scarcity and substantial glacier change. However, there remains a lack of understanding of snow processes and quantification of the contribution of melt to runoff. Here we apply a distributed glacio-hydrological model over the Rio Santa basin to disentangle the role of the cryosphere in the Andean water cycle. Only at the highest elevations (&amp;gt;5000 m a.s.l.) is the snow cover continuous; at lower elevations, the snowpack is thin and ephemeral, with rapid cycles of snowfall and melt. Due to the large catchment area affected by ephemeral snow, its contribution to catchment inputs is substantial (23% and 38% in the wet and dry season, respectively). Ice melt is crucial in the mid-dry season (up to 44% of inputs). Our results improve estimates of water fluxes and call for further process-based modelling across the Andes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02379-x/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2379_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 英国夏季干旱的海洋司机</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02367-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Oceanic drivers of UK summer droughts&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Amulya Chevuturi; Marilena Oltmanns; Maliko Tanguy; Ben Harvey; Cecilia Svensson; Jamie Hannaford&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在气候变化下，英国的干旱预计将变得更加频繁，从而强大了了解其基本原因的需求。我们的研究研究了英国夏季干旱的海洋驱动因素和相关的远程连接途径。具体而言，我们评估了英国和两个北大西洋海面温度（SST）模式的标准化降水和水流指数之间的统计联系，这些模式与以前曾与淡水流入亚极区域相关。我们的发现表明，北大西洋SST通过更改北大西洋电流的位置（与北大西洋夏季喷气流的位置相连），从而提前1。5年的英国水文学会影响英国的水文学。这一遥相关途径的漫长交货时间可以为英国在整个季节性到年际时期标准中的干旱预测，并最终在英国的干旱风险上增加了可持续水资源管理的发展。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;UK droughts are projected to become more frequent under climate change, reinforcing the need to understand their underlying causes. Our study examines oceanic drivers of UK summer droughts and the associated teleconnection pathways. Specifically, we evaluate statistical links between standardized precipitation and streamflow indices for the UK and two North Atlantic Sea surface temperature (SST) patterns which have previously been linked to the influx of freshwater into the subpolar region. Our findings reveal that the North Atlantic SST influences UK hydrology up to 1.5 years in advance by altering the position of the North Atlantic Current, which is coupled to the location of the North Atlantic summer jet stream. The long lead time of this teleconnection pathway can inform UK drought forecasting across seasonal to interannual timescales and ultimately contribute to the advancement of sustainable water resource management in the face of increasing drought risks in the UK.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02367-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2367_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 在不断变化的气候下，从热浪到大雨的加速变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01113-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Accelerated shifts from heatwaves to heavy rainfall in a changing climate&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jian Li; Shuo Wang; Jinxin Zhu; Dagang Wang; Tongtiegang Zhao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在温暖的气候下，连续的热浪和大雨（HW -HR）事件随着频率的增加而发生。时间间隔定义为热浪结束与大降雨开始之间的持续时间，会影响环境条件和两个连续的极端事件之间的区域恢复。但是，连续的HW-HR事件之间过渡的动力学仍然知之甚少。在这项研究中，我们使用来自中国大陆2000多个站点的气象数据，研究了1970年至2019年中国连续HW-HR事件的时间间隔的变化。我们的结果表明，时间间隔在24.1％的电台中显着缩短。这种趋势主要是由短期事件（STE）的比例增加驱动的，该事件（STE）定义为连续事件，在1-2天内以时间间隔定义。从1970年到2019年，STE的比例显着增加，每十年1.4％。我们还发现，在连续的HW-HR事件中，气候变化引起的大气变量异常，尤其是对流可用的势能，2 m温度和相对湿度，可能会导致Stes比例的增加。此外，我们的研究评估了过去二十年来人口接触的变化。我们发现，该国四分之三以上的暴露面积增加了，Ste的增加占总暴露的65.3％。我们的发现强调了连续HW-HR事件期间优先级灾难响应的重要性，并实施有效的风险管理策略来减轻人口暴露于极端事件。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Consecutive heatwave and heavy rainfall (HW‐HR) events are occurring with increasing frequency in a warming climate. The time interval, defined as the duration between the end of a heatwave and the onset of heavy rainfall, affects both environmental conditions and the regional recovery between two consecutive extreme events. However, the dynamics of the transition between consecutive HW-HR events remain poorly understood. In this study, we examine the changes in the time interval of consecutive HW-HR events in China from 1970 to 2019, using meteorological data from over 2000 stations across mainland China. Our results reveal that the time interval has significantly shortened at 24.1% of the stations. This trend is primarily driven by an increased proportion of short-time events (STEs), defined as consecutive events with time intervals within 1–2 days. From 1970 to 2019, the proportion of STEs increased significantly, at a rate of 1.4% per decade. We also find that climate change-induced anomalies in atmospheric variables during the consecutive HW-HR events, especially convective available potential energy, 2 m temperature, and relative humidity, may contribute to this rise in the proportion of STEs. Additionally, our study assesses changes in population exposure to STEs over the past two decades. We find that the area of exposure has increased across more than three-quarters of the country, with the increases in STEs contributing to 65.3% of the overall rise in exposure. Our findings highlight the importance of prioritizing disaster response during consecutive HW-HR events and implementing effective risk management strategies to mitigate population exposure to extreme events.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01113-w/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1113_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | Viking 2着陆点的弗罗斯特（Frost）的高氯酸盐盐水形成</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02411-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Perchlorate brine formation from frost at the Viking 2 landing site&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Vincent F. Chevrier&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;盐水在火星表面的存在和稳定性在行星探索中仍然是一个重要的谜。提出的盐水形成的先前机制包括冰盐混合物和盐差异的融化。然而，熔化缺乏充电机制，而二线会因火星的极端表面干燥而阻碍。这项研究探讨了一个未充分散布的过程：季节性霜在盐水形成中的作用。利用Viking 2 Lander的气象数据（与凤凰城的唯一任务一起观察原位水霜的形成），我证明，作为霜冻的冬季，在冬季结束时，盐水可以在大约30个溶胶中形成。稳定的盐水表现出0.52的水活性上限，对应于高氯酸盐钙的共晶点，这是在各个火星地区检测到的一种盐，可能包括维京2个着陆点。因此，我得出的结论是，高氯酸钙可以在短时间内与霜接触时产生少量的液态盐水。霜冻的季节性表明这些盐水复发，并可能留下长期的烙印。因此，被霜冻的地区是未来居住能力和天体探索的主要候选人。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The presence and stability of brines on Mars’s surface remain a significant mystery in planetary exploration. Previous mechanisms proposed for brine formation include melting of ice-salt mixtures and salt deliquescence. However, melting lacks a recharge mechanism, and deliquescence is impeded by Mars’s extreme surface aridity. This study explores an underexplored process: the role of seasonal frost in brine formation. Utilizing meteorological data from the Viking 2 lander—the only mission, with Phoenix, to observe in situ water frost formation—I demonstrate that brines can form over approximately 30 sols at the end of winter as frost sublimates. The stable brines exhibit a water activity upper limit of 0.52, corresponding to the eutectic point of calcium perchlorate, a salt detected in various Martian regions, likely including the Viking 2 landing site. Consequently, I conclude that calcium perchlorate can generate small amounts of liquid brine in contact with frost for brief periods. The seasonal nature of frost suggests these brines recur and may leave long-term imprints. Therefore, frost-covered regions are prime candidates for future habitability and astrobiological exploration.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02411-0/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2411_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | Fongyun-3卫星系列的协同合并序列的无缝分辨率土壤水分</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05263-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Seamless finer-resolution soil moisture from the synergistic merging of the FengYun-3 satellite series&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Daniel F. T. Hagan; Seokhyeon Kim; Guojie Wang; Xiaowen Ma; Yifan Hu; Yi Y. Liu; Alexander Barth; Haonan Liu; Waheed Ullah; Isaac K. Nooni; Samuel A. Bhatti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在过去的几年中，已经启动了更多带有微波成像仪的卫星，从而使更多的观察值可用于在全球获得土壤水分估计。中国的努力导致了能够填补全球土壤湿度数据差距的宫山（FY）被动微波观测（FY-3B，C，D）的推出。在这项研究中，我们通过合并技术的合并技术从2011年的空间分辨率开发了一个合并的土壤水分数据集，该空间分辨率为0.15°，该系列跨度（本研究中的2020年），使用输入母产物的信噪比将均方误差（MSE）最小化。在这里，我们结合了从三个卫星观测值中的上升和下降观测值，以获得亚每日估计。最后，我们将合并后的每日FY土壤水分平均为每日估计，并使用深度学习插值方法进行填充，以重建缺失的日子，同时保留合并的FY数据的特征。这项研究的结果旨在提供针对使用全球卫星土壤水分观察的挑战的数据集。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In the last years, more satellites with microwave imagers have been launched, making more observations available to obtain soil moisture estimates globally. China’s endeavour has resulted in the launch of the FengYun (FY) passive microwave observations (FY-3B, C, D) capable of filling in global soil moisture data gaps. In this study, we develop a merged soil moisture dataset at a spatial resolution of 0.15° from the FY series which spans 2011 to present time (2020 in this study) by a merging technique that minimizes mean square error (MSE) using the signal-to-noise ratio of the input parent products. Here, we combine the ascending and descending observations from the three satellite observations to obtain sub-daily estimates. Finally, we averaged the merged sub-daily FY soil moisture into daily estimates and gap-fill it using a deep learning interpolation approach to reconstruct the missing days while preserving the characteristics of the Merged FY data. The results of this study aim to provide datasets that meet challenges in using global satellite soil moisture observations.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05263-7/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5263_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 巴基斯坦纳马山谷的水信网络</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05310-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Hydrometeorological Network of Namal Valley, Pakistan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Muhammad Sheraz; Talha Manzoor; Malik Jahan Khan; Usman Ali; Hamza Tariq; Shabeh ul Hasson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文介绍了从位于巴基斯坦Mianwali区的Namal Lake集水区部署的传感器网络收集的数据。该湖是纳马尔大坝的水库。传感器网络由跨越425平方公里区域的流域中的14个独特的观测点组成。数据包括在所有传感器位置的分辨率为0.246 mm的降水测量以及在7个位置（包括湖泊本身）以1 mm分辨率的水位测量。第一个传感器安装于2020年11月进行，最后一个传感器安装于2022年7月。这两个变量的相关时间序列均以10分钟的采样频率生成。数据集的多个聚合已在每小时，每日和每月的时间表上提供。数据可用于校准各种应用的水文模型，例如洪水预测，分水岭管理和储层运营决策。该数据集还有助于理解季风边缘类似小流域中的水信过程。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This article describes data collected from a sensor network deployed in the catchment of The Namal Lake, situated in Mianwali district, Pakistan. The lake serves as a reservoir for the Namal Dam. The sensor network consists of 14 unique observation points in a watershed spanning a 425 sq km area. The data includes measurements of precipitation at a resolution of 0.246 mm at all sensor locations and measurements of water level at a 1 mm resolution at 7 locations (including the lake itself). The first sensor installation was made in November 2020 with the last one deployed in July 2022. The associated time series for both variables is generated at a 10-minute sampling frequency. Multiple aggregations of the dataset have been made available at hourly, daily, and monthly timescales. The data can be used for calibrating hydrological models for various applications such as flood prediction, watershed management, and decision-making for reservoir operation. The dataset also contributes to understanding the hydrometeorological processes in similar small catchments at the Monsoon Margin.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05310-3/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5310_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | SC-PREC4SA：南美的串行完成每日降水数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05312-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;SC-PREC4SA: A serially complete daily precipitation dataset for South America&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Adrian Huerta; Roberto Serrano-Notivoli; Stefan Brönnimann&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;这项研究介绍了南美（SC-Prec4SA）的串行完整降水数据集，这是一个每日降水数据集（1960-2015），旨在解决观察差距并确保各种气候之间的时间一致性。 RAW数据集经过了质量控制，填充差距和均匀化程序。应用的强大质量控制突出了常见但也被忽视的问题，从而提高了数据可靠性。在潮湿的天数（潮湿的幅度）预测中，填充间隙的平均准确性为70％（60％）。这些指标突出了填充过程的可靠性，尤其是在车站网络稀疏的混合气候中。均质化算法主要集中在潮湿的日子上，有效地降低了不均匀性，同时保留了整个南美的降水量变异性。通过集成了来自7794个电台的统一框架和多个输出，SC-PREC4SA提供了一个强大的数据集，该数据集可捕获具有较高至中等准确性和一致性的每日降水模式。它为气候研究，水文建模和水资源管理提供了宝贵的资源，解决了南美降水数据可用性和质量的长期挑战。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This study introduces the serially complete precipitation dataset for South America (SC-PREC4SA), a daily precipitation dataset (1960-2015) designed to address observational gaps and ensure temporal consistency across diverse climates. The raw dataset underwent quality control, gap-filling, and homogenization procedures. Applied robust quality control highlighted common but also overlooked issues, enhancing data reliability. Gap-filling achieved a mean accuracy of 70 % (60 %) in the prediction on wet/dry days (wet-day magnitude). These metrics highlight the reliability of the gap-filling process, particularly in mixed climates, where station networks are sparse. The homogenization algorithm, focused primarily on wet days, effectively reduced inhomogeneities while preserving precipitation variability across South America. By integrating a unified framework and multiple outputs from 7794 stations, SC-PREC4SA provides a robust dataset that captures daily precipitation patterns with high to moderate accuracy and consistency. It offers a valuable resource for climate research, hydrological modeling, and water resource management, addressing longstanding challenges in precipitation data availability and quality for South America.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05312-1/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5312_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 全球时空时代ERA5降水降级至km，并使用生成型AI降低了缩放和次小时尺度</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01103-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Global spatio-temporal ERA5 precipitation downscaling to km and sub-hourly scale using generative AI&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Luca Glawion; Julius Polz; Harald Kunstmann; Benjamin Fersch; Christian Chwala&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;降水的空间和时间分布显着影响人类的生命。虽然重新分析数据集提供了一致的长期全球降水信息，从而可以调查以降雨驱动的危害（例如大型洪水），但他们缺乏捕获高时空降水量的高时空变异性和局部局部降雨量的高度差异的解决方案。在这里，我们介绍了Spategan-era5，这是全球范围内首个基于深度学习的时空降水数据。 Spategan-era 5增强了ERA5降水数据从24 km，1 h至2 km和10分钟，提供具有现实时空模式和准确的降雨速率分布的高分辨率降雨场，包括极端。它的计算效率使大量解决方案能够生成大量的解决方案，以解决降低挑战固有的不确定性，并支持为任意ERA5时期和需求的任意ERA5时期和区域生成高分辨率降水数据的实际适用性。 Spategan-era-5仅根据德国的数据进行了培训，并在美国和澳大利亚进行了验证，考虑到包括热带降雨制度在内的各种气候，Spategan-era5表现出强烈的概括，表明全球适用性强大。它满足了水文和气象研究中高分辨率降水数据的关键需求。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The spatial and temporal distribution of precipitation significantly impacts human lives. While reanalysis datasets provide consistent long-term global precipitation information that allows investigations of rainfall-driven hazards like larger-scale flooding, they lack the resolution to capture the high spatio-temporal variability of precipitation and miss intense local rainfall events. Here, we introduce spateGAN-ERA5, the first deep learning-based spatio-temporal downscaling of precipitation data on a global scale. SpateGAN-ERA5 enhances ERA5 precipitation data from 24 km and 1 h to 2 km and 10 min, delivering high-resolution rainfall fields with realistic spatio-temporal patterns and accurate rain rate distribution, including extremes. Its computational efficiency enables the generation of a large ensemble of solutions, addressing uncertainties inherent to downscaling challenges and supports practical applicability for generating high-resolution precipitation data for arbitrary ERA5 time periods and regions on demand. Trained solely on data from Germany and validated in the US and Australia, considering diverse climates, including tropical rainfall regimes, spateGAN-ERA5 demonstrates strong generalization, indicating robust global applicability. It fulfills critical needs for high-resolution precipitation data in hydrological and meteorological research.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01103-y/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1103_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>