<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 02:17:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 区域尺度的智能优化和地形影响恢复全球降水数据差距</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02624-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Regional-scale intelligent optimization and topography impact in restoring global precipitation data gaps&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jiahan Wang; Jiaqi Chen; Peng Shen; Xiaoling Guan; Xiangmei Liu; Christian Massari; Zongzhi Wang; Mingming Feng; Qingxuan Wang; Youbei Lu; Ersa Wei; Yonghao Wang; Gulomjon Umirzakov; Bin Yong&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;地面降雨观测对于改善量规调整的卫星降水估计至关重要，特别是在全球降水测量任务时代。但是，超过60％的国家缺乏完整的基于表面的降雨量表网络，严重限制了全球卫星降水检索的准确性。在这里，我们提出了一个模型，该模型将区域尺度的智能优化，地形分析和端到端神经网络整合在一起，以合并多源降水数据并重建全球时空降水场与跨尺度的分辨率数据差距。我们的评估表明，该模型基本上提高了卫星沉淀精度，将相关系数从0.66提高到0.77。特别是，在应用模型时，卫星估计值和复杂地形上的卫星估计显示出明显的改善。这些发现表明，所提出的方法具有在暴风雨监测和洪水预测中的未来应用，尤其是在具有稀疏观察数据的山区。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ground rainfall observations are essential for improving gauge-adjusted satellite precipitation estimates, particularly in the Global Precipitation Measurement mission era. However, over 60% of countries lack a complete surface-based rainfall gauge network, severely constraining the accuracy of global satellite precipitation retrievals. Here we present a model that integrates regional-scale intelligent optimization, topographic analysis, and an end-to-end neural network to merge multi-source precipitation data and reconstruct global spatiotemporal precipitation fields with resolved data gaps across scales. Our evaluation demonstrates that the model substantially improves satellite precipitation accuracy, increasing the correlation coefficient from 0.66 to 0.77. In particular, satellite estimates at high rain rates and over complex terrains show marked improvement when the model is applied. These findings suggest that the proposed approach holds strong potential for future applications in storm monitoring and flood forecasting, especially in mountainous regions with sparse observational data.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02624-3/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2624_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>