<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 02:21:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 时空变异性的差异和印度东西方海岸之间复合沿海极端的风险</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01045-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Disparity in spatiotemporal variability and risk of compound coastal extremes between India’s East-West coasts&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Diljit Dutta; V. V. Srinivas; Govindasamy Bala&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;印度东海岸在6月至11月期间的极端风暴浪涌降落（SS-RF）容易受到季风和季风后孟加拉湾的不同强度的驱动。相反，西海岸主要见证了这些极端，主要是在季风期间，由阿拉伯海的抑郁症和沿海地区的低压槽驱动。当印度洋偶极子与厄尔尼诺南部振荡的中性（LaNiña或中性）阶段共同发生时，西部（东）海岸的较高频率是在西部（东）海岸的。此外，东海岸（孟买以外的西海岸）的SS-RF极端是风暴潮（降雨）占主导地位，在Haldia（孟买）的风险较高。另一方面，由于潮汐范围的差异和沿海潮流的季节性，在东部（西）海岸看到了较高（较低）的同时海平面降落极端频率。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Indian East Coast is susceptible to concurrent storm surge-rainfall (SS-RF) extremes during June–November, driven by low-pressure systems of varying intensity from the Bay of Bengal during monsoon and post-monsoon seasons. Contrarily, the West Coast witnesses these extremes primarily during monsoon, driven by depressions in the Arabian Sea and troughs of low pressure along the coast. Higher frequency of these extremes was witnessed on the West (East) Coast when the positive (negative) phase of the Indian Ocean Dipole co-occurred with the Neutral (La Niña or Neutral) phase of El Niño Southern Oscillation. Further, the SS-RF extremes on the East Coast (West Coast except Mumbai) were storm surge (rainfall) dominant, with higher risk at Haldia (Mumbai). On the other hand, a higher (lower) frequency of concurrent sea level-rainfall extremes was witnessed on the East (West) Coast due to disparity in tidal ranges and seasonality of coastal currents.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01045-5/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1045_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 跨县的节水策略应针对中国的制造业和农业部门</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02292-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Water-saving strategies across prefectures should target the manufacturing and agriculture sectors in China&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zongyong Zhang; Yuli Shan; Martin R. Tillotson; Philippe Ciais; Xu Zhao; Dandan Zhao; Hong Yang; Jingwen Huo; Zhao Zeng; Xian Li; Heran Zheng; Bofeng Cai; Wanqing Wang; Wang Kai; Guanlin Li; Geng Niu; Dabo Guan; Junguo Liu; Yu Hao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在包括中国在内的许多新兴经济体中，缺水是全球挑战。中国是最广泛的淡水使用者之一，在县级设定了2030年的水效率提高目标。但是，在各个部门和部门之间没有系统的用水和储蓄比较。在这里，我们使用了10,608个工业和1715个农业子行业的水的水抽水数据集用于343个县，并探索了减少用水量的机会。结果表明，最低水效率的工业子行业中有10％代表着不成比例的46％用水。可以实现18.9公里&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; （±3.2％）行业的节水和50.3公里&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; （±2.3％）的农业，相当于俄罗斯的年度需求。少数部门，包括布料（ING）和化学制造，米饭，蔬菜和水果培养，可能对节水最大的贡献。我们的研究对于识别用于单个各个部门的用水和效率信息至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water scarcity is a global challenge in many emerging economies, including China. China is one of the most extensive freshwater users and has set water efficiency improvement goals for 2030 at the prefecture level. However, no systematic water use and savings comparison exists across prefectures and sectors. Here, we used datasets of water withdrawal for 10,608 industrial and 1715 agricultural sub-sectors for 343 prefectures, and explored the opportunities to reduce water use. Results show that 10% of the least water-efficient industrial sub-sectors represent a disproportionate 46% water use. 18.9 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; (±3.2%) water saving in industry and 50.3 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; (±2.3%) in agriculture could be achieved, equivalent to Russia’s annual demand. A minority of sectors, including cloth(ing)- and chemical-manufacturing, rice-, vegetable- and fruit-cultivation, could contribute the most to water savings. Our study is essential for identifying water use and efficiency information for individual prefectures and sectors.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02292-3/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2292_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 降雨和失败的大坝有多极端</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-59261-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;How extreme rainfall and failing dams unleashed the Derna flood disaster&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ayman Mokhtar Nemnem; Ahad Hasan Tanim; Audrika Nahian; Sadik Khan; Erfan Goharian; Jasim Imran&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2023年9月11日，丹尼尔（Daniel）在瓦迪·德纳（Wadi Derna）流域释放了前所未有的降雨，引发了现代历史上最毁灭性的洪水之一，这是利比亚沿海城市的德尔纳（Derna）。这项研究使用综合建模方法重建了灾难，该方法结合了卫星图像，水文，液压和岩土技术模拟，机器学习，目击者帐户和数字高程数据，以评估层叠大坝故障的影响。我们的发现表明，该地区的大坝即使在结构上是合理的，也将为极端的径流提供最小的保护。但是，他们的失败释放了破坏性的浪潮，扩大了灾难的幅度和破坏。在这里，我们表明，老化洪水控制基础设施的崩溃，风险评估和应急准备不足，使灾难的影响升级。我们的发现强调了对系统的大坝安全评估，增强洪水预测以及适应性风险管理策略的迫切需求，这些策略应对极端气候和基础设施脆弱性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;On September 11, 2023, Storm Daniel unleashed unprecedented rainfall over the Wadi Derna watershed, triggering one of the most devastating floods in modern history, striking Derna, a coastal city in Libya. This study reconstructs the disaster using an integrated modeling approach that combines satellite imagery, hydrologic, hydraulic, and geotechnical simulations, machine learning, eyewitness accounts, and digital elevation data to assess the impact of cascading dam failures. Our findings reveal that the region’s dams, even if structurally sound, would have provided minimal protection against the extreme runoff. However, their failure unleashed a destructive surge wave, amplifying the disaster’s magnitude and devastation. Here, we show that the collapse of aging flood control infrastructures, compounded by inadequate risk assessment and emergency preparedness, dramatically escalated the disaster’s impact. Our findings underscore the urgent need for systematic dam safety evaluations, enhanced flood forecasting, and adaptive risk management strategies that address climate extremes and infrastructure vulnerabilities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-59261-9/MediaObjects/41467_2025_59261_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 通过增加的营养供应减少了最近沉积泥炭中碳的积累</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-59387-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Carbon accumulation in recently deposited peat is reduced by increased nutrient supply&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Betty Ehnvall; Joshua L. Ratcliffe; Carolina Olid; Jacob Smeds; Kevin Bishop; Jonatan Klaminder; Chuxian Li; Carl-Magnus Mörth; Mats B. Nilsson; Mats G. Öquist&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;高纬度米尔斯存储了全球土壤碳的相当一部分。当前的理解表明，湿润的条件会促进碳的积累。该范式主要基于温带的浮雕沼泽，并忽略了集水区域中矿物质水的影响，尽管大多数北方的米尔斯都是矿物源性卵子。在这里，我们表明，矿源性水是对过去世纪碳积累的主要负面影响。在上一千年中形成的米尔斯中，这种效果最为明显。除了在刺激衰减和生产力的高架中，矿化水没有提高生产率，而是刺激有机物衰减。这些发现重塑了我们对碳循环在高宽容下的理解，强调了降水 - 蒸发的变化如何影响芬斯的碳固执，而碳则在阳离子中广泛存在。与对温带地区的期望相反，我们认为，亚北极泥炭地的流域输入增加不太可能增强泥浆碳的积累。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;High-latitude mires store a considerable part of the global soil carbon. Current understanding suggests that wetter conditions promote carbon accumulation. This paradigm is based primarily on temperate ombrogenic bogs and overlooks the influence of minerogenic water from the catchment area, despite most northern mires being minerogenic fens. Here we show that minerogenic water is the main negative influence on past century carbon accumulation in boreal fens. This effect is most pronounced in mires formed during the last millennia. Rather than enhancing productivity, minerogenic water stimulates organic matter decay, apart from in elevated hummocks where both decay and productivity were stimulated. These findings reshape our understanding of carbon cycling at high-latitudes, highlighting how shifts in precipitation-evapotranspiration may impact carbon sequestration in fens, which are widespread in the circum-arctic. Contrary to expectations for temperate regions, we argue that increased catchment water input in sub-arctic peatlands is unlikely to enhance mire carbon accumulation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-59387-w/MediaObjects/41467_2025_59387_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 极端和平均降水对土地使用和土地覆盖变化的不同反应</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01049-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Different responses of extreme and mean precipitation to land use and land cover changes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Meng Zhang; Yanhong Gao; Jun Ge&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;土地利用和土地覆盖变化（LULCCS）可以通过表面能量，水通量和大规模大气循环的变化来影响降水，这对自然和社会的可持续发展产生了很大的影响。但是，与平均变化相比，这些贡献者对极端降水变化的影响和机制仍需要研究。在这里，我们使用水分预算方程将基于CMIP6-LUMIP实验的三个主要因素（蒸散量，大气平均循环和水蒸气）分解为三个主要因素（蒸散量，大气平均循环和水蒸气）。由于历史（1995- 2014年）和未来（2080-2099）时期，由于LULCCS引起的平均降水量的全球减少可以归因于蒸散和大气平均循环的贡献相对较高。相反，在最高干燥月份，降水减少大约是多年平均变化的2-3倍。代表平均循环变化的动态贡献者超过蒸散量，因为驱动大多数景观的主要降水量减少的主要因素。 LULCCS引起的极端降水变化的社会经济影响大于平均状态的社会经济影响，尤其是将来。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Land use and land cover changes (LULCCs) can influence precipitation via changes in surface energy, water flux, and large-scale atmospheric circulation, with great implications for the sustainable development of nature and society. However, the impacts and mechanisms of these contributors to extreme precipitation changes compared with mean changes still need to be investigated. Here, we used the moisture budget equation to decompose precipitation changes into three primary contributing factors (evapotranspiration, atmospheric mean circulation, and water vapor) based on CMIP6-LUMIP experiments. A global reduction in mean precipitation due to LULCCs can be attributed to relatively equal contributions of changes in evapotranspiration and atmospheric mean circulation over the historical (1995–2014) and future (2080–2099) periods. In contrast, during the top drying month, the precipitation reduction is approximately 2–3 times greater than the multi-year mean change. The dynamic contributor representing the mean circulation change surpasses evapotranspiration as the primary contributor driving the extreme precipitation decrease in the majority of the landscape. The socioeconomic impacts of LULCCs-induced extreme precipitation changes are greater than those of the mean state, especially in the future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01049-1/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1049_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 由情节水流形状的南极地面区域环境</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01687-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A West Antarctic grounding-zone environment shaped by episodic water flow&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Huw J. Horgan; Craig Stewart; Craig Stevens; Gavin Dunbar; Linda Balfoort; Britney E. Schmidt; Peter Washam; Mauro A. Werder; Darcy Mandeno; James Marschalek; Christina Hulbe; Nicholas Holschuh; Richard Levy; Benjamin Hurwitz; Stefan Jendersie; Katelyn Johnson; Justin Lawrence; Regine Morgenstern; Andrew D. Mullen; Enrica Quartini; Wilson Sauthoff; Matthew Siegfried; Holly Still; Sam Thorpe-Loversuch; Tina van de Flierdt; Ryan Venturelli; Arran Whiteford&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在南极洲的冰盖下，一个鲜为人知的液态水网络连接了广阔的景观，并有助于压倒冰的运动。当这种亚冰川水到达冰架下的海洋腔时，它将与海水混合，放大熔体，并在冰底部形成深层通道的某些地方。在这里，我们介绍了一个热水钻孔的钻孔，记录了进入Kamb Ice Stream和Ross Ice架子地面的海洋腔的亚冰河水。我们的观察结果表明，熔体已经去除了大约三分之一的冰厚度，但测量结果表明，在浊羽中冰山下排放的速率较低。从通道地板上芯的沉积物显示出更大的排放事件，并从不同的地质领域沉积了材料。我们量化了冰川下排放，并将我们的观察结果与上游的集水区联系起来。我们得出的结论是，离散的排放事件可能会占主导地位的通道熔体和沉积物的运输，并导致坎布冰流下游的广泛冰壳特征。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Beneath Antarctica’s ice sheets, a little-observed network of liquid water connects vast landscapes and contributes to the motion of the overriding ice. When this subglacial water reaches the ocean cavity beneath ice shelves, it mixes with seawater, amplifying melt and in places forming deep channels in the base of the ice. Here we present observations from a hot-water-drilled borehole documenting subglacial water entering the ocean cavity at the grounding zone of Kamb Ice Stream and the Ross Ice Shelf. Our observations show that melt has removed approximately a third of the ice thickness, yet measurements reveal low rates of subglacial discharge in a turbid plume. Sediment cored from the channel floor shows larger discharge events occur and episodically deposit material from distinct geological domains. We quantify subglacial discharge and link our observations to the catchment upstream. We conclude that discrete discharge events are likely to dominate channel melt and sediment transport and result in the extensive ice-shelf features downstream of Kamb Ice Stream.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01687-3/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1687_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Water | 通过全球水模型模拟的水文通量和储藏中的相似性和不同模式</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00435-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Similarities and divergent patterns in hydrologic fluxes and storages simulated by global water models&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Amar Deep Tiwari; Yadu Pokhrel; Julien Boulange; Peter Burek; Luca Guillaumot; Simon N. Gosling; Manolis Grillakis; Naota Hanasaki; Aristeidis Koutroulis; Sebastian Ostberg; Kedar Otta; Hannes Müller Schmied; Yusuke Satoh; Bridget Scanlon; Tobias Stacke; Tokuta Yokohata&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球水模型（GWMS）是在不断变化的气候和加速人类干预措施下了解地球的水周期和水资源管理的关键工具。尽管已经评估了GWM的水文通量（例如，河流排放）和代表人类活动的作用，但了解模型同时再现通量和储藏的能力（例如，陆生储水（TWS））存在持续的差距。在这里，我们表明八个最先进的GWM并不始终繁殖放电，并且在各种地理和气候区域之间具有相同功效的TWS。此外，随着人类影响加剧，排放的模型性能会恶化。尽管在全球主要河流盆地的三分之二中发现了模拟和观察到的TWS趋势之间的一般协议，但模型倾向于低估这两个方向的趋势。同样，在全球主要的河流盆地中，没有任何单一模型能够准确，均匀地模拟TWS趋势和季节性。尽管与以前的报告相比，捕获盆地平均TWS趋势的改善，空间分布和季节性波动已经实现，但仍在准确地重现通量和储藏量的挑战，这主要是由于不足以使人类活动的代表不足，在严重管理的地区。这项研究强调了GWM性能中的关键差异，强调了进一步的模型增强的需求，这对于改善气候变化下的改进和更健壮的水文评估和预测至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Global water models (GWMs) are critical tools for understanding the Earth’s water cycle and water resource management under a changing climate and accelerating human interventions. Although GWMs have been evaluated for hydrologic fluxes (for example, river discharge) and the role of representing human activities, there is a persistent gap in understanding models’ ability to simultaneously reproduce fluxes and storages (for example, terrestrial water storage (TWS)). Here we show that eight state-of-the-art GWMs do not consistently reproduce discharge and TWS with the same efficacy across varied geographic and climatic regions. Furthermore, model performance for discharge deteriorates as human impacts intensify. While a general agreement between simulated and observed TWS trends is found in two-thirds of major global river basins, models tend to underestimate the trends in both directions. Likewise, no single model simulates TWS trends and seasonality accurately and uniformly across major global river basins. Although improvements in capturing basin-averaged TWS trends, spatial distributions and seasonal fluctuations have been achieved compared with previous reports, challenges remain in accurately reproducing both fluxes and storages, owing primarily to inadequate representation of human activities in heavily managed regions. This study underscores critical disparities in GWM performance, emphasizing the need for further model enhancements, which is crucial for improved and more robust hydrologic assessments and predictions under climate change.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00435-6/MediaObjects/44221_2025_435_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 半连续释放Cordilleran冰盖融化在20,000至17，000年前</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01694-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Semi-continuous release of Cordilleran Ice Sheet meltwater between 20,000 and 17,000 years ago&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Paul S. Wilcox; Michael C. Meyer; Daniela Festi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;最后一次脱气过程中冰片融化事件的陆地证据异常罕见。但是，它们是海洋记录的有价值的补充，表明巨大的冰片融化了进入东北太平洋，称为西库事件。在这里，我们描述并与最后一次脱水片中的岩壁冰川折叠式平原上的陆地山脉冰纸融化档案馆约会，显示了大约20,000至17，000年前的半连续融水事件。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Terrestrial evidence of ice-sheet meltwater events during the last deglaciation are exceptionally rare. However, they are a valuable complement to marine records that suggest immense ice-sheet meltwater pulses discharging into the Northeast Pacific, termed Siku events. Here we describe and date a terrestrial Cordilleran Ice Sheet meltwater archive in a karstified glacial outwash plain during the early last deglaciation, showing semi-continuous meltwater events between about 20,000 and 17,000 years ago.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01694-4/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1694_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 同时叠加的冰层和格陵兰冰块上的融水径流</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-59237-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Concurrent superimposed ice formation and meltwater runoff on Greenland’s ice slabs&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Andrew Tedstone; Horst Machguth; Nicole Clerx; Nicolas Jullien; Hannah Picton; Julien Ducrey; Dirk van As; Paolo Colosio; Marco Tedesco; Stef Lhermitte&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;格陵兰冰盖上的河流和泥田越来越多地在蓄能区占据近乎易感的冰板的位置发展。但是，在这些地区的径流与保留之间的划分仍然没有得到测量。我们将叠加的冰形成在可见的径流极限周围的平板上进行现场测量。叠加冰的数量因靠近可见的地表水和表面斜率而变化，这突显了融化在重新冻结之前可以侧向流动的。我们使用秋季湿度的热传导建模和雷达观察结果表明，在我们的野外地区，夏季在夏季形成的叠加冰中有65％，其余的在秋天的遗物上冰川上的水文网络。总体而言，可见的径流极限重新融化了84％的熔体。我们估计在2017年至2022年之间，我们估计板块重新融化了56级熔体（根据平板范围的26-69吉甘顿）。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Rivers and slush fields on the Greenland Ice Sheet increasingly develop in locations where the accumulation zone hosts near-impermeable ice slabs. However, the division between runoff versus retention in these areas remains unmeasured. We present field measurements of superimposed ice formation onto slabs around the visible runoff limit. The quantity of superimposed ice varies by proximity to visible surface water and the surface slope, highlighting that meltwater can flow laterally before refreezing. We use heat conduction modelling and radar observations of autumn wetness to show that in our field area in 2022, 65% of superimposed ice formed during summer and the rest during autumn in the relict supraglacial hydrological network. Overall, 84% of melt around the visible runoff limit refroze. Ice-sheet-wide we estimate that slabs refroze 56 gigatonnes of melt (26-69 gigatonnes according to slab extent) between 2017 and 2022. Slabs are thus both hotspots of refreezing and emerging zones of runoff.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-59237-9/MediaObjects/41467_2025_59237_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 大气水分升高升级了大气河在南极气候系统中的未来影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02333-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Rising atmospheric moisture escalates the future impact of atmospheric rivers in the Antarctic climate system&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Michelle L. Maclennan; Andrew C. Winters; Christine A. Shields; Rudradutt Thaker; Léonard Barthelemy; Francis Codron; Jonathan D. Wille&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;尽管它们相对罕见，但大气河还是南极表面质量平衡的关键因素。但是，大气河流在调节南极海平面贡献中的未来作用是不确定性的主要领域。在这里，我们利用高分辨率的气候模拟表明，南极大气河对大气水分的未来增加非常敏感，从而导致大气河频率增加了一倍，从2066-2100的降水量增加了2.5倍，从2066  -  2100年下降，在当今的阈值中，大气阈值对大气河流的检测。但是，未来的降水影响至关重要取决于检测阈值：考虑到阈值的水分增加会导致大气河频率的较小，区域变化，这主要是由于极性喷射最大风速的向东转移。我们的结果强调了使用大型集合来量化南极大气河对预计水分变异性的反应的重要性，这在仅使用少数合奏成员时可能不会被捕获。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Despite their relative rarity, atmospheric rivers are key contributors to the surface mass balance of Antarctica. However, the future role of atmospheric rivers in modulating Antarctic sea-level contributions is a major area of uncertainty. Here, we leverage high-resolution climate simulations to show that Antarctic atmospheric rivers are highly sensitive to future increases in atmospheric moisture, leading to a doubling of atmospheric river frequencies and 2.5 × increase in precipitation from 2066–2100 under present-day thresholds for atmospheric river detection. However, future precipitation impacts are critically dependent on the detection threshold: accounting for moisture increases in the threshold produces smaller, regional changes in atmospheric river frequency, primarily resulting from an eastward shift in the polar jet maximum wind speeds. Our results underscore the importance of using large ensembles to quantify Antarctic atmospheric river responses to variability in projected moisture, which may not be captured when using only a few ensemble members.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02333-x/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2333_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>