<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 02:08:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 使用数据驱动和基于专家的方法绘制国家土壤水文小组环境应用图</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05853-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;National soil hydrologic groups map for environmental applications using data-driven and expert-based methods&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Brigitta Szabó; Ronald András Kolcsár; János Mészáros; Annamária Laborczi; Katalin Takács; Gábor Szatmári; András Makó; Kálmán Rajkai; Balázs Benyhe; Károly Barta; László Pásztor; Zsófia Bakacsi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;区域和国家 3D 土壤水力图增强了对土壤水力特性的了解，这对于环境评估至关重要。然而，在大型模型中通常需要数据聚合，以促进复杂土壤特性的建模。本研究展示了匈牙利土壤水文群地图，该地图是通过 k 均值聚类和基于专家的规则得出的。聚类应用于 100 m 分辨率 3D HU-SoilHydroGrids 数据库，考虑六个深度的八个水力参数。对于具有极端特征的稀有土壤类型，这些地图的准确性受到限制，因为它们的空间范围较小且在国家数据集中的代表性稀疏。为了解释这些代表性不足的土壤类型，我们使用基于专家的规则（包括土壤剖面深度、遗传类型、电导率和可交换钠含量）细化每个基于统计的聚类。最终分类包括 68 个土壤水文组，由不同的水力特性定义，例如描述保水性的 van Genuchten 参数和饱和导水率。该国家地图通过对类似土壤进行一致处理，支持匈牙利全国范围的水文建模、环境管理和农业规划。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Regional and national 3D soil hydraulic maps enhance understanding of soil hydraulic properties, essential for environmental assessments. However, data aggregation is often necessary in large-scale models to facilitate the modelling of complex soil characteristics. This study presents a soil hydrologic groups map for Hungary, derived through k-means clustering and expert-based rules. Clustering was applied to the 100 m resolution 3D HU-SoilHydroGrids database, considering eight hydraulic parameters across six depths. The accuracy of these maps is limited for rare soil types with extreme characteristics due to their small spatial extent and sparse representation in national datasets. To account for these underrepresented soil types, we refined each statistics-based cluster using expert-based rules incorporating soil profile depth, genetic type, electrical conductivity, and exchangeable sodium content. The final classification includes 68 soil hydrologic groups, defined by distinct hydraulic properties, such as van Genuchten parameters to describe water retention, and saturated hydraulic conductivity. This national map supports country-wide hydrological modelling, environmental management, and agricultural planning in Hungary by enabling consistent treatment of similar soils.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05853-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5853_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 巴西地下水井数据库 (GWDBrazil)</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05843-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A groundwater well database for Brazil (GWDBrazil)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; José Gescilam S. M. Uchôa; Paulo Tarso S. Oliveira; André S. Ballarin; Didier Gastmans; Jamil A. A. Anache; Bridget R. Scanlon; Clyvihk R. Camacho; Valmor J. Freddo Filho; Edson C. Wendland&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;充分的时空原位地下水位测量对于可持续水管理至关重要。尽管它们很重要，但缺乏统一、质量控制的数据集阻碍了巴西的大规模地下水研究。我们与巴西地质调查局合作，推出了巴西地下水井数据库 (GWDBrazil)，该数据库整合并标准化了超过 351,000 口井的信息，记录可追溯到 1900 年至 2024 年，其中约 450 口井在 2010 年至 2024 年期间每天进行连续监测。采用交叉验证步骤以确保数据准确性。 GWDBrazil 提供表格格式和矢量点格式，包括位置、井深和井目的等信息。该数据集还提供支持地表水和地下水综合管理的数据，例如每口井到最近河流的距离和含水层信息。该数据集旨在为研究人员、决策者和利益相关者提供宝贵的资源，为支持巴西的综合水资源管理战略提供重要信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sufficient spatiotemporal in-situ groundwater-level measurements are essential for sustainable water management. Despite their importance, lack of harmonized, quality-controlled datasets has hindered large-scale groundwater studies in Brazil. In collaboration with the Geological Survey of Brazil, we present the Groundwater Well Database for Brazil (GWDBrazil), which consolidates and standardizes information from over 351,000 wells, with records dating from 1900 to 2024, including about 450 wells with continuous daily monitoring from 2010 to 2024. Cross-verification steps were applied to ensure data accuracy. GWDBrazil is available in both tabular format and vector points, comprising information such as location, well depth, and well purpose. The dataset also provides data to support integrated surface water and groundwater management, such the distance from each well to the nearest river and aquifer information. This dataset is intended to serve as a valuable resource for researchers, decision-makers, and stakeholders, providing essential information to support comprehensive water management strategies in Brazil.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05843-7/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5843_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 理清科罗拉多河 2026 年后运营的气候和政策不确定性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-63635-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Disentangling climate and policy uncertainties for the Colorado River post-2026 operations&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Bowen Wang; Benjamin Bass; Alex Hall; Stefan Rahimi; Lei Huang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;科罗拉多河流域的米德湖和鲍威尔湖支撑着美国西部的水和水力供应。虽然目前监管该流域的政策将于 2026 年到期，但由于气候变化和政策不确定性交织在一起，规划仍然具有挑战性。根据 10 个动态缩小的 CMIP6 全球气候模型的流量预测以及添加和消除内部变异性的独特方法，我们评估了鲍威尔和米德在现有和替代政策下的未来状况。由于预计流量下降，根据现有政策，两个水库将面临 2060 年之前达到死池的巨大风险（&amp;gt;80% 的可能性）。采用最近提出的替代政策可以减少但不能消除此类风险。所有政策还表现出临界点，即水库水位可能会随着流量的轻微变化而迅速变化。可持续的政策可能需要更大幅度的削减，以进一步降低水库的死池风险，并为突然变化提供更好的缓冲。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lakes Mead and Powell in the Colorado River Basin underpin water and hydropower supply for the western United States. While the policies currently regulating the basin will expire by 2026, planning remains challenging due to intertwined climate variability and policy uncertainties. Based on streamflow projections from 10 dynamically downscaled CMIP6 global climate models and unique methods that add and remove internal variability, we evaluate future conditions at Powell and Mead under existing and alternative policies. Due to projected streamflow declines, under existing policy, both reservoirs will face substantial risks (&amp;gt;80% likelihood) of reaching dead pool before 2060. Adopting recently proposed alternative policies reduces but doesn’t eliminate such risks. All policies also exhibit tipping points where reservoir levels can change rapidly with a slight change in streamflow. A sustainable policy may require larger reductions to further reduce the reservoirs’ dead pool risks and provide better buffers from sudden changes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-63635-4/MediaObjects/41467_2025_63635_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 翼坝对河流水位和河床水位的影响受河床荷载类型的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02739-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Wing dam effects on water and bed levels in rivers are influenced by bedload type&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Gergely Tihamér Török; Gary Parker&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;密西西比河和多瑙河等河流中使用的翼坝通过在低流量时增加水深来改善航行。它们的水貌影响很复杂，其对洪水风险的影响仍然存在争议。在这里，我们开发了一种方法，可以从详细的数值计算中识别当地的物理模式，从而能够扩展到以前难以研究的更大的河段和更长的时间尺度。我们应用这种数值方法来评估几十年到几个世纪以来翼坝对水和河床水位的影响。我们的研究结果表明，河床物质容易发生铠装的河流往往会因翼坝而出现长期水位上升，而其他河流则可能会出现水位下降。调整到新的稳定条件需要几十年的时间，即使在均匀的河床上，水位也会暂时上升。对于密西西比河，翼坝可能导致最初水位上升，但效果随着时间的推移而减弱，表明河床反应不断变化。这些发现有助于设计洪水风险的最佳翼坝配置。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Wing dams, used in rivers like the Mississippi and Danube, improve navigation by increasing water depth during low flow. Their hydromorphological effects are complex, and their influence on flood risk remains debated. Here we developed an approach that identifies local physical patterns from detailed numerical calculations, enabling extension to larger river sections and longer time scales previously difficult to study. We apply this numerical method to assess wing dam impacts on water and bed levels over decades to centuries. Our results show that rivers with bed materials prone to armouring tend to experience long-term water level increases due to wing dams, while others may see decreases. Adjustments to new stable conditions take decades, with temporary water level rises even in uniform beds. For the Mississippi River, wing dams likely caused initial water level increases, but effects declined over time, indicating evolving riverbed responses. These findings help design flood risk–optimal wing dam configurations.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02739-7/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2739_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Climate Change | 自 20 世纪 80 年代以来全球河流峰值流量的同步</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-025-02427-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Synchronization of global peak river discharge since the 1980s&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yixin Yang; Long Yang; Gabriele Villarini; Fang Zhao; Danqing Huang; Gabriel A. Vecchi; Qiang Wang; Yida Sun; Fuqiang Tian&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;与单个事件相比，在多个地区同时发生的河流洪水往往会导致更大的社会和环境影响。然而，控制河流峰值流量在空间上遥远和邻近位置的全球互连的模式和机制在很大程度上仍未被探索。在这里，根据 4,407 个观测水文站的全球年度峰值流量数据库，我们确定了跨越数千公里的远程关联流量峰值的中心。我们显示了远程连接的流域数量和总流域面积不断增加的趋势，表明自 20 世纪 80 年代以来全球河流峰值流量的同步性增强。通过温度和降水异常的扰动，海洋-大气振荡决定了排放峰值的全球耦合模式和时间演变。我们的研究结果强调了气候变暖时全球河流峰值流量的新特征，这有利于协调洪水风险管理。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Riverine floods that occur simultaneously over multiple regions often lead to amplified societal and environmental impacts compared to individual events. However, the pattern and mechanisms governing the global interconnection of peak river discharge across spatially distant and proximate locations remain largely unexplored. Here, on the basis of a global annual peak discharge database from 4,407 observational hydrometric stations, we identify hubs for remotely linked discharge peaks spanning thousands of kilometres. We show increasing trends in the number of remotely linked watersheds and the total drainage area, pointing to amplified synchronization of global peak river discharge since the 1980s. Ocean–atmosphere oscillations, through the perturbation of both temperature and precipitation anomalies, dictate the global coupling pattern and temporal evolution of discharge peaks. Our findings highlight an emergent profile of global peak river flow in a warming climate that can benefit coordinated flood risk management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41558-025-02427-6/MediaObjects/41558_2025_2427_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 森林砍伐和森林火灾导致的拦截减少增加了大规模河流洪水的风险</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02748-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Interception reduction from deforestation and forest fire increases large-scale fluvial flooding risk&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Tae-Ho Kang; Ashish Sharma; Lucy Marshall; Young-Oh Kim&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;人们注意到，森林砍伐后灾难性洪水发生的频率更高，但可用于在大空间尺度上检验这种联系的观测数据有限。在这里，我们使用了影响澳大利亚 25,000 km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;地区的特大森林火灾的数据，显示森林冠层迅速丧失，半个多世纪以来，人们一直在以最小的人为影响仔细观察径流的产生。这为评估森林冠层损失对大规模河流洪水的影响提供了独特的机会。国家控制的假设检验（控制气候和流域状态以增强鲁棒性）显示，森林损失处理导致的年度最大流量在统计上显着增加。这项自然实验的理由是，森林损失对大范围森林冠层、落叶和根区土壤拦截潜力的影响可能对河流洪水产生可识别的影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Catastrophic flooding has been noted to occur with greater frequency following deforestation, but limited observations have been available to test this connection over large spatial scales. Here we used the data of mega forest fires impacting a region of 25,000 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; in Australia exhibiting rapid loss in forest canopy, where the runoff generation has been carefully observed with minimum anthropogenic influences for more than half a century. This provides a unique opportunity to assess the impact of the forest canopy loss on large-scale fluvial flooding. A state-controlled hypothesis test, with the climate and watershed states controlled to enhance robustness, shows a statistically significant increase in annual maximum flows resulting from the forest loss treatment. The reasoning for this natural experiment is that the forest loss impact on the interception potential of forest canopy, fallen leaves, and root-zone soils in wide region could have a recognizable impact on the fluvial flood.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02748-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2748_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 冰缘地区的地貌和生物流连通性被破坏</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02812-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Disrupted geomorphic and biotic stream connectivity in paraglacial regions&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lina E. Polvi; Lovisa Lind&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;生态和地貌理论假设纵向连通性；在这里，我们测试这些概念是否适用于具有湖泊和粗冰川沉积物的自然断开的冰缘河流网络。我们确定了河道宽度的下游水力几何关系（DHG）；对瑞典北部两个流域（一个在前最高海岸线 (FHC) 之上，一个在之下）超过 10 公里的过程域（急流、平地、湖泊）河岸植被进行了清查。在FHC之下，来自海洋/三角洲沉积的更细的沉积物可能允许更多的河流自我调整。 DHG 关系总体较弱，局部宽度变化较大，但在 FHC 流域以下稍强，发现了湖泊效应，湖泊下游河道较宽。下游河岸植被物种密度并未像连通的河流网络那样大幅增加，河段之间的植被相似性与距离的相关性较弱，表明扩散受到破坏。这些发现表明，以前的冰川流域高度分散，当地因素主导着地貌和生态模式。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ecological and geomorphic theory assume longitudinal connectivity; here, we test whether these concepts apply in naturally disconnected paraglacial stream networks with lakes and coarse glacial sediment. We determined downstream hydraulic geometry relationships (DHG) for channel width; riparian vegetation was inventoried across process domains (rapids, flats, lakes) over 10 km in two northern Swedish catchments—one above and one below the former highest coastline (FHC). Below the FHC, finer sediment from marine/deltaic deposition may allow more stream self-adjustment. DHG relationships were weak overall, with large local width variation, but slightly stronger in the FHC-below catchment, where a lake-effect was found, with wider channels downstream of lakes. Riparian vegetation species density did not substantially increase downstream as in connected stream networks, and vegetation similarity between reaches was weakly related to distance, suggesting disrupted dispersal. These findings indicate that formerly glaciated catchments are highly fragmented, with local factors dominating geomorphic and ecological patterns.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02812-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2812_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 质量受控、可靠的地下水位数据以及印度相应的具体产量</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05899-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Quality controlled, reliable groundwater level data with corresponding specific yield over India&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Satish Kumar Kuruva; Maya Raghunath Suryawanshi; Amin Shakya; Chethan VA; Balaram Shaw; Vandana Sukumaran; Retinder Kour; Aayushi Kochar; Shard Chander; Bhaskar R. Nikam; Nagesh Kumar Dasika; Bramha Dutt Vishwakarma&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;地下水是家庭、农业和工业使用的重要资源，由于人口增长和气候变化，其需求不断增长。多项研究表明，印度西北部地区的地下水正在以不可持续的速度消耗，但印度南部却出现了相反的趋势。为了更好地研究地下水动态，质量受控且可靠的井数据至关重要，但目前却缺失。在这里，我们处理印度 32,299 口井的季节性地下水位，以获得可靠的井数据并提供各自的具体产量。最初，没有数据和负值的孔被删除。随后对每口井采用三西格玛方法以消除异常值。最后，保留每年至少有两个值且没有值连续重复两次以上的井，从而获得 2,759 口可靠井。我们使用基于矢量化的方法对含水层类型进行分类，并根据水文地质图估算具体产量。我们还提供数据和脚本的开放访问，以便研究人员可以研究地下水变化，将 GRACE 和基于模型的地下水估计与现场井数据进行比较。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Groundwater is a vital resource for domestic, agricultural, and industrial use, with its demand growing due to population growth and climate change. Several studies have identified groundwater depleting in India at unsustainable rate over North-west part, but a contrasting trend is observed in the southern India. To better study groundwater dynamics quality-controlled and reliable well data is essential, which is missing. Here we process seasonal groundwater levels from 32,299 wells across India to obtain reliable well data and provide respective specific yields. Initially, wells with no data and negative values are removed. Later three-sigma method is imposed on each well to eliminate outliers. Finally, wells with at least two values per year, with no value repeating more than twice consecutively, are retained, resulting in 2,759 reliable wells. We used vectorization-based method to classify aquifer types and estimated specific yields based on hydrogeological map. We also provide open access to data and scripts so that researchers can study groundwater variations, compare GRACE and model-based groundwater estimates against in-situ well data.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05899-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5899_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Water | 水文传感器网络的可扩展、自适应和风险告知设计</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00496-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Scalable, adaptive and risk-informed design of hydrological sensor networks&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jeil Oh; Matt Bartos&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流监测网络对于了解和管理地球水资源至关重要，但它们的部署很少在系统规模上进行协调来实现这些目标。我们提出了一个用于设计水流监测网络的数据驱动框架，该框架可以改进水文预测，同时适应社会环境限制。该方法使用揭示等级的 QR 分解来隔离最能捕获从回顾性模拟获得的水文时间序列的时空结构的监测点。使用 44 年的再分析数据进行评估，我们发现与现有方法相比，我们的传感器放置方法能够更好地重建未测量位置的水流。我们的方法适应现有计量网络的增量扩展，并整合洪水风险等运营优先事项，而不会影响水文预测的准确性。该框架在不同的水文状况中得到了验证，为计量网络设计提供了一种可扩展且稳健的方法，使水资源管理者能够做出更明智的决策。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Stream monitoring networks are essential for understanding and managing Earth’s water resources, yet their deployment is rarely coordinated at the system scale to meet these objectives. We present a data-driven framework for the design of streamflow monitoring networks that improves hydrological predictions while also accommodating socio-environmental constraints. This approach uses a rank-revealing QR decomposition to isolate monitoring sites that best capture the spatiotemporal structure of hydrological time series obtained from retrospective simulations. Evaluated using 44 years of reanalysis data, we find that our sensor placement approach enables better reconstructions of streamflow at ungauged locations compared with existing methods. Our approach accommodates incremental expansion of existing gauge networks and integrates operational priorities, such as flood risk, without compromising the accuracy of hydrological predictions. Demonstrated across diverse hydrological regimes, this framework provides a scalable and robust method for gauge network design that will empower water managers to make more informed decisions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00496-7/MediaObjects/44221_2025_496_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 气候变化和人类活动加剧了大河下游径流变异风险</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02759-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Climate change and human activities amplify runoff variability risks in lower reaches of large rivers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ju Gao; Chunhui Li; Xiong Zhou; Yujun Yi; Xuan Wang; Qiang Liu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候变化和人类活动对径流变化的贡献已经在多个单独流域进行了研究，但上下游相互作用关系仍未得到充分探索。在这里，我们提出了一个三层归因框架来研究黄河流域径流变化的时空模式、潜在驱动因素和上下游关系（1952-2021）。结果表明，气候（相对于全流域上游-8.6%到下游7.1%）和人为干扰（15.2%-92.9%）因素的纵向累积效应导致下游地区径流变化风险较高，季节性波动更加明显（尤其是水库调节河段）。冰川、湖泊和水库的蓄水能力导致气候变化和人类活动对径流变化的滞后影响，同时也是流域间水资源调节的关键驱动因素。整合对多尺度水文变异驱动因素和空间相互作用机制的全面理解对于推进适应性流域管理和可持续水资源配置至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The contributions of climate change and human activities to runoff variation have been examined in multiple individual catchments, but upstream-downstream interaction relationships remain underexplored. Here, we propose a three-tiered attribution framework to investigate the spatiotemporal patterns, underlying drivers, and upstream-downstream relationships of runoff variations in the Yellow River Basin (1952–2021). The results indicate that the longitudinal cumulative effects of climatic (ranging from −8.6% upstream to 7.1% downstream relative to the whole basin) and anthropogenic disturbance (15.2%-92.9%) factors lead to higher risks of runoff variations in downstream regions, with more pronounced seasonal fluctuations (particularly in reservoir-regulated reaches). Glaciers, lakes, and reservoirs’ storage capacities cause lagged effects of climate change and human activities on runoff variations, while simultaneously serving as critical drivers for inter-basin water resource regulation. Integrating comprehensive understanding of multi-scale hydrological variability drivers and spatial interaction mechanisms is essential for advancing adaptive river basin management and sustainable water resources allocation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02759-3/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2759_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>