<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 02:05:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 全球灌溉水源 60 米分辨率缩小估算（2000-2015 年）</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05920-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Downscaled global 60-meter resolution estimates of irrigation water sources (2000–2015)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Fengwei Hung; Davide Danilo Chiarelli; James S. Famiglietti; Marc F. Müller&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;该数据集提供高分辨率 (60 m) 全球灌溉地图，以支持水资源和农业管理。它确定了 2000 年、2005 年、2010 年和 2015 年农田可能的灌溉状况（雨养或灌溉）和水源（地下水或地表水）。我们使用 (i) 高分辨率 (30 m) 农田和附近地表水之间的空间模式，以及 (ii) 全球作物模型的灌溉用水需求，缩小了源自国家和次国家统计数据 (GMIA) 的 10 公里灌溉数据集。验证使用了印度的家庭农业调查（N = 8,355）和美国的油井数据库（N = 1,505,371）。在美国，我们的方法在区分井 2 公里范围内的地下水使用方面达到了 85% 的准确度，远高于 GMIA (25%)。在印度地下水占主导地位的地区，我们的预测结果与 GMIA 相当（73% 与 72%）。这些结果表明我们的数据集提供了更准确和空间详细的灌溉水源表示，从而改进了农业用水的分析。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This dataset provides high-resolution (60 m) global irrigation maps to support water resource and agricultural management. It identifies the likely irrigation status (rainfed or irrigated) and water source (groundwater or surface water) of croplands for 2000, 2005, 2010, and 2015. We downscaled a 10-km irrigation dataset derived from national and subnational statistics (GMIA) using (i) spatial patterns between high-resolution (30 m) cropland and nearby surface water, and (ii) irrigation water requirements from a global crop model. Validation used household agriculture surveys in India (N = 8,355) and a U.S. well database (N = 1,505,371). In the U.S., our method achieved 85% accuracy in distinguishing groundwater use within 2 km of wells – substantially higher than GMIA (25%). In India’s groundwater-dominated regions, our estimates performed comparably to GMIA (73% vs. 72%). These results suggest our dataset offers a more accurate and spatially detailed representation of irrigation water sources, enabling improved analysis of agricultural water use.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05920-x/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5920_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 水分和温度来源是 2023 年亚马逊创纪录干旱异常的关键驱动因素</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02771-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Moisture and temperature sources were key drivers of the anomalies for the record-breaking of 2023 Amazon drought&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; José C. Fernández-Alvarez; Raquel Nieto; Sergio M. Vicente-Serrano; David Carvalho; Luis Gimeno&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2022-24年创纪录的亚马逊干旱延伸至奥里诺科河和塞拉多地区，其特点是2023-24水文年干湿过渡季节（2023年9月至11月）出现严重干旱。尽管海洋水分源表现出负异常，但这种情况并不是由偏远来源或该地区本身的水分不足造成的。这是由普遍的大气稳定性引起的，抑制了该地区的对流，从而抑制了降水，而且极端高温是其主要驱动因素，从2022-23拉尼娜到2023-24厄尔尼诺的过渡，放大了变量的异常。尽管大气湿度异常高，但不足以补偿高温，导致相对湿度值降低和大气蒸发需求增加。该地区未沉淀的水分被输送到对流足够不稳定的地区，导致2023年9月至10月乌拉圭/巴西-南大西洋边缘河流域出现高降水和洪水。目标区域的温度异常有两个来源：导致变暖的本地因素和导致变冷的外部因素。结果表明，由于区域本身和区域外的沉降导致绝热变暖的重要性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The record-breaking 2022–24 Amazon-drought, which extended into the Orinoco and Cerrado regions, was characterized by severe-dry conditions during the dry-to-wet transition-season of the 2023–24 hydrological years (September-November/2023). This situation was not driven by a moisture-deficit from either remote sources or the region itself, although oceanic moisture sources exhibited negative anomalies. It was caused by the prevailing atmospheric stability, which inhibited convection and therefore precipitation in this region, and by extremely high temperatures having as its main driver the transition from 2022–23 La Niña to 2023–24 El Niño, which amplified the anomalies in the variables. Although atmospheric moisture was anomalously high, it was insufficient to compensate for the high temperatures, which led to reduced relative humidity values and enhanced atmospheric evaporative demand. Moisture that did not precipitate in the region was transported to areas where there was sufficient instability for convection, resulting in high precipitation and floods in the Uruguay/Brazilian-South-Atlantic-Marginal river basins in September-October/2023. The temperature anomaly over the target region had two sources: a local one contributing to warming and an external one contributing to cooling. The results show the importance of adiabatic warming due to subsidence in the region itself and outside the region.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02771-7/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2771_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>