<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 02:11:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 洪水死亡和流离失所会影响发展中国家洪泛区的人类移民</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02293-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Flood fatalities and displacement influence human migration in floodplains of developing countries&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ning Wang; Fubao Sun; Siquan Yang; Yao Feng; Hongquan Sun; Zhonggen Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;了解驱动人类在洪泛区中移民的原因对于缓解风险并增强对洪水的韧性至关重要。但是，现有的全球分析尚未完全探索这些复杂的动态。在这里，我们介绍了一个度量，人类渗透距离的变化，以跟踪2000年至2018年洪泛区的迁移，探索气候和人为影响的相互作用。我们发现，在包括印度，阿根廷，巴西和尼日利亚在内的发展中国家中，洪水死亡和流离失所会强烈影响移民决策，通常迫使人口由于洪水损失的记忆或资源需求而驱逐出洪水泛滥的地区。相反，具有较高洪水保护的地区，例如美国，显示出偏离危险地区的迁移趋势。气候驾驶员（如洪水淹没区）在澳大利亚造成了更大的影响。值得注意的是，在菲律宾和肯尼亚，消除干旱的替代方案的缓解导致人口向容易发生洪水的地区增加，强调了多种危害之间的复杂相互作用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understanding what drives human migration in floodplains is critical for mitigating risks and enhancing resilience to floods. However, existing global analyses have not fully explored these complex dynamics. Here we introduce a metric, human-flood distance change, to track migration in floodplains from 2000 to 2018, exploring the interplay of climatic and anthropogenic influences. We find that in developing countries, including India, Argentina, Brazil and Nigeria, flood fatalities and displacement strongly influence migration decisions, often forcing populations to move away or toward flood-prone areas due to flood damage memory or resource needs. Conversely, regions with higher flood protection, such as the United States, show migration trends away from hazardous areas. Climatic drivers, like flood inundation area, exert stronger influences in Australia. Notably, in the Philippines and Kenya, the easing of drought-flood abrupt alternation has led to increased population movement toward flood-prone areas, underscoring the complex interactions between multiple hazards.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02293-2/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2293_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>