<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 01:58:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 紧急约束表明，未来全球蒸散量的增加速度较慢</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00932-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yuanfang Chai; Yao Yue; Louise Slater; Chiyuan Miao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球陆地蒸散量（ET）的预测受到巨大的不确定性的困扰。在这里，我们在SSP126的低排放情况下，在SSP126的低排放趋势下，在SSP126的低排放趋势下，我们发现了预计的全球ET趋势（2015-2100）（2015-2100）（2015-2100）（2015-2100）和历史蒸气压力不足（VPD）趋势之间的双变量紧急约束关系的，我们在28个CMIP6型号中，当水的供应受到限制时，在SSP370和SSP585的高排放方案下。将多个观察数据集结合到分层的紧急约束框架中，我们发现RAW CMIP6模型高估了未来的年度ET增长率。最初的预测为0.233±0.107毫米&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; （SSP126），0.360±0.244毫米年度&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; （SSP370）和0.506±0.365 mm年&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; （SSP585）的原始预测被调整为0.193±0.074 mm y &lt;sup&gt;-1-1，0.193&lt;/sup&gt; ±0.074毫米 - 纽0.184毫米&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; 1年和0.391±0.299毫米&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; 。修订后的预测不确定性减少了18.1–31.1％。这些发现突出了合并观察性约束以提高ET预测的可靠性的价值，这对于理解未来的全球水周期至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Projections of global terrestrial evapotranspiration (ET) are plagued by sizeable uncertainties. Here, we uncover bivariate emergent constraint relationships between projected global ET trends (2015–2100) and historical vapour pressure deficit (VPD) trends (1980–2014) under the low emission scenario of SSP126 when water supply is sufficient, and with historical precipitation trends under the high emission scenarios of SSP370 and SSP585 when water availability is limited, across 28 CMIP6 models. Combining multiple observational datasets into a Hierarchical Emergent Constraint framework, we find the raw CMIP6 models overestimate future annual ET growth rates. The original projections of 0.233 ± 0.107 mm year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; (SSP126), 0.360 ± 0.244 mm year−&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; (SSP370) and 0.506 ± 0.365 mm year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; (SSP585) are adjusted downwards to 0.193 ± 0.074 mm year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;, 0.272 ± 0.184 mm year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; and 0.391 ± 0.299 mm year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;. The revised projection uncertainties are reduced by 18.1–31.1%. These findings highlight the value of incorporating observational constraints to improve the reliability of ET projections, which are critical for understanding the future global water cycle.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00932-1/MediaObjects/41612_2025_932_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 灌溉和森林砍伐的对比对兰坎·曼旺河流域水文学的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02093-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hao Huang; Junguo Liu; Luca Guillaumot; Aifang Chen; Inge E. M. de Graaf; Deliang Chen&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;灌溉扩展和随后的森林砍伐基本上影响了较大的盆地变异性。但是，鉴于水文变量之间的复杂相互作用，需要对共存土地使用变化内的水文影响更全面地理解。在这里，我们使用历史河流测量值和卫星观测来应用地表水耦合模拟，以评估兰开冈河流域水文学的长期和季节性变化。增加灌溉升高的土壤水分，但地下水储存枯竭。相反，森林砍伐可减少土壤水分，并增加陡峭地形区域的横向流量，以补偿地下水耗尽。灌溉通过增强蒸散和基流的影响影响了径流，这对径流的变化具有相反的影响，从而导致混合的空间模式减少和增加。同时，由于森林砍伐偏移而导致的土壤水分减少，由于灌溉而增加的蒸散量增加，导致径流的范围比减少的降低更大。这些说明了不同土地使用变化和复杂系统评估的途径的独特水文影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Irrigation expansion and subsequent deforestation substantially affect large basin variability. However, given the complex interactions between hydrological variables, a more comprehensive understanding of the hydrological impacts within the coexisting land use changes is needed. Here, we applied surface-groundwater-coupled simulations with historical river gauges and satellite observations to evaluate long-term and seasonal changes in Lancang-Mekong River Basin hydrology. Increasing irrigation elevated soil moisture but depleted groundwater storage. Conversely, deforestation reduced soil moisture, and increased lateral flow in areas with steep terrain compensated for groundwater depletion. Irrigation affected runoff by augmenting evapotranspiration and baseflow, which had opposite implications for runoff changes, causing a mixed spatial pattern of decreases and increases. Meanwhile, decreases in soil moisture due to deforestation offset increases in evapotranspiration due to irrigation, resulting in wider areas of runoff increases than decreases. These illustrate the distinct hydrological impacts of different land use changes and a pathway to complex system assessments.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02093-8/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2093_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 解密蒸散量在降低土地相对湿度趋势中的作用</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02076-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yeonuk Kim; Mark S. Johnson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;近几十年来，土地上的相对湿度有所下降，干旱和野火的增加。先前的解释将这种趋势归因于从海洋中的水分对流不足以维持当前水平，但这忽略了陆地蒸散液提供的大气水分。重要的是，当前的最新气候模型继续低估了观察到的土地相对湿度趋势。在这里，我们表明，相对于给定的基线，特定的湿度的变化（由海洋平流都没有责任）在数量上等同于全球范围内蒸散量的相对变化。尽管存在蒸散趋势差异，但在气候模型和气候重新分析数据集中，这一发现是一致的。蒸散趋势的差异被确定为在气候模型中表达的相对湿度趋势偏见的显着原因。这些结果表明，当前的气候模型可能高估了蒸散量的强化，从而导致大气干燥的低估，对准确预测干旱，野火和气候适应的影响至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In recent decades, relative humidity over land has declined, driving increases in droughts and wildfires. Previous explanations attribute this trend to insufficient moisture advection from the ocean to sustain the current level, but this ignores atmospheric moisture supplied from terrestrial evapotranspiration. Importantly, current state-of-the-art climate models continue to underestimate the observed relative humidity trend over land. Here, we show that changes in specific humidity over land relative to a given baseline, unaccounted for by ocean advection, are quantitatively equivalent to relative changes in evapotranspiration on a global scale. This finding is consistent across climate models and climate reanalysis datasets, despite discrepancies in evapotranspiration trends among them. Differences in evapotranspiration trends are identified as a prominent cause of the bias in relative humidity trend expressed in climate models. These results suggest that current climate models may overestimate evapotranspiration intensifications, leading to an underestimation of atmospheric drying, with critical implications for accurately predicting droughts, wildfires, and climate adaptation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02076-9/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2076_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 使用Daymet的高分辨率，网格的产品用于蒸气压力不足</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04544-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Nicholas K. Corak; Peter E. Thornton; Lauren E. L. Lowman&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;蒸气压力不足（VPD）是评估干旱条件和评估植物水应力的关键变量。全球和区域VPD的网格产品无法从卫星遥感，模型重新分析或地面观察数据集中免费获得。我们以1公里的空间分辨率和每日时间步骤介绍了美国大陆和加拿大北部和加拿大北部（CONUS+）的第一个网格VPD产品的两个版本。我们根据日常每日温度和平均每日蒸气压力得出VPD，并根据（1）由Köppen-Geiger分类确定的气候和（2）由国际地质 - 双聚球计划确定的土地覆盖率的估计值。来自代表不同气候和土地覆盖分类的253个Ameriflux站点的基于地面的VPD数据用于改善CONUS+网格中每个像素的日光衍生的VPD估计值，以生成最终数据集。我们根据独立的观察和重新分析数据评估了Daymet衍生的VPD。 CONUS+ VPD数据集将有助于调查包括干旱和野火在内的骚乱，并为土地管理策略提供信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Vapor pressure deficit (VPD) is a critical variable in assessing drought conditions and evaluating plant water stress. Gridded products of global and regional VPD are not freely available from satellite remote sensing, model reanalysis, or ground observation datasets. We present two versions of the first gridded VPD product for the Continental US and parts of Northern Mexico and Southern Canada (CONUS+) at a 1 km spatial resolution and daily time step. We derived VPD from Daymet maximum daily temperature and average daily vapor pressure and scale the estimates based on (1) climate determined by the Köppen-Geiger classifications and (2) land cover determined by the International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme. Ground-based VPD data from 253 AmeriFlux sites representing different climate and land cover classifications were used to improve the Daymet-derived VPD estimates for every pixel in the CONUS+ grid to produce the final datasets. We evaluated the Daymet-derived VPD against independent observations and reanalysis data. The CONUS+ VPD datasets will aid in investigating disturbances including drought and wildfire, and informing land management strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04544-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4544_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>