<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 02:10:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 里海水平的快速下降威胁生态系统完整性，生物多样性保护和人类基础设施</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02212-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Rapid decline of Caspian Sea level threatens ecosystem integrity, biodiversity protection, and human infrastructure&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Rebecca Court; Matteo Lattuada; Nataliya Shumeyko; Mirgaliy Baimukanov; Tariyel Eybatov; Altynay Kaidarova; Elchin V. Mamedov; Eldar Rustamov; Aselle Tasmagambetova; Matthias Prange; Thomas Wilke; Christopher Hassall; Simon J. Goodman&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;里海是世界上最大的内陆水体，为数百种地方性和迁徙物种提供了栖息地，以及维持数百万人的生态系统服务。预计全球变暖将使水位的下降速度高达21 m乘以2100。使用地理空间分析，我们评估了海平面下降对栖息地，保护区和人类基础设施的影响。我们表明，仅5-10 m的水位下降将严重破坏关键的生态系统（包括流行的里海印章和st鱼的栖息地），将现有的海洋保护区覆盖量减少多达94％，并使数十亿美元的公民和工业基础设施过时。建议用预先避免的动态方法替换传统的静态保护计划，该方法允许保护区追踪变化的生态系统，以帮助原始的里海生物多样性适应这些变化，并避免与针对保护人类活动的缓解工作的冲突。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Caspian Sea is the world’s largest landlocked waterbody, providing habitat for hundreds of endemic and migratory species, along with ecosystem services that sustain millions of people. Global warming is projected to drive declines in water levels of up to 21 m by 2100. Using geospatial analyses, we assessed the impact of sea level decline on habitats, protected areas, and human infrastructure. We show that a water level decline of just 5–10 m will critically disrupt key ecosystems (including habitats for endemic Caspian seals and sturgeon), reduce existing marine protected area coverage by up to 94%, and render billions of dollars of civil and industrial infrastructure obsolete. Replacing traditional static conservation planning with a pre-emptive, dynamic approach that allows protected areas to track shifting ecosystems, is recommended to help endemic Caspian Sea biodiversity adapt to these changes, and to avoid conflicts with mitigation efforts directed at protecting human activities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02212-5/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2212_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 灌溉区域下午降雨量增加的观察证据</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-58729-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Observational evidence of increased afternoon rainfall downwind of irrigated areas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; P. Greve; A. U. Schmitt; D. G. Miralles; S. McDermid; K. L. Findell; A. García-García; J. Peng&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;灌溉在解决日益增长的全球人口的粮食需求中起着至关重要的作用。它代表了耦合的水和能量周期上最关键，最直接的人类干预措施之一。随着灌溉农田的不断扩大，了解广泛灌溉的气候影响变得越来越重要。然而，对灌溉区域附近降雨模式的影响尚不清楚。在这里，使用两个全球高分辨率，每日降水数据集，我们表明下午降雨事件的发生频率更高10公里至50 km，而广泛灌溉的土地上的频率较低。但是，我们还发现，灌溉区域下风的大雨总量低于上风。我们的结果建立了围绕灌溉区域的局部降水动态的大规模观察证据。这些见解将有助于限制下一代气候和天气预报模型中这些过程的表示，并为区域水管理提供宝贵的见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Irrigation plays a vital role in addressing the growing food demand of an increasing global population. It represents one of the most critical and direct human interventions on the coupled water and energy cycles. As irrigated farmland continues to expand, understanding the climate impact of extensive irrigation becomes increasingly important. Yet, the effect on rainfall patterns near irrigated areas remains unclear. Here, using two global, high-resolution, sub-daily precipitation datasets, we show that afternoon rain events occur more often 10 km to 50 km downwind and less often upwind of extensively irrigated land. However, we also find that the total amount of heavy afternoon rain downwind of irrigated areas is lower than upwind. Our results establish large-scale observational evidence of the local precipitation dynamics surrounding irrigated areas; these insights will help constrain the representation of these processes in next-generation climate and weather forecasting models and provide valuable insights for regional water management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-58729-y/MediaObjects/41467_2025_58729_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Climate Change | 湖泊的地下热浪</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-025-02314-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Subsurface heatwaves in lakes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; R. Iestyn Woolway; Miraj B. Kayastha; Yan Tong; Lian Feng; Haoran Shi; Pengfei Xue&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;湖热水（极端热水事件）可能会大大破坏水生生态系统。尽管对表面热浪进行了充分的研究，但它们的湖泊内垂直结构在很大程度上尚未探索。在这里，我们使用时空建模框架分析了地下湖Heatwaves（表面下方发生的极端热事件）的特征。我们的发现表明，地下热浪频繁，通常持续时间更长，但强度不如表面事件。在过去40年中，深水热浪（底部热浪）的频率（7.2天十年&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ），持续时间（2.1天十年&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ）和强度（0.2°C天数&lt;sup&gt;）&lt;/sup&gt; 。此外，在表面和底部同时发生极端热量的垂直复合热浪已增加了3.3天&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; 。到本世纪末，热浪模式的变化，尤其是在高排放下的变化，预计将加剧。这些发现凸显了对地下监测的需求，以充分理解和预测湖泊热浪的生态影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lake heatwaves (extreme hot water events) can substantially disrupt aquatic ecosystems. Although surface heatwaves are well studied, their vertical structures within lakes remain largely unexplored. Here we analyse the characteristics of subsurface lake heatwaves (extreme hot events occurring below the surface) using a spatiotemporal modelling framework. Our findings reveal that subsurface heatwaves are frequent, often longer lasting but less intense than surface events. Deep-water heatwaves (bottom heatwaves) have increased in frequency (7.2 days decade&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;), duration (2.1 days decade&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;) and intensity (0.2 °C days decade&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;) over the past 40 years. Moreover, vertically compounding heatwaves, where extreme heat occurs simultaneously at the surface and bottom, have risen by 3.3 days decade&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;. By the end of the century, changes in heatwave patterns, particularly under high emissions, are projected to intensify. These findings highlight the need for subsurface monitoring to fully understand and predict the ecological impacts of lake heatwaves.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41558-025-02314-0/MediaObjects/41558_2025_2314_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 每月0.05°冬季雪地深度数据集，用于21 cmip6型号的北半球</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04925-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Monthly 0.05° winter months snow depth dataset for the Northern Hemisphere from 21 CMIP6 models&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Shiqiu Lin; Xiaona Chen; Shunlin Liang; Yangxiaoyue Liu; Yu Li; Huan Li&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;准确的积雪深度数据集对于水资源管理，全面的气候变化评估以及在快速气候变化的背景下对冰雪经济的可持续发展至关重要。为了创建针对北半球冬季（NHMSD）量身定制的高分辨率每月雪深度数据集（NHMSD），该研究采用了Delta统计降低方法，并结合了一种空间特征转移技术，以优化从21个主要的一般循环模型和四个共享社会经济学途径源为CMIP6 cmip6 Project。 The NHMSD stands as the world&amp;#39;s pioneering long-term 0.05° snow depth dataset, encompassing the historical era from 1980 to 2014 and extending into future projections from 2015 to 2100. Validation using 2062 ground snow depth observations has confirmed that NHMSD outperforms reanalysis datasets, including ERA5-Land and GLDAS, in terms of root mean square error, bias, and mean absolute error for the时期1980- 2014年和2015  -  2023年。该数据集有助于探索北半球未来情况下雪深的潜在变化。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Accurate snow depth datasets are crucial for water resource management, comprehensive climate change evaluations, and the sustainable advancement of the ice-and-snow economy in the context of rapid climate change. To create a high-resolution monthly snow depth dataset tailored for the Northern Hemisphere winter months (NHMSD), this study employed the Delta statistical downscaling method, in conjunction with a spatial feature transfer technique, to refine snow depth data derived from 21 major general circulation models and four shared socioeconomic pathways sourced from the CMIP6 project. The NHMSD stands as the world’s pioneering long-term 0.05° snow depth dataset, encompassing the historical era from 1980 to 2014 and extending into future projections from 2015 to 2100. Validation using 2062 ground snow depth observations has confirmed that NHMSD outperforms reanalysis datasets, including ERA5-Land and GLDAS, in terms of root mean square error, bias, and mean absolute error for the periods 1980–2014 and 2015–2023. This dataset facilitates the exploration of potential alterations in snow depth under future scenarios in the Northern Hemisphere.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04925-w/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4925_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>