<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 02:05:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Water | 农业生态干旱响应二氧化碳去除的滞后和可逆性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00487-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Hysteresis and reversibility of agroecological droughts in response to carbon dioxide removal&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Laibao Liu; Mathias Hauser; Michael Windisch; Sonia I. Seneviratne&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;随着气候变化的影响，农业生态干旱将增加，成为对生态系统和人类社会的最大威胁之一。为了减轻气候变化和农业生态干旱的日益增长的风险，越来越多的二氧化碳（CDR）被认为是不可避免的。但是，目前尚不清楚是否会因大气中的大气CDR对称逆转大气CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;排放引起的农业生态干旱的增加。在这里，我们通过利用CDR模型对比项目的理想大气CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;发射和去除实验来研究这个问题，涉及八个地球系统模型，并开发了一种量化气候滞后和可逆性的新方法。我们发现，热点区域的干旱增加不能与等效的CDR对称逆转：在CDR途径下的干旱严重程度比排放途径下的干旱严重程度高65％±30％；当CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;排放通过等效的CDR平衡时，干旱频率的增加仅会部分逆转73％±18％。在地中海，中美洲北部，西部和南部非洲和澳大利亚南部，干旱滞后和不可逆性最为明显。我们的发现意味着与CDR相关的不可逆转的干旱影响，强调了规划长期干旱适应的需求。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Agroecological droughts are expected to increase with climate change, becoming one of the greatest threats to ecosystems and human society. To mitigate climate change and the growing risk of agroecological droughts, carbon dioxide removal (CDR) is increasingly recognized as unavoidable. However, it remains unclear whether the increase of agroecological drought due to atmospheric CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions will be symmetrically reversed by an equivalent atmospheric CDR. Here we investigate this question by utilizing an idealized atmospheric CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emission and removal experiment from the CDR Model Intercomparison Project, involving eight Earth system models, and develop a new methodology to quantify climate hysteresis and reversibility. We find that drought increases in hotspot regions cannot be symmetrically reversed by an equivalent CDR: drought severity under the CDR pathway is 65% ± 30% greater than under the emission pathway; drought frequency increases are only partially reversed by 73% ± 18% when CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions are balanced by equivalent CDR. Drought hysteresis and irreversibility are most pronounced in the Mediterranean, northern Central America, west and east southern Africa and southern Australia. Our findings imply irreversible drought impacts associated with CDR, highlighting the need for planning long-term drought adaptations.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00487-8/MediaObjects/44221_2025_487_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>