<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 02:21:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 火星斜坡上的条纹干燥</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-59395-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Streaks on martian slopes are dry&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Valentin Tertius Bickel; Adomas Valantinas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;斜坡条纹是火星斜率上的深色反照率特征，它们会自发地形成，并逐渐消失了数十年。与季节性重复的斜坡线条一起，条纹形成还归因于水过程，这意味着在火星表面上存在瞬时但大量的液态水或盐水，对当今的火星的可居住性具有重要意义。在这里，我们使用一种深厚的学习方法来创建第一个一致的全球目录，为半百万个单独的斜率连续。我们表明，坡度的变形可修改不到火星表面的0.1％，但每年火星年的几种全球风暴等效物都可能在火星尘埃周期中发挥重要作用。我们的全球地球统计分析挑战了潮湿的形成模型，而是支持季节性灰尘递送和诸如风能和气象撞击之类的充满活力的触发因素。我们进一步确定了重复的斜坡形成，季节性灰尘沉积和尘埃魔鬼活动之间的定性时空关系。我们的发现表明，现代火星的斜坡通常不会体验到水或盐水的短暂流动，这意味着可以探索轴承痕迹地形而不会引起行星保护的问题。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Slope streaks are dark albedo features on martian slopes that form spontaneously and fade over years to decades. Along with seasonally recurring slope lineae, streak formation has been attributed to aqueous processes, implying the presence of transient yet substantial amounts of liquid water or brines on Mars’ surface, with important implications for present-day Mars’ habitability. Here, we use a deep learning-enabled approach to create the first consistent, global catalog of half a million individual slope streaks. We show that slope streaks modify less than 0.1% of the martian surface, but transport several global storm equivalents of dust per Mars year, potentially playing a major role in the martian dust cycle. Our global geostatistical analysis challenges wet streak formation models and instead supports dry streak formation, driven by seasonal dust delivery and energetic triggers like wind and meteoritic impacts. We further identify a qualitative, spatiotemporal relation between recurring slope lineae formation, seasonal dust deposition, and dust devil activity. Our findings suggest that modern Mars’ slopes do not commonly experience transient flows of water or brines, implying that streak bearing terrain can be explored without raising planetary protection concerns.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-59395-w/MediaObjects/41467_2025_59395_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Climate Change | 超过1.5°C后，不可逆的冰川变化和槽水数百年</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-025-02318-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Irreversible glacier change and trough water for centuries after overshooting 1.5 °C&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lilian Schuster; Fabien Maussion; David R. Rounce; Lizz Ultee; Patrick Schmitt; Fabrice Lacroix; Thomas L. Frölicher; Carl-Friedrich Schleussner&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;超过前工业水平以上的全球变暖超过1.5°C已成为一种明显的可能性，但是这种过冲对山地冰川的后果及其对提高海平面和影响水分的贡献的后果尚不清楚。在这里，我们表明超过并返回到1.5°C以下将对冰川质量和几个世纪的径流产生不可逆转的后果。全球气候和冰川模拟计划，即3.0°C的峰值和排列情况将导致全球冰川质量损失增加2500，而不是将变暖限制在1.5°C而不会过度冲击的情况下。在峰值温度后冰川再生的盆地中，冰川径流比冰川稳定的情况更降低，这是我们称为“槽水”的现象。一半研究的冰川盆地显示出冰川径流减少，而峰值变暖后几十年没有几个世纪。这些发现强调了近期排放降低和限制温度过冲的紧迫性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Exceeding 1.5 °C of global warming above pre-industrial levels has become a distinct possibility, yet the consequences of such an overshoot for mountain glaciers and their contribution to raising sea levels and impacting water availability are not well understood. Here we show that exceeding and then returning to below 1.5 °C will have irreversible consequences for glacier mass and runoff over centuries. Global climate and glacier simulations project that a 3.0 °C peak-and-decline scenario will lead to 11% more global glacier mass loss by 2500 compared with limiting warming to 1.5 °C without overshooting. In basins where glaciers regrow after peak temperature, glacier runoff reduces further than if the glaciers stabilize, a phenomenon we call ‘trough water’. Half the studied glaciated basins show reduced glacier runoff with overshoot compared with without for decades to centuries after peak warming. These findings underscore the urgency of near-term emissions reductions and limiting temperature overshoot.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41558-025-02318-w/MediaObjects/41558_2025_2318_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Water | 密集的灌溉缓冲区地下水在关键的欧洲面包板中下降</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00445-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Intensive irrigation buffers groundwater declines in key European breadbasket&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Grace Carlson; Christian Massari; Marco Rotiroti; Tullia Bonomi; Elisabetta Preziosi; Andrew Wilder; Destinee Whitaker; Manuela Girotto&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;意大利北部的PO平原是一个关键的农业地区，也是欧盟最大的水使用者之一。最近的干燥条件使未来的水资源可用性受到质疑。这项研究检查了由重力恢复和气候实验卫星观察到的地下水储存的时空变化以及2002年至2022年的1000多个地下水井。与2002-2022-2022-222的费率相比，从2015年到2022年，从2015年到2022年，地下水储存率下降了一倍以上。我们还表明，季节性和长期地下水的可用性受灌溉活动的强烈影响。灌溉区域的地下水储存与阿尔卑斯山的积雪高度相关，并且与非灌溉区域相比显示出更高的稳定性，而这些地区在干旱年份的下降幅度急剧下降。这表明，使用融雪的主要提供的水，在地下含水层中充实并帮助维持高水位桌，这使灌溉农田的基础含水剂富含蓄水量，使灌溉效率低下，使灌溉效率低下，这使灌溉农田具有抗干旱的负面影响。这些发现可以帮助指导气候驱动的对灌溉系​​统的适应，以解释对地下水充电的影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Po Plain in northern Italy is a critical agricultural region and one of the largest water users in the European Union. Recent dry conditions have put future water resource availability into question. This study examines spatio-temporal variations in groundwater storage observed by the Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment satellites and more than 1,000 groundwater wells from 2002 to 2022. We find that the rate of groundwater storage decline more than doubled from 2015 to 2022 as compared to the 2002–2022 rate. We also show that seasonal and long-term groundwater availability is strongly influenced by irrigation activities. Groundwater storage in irrigated areas is highly correlated to snow accumulation in the Alps and shows more stability as compared to non-irrigated areas, which experience dramatic declines during drought years. This indicates that inefficient irrigation practice, using water largely supplied by snowmelt, recharges underground aquifers and helps maintain high water tables, making aquifers underlying irrigated farmland resilient to the negative consequences of drought. These findings can help guide climate-driven adaptations to irrigation systems that account for the impact on groundwater recharge.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00445-4/MediaObjects/44221_2025_445_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>