<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 02:19:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 21世纪气候变化下的尼罗河流域水流状况</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02813-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Nile basin flow regimes under 21st century climate variability&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hesham Elhaddad; Mohamed Sultan; Eugene Yan; Duc Tran; Hugo E. Torres-Uribe; Hadi Karimi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;尼罗河流域是超过3亿人口的淡水资源，在气候变化和跨境水纠纷的影响下面临着前所未有的水文风险。然而，对极端水流事件的全流域预测仍然受到支离破碎的模型和气候不确定性整合不足的限制。在这里，我们使用经过校准的、气候驱动的土壤和水评估工具模型来评估下游国家未来的洪水风险，该模型是在 SSP2-4.5 和 SSP5-8.5 情景下由偏差校正的 CMIP6 模型强制执行的，这标志着此类工具首次针对尼罗河流域下游地区进行应用。我们的结果表明，21 世纪的 100 年峰值流量增加了 63% (SSP2-4.5) 和 85% (SSP5-8.5)，在高排放情景下，极端洪水几乎每十年就会发生一次。我们的气候驱动的水文模型、风险分析和气候预测强调需要协调规划、提供可操作的风险信息以及区域合作和准备框架，以减轻未来的洪水风险并应对尼罗河流域的水安全挑战。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Nile Basin, a freshwater resource for over 300 million people, faces unprecedented hydrological risks under climate change and transboundary water disputes. Yet, basin-wide projections of extreme streamflow events remain limited by fragmented modeling and insufficient integration of climate uncertainty. Here, we assess future flood risk in downstream countries using a calibrated, climate-driven Soil and Water Assessment Tool model, forced by bias-corrected CMIP6 models under the SSP2-4.5 and SSP5-8.5 scenarios, marking the first application of its kind targeting the Nile Basin downstream regions. Our results indicate a 63% (SSP2-4.5) and 85% (SSP5-8.5) increase in 100-year peak discharges in the 21st century, with extreme floods occurring nearly every decade under high-emission scenarios. Our climate-driven hydrologic modeling, risk analysis, and climate projections emphasize the need for coordinated planning, provide actionable risk information, and a framework for regional cooperation and preparedness to mitigate future flood risks and address water security challenges in the Nile Basin.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02813-0/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2813_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Sustainability | 采砂减少了洞里萨湖的临界洪水脉冲</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-025-01677-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Sand-mining-driven reduction in Tonle Sap Lake’s critical flood pulse&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; L. Q. Quan; C. R. Hackney; G. Vasilopoulos; T. Coulthard; N. N. Hung; S. E. Darby; D. R. Parsons&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;洞里萨湖 (TSL) 是世界上生产力最高的湖泊湿地生态系统之一，由每年一次的洪水脉冲维持，洪水在季风期间使湄公河下游的水流逆转，并在旱季将淡水返回下游。最近逆流的减少此前被归因于气候变化和上游筑坝。然而，我们在这里表明，1998年至2018年间，由于采砂和上游泥沙截留，湄公河主干河床降低，使逆流减少了40%至50%（高流量至低流量年份范围；中等流量为47%）。预计到 2038 年，由于正在进行的采砂导致河床进一步降低，与 1998 年相比，预计逆流将下降 69% (64–73%)。我们展示了这些变化如何影响整个湄公河下游系统的湖泊流量调节服务。具体而言，季风期间 TSL 逆流减少使流向湄公河三角洲的流量增加了约 26 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; (31–23 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; )，增加了洪水风险，同时减少了旱季流量约 59% (50–61%)，导致湄公河三角洲地区海水入侵加剧和农业产量下降。我们的研究结果强调了过度采砂对 TSL-湄公河系统可持续性的生存威胁。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Tonle Sap Lake (TSL), one of the world’s most productive lake–wetland ecosystems is sustained by an annual flood pulse that reverses Lower Mekong River flow into the lake during the monsoon and returns freshwater downstream during the dry season. Recent declines in the reverse flow have previously been attributed to climate change and upstream damming. However, here we show that between 1998 and 2018, riverbed lowering of the Mekong mainstem, driven by sand mining and upstream sediment trapping, has reduced the reverse flow by between 40 and 50% (high- to low-flow year range; 47% for medium flows). Projections to 2038, with additional riverbed lowering driven by ongoing sand mining, predict reverse flow declines of 69% (64–73%) compared with 1998. We show how these changes affect the lake’s flow regulation services across the Lower Mekong system. Specifically, the reduced TSL reverse flow increases flows to the Mekong Delta by ~26 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; (31–23 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;) during the monsoon, heightening flood risk, while decreasing dry-season flows by ~59% (50–61%), contributing to intensified saltwater intrusion and diminished agricultural yields across the Mekong’s Delta. Our results underscore how excessive sand extraction is an existential threat to the TSL–Mekong system’s sustainability.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41893-025-01677-8/MediaObjects/41893_2025_1677_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>