<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 02:34:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 用于预测大气河流和极端降水的区域高分辨率人工智能天气模型</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01265-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A regional high resolution AI weather model for the prediction of atmospheric rivers and extreme precipitation&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jorge Baño-Medina; Agniv Sengupta; Daniel Steinhoff; Patrick Mulrooney; Thomas Nipen; Mario Santa-Cruz; Yanbo Nie; Luca Delle Monache&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;准确的降水预报通常依赖于高分辨率数值天气预报（NWP）模型，这对于捕获精细尺度和非线性大气动力学至关重要。然而，这些模型的计算需求可能很大。利用人工智能 (AI) 的最新进展，我们提出了一种拉伸网格人工智能驱动的天气模型，在美国西部的水平网格增量为 6 公里，在全球其他地区的水平网格增量为约 31 公里。该模型采用自回归框架在几分钟内生成预测，并根据全球和区域数值天气预报系统以及较低分辨率的人工智能模型进行评估。我们的结果表明，区域人工智能模型减少了24小时累积降水误差，与区域数值天气预报模型具有竞争力，并有效捕捉极端降水事件，特别是与大气河流有关的事件，而全球较粗略的模型经常低估这些事件。这项工作强调了区域高分辨率人工智能模型在公里级降水预报方面的潜力，并讨论了未来发展的一些挑战。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Accurate precipitation forecasting often relies on high-resolution numerical weather prediction (NWP) models, which are essential for capturing fine-scale and nonlinear atmospheric dynamics. However, the computational demands of these models can be substantial. Leveraging recent advancements in artificial intelligence (AI), we present a stretched-grid AI-driven weather model with 6-km horizontal grid increments over the Western United States and ~31 km in other regions globally. The model employs an autoregressive framework to generate forecasts in minutes and is evaluated against global and regional NWP systems, as well as a lower-resolution AI model. Our results show that the regional AI model reduces 24-h accumulated precipitation errors, performs competitively with the regional NWP model, and effectively captures extreme precipitation events, particularly those linked to atmospheric rivers, which global coarser models often underestimate. This work underscores the potential of regional, high-resolution AI models for precipitation forecasting at km-scales, and discusses some of the challenges for future development.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-27103-9/MediaObjects/41598_2025_27103_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 一种改进的基于多源河流数据融合的全球河流矢量数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06399-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;An improved global river vector dataset based on multi-source river data fusion&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yensen Liu; Jianhua Wang; Changjun Liu; Yaohuan Huang; Yuanyuan Liu; Jie Liu; Fuxin Chai; Sheng Chen; Min Li; Wei Qu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;高精度的全球河流数据集对于水文学和环境研究至关重要。尽管已经开发并广泛采用了几个全球河流数据集，但它们经常与许多地区的实际河流分布存在显着偏差。在本研究中，我们提出了一种多源矢量河流数据融合框架，以生成具有拓扑信息的高空间精度全球河流数据集，名为 GSriver。通过将高空间分辨率但拓扑不完整的 OpenStreetMap (OSM) 水道与 HydroRIVERS 集成，并使用全球河流拓扑 (GRIT) 数据集补充缺失的部分，GSriver 保留了完整的河流拓扑，同时显着提高了空间精度。针对美国高精度 NHDPlus 数据集的验证表明，GSriver 相对 MERIT、GRIT 和 HydroRIVERS 的空间精度分别提高了 36.3%、40.7% 和 56.7%。 GSriver 中超过 40% 的节点与 NHDPlus 的偏差小于 10 米。该方法利用众包数据的优势，解决了传统 DEM 河流数据集的空间精度限制，为构建大规模河流数据集提供了可扩展且经济高效的解决方案。 GSriver 可在 https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.30119851.v3 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;上公开获取。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;High-precision global river datasets are crucial for hydrology and environmental research. Although several global river datasets have been developed and widely adopted, they often suffer from significant deviations from actual river distributions in many areas. In this study, we propose a multi-source vector river data fusion framework to generate a high spatial accuracy global river dataset with topological information, named GSriver. By integrating high-spatial-resolution but topologically incomplete OpenStreetMap (OSM) waterways with HydroRIVERS and supplementing missing segments with the Global River Topology (GRIT) dataset, GSriver preserves complete river topology while significantly enhancing spatial accuracy. Validation against the high-precision NHDPlus dataset of the United States reveals that GSriver improves spatial accuracy over MERIT, GRIT, and HydroRIVERS by 36.3%, 40.7%, and 56.7%, respectively. More than 40% of nodes in GSriver deviate less than 10 meters from NHDPlus. This approach addresses the spatial accuracy limitations of conventional DEM-derived river datasets by leveraging the advantages of crowdsourced data, offering a scalable and cost-effective solution for constructing large-scale river datasets. GSriver is publicly available at https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.30119851.v3&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-27225-0/MediaObjects/41598_2025_27225_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 通过新的夹带率参数化改进 CIESM 中的降水模拟</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01282-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Improving precipitation simulations in CIESM through a new entrainment rate parameterization&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xin He; Chunsong Lu; Guang J. Zhang; Junjun Li; Lei Zhu; Hengqi Wang; Te Li; Xiaohao Guo; Sinan Gao; Yuhao Lin; Kai Yang; Wenhui Liu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;夹带率参数化对于对流方案很重要，但在气候模型中不确定。一种新的深对流夹带率（λ）参数化（HL参数化）是根据飞机观测发展而来，并应用于社区综合地球系统模型1.1.0版的对流方案中（Song和Zhang，2018，https://doi.org/10.1002/2017MS001191），取代了之前使用的参数化（Gregory参数化）。与Gregory参数化相比，HL参数化模拟了整体更大的λ值，改善了30°S-30°N区域的对流和大范围降水模拟，与观测结果吻合更好。其机理是，与Gregory参数化相比，HL参数化在宏观物理和微观物理上抑制了深对流云的发展。间接地，与Gregory参数化相比，HL参数化增加了大范围降水，减少了浅层对流降水，使总降水量更接近观测值。 HL参数化增强了模式模拟降水的能力，为改进气候模式中的深对流方案提供了有价值的参考。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Entrainment rate parameterization is important for convection schemes but uncertain in climate models. A new deep convective entrainment rate (λ) parameterization (HL parameterization) is developed from aircraft observations and implemented into the convection scheme (Song and Zhang, 2018, https://doi.org/10.1002/2017MS001191) in the Community Integrated Earth System Model version 1.1.0, replacing the previously used parameterization (Gregory parameterization). Compared with the Gregory parameterization, the HL parameterization simulates overall larger λ values and improves convective and large-scale precipitation simulations in the 30°S-30°N region, agreeing better with observations. The mechanism is that the HL parameterization suppresses deep convective cloud development macrophysically and microphysically compared with the Gregory parameterization. Indirectly, compared with the Gregory parameterization, the HL parameterization increases large-scale precipitation and reduces shallow convective precipitation, lowering total precipitation closer to observations. The HL parameterization enhances the model’s ability to simulate precipitation, providing a valuable reference for improving the deep convection scheme in climate models.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-27255-8/MediaObjects/41598_2025_27255_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 青藏高原次日降水对区域气候变化的响应及机制</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01275-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Response and mechanisms of sub-daily precipitation over the Tibetan Plateau to regional climate change&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yuanyuan Ma; Xiaoxue Hu; Xianhong Meng; Di Ma&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;青藏高原（TP）是气候变化的敏感地区，其降水变化引起了科学界的广泛关注。本研究将动态降尺度模拟与故事情节归因方法相结合，研究东亚（RCC）和青藏高原（PCC）区域气候变化对青藏高原次日降水量的影响。 RCC 显着减少了总体降水，主要是通过减少早晨降水和层状降水，但通过增加对流降水来增加下午降水。此外，RCC 降低了降水频率和降水强度，尤其是早晨层状降水。与 RCC 相比，PCC 对降水的影响更小且统计意义更小。 RCC 的相反的上午-下午效应源于不同的物理机制：RCC 稳定大气并减少早晨的湿度，抑制对流，同时增强下午的不稳定性、湿度和对流能量。 RCC 引起的降水变化的区域差异归因于水分通量和大气动力学的变化。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tibetan Plateau (TP) is a sensitive region of climate change, with its precipitation change attracting considerable scientific attention. This study couples dynamical downscaling simulation with the storyline attribution approach to investigate the impact of regional climate change over East Asia (RCC) and TP (PCC) on the sub-daily precipitation over TP. RCC significantly reduces overall precipitation, mainly through decreased morning and stratiform precipitation, but enhances afternoon precipitation by increasing convective precipitation. Furthermore, RCC reduces the precipitation frequency and precipitation intensity, most substantially for morning stratiform precipitation. PCC exerts smaller and less statistically significant impact on precipitation than RCC. The opposing morning–afternoon effects of RCC stem from differing physical mechanisms: RCC stabilizes the atmosphere and reduces moisture in the morning, suppressing convection, while it enhances instability, moisture, and convective energy in the afternoon. Regional differences in RCC-induced precipitation changes are attributed to variations in moisture flux and atmospheric dynamics.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06178-z/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6178_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 支持秘鲁河流桥梁脆弱性评估的多维数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06374-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Multidimensional Datasets Supporting Vulnerability Assessments of Riverine Bridges in Peru&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Alain Jorge Espinoza Vigil; Joel Ccanccapa Puma; Alan Huarca Pulcha; Alejandra Ticona-Quispe; Diego Huarcaya-Perez; Alberth Gonzales-Turpo; Roly Cusihuaman-Casquina; Flor Lucana-Hancco; Julian Booker&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流桥梁是重要但脆弱的基础设施，经常遭受因气候变化而大幅增加的水文灾害。因此，它们需要确保弹性和足够的使用寿命的设计。该数据描述符提供了两项科学研究中使用的数据，重点是评估秘鲁阿雷基帕市横跨辣椒河的桥梁的脆弱性，主要通过水文数据、地形和土壤数据以及水力建模。因此，两项研究中使用的数据使得能够对桥梁进行脆弱性评估，包括定量和定性方面，解决了与河流桥梁评估相关的研究中的数据差距。这两项研究都通过整合多种数据类型，共同为河流桥梁脆弱性分析提供了一个全面的框架，而不是作为独立的调查。这些数据不仅可以用于评估桥梁的脆弱性，还可以纳入未来基础设施风险评估的研究中。对此处提供的数据进行适当管理可以为负责实施弹性和可持续基础设施的当局的决策过程提供信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Riverine bridges are critical yet vulnerable infrastructure, constantly exposed to hydrological hazards substantially increased by climate change. Consequently, they require designs that ensure resilience and an adequate useful life cycle. This data descriptor presents data used in two scientific studies focused on assessing the vulnerability of bridges spanning the Chili River in the city of Arequipa, Peru, mainly through hydrological data, terrain and soil data and hydraulic modeling. Therefore, the data employed in both studies enable vulnerability assessments of bridges that encompass both quantitative and qualitative aspects, addressing the data gap in research related to the assessment of riverine bridges. Both studies, by incorporating a diverse range of data types, collectively provide a comprehensive framework for the analysis of riverine bridge vulnerability, rather than functioning as independent investigations. Such data not only serves to assess bridge vulnerability but can also be integrated into future research on infrastructure risk assessments. Proper management of the data presented herein can inform decision-making processes for authorities responsible for implementing resilient and sustainable infrastructure.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-27314-0/MediaObjects/41598_2025_27314_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 北大西洋涛动对喜马拉雅山脉中东部夏季降水的非平稳影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01268-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Non-stationary influence of the North Atlantic Oscillation on summer precipitation in the Central-Eastern Himalayas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Qiang Zhang; Xuelong Chen; Yaoming Ma; Dianbin Cao; Yangkun Lyu; Shuai Hu; Yiting Yang; Zeyong Hu; Xin Xu; Sunil Subba&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;了解喜马拉雅山脉中东部 (CEH) 夏季降水的年际变化对于指导有效的水资源管理和支持南亚的社会经济发展至关重要。然而，气候变化影响 CEH 夏季降水变化的机制仍不清楚。 CEH夏季降水受到多种气候因素的调节，其中厄尔尼诺-南方涛动是持续的弱力量，夏季北大西洋涛动（SNAO）产生非平稳影响。 SNAO 可以在南亚引发异常反气旋，将低空风引导至喜马拉雅山南坡，通过地形机械强迫诱发降水异常。 SNAO驱动的异常反气旋向CEH以南的位置移动调节了SNAO与CEH夏季降水变化之间的耦合和解耦关系。因此，了解SNAO与CEH夏季降水之间的动态联系是提高降水预测精度的关键。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understanding the interannual variability of summer precipitation across the Central-Eastern Himalayas (CEH) is essential for guiding efficient water management and supporting socio-economic development in South Asia. However, the mechanisms through which climate variability shapes CEH summer precipitation variability remain insufficiently understood. Summer precipitation in the CEH is modulated by multiple climate factors, with the El Niño–Southern Oscillation as a sustained weak force and the summer North Atlantic Oscillation (SNAO) exerting non-stationary effects. The SNAO can trigger an anomalous anticyclone over South Asia, directing low-level winds toward the Himalayas’ southern slopes, inducing precipitation anomalies through topographic mechanical forcing. The position shift of the SNAO-driven anomalous anticyclone to the south of the CEH modulates the coupled and decoupled relationship between SNAO and CEH summer precipitation variability. Therefore, understanding the dynamic links between the SNAO and CEH summer precipitation is key to enhancing precipitation prediction accuracy.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-26815-2/MediaObjects/41598_2025_26815_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | SMCR：第一个卫星全天候/1公里土壤湿度气候记录（1980-2023）</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06432-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;SMCR: A first satellite-derived all-weather daily/1-km Soil Moisture Climatological Record (1980–2023)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Shuangxue Zhai; Pei Leng; Chunfeng Ma; Abba Aliyu Kasim; Tian Ma; Hongyuan Huo; Si-Bo Duan; Xiangyang Liu; Zhao-Liang Li&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;土壤湿度（SM）长期以来被认为是重要的气候变量之一。然而，还没有来自卫星的超过 30 年的精细时空分辨率的全球 SM 气候记录。基于最新版本的25 km CCI SM数据和SoilGrids衍生的1 km土壤数据，首先利用三重配置分析算法，并借助ERA5、GLEAM和GLDAS衍生的SM，获得了空间连续的CCI数据集。随后，考虑到水力参数的子网格变异性，使用降尺度方法以 1 km 的精细分辨率导出 SM。最后，开发了第一个具有全球无缝覆盖的精细时空分辨率的卫星 SM 气候记录（1980-2023）。针对 372 个全球现场观测的综合验证得出平均无偏均方根误差为 0.051 m &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; /m &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; 。具体来说，首先在四个具有密集观测站的网络中对经过验证的准确性进行基于贝叶斯统计的可信度分析。结果表明，这些网络的准确度评估的平均可信度为 83.5%。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Soil moisture (SM) has long been recognized as one of the essential climate variables. However, there are no satellite-derived global SM climatological records spanning over 30 years at fine spatiotemporal resolution. Based on the latest version of the 25 km CCI SM data and 1 km soil data derived from the SoilGrids, a spatially continuous CCI dataset was first obtained using the triple collocation analysis algorithm with the assistance of SM derived from the ERA5, GLEAM, and GLDAS. Subsequently, SM was derived at a fine resolution of 1 km using a downscaling approach considering the sub-grid variability of hydraulic parameters. Finally, the first satellite-derived SM climatological record (1980–2023) at fine spatiotemporal resolution with global seamless coverage was developed. A comprehensive validation against 372 global in-situ observations yielded an averaged unbiased root mean square error of 0.051 m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;. Specifically, a Bayesian statics-based credibility analysis of the validated accuracy was first conducted at four networks with dense observation stations. Results indicated an averaged credibility of 83.5% of the accuracy assessment at these networks.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01265-9/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1265_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>