<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 01:58:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 自动化河流屏障对象检测的带注释的卫星图像数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04590-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jianping Wu; Wenjie Li; Hongbo Du; Yu Wan; Shengfa Yang; Yi Xiao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全世界已经建造了数百万河屏障，用于防洪，水力发电和农业灌溉。缺乏关于河流障碍位置和类型的全面记录，尤其是包括堰在内的小障碍，限制了我们评估其社会和环境影响的能力。将卫星图像与对象检测算法集成在一起，有望自动识别全球范围。但是，实现此目标需要高质量的图像数据集来进行算法培训和测试。因此，本研究提出了一个名为河流屏障对象检测（RBOD）的大规模数据集。它包含4,872个高分辨率卫星图像和11,741个精心注释的定向边界盒（OBB），其中包括五类河流屏障。使用五种典型对象检测算法验证了RBOD数据集的有效性，该算法为将来的应用提供了性能基准。据我们所知，RBOD是第一个用于河流屏障对象检测的公开数据集，为理解和管理河流屏障提供了宝贵的资源。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Millions of river barriers have been constructed worldwide for flood control, hydropower generation, and agricultural irrigation. The lack of comprehensive records on river barriers’ locations and types, particularly small barriers including weirs, limits our ability to assess their societal and environmental impacts. Integrating satellite imagery with object detection algorithms holds promise for the automatic identification of river barriers on a global scale. However, achieving this objective requires high-quality image datasets for algorithm training and testing. Hence, this study presents a large-scale dataset named the River Barrier Object Detection (RBOD). It comprises 4,872 high-resolution satellite images and 11,741 meticulously annotated oriented bounding boxes (OBBs), encompassing five classes of river barriers. The effectiveness of the RBOD dataset was validated using five typical object detection algorithms, which provide performance benchmarks for future applications. To the best of our knowledge, RBOD is the first publicly available dataset for river barrier object detection, providing a valuable resource for the understanding and management of river barriers.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04590-z/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4590_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>