<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 02:33:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 格陵兰主要冰流对湖泊排水事件的速度和崩解响应</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01858-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Velocity and calving response of a major Greenland ice stream to a lake drainage event&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Adrien Wehrlé; Martin P. Lüthi; Andrea Kneib-Walter; Ana Nap; Hugo Rousseau; Guillaume Jouvet; Fabian Walter&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;卡拉利特努纳特（格陵兰岛）冰盖的出口冰川和冰流将冰从内陆输送到海洋，因此在北极加速变暖的背景下，了解它们的动态至关重要。冰川流动动力学主要由卫星监测，因此在短于采集频率（通常是天）的时间尺度上发生的重要过程仍然未被检测到。因此，对快速流动冰川的短期动力学仍然知之甚少，并且在数值模型中也没有得到充分的约束。在这里，我们利用全球导航卫星系统站和地面雷达干涉仪对格陵兰岛最快的冰流——康吉亚（雅各布港伊斯布雷）的 Sermeq Kujalleq 进行的高速现场观测，来表征其对两个地表湖泊排水的响应。随后的冰下洪水引起了一股更快的水流脉冲，该脉冲迅速向下游传播——在 4 小时内传播了 16 公里——到达终点，在那里引发了比平常更长的崩解事件，持续了 2 小时。这种加速脉冲的无阻尼和快速传播，以及周围剪切裕度的瞬时响应，表明冰流系统内的强耦合。我们的研究结果强调了内陆地区如何能够在对冰运动的长期影响最小的情况下适应较大的扰动，并有效地将其传播到下游，从而在冰川末端引发不可逆转的变化。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Outlet glaciers and ice streams of the ice sheet of Kalaallit Nunaat (Greenland) transport ice from the interior towards the ocean, so understanding their dynamics is crucial in the context of accelerating Arctic warming. Glacier flow dynamics are predominantly monitored by satellites, thus important processes that occur on timescales shorter than the acquisition frequency (typically days) remain undetected. Therefore, the short-term dynamics of fast-flowing glaciers remains poorly understood and insufficiently constrained in numerical models. Here we use high-rate field observations by global navigation satellite system stations and a Terrestrial Radar Interferometer on Greenland’s fastest ice stream, Sermeq Kujalleq in Kangia (Jakobshavn Isbræ), to characterize its response to the drainage of two surface lakes. The ensuing subglacial flood caused a pulse of faster flow that rapidly propagated downstream—over 16 km within 4 hours—towards the terminus, where it triggered a longer than usual calving episode, lasting 2 hours. The undamped and fast propagation of this speed-up pulse, together with the instantaneous response of the surrounding shear margins, indicate strong coupling within the ice-stream system. Our results highlight how inland areas can accommodate large disturbances with minimal long-term impact on ice motion and efficiently propagate them downstream to trigger irreversible changes at glacier termini.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-26567-z/MediaObjects/41598_2025_26567_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 开发每日缩小尺度、偏差校正的 CMIP6 气候数据集，用于估算南亚参考蒸散量 (ETo)</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06149-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Development of daily downscaled, bias-corrected CMIP6 climate datasets for estimating reference evapotranspiration (ETo) in South Asia&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Aniruddha Saha; Manoj Kumar Jain; Pranita Joshi; Subhankar Das; Naimesh Singh Rawat&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;潜在蒸散量在水文分析中起着至关重要的作用。因此，在各种气候变化情景下，可靠地预测当地尺度的潜在蒸散量和/或参考蒸散量（ETo）至关重要。为了实现这一目标，必须缩小各种大气环流模型的气候数据集并纠正偏差，以提高其准确性。在这项研究中，我们开发了 0.25° 空间分辨率的每日偏差校正 ETo 数据集。我们使用耦合模型比对项目第 6 阶段 (CMIP6) 的输出来了解历史路径和四个共享社会经济路径。这些数据集包括来自南亚不同空间尺度的 12 个不同模型的温度、太阳辐射、风速和相对湿度。使用分位数映射方法进行偏差校正。由此产生的偏差校正气候变量（存储库中提供的数据集）随后被用来估计南亚历史和未来的 ETo。根据 ERA-5 再分析观察数据进行评估时，原始数据集和偏差校正数据集之间存在显着差异。 Penman-Monteith 方法用于 ETo 估计，以减少基于温度的方法的不确定性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Potential evapotranspiration plays a crucial role in hydrological analysis. Therefore, reliable projection of potential evapotranspiration and/or reference evapotranspiration (ETo) at the local scale under various climate change scenario is essential. To achieve this, climate datasets from various General Circulation Models must be downscaled and bias corrected to enhance their accuracy. In this study, we developed daily bias-corrected datasets of ETo at 0.25° spatial resolution. We used outputs from the Coupled Model Intercomparison Project Phase 6 (CMIP6) for the historical and four Shared Socioeconomic Pathways. The datasets include temperature, solar radiation, wind speed, and relative humidity from 12 different models at various spatial scales for South Asia. The bias correction was performed using the Quantile-Mapping approach. The resulting bias-corrected climate variables (dataset available in repository) were subsequently used to estimate historical and future ETo over South Asia. A significant difference was observed between the original and bias-corrected datasets when evaluated against the ERA-5 reanalysis observation data. Penman-Monteith method was utilized for ETo estimation to reduce the uncertainties of temperature-based methods.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs42949-025-00288-8/MediaObjects/42949_2025_288_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | GDROM v2：美国大陆 2,017 个大型水库运行变量时间序列和规则清单</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06162-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;GDROM v2: An Inventory of Operation Variables Time Series and Rules for 2,017 Large Reservoirs across the CONUS&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zihan Zheng; Ximing Cai; Linshui Zhang; James Li; Yanan Chen&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水库调度在水管理中发挥着核心作用，满足人类多样化的需求，同时影响水文过程。然而，对于大多数水库来说，缺乏完整的日常运行记录和现实的运行规则限制了它们在大型水文模型中的表现。为了解决这个问题，我们提出了 GDROM v2，这是一个包含美国本土 (CONUS) 2,017 个水库的全国数据集，建立在包含 452 个水库的原始 GDROM 的基础上。 GDROM v2 提供（1）流入、释放和存储变量的每日时间序列，通过现有数据集和重建估计的数据融合进行集成； (2)针对数据丰富的水库采用原始GDROM的操作规则，并使用迁移学习导出针对数据有限的水库的操作规则。验证结果表明，重建的变量时间序列与观测值相当吻合；派生的操作规则在不同的数据可用性条件下优于现有的基准模型。 GDROM v2 通过开放数据平台 (Hydroshare.org) 公开提供，提供了整个 CONUS 地区最大的水库运行变量时间序列和实际运行规则集合，为水文建模和水管理研究提供了有用的资源。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Reservoir operation plays a central role in water management, satisfying diverse human demands and simultaneously influencing hydrologic processes. Yet for most reservoirs, the lack of complete daily operation records and realistic operation rules constrains their representation in large-scale hydrological models. To address this, we present GDROM v2, a nationwide dataset of 2,017 reservoirs across the Contiguous United States (CONUS), building upon the original GDROM of 452 reservoirs. GDROM v2 provides (1) daily time series of inflow, release, and storage variables, integrated through data fusion of existing datasets and reconstructed estimates; (2) operation rules adopted from original GDROM for data-rich reservoirs and derived for data-limited reservoirs using transfer learning. Validation results show that the reconstructed variable time series reasonably agree with observations; derived operation rules outperform existing benchmark models across diverse data availability conditions. GDROM v2, publicly available via an open-data platform (Hydroshare.org), offers the largest collection of reservoir operation variables time series and realistic operation rules across the CONUS, providing a useful resource for hydrological modeling and water management studies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02901-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2901_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 瑞士上空每小时 10 m 分辨率的潜在光照可用性图</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06152-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Hourly potential light availability maps at 10 m resolution over Switzerland&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Clare Webster; Christian Ginzler; Mauro Marty; Anita Nussbaumer; Giulia Mazzotti; Tobias Jonas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文介绍了 SwissRad10 数据集，其中包含整个年度太阳活动周期中 10 m 和每小时分辨率的新型全国光可用性地图。计算变量天空视野系数和直射光束透射率，从而可以直接估计地面的直射光和漫射光。该数据集使用详细的基于合成半球图像的树冠辐射模型 (CanRad) 以及来自 swissSURFACE3D 数据集的最新机载激光雷达和地形表面数据进行计算，并解析了瑞士每棵树投射的阴影。下面和相邻的森林冠层像素包括针对叶上和叶下冠层结构计算的光可用性，并且域中的所有像素都包括仅地形计算。这些数据对于评估森林微生境对植物和动物的适宜性、通过森林微气候相关的学科（例如生物地球化学和雪模型）以及针对碳和水通量的生态系统研究非常重要。本文提出的全国光可用性地图将为光可用性的动态和驱动因素提供有价值的见解，为生态和环境科学领域的研究人员、从业者和决策者提供宝贵的资源。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This paper presents the SwissRad10 dataset, containing novel nationwide light availability maps at 10 m and hourly resolution across an entire annual solar cycle. The variables sky-view factor and direct-beam transmissivity are calculated, allowing direct estimation of both direct and diffuse light at the ground surface. The dataset is calculated using the detailed synthetic hemispheric image-based Canopy Radiation Model (CanRad) with the latest airborne lidar and terrain surface data from the swissSURFACE3D dataset and resolves the shadow cast by every single tree in Switzerland. Below and adjacent forest canopy pixels include light availability calculated for both leaf-on and leaf-off canopy structure, and all pixels in the domain include a terrain-only calculation. This data is important for, e.g. assessing forest microhabitat suitability for both plants and animals, for disciplines linked via forest microclimate such as biogeochemistry and snow modelling, as well as for ecosystem research targeting carbon and water fluxes. The nationwide light availability maps presented in this paper will offer valuable insights into the dynamics and drivers of light availability, serving as a valuable resource for researchers, practitioners, and decision-makers working in the field of ecology and environmental sciences.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01858-2/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1858_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 在全球通量站点使用全因子方法对每日潜热通量观测进行间隙填充</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06144-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Gap-Filling for Daily Latent Heat Flux Observations with the Full-factorial method at Global Flux Sites&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xiaowei Wang; Fujiao Tang; Yazhen Jiang; Yunsheng Lou&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;潜热通量（LE）在水能循环中起着至关重要的作用。 LE 的涡流协方差 (EC) 测量经常会因天气或设备故障而出现数据缺口。本研究提出了一种新颖的框架，结合中值调整的全因子和迭代方法来填补 LE 数据空白。研究结果表明，该框架在整个陆地表面表现出稳定的间隙填充，孤立间隙的 RMSE 为 14.69-19.51 W/m &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ，长期缺失期（5-50 天）的平均值为 24.41 W/m &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; 。间隙填充 LE 数据与相邻测量的时间动态和波动密切匹配。根据填空的 LE 数据，所有站点都表现出可用能量和湍流通量之间的强相关性，RMSE 值范围为 28.41–38.01 W/m &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ，并且各站点的平均能量闭合为 0.79。与 ERA5-Land 和 GLEAM 产品相比，填补空白的数据显着优于这两种 LE 产品。总体而言，填充的LE数据质量较高，显着提高了观测数据的可用性。来自 265 个站点（1509 个站点年）的完整时间序列数据对于 LE 模型验证和需水量评估非常有价值。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Latent heat flux (LE) plays a crucial role in the water-energy cycle. Eddy covariance (EC) measurements of LE frequently suffer from data gaps due to weather or equipment malfunctions. This study presents a novel framework combining median-adjusted full-factorial and iterative methods to fill LE data gaps. The findings indicate that the framework exhibits stable gap-filling across land surfaces, showing RMSEs of 14.69–19.51 W/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; for isolated gaps and averaging 24.41 W/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; for long-term missing periods (5–50 days). Gap-filled LE data closely matched temporal dynamics and fluctuations of adjacent measurements. Based on gap-filled LE data, all sites demonstrated strong correlations between available energy and turbulent fluxes, with RMSE values ranging 28.41–38.01 W/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; and achieving an average energy closure of 0.79 across sites. Compared to ERA5-Land and GLEAM products, the gap-filled data significantly outperformed both LE products. Overall, the filled LE data are of high quality and significantly improve the usability of observed data. The complete time-series data from 265 sites (1509 site-years) are valuable for LE model validation and water demand assessments.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06149-4/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6149_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 次季节到季节径流预测的混合框架：集成数值和统计模型</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01273-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A hybrid framework for sub-seasonal to seasonal streamflow prediction: integrating numerical and statistical models&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lingfeng Li; Huan Wu; Lulu Jiang; Yiwen Mei; John S. Kimball; Lorenzo Alfieri; Zhijun Huang; Ying Hu; Sirong Chen; Shaorou Dong; Yaming Hu; Wei Wu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;次季节到季节（S2S）降水预报长期以来被视为“预报沙漠”，因为超过七个提前天的技术有限，从而破坏了下游水文预报。然而，与降水相比，径流的可预测性更高，而且其相对于降水预报的不成比例的改善常常被忽视。本研究将分布式水文模型与概率统​​计模型相结合，通过同化统计水文气候关系来增强 S2S 洪水预报。该集成方法在珠江流域复杂水文的 24 个水文站进行了验证。其适度的预测显示，第 2 至 6 周的平均纳什-萨特克利夫效率 (NSE) 得分为 0.36 至 0.16，与单独的水文模型相比，连续排名概率得分技能 (CRPSS) 提高了 15%。这项研究强调了整合物理和统计模型来改进 S2S 水流预测的价值，为提高易发洪水流域的预测技能提供了一条实用途径。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sub-seasonal to seasonal (S2S) precipitation forecasting has long been regarded as a “forecasting desert” due to limited skill beyond seven lead days, undermining downstream hydrological forecasts. However, the higher predictability of streamflow compared to precipitation, and its disproportionate improvement relative to precipitation forecast, have often been overlooked. This study integrates a distributed hydrological model with a probabilistic statistical model to enhance S2S flood forecast by assimilating statistical hydroclimate relationships. The ensemble approach is validated at 24 hydrological stations across Pearl River Basin with complex hydrology. Its modest forecasts show mean Nash–Sutcliffe Efficiency (NSE) scores ranging from 0.36 to 0.16 for weeks 2 to 6, and a 15% improvement in Continuous Ranked Probability Score Skill (CRPSS) compared to hydrological model alone. This study underscores the value of integrating physical and statistical models to improve S2S streamflow prediction, offering a practical pathway to enhance forecast skill in flood-prone basins.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06162-7/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6162_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 早期落叶的生物物理反馈增强了中国的非侵蚀性降水</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-03054-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Biophysical feedback from earlier leaf-out enhances nonerosive precipitation in China&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zhuoran Yan; Jiuchun Yang; Han Zhang; Wenbo Li; Yeqiao Wang; Huanjun Liu; Lingxue Yu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;提早落叶可增强春季土地与大气之间的水分交换。然而，其对降水强度的影响尚不清楚，阻碍了水侵蚀的动态监测。在这里，我们结合了遥感、再分析数据和耦合的陆地-大气模型来解决这一知识差距。结果发现，中国温带地区春季降水量呈增加趋势，同时落叶提前。模拟分离了物候影响并将其归因于非侵蚀性降水的增强。中温带半湿润地区响应14天的落叶提前表现出最大的增量（3.03±3.66毫米）。相反，在植被稀疏的地区（覆盖率&amp;lt;50%），侵蚀性降水减少，从而加剧了水分梯度的不均匀性。对流可用势能的升高促进了更频繁的降水，抑制了侵蚀性倾盆大雨所需的深层水分积累。温带夏季和秋季的模拟侵蚀性降水也有所减少。研究结果强调了植被在降水重新分配中的作用，超出了地表拦截的范围，要求保护规划考虑双向植被-气候反馈。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Earlier leaf-out enhances spring moisture exchange between land and atmosphere. However, its impact on precipitation intensity remains unclear, hampering dynamic monitoring on water erosion. Here we combined remote sensing, reanalysis data, and coupled land-atmosphere model to address this knowledge gap. Results observed an increasing trend in spring precipitation accompanied by earlier leaf-out across temperate China. The simulations isolated the phenological impacts and attributed it to the enhancement of nonerosive precipitation. The mid-temperate semi-humid region exhibited the largest increase (3.03 ± 3.66 mm) in response to 14-days leaf-out advancement. Conversely, erosive precipitation declined in sparsely vegetated areas (&amp;lt;50% cover), sharpening the heterogeneity of moisture gradient. Elevated convective available potential energy promoted more frequent precipitation, inhibiting the deep moisture accumulation required for erosive downpours. Simulated erosive precipitation also declined in temperate summer and autumn. Findings highlight vegetation’s role in precipitation redistribution beyond surface interception, requiring conservation planning to consider bidirectional vegetation-climate feedback.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06152-9/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6152_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 降水灾害热点取决于历史气候变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-66601-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Precipitation disaster hotspots depend on historical climate variability&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Iris de Vries; Maybritt Schillinger; Erich Fischer; Sebastian Sippel; Reto Knutti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;创纪录的高降水事件与影响有关，因为它们比任何观测到的事件都更严重，并且可能导致不可预见的后果。气候变化增加了平均破纪录的概率，但当前当地破纪录的概率和当地的防灾准备也取决于观测到的降水历史。在这里，我们表明历史变异性决定了当前和未来破纪录的可能性：当前记录较低的地区面临的风险更大。气候变化非线性地改变了这种模式：温和的气候变化（SSP2-4.5）使到2050年平均破纪录的概率增加了40%，但高电流记录对气候变化最敏感，破纪录的概率增加高达75%。因此，当前记录较低的地区面临的风险最大，而当前记录较高的地区则因气候变化而面临的风险增加最快。准备不足进一步增加了灾害风险。如果上一次破纪录的事件发生在很久以前，当地社会很可能对下一次破纪录事件毫无准备。由于贫困和快速城市化，许多破纪录概率高的地区的脆弱性和暴露程度很高，导致重大迫在眉睫的威胁。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Record-high precipitation events are relevant for impacts since they are more severe than any observed event and can lead to unforeseeable consequences. Climate change increases average record-breaking probability, but the current, local record-breaking probability and local disaster preparedness are dependent on observed precipitation history as well. Here, we show that historical variability shapes current and future record-breaking probabilities: regions with low current records are more at risk. Climate change modifies this pattern non-linearly: moderate climate change (SSP2-4.5) increases average record-breaking probability by 2050 by 40%, but high current records are most sensitive to climate change with a record-breaking probability increase of up to 75%. Thus, regions with low current records are most at risk, but regions with high current records see the steepest risk increase with climate change. Disaster risk is further increased by low preparedness. If the last record-breaking event is long ago, local society is more likely to be unprepared for the next one. Vulnerability and exposure in many regions with high record-breaking probability is high due to poverty and rapid urbanisation, resulting in a major imminent threat.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06144-9/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6144_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>