<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 02:23:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 水碳结构级联效应非线性影响季风盆地生态系统生产功能</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02885-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Water-carbon-structure cascade effect nonlinearly impacts ecosystem production functions in monsoon basins&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lintong Huang 
            (黄林童); Yaxuan Dai 
            (戴雅璇); Siyuan Cheng 
            (程思源); Wenxian Guo 
            (郭文献); Hongxiang Wang 
            (王鸿翔)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;流域尺度上水、碳和生态系统结构之间的耦合机制和级联效应仍不清楚。在这里，我们从生态系统动态变化的角度，结合InVEST生态系统过程模型和机器学习技术，提出了水-碳结构-功能关系分析框架。我们发现整个流域的整体生态系统活力在 2.3% 到 5.3% 之间。四大生态系统类型空间结构分异加剧。在网格层面，水-碳主要表现出协同行为。季风区相对较低的平均水碳值是限制生态系统收益的关键。 2010年和2022年，限制水-碳相互作用的结构阈值进一步下降。此外，供水条件下水-碳结构-功能关系在空间上呈现出鞍形、平台形和峰形格局。一旦水利用和结构特征达到相应的阈值，生态系统的生产功能就进入稳定状态，不再随单一变量的变化而大幅波动。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The coupling mechanisms and cascading effects among water, carbon, and ecosystem structure at the basin scale remain insufficiently understood. Here we take the perspective of ecosystem dynamic change, integrating the InVEST ecosystem process model and machine learning techniques, and propose a water-carbon-structure-function nexus analysis framework. We found that the overall ecosystem dynamism ranged from 2.3% to 5.3% across the basin. Spatial structural differentiation among the four major ecosystem types intensified. At the grid level, water-carbon showed predominantly synergistic behavior. The relatively low average water-carbon values in monsoon zones were key to limiting ecosystem gains. The structural thresholds constraining water-carbon interactions declined further in 2010 and 2022. Additionally, the water-carbon-structure-function nexus exhibits saddle-shaped, platform-shaped, and peak-shaped patterns spatially under water supply conditions. Once water utilization and structural characteristics reach their corresponding thresholds, the ecosystem’s productive function enters a steady state and no longer fluctuates significantly with changes in a single variable.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02885-y/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2885_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 1984-2022 年地表水变迁：年度分辨率的全球数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06013-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Surface Water Transitions 1984–2022: A Global Dataset at Annual Resolution&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Gustavo Willy Nagel; Stephen E. Darby; Julian Leyland&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;卫星技术和云计算的最新进展使得全球范围内的长期地表水变化监测成为可能。由季节性波动和气候事件驱动的地表水的动态性质给准确解释这些动态带来了挑战。在这里，我们介绍了第一个全球数据集，该数据集以年度分辨率确定了 1984 年至 2022 年地表水上升或衰退的时间。我们的方法侧重于通过过滤掉季节性或短期波动来识别地表水特征的持续变化。使用一种新颖的算法，我们绘制了全球地表水转变的时间，包括河流、湖泊、水库、洪水淹没的农业和沿海地区。数据集中，每个 30 m × 30 m 像素记录了水位上升或衰退的情况，并指定了过渡年份。该数据集使用户能够可视化变化的位置、类型和幅度，同时其对时间的关注为水动态驱动因素提供了新的见解。该数据集专为可访问性而设计，支持科学研究以及非政府组织、政策制定者和水资源管理者应对地表水相关挑战。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Recent advances in satellite technology and cloud computing have enabled global-scale monitoring of long-term surface water changes. The dynamic nature of surface water, driven by seasonal fluctuations and climatic events, presents challenges for accurately interpreting these dynamics. Here, we introduce the first global dataset that identifies the timing, at annual resolution, of surface water advance or recession from 1984 to 2022. Our approach focuses on identifying persistent changes in surface water features by filtering out seasonal or shorter-term fluctuations. Using a novel algorithm, we mapped the timing of surface water transitions globally, including rivers, lakes, reservoirs, flooded agriculture, and coastal regions. In the dataset each 30 m × 30 m pixel records whether water advance or recession occurred and specifies the year of transition. This dataset enables users to visualize the location, type, and magnitude of changes, while its focus on timing provides new insights into the drivers of water dynamics. Designed for accessibility, the dataset supports scientific research as well as NGOs, policymakers, and water managers in addressing surface water-related challenges.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06013-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6013_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 表观最佳土壤湿度等于田间持水量吗？</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-65470-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Is apparent optimum soil moisture equivalent to field capacity?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ying Zhao; Qiuli Hu; Lizhu Suo; Yi Wang; Allen Hunt&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;这篇文章没有摘要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This article has no abstract.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-65470-z/MediaObjects/41467_2025_65470_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>