<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 02:06:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 气候干预对中国南北水鸿沟的不同影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02708-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Divergent impacts of climate interventions on China’s north-south water divide&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xiao Zhang; Yuanchao Fan; Jerry Tjiputra; Helene Muri; Qiao Chen&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;基于太阳辐射修饰的气候干预措施可能会导致区域水文变化不均匀，同时减轻变暖。在这里，我们使用挪威地球系统模型，调查了气候干预对中国北干旱南部洪水模式的影响，并补充了火山数据。我们的结果表明，赤道平流层气溶胶注入可以减少南北水的鸿沟，从而减少半球间和赤道至北极对北极的温度梯度，从而改变大气循环和东亚季风以增加中国北部的降水量和地表径流，同时与南方相比，在北部降低了北部的降水量，相比之下。 Pinatubo火山喷发后观察到的降水变化支持了这种机制。相比之下，海洋云亮起可能会加剧南部的洪水风险，而卷心云稀疏和减少中等排放可能会加剧北部的干旱。我们的发现揭示了不同气候干预措施对区域氢化的不同影响，强调了其全球干预效率和区域水安全之间的潜在协同作用和权衡。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Solar radiation modification-based climate interventions may cause uneven regional hydrological changes while mitigating warming. Here, we investigate the effects of climate interventions on China’s North Drought-South Flood pattern using the Norwegian Earth System Model supplemented by volcanic data. Our results indicate that equatorial stratospheric aerosol injection could mitigate the north-south water divide by reducing inter-hemispheric and equator-to-North-pole temperature gradients, thereby modifying atmospheric circulation and the East Asian monsoon to increase precipitation and surface runoff in northern China while reducing them in the south, compared to the high emissions scenario. This mechanism is supported by observed precipitation changes following the Mount Pinatubo volcanic eruption. In contrast, marine cloud brightening may intensify southern flood risks, while cirrus cloud thinning and moderate emissions reduction might exacerbate northern droughts. Our findings reveal distinct regional hydroclimatic impacts of different climate interventions, highlighting potential synergies and trade-offs between their global intervention efficacy and regional water security.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02708-0/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2708_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>