<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 02:29:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 水下沙丘高度的双峰性表明在高流量时闪烁行为</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-61248-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Bimodality in subaqueous dune height suggests flickering behavior at high flow&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Sjoukje I. de Lange; Roeland C. van de Vijsel; Paul J. J. F. Torfs; Nick P. Wallerstein; Antonius J. F. Hoitink&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河床形式通过改变床粗糙度来影响河流液压。随着流速的增加，沙床从平床到涟漪，沙丘和上层舞台床的河流过渡。尽管先前的研究注意到，床形高度随着流动强度和床配置之间的快速变化增加了，但后者仍在研究。在这里，我们揭示了基于早期实验的数据和一个互补实验，在低和高的沙丘高度之间的运输阶段闪烁。在此运输阶段之上，沙丘高度分布中的第二种模式变得越来越独特，表明临界过渡。第二种模式的出现可能是由于悬浮沉积物浓度影响湍流的时间变化而引发的，或者可能是由沙丘运动学导致的，使大沙丘能够长得更长。这种闪烁的行为挑战了单个快照以捕获系统的床几何形状，影响现场测量和实验设计，并质疑地貌学中经典的平衡方程。我们的研究要求进一步的研究以了解和量化高运输阶段沉积物床的闪烁行为。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;River bedforms influence fluvial hydraulics by altering bed roughness. With increasing flow velocity, the sand-bedded river transitions from a flat bed to ripples, dunes, and an upper stage plane bed. Although prior research notes increased bedform height variation with flow strength and rapid shifts between bed configurations, the latter remains understudied. Here, we reveal flickering between low and high dune heights for transport stages exceeding 18, based on data from earlier experiments and a complementary experiment. Above this transport stage, the second mode in the dune height distributions becomes increasingly distinctive, suggesting a critical transition. The emergence of the second mode is potentially triggered by temporal changes in suspended sediment concentration impacting turbulence, or might result from dune kinematics enabling larger dunes to grow and persist longer. This flickering behavior challenges the adequacy of a single snapshot to capture the system’s bed geometry, impacting field measurements and experimental designs, and questions a classical equilibrium equation in geomorphology. Our study calls for further research to understand and quantify flickering behavior in sediment beds at high transport stages.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-61248-5/MediaObjects/41467_2025_61248_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>