<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 02:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 与单年的LaNiñas相比，多年LaNiñas对土壤水分的扩增影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01175-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Amplified impacts of multi-year La Niñas on soil moisture compared to single-year La Niñas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Tingting Zhu; Jin-Yi Yu; Min-Hui Lo&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;这项研究使用2200年的CESM1模拟，AGCM实验和观察数据研究了12月至1月1月（DJF）对多年（MY）和单年（SY）LaNiñas的土壤水分反应。确定了我的LaNiñas放大SyLaNiñas对土壤水分的影响的四个地区：北美，澳大利亚，中东和萨赫勒。 SyLaNiñas通常会在中东和北美引起土壤水分干燥，并在澳大利亚和萨赫勒（Sahel）润湿。由于降水异常的加强或降水引起的土壤水分异常的积累，我的LaNiñas在第二个DJF中增强了这些效果，除非在Sahel中部分由蒸发异常驱动。土壤水分的变化与LaNiña引起的海面温度变化有关印度洋（澳大利亚和中东）和太平洋（用于北美）。从1948年到2022年，观察到的我的LaNiña事件在很大程度上支持了这些扩增的效果。这些发现强调了需要将我的LaNiñas纳入区域农业和水资源管理策略，以更好地预期和减轻其影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This study examines December-January-February (DJF) soil moisture responses to multi-year (MY) and single-year (SY) La Niñas using a 2200-year CESM1 simulation, AGCM experiments, and observational data. Four regions where MY La Niñas amplify SY La Niñas’ impacts on soil moisture were identified: North America, Australia, the Middle East, and the Sahel. SY La Niñas typically cause soil moisture drying in the Middle East and North America and wetting in Australia and the Sahel. MY La Niñas enhance these effects in the second DJF due to the strengthening of precipitation anomalies or the accumulation of precipitation-induced soil moisture anomalies, except in the Sahel where wetting is driven in part by evapotranspiration anomalies. Soil moisture variations are linked to La Niña-induced sea surface temperature changes in the Indian Ocean (for Australia and the Middle East) and the Pacific Ocean (for North America). These amplified effects are largely supported by the observed MY La Niña events from 1948 to 2022. These findings emphasize the need to integrate MY La Niñas into regional agriculture and water resource management strategies to better anticipate and mitigate their impacts.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01175-w/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1175_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 干旱地区储层建筑的历史数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05712-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Historical dataset of reservoir construction in arid regions&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Enwei Huang; Guofeng Zhu; Gaojia Meng; Yuhao Wang; Longhu Chen; YuXin Miao; QingYang Wang; Xinyue Shi; Ling Zhao; Qinqin Wang; Xiaoyu Qi; Xuan Zhang; Yinying Jiao; Siyu Lu; Rui Li; WenMin Li&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水库对于防洪，灌溉和发电很重要，而在干旱地区缺水的稀缺使水库的作用更加重要。我们在中国的干旱地区分发了669个水库，并补充了与水库相关的历史和社会经济数据，数据集中的水库信息完成学位达到98.53％。研究表明，中国干旱地区的水库的建设通常可以分为快速增长，稳定的生长和高质量的生长阶段。根据干旱地区的水文模式，干旱地区的储层的空间分布与农业土地和人口的分布有着强烈的重叠，并且储层的建设显着影响社会经济发展。中国干旱地区的储层建设的历史和社会经济数据集为解决水库建设和遗弃，储层最佳和调度，有效利用区域水资源，生态建设和可持续发展的问题提供了科学依据。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Reservoirs are important for flood control, irrigation, and electricity generation, and the scarcity of water resources in arid areas makes the role of reservoirs even more important. We registered 669 reservoirs distributed in China’s arid zones and supplemented the reservoir-related historical and socio-economic data, and the reservoir information completion degree in the dataset reached 98.53%. The study showed that the construction of reservoirs in China’s arid zones can generally be divided into rapid growth, stable growth, and high-quality growth phases. According to the hydrological pattern of the arid zone, the spatial distribution of reservoirs in the arid zone overlaps strongly with the distribution of agricultural land and population, and the construction of reservoirs significantly affects socio-economic development. The historical and socio-economic dataset of reservoir construction in China’s arid zones provides a scientific basis for solving the problems of reservoir construction and abandonment, reservoir optimality and scheduling, efficient use of regional water resources, ecological construction, and sustainable development.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05712-3/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5712_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>