<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 02:09:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 极端干旱的波动事件威胁着长江生态系统中水生浮游生物社区的生物多样性和稳定性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02143-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Extreme drought-heatwave events threaten the biodiversity and stability of aquatic plankton communities in the Yangtze River ecosystems&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jixuan Lyu; Yong Shi; Tao Liu; Xiaomei Xu; Shengjing Liu; Guang Yang; Dong Peng; Yubing Qu; Shuo Zhang; Chonghao Chen; Yanxu Zhang; Jianhua Gao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流对生物地球化学周期至关重要，连接陆地，海洋和大气系统。但是，他们的生态系统越来越受到极端天气事件的威胁。在这里，我们使用了环境DNA方法来评估极端干旱的事件对长江河水群社区的影响。我们表明，极端干旱的事件减少了社区的α多样性，增加了其β多样性，并同时简化了不稳定的社区网络结构。该事件还将主要的藻类分类单元从芽孢杆菌转移到蓝细菌，并伴随着有机碳和不稳定有机碳含量的增加。在全球范围内，在高纬度地区，在极端干旱的波动事件中，温度升高更为明显，可能会增加对河流生态系统生物多样性和稳定性的影响。我们的发现突出了河流生态系统对极端事件的脆弱性，并强调了减轻气候变化对河流生态系统的影响的必要性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Rivers are crucial to biogeochemical cycles, connecting terrestrial, oceanic, and atmospheric systems. However, their ecosystems are increasingly threatened by extreme weather events. Here we used the environmental DNA approach to assess the impact of extreme drought-heatwave events on the aquatic plankton communities of the Yangtze River. We showed that an extreme drought-heatwave event reduced the α diversity of communities, increased their β diversity, and simultaneously simplified and destabilized community network structure. This event also shifted the dominant algae taxa from Bacillariophyta to Cyanobacteria, accompanied by increases in organic carbon and labile organic carbon contents. Globally, temperature rises during this extreme drought-heatwave event are more pronounced in high-latitude regions, likely amplifying impacts on river ecosystem biodiversity and stability. Our findings highlight the vulnerability of river ecosystems to extreme events and underscore the need to mitigate climate change’s effects on river ecosystems.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02143-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2143_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>