<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 02:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 巨大的冰山融合水增加了上海分层和垂直混合</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01659-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Giant iceberg meltwater increases upper-ocean stratification and vertical mixing&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Natasha S. Lucas; J. Alexander Brearley; Katharine R. Hendry; Theo Spira; Anne Braakmann-Folgmann; E. Povl Abrahamsen; Michael P. Meredith; Geraint A. Tarling&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;冰上质量损失是气候变化最明显的表现之一，南极通过熔化或通过产犊将质量排入海洋。后者产生的冰山可以改变海洋水性，通常与来源很远。这会影响上海上的物理学和主要生产力，对大气碳的缩减有影响。迄今为止，由于缺乏近端测量而阻碍了对冰山修饰的详细理解。在这里，从水下滑翔机对巨型冰山进行的独特测量可以定量融化对南方大洋上层物理和生物过程的影响，该地区对于全球热和碳螯合物而言非常重要。冰山基融化侵蚀了季节性产生的冬季水层分层，通常形成强大的势能屏障，以垂直交换地面和深水，而淡水径流会增加，而浅滩近地表分层。营养丰富的较深水域融合了装有陆原材料的融合水，通风至最大分层以下，提供了一种减轻关键的临界浮游植物限制成分的潜在机制。区域历史水文数据表明，在另一个大型冰山的通过期间，类似的分层变化，这表明它们可能是修饰冬季水的重要途径。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ice-sheet mass loss is one of the clearest manifestations of climate change, with Antarctica discharging mass into the ocean via melting or through calving. The latter produces icebergs that can modify ocean water properties, often at great distances from source. This affects upper-ocean physics and primary productivity, with implications for atmospheric carbon drawdown. A detailed understanding of iceberg modification of ocean waters has hitherto been hindered by a lack of proximal measurements. Here unique measurements of a giant iceberg from an underwater glider enable quantification of meltwater effects on the physical and biological processes in the upper layers of the Southern Ocean, a region disproportionately important for global heat and carbon sequestration. Iceberg basal melting erodes seasonally produced winter water layer stratification, normally forming a strong potential energy barrier to vertical exchange of surface and deep waters, while freshwater run-off increases and shoals near-surface stratification. Nutrient-rich deeper waters, incorporating meltwater loaded with terrigenous material, are ventilated to below this stratification maxima, providing a potential mechanism for alleviating critical phytoplankton-limiting components. Regional historical hydrographic data demonstrate similar stratification changes during the passage of another large iceberg, suggesting that they may be an important pathway of aseasonal winter water modification.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01659-7/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1659_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 从2000年到2023年的中国湖泊和水库的高分辨率水质数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04915-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;High Resolution Water Quality Dataset of Chinese Lakes and Reservoirs from 2000 to 2023&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Shilong Luan; Huixiao Pan; Ruoque Shen; Xiaosheng Xia; Hongtao Duan; Wenping Yuan; Jing Wei&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水质参数（pH，溶解的氧（DO），总氮（TN，包括有机氮和无机氮），总磷（TP），铜管指数（COD &lt;sub&gt;MN&lt;/sub&gt; ）（COD MN），浊度（TUR），电导率（EC），电导率（EC），以及溶解有机碳（DOC）和溶解的有机碳和溶解性。在这项研究中，我们使用随机森林（RF）模型开发了从2000年到2023年的这些关键水质参数的每月数据集，用于近180,000个湖泊和水库。这些RF模型考虑了所研究湖泊和储层盆地中气候，土壤特性和人为活动的影响，并有效地捕获了其水质参数的空间和时间变化，其相关系数（r &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ）范围为0.65至0.65至0.76。有趣的是，在此期间观察到TUR和EC的增加，而pH，DO和其他参数显示出最小的波动。该数据集对于进一步评估水生生态系统的生态，环境和气候功能具有重要价值。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water quality parameters (pH, dissolved oxygen (DO), total nitrogen (TN, includes both organic nitrogen and inorganic nitrogen), total phosphorus (TP), permanganate index (COD&lt;sub&gt;Mn&lt;/sub&gt;), turbidity (Tur), electrical conductivity (EC), and dissolved organic carbon (DOC)) are important to evaluate the ecological health of lakes and reservoirs. In this research, we developed a monthly dataset of these key water quality parameters from 2000 to 2023 for nearly 180,000 lakes and reservoirs across China, using the random forest (RF) models. These RF models took into account the impacts of climate, soil properties, and anthropogenic activities within basins of studied lakes and reservoirs, and effectively captured the spatial and temporal variations of their water quality parameters with correlation coefficients (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;) ranging from 0.65 to 0.76. Interestingly, an increase in Tur and EC was observed during this period, while pH, DO, and other parameters showed minimal fluctuations. This dataset is of significant value for further evaluating the ecological, environmental, and climatic functions of aquatic ecosystems.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04915-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4915_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 全球农田水利用效率的20年数据集（2001-2020）分辨率为1公里</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04904-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A 20-year dataset (2001–2020) of global cropland water-use efficiency at 1-km grid resolution&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Min Jiang; Chaolei Zheng; Li Jia; Jiu Chen&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;农田水利用效率（WUE）是可持续利用农业水资源的重要指标。缺乏具有高空间分辨率的长期全球农田WUE数据集限制了我们对Cropland Wue的全球和区域模式的理解。这项研究从2001年至2020年开发了1公里的空间分辨率，开发了一项长期的全球农田WUE数据集。从Etmonitor Global Global Evapotranspiration Dataset中检索到净初级生产力（NPP）和蒸散量之间的比率。全球农田NPP是通过从总生产（GPP）中减去植物呼吸来估算的，该植物呼吸是通过使用通量较高的观察数据对不同的全球气候区域进行了优化后使用改进的轻松效率模型估算的。与通量塔的地面测量值相比，生成的WUE产品具有较高的相关效率（0.76）和较低的均方根误差（0.5 g c/kg H &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; O/yr）的精度良好。该数据集可以用作基本数据，以提高对可持续发展的用水利用的有效利用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Cropland water-use efficiency (WUE) is an essential indicator for the sustainable utilization of agricultural water resources. The lack of long-term global cropland WUE datasets with high spatial resolution limits our understanding of global and regional patterns of cropland WUE. This study developed a long-term global cropland WUE dataset at 1-km spatial resolution from 2001 to 2020. The cropland WUE was obtained as the ratio between net primary productivity (NPP) and evapotranspiration that was retrieved from ETMonitor global evapotranspiration datasets. The global cropland NPP was estimated by subtracting plant respiration from gross primary production (GPP), which was estimated using an improved light-use efficiency model after being optimized for different global climate zones using flux-tower observation data. The generated WUE product showed good accuracy with high correlation efficiency (0.76) and low root mean square error (0.5 g C/kg H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O/yr) compared with the ground measurements at flux towers. This dataset can be used as fundamental data to advance the efficient utilization of water use for sustainable development.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04904-1/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4904_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>