<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 02:17:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 季节性速度模式为软床亚冰川水文连续性提供了见解</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02198-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Seasonal velocity patterns provide insights for the soft-bed subglacial hydrology continuum&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jane K. Hart; Nathaniel R. Baurley; Amy Bonnie; Benjamin A. Robson; Graeme Bragg; Kirk Martinez&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;冰川下水文学在控制冰川行为，影响冰川撤退以及对海平面上升的贡献中起着重要作用。在这里，我们提供了来自四个软床的温带冰川的详细季节性数据集，并展示了从通道到多通道分布行为的连续冰川水文学。我们的结果说明了这种连续体如何受到直至晶粒尺寸和水下过程的影响，我们量化了基础滑动和变形的相对时间。这些不同的水文学具有独特的季节性速度模式，尽管已使用多数据流进行了识别，但我们建议可以使用仅基于Sentinel-1卫星的冰川速度数据进行分类。在更大的数据集上对冰川亚冰川水文进行分类的能力将允许更好地参数化冰盖模型的冰川过程。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Subglacial hydrology plays an important role in controlling glacier behaviour, influencing glacier retreat and the resulting contributions to sea level rise. Here we present a detailed seasonal data set from four soft-bedded temperate glaciers and demonstrate a continuum of subglacial hydrology from channelized to a multichannel distributed behaviour. Our results illustrate how this continuum may be affected by till grain size and subaqueous processes, and we quantify the relative timings of basal sliding and deformation. These different hydrologies have a distinctive seasonal velocity pattern, which although have been identified using a multi-data stream, we suggest can be classified using solely Sentinel-1 satellite-based glacier velocity data. The ability to categorize subglacial glacier hydrology over a much larger data set would allow a better parameterization of subglacial processes for ice sheet models.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02198-0/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2198_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 季节性降水预测的可解释的机器学习模型</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02207-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;An interpretable machine learning model for seasonal precipitation forecasting&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Enzo Pinheiro; Taha B. M. J. Ouarda&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;季节性气候预测对社会福利很重要，因为它支持决策者采取积极步骤来减轻不利气候条件的风险或利用有利的风险。在这里，我们介绍了Telnet，这是一种序列到序列的机器学习模型，用于短期铅铅季节性降水预测。该模型采用过去的季节性降水值和气候指数，以预测接下来六个重叠季节目标区域每个网格点的经验降水分布。 Telnet具有简单的编码器架构架构，可以通过有限的数据对模型进行培训，这在气候预测中通常是这样。它的确定性和概率性能得到了彻底评估，并将其与最先进的动力学和深度学习模型进行比较，该模型由于其高气候可预测性，用于季节性预测研究。培训，验证和测试集被多次重新采样，以估计与小数据集相关的不确定性。结果表明，在多个初始化月份和交货时间内，Telnet排名最精确，最精确，尤其是在可预测信号最强的雨季中。此外，该模型允许实例和铅的预测通过其可变选择权重。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Seasonal climate forecasting is important for societal welfare, as it supports decision-makers in taking proactive steps to mitigate risks from adverse climate conditions or to take advantage of favorable ones. Here, we introduce TelNet, a sequence-to-sequence machine learning model for short-to-medium lead seasonal precipitation forecasting. The model takes past seasonal precipitation values and climate indices to predict an empirical precipitation distribution for every grid point of the target region for the next six overlapping seasons. TelNet has a simple encoder-decoder-head architecture, allowing the model to be trained with a limited amount of data, as is often the case in climate forecasting. Its deterministic and probabilistic performance is thoroughly evaluated and compared with state-of-the-art dynamical and deep learning models in a prominent region for seasonal forecasting studies due to its high climate predictability. The training, validation, and test sets are resampled multiple times to estimate the uncertainty associated with a small dataset. The results show that TelNet ranks among the most accurate and calibrated models across multiple initialization months and lead times, especially during the rainy season when the predictable signal is strongest. Moreover, the model allows instance- and lead-wise forecast interpretation through its variable selection weights.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02207-2/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2207_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>