<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 02:21:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 从自动库存充实到极端降雨引起的大规模浪费的可解释多类建模</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02816-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;From automated inventory enrichment to interpretable multiclass modeling of extreme rainfall-induced mass wasting&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Chuanjie Xi; Wen-Jie Xu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候变化正在加剧降雨引起的大规模浪费风险，而当前清单中有关故障类型和来源区域的详细信息有限，阻碍了机械洞察力。在这里，我们提出了一种基于空间算法的自动标记方法，用于增强大规模浪费库存。根据运动行为，事件分为四种类型。根据 2023 年 7 月中国北京的极端降水事件创建了目视解释清单，以验证所提出的方法。结果显示，手动和自动标记之间的总体一致性为 82% 至 85%，其中泥石流的一致性较低 (59%)。然后将该方法应用于更大的库存，以自动识别故障类型并描绘源区域。使用 Shapley 附加解释，我们根据下游分析中的自动标签量化了大量浪费类型的因子贡献。该方法无需大型标记数据集即可增强库存，并提供针对大规模浪费控制的特定类型的见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate change is amplifying rainfall-induced mass-wasting risks, while limited detail on failure types and source areas in current inventories hinders mechanistic insight. Here we present a spatial algorithm-based automatic labeling method for enhancing mass-wasting inventories. Events are distinguished into four types based on movement behavior. A visually interpreted inventory was created from the July 2023 extreme precipitation event in Beijing, China, to validate the proposed method. Results show an overall consistency of 82% to 85% between manual and automatic labeling, with lower consistency for debris floods (59%). The method was then applied to a larger inventory to automatically identify failure types and delineate source areas. Using Shapley Additive Explanations, we quantified factor contributions by mass-wasting types based on the automatic labels in a downstream analysis. This method enhances inventories without large labeled datasets and provides type-specific insights into controls on mass wasting.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02816-x/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2816_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 印度次大陆水分预算组成部分的每小时数据集（1940-2024）</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06044-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;An Hourly Dataset of Moisture Budget Components Over the Indian Subcontinent (1940–2024)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Akash Singh Raghuvanshi; Ankit Agarwal&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;根据 1940 年至 2024 年期间印度次大陆及周边海洋区域的 ERA5 再分析构建的大气水分预算成分网格数据集，称为 ERA5moistIN。该数据集具有 0.25 度的空间和每小时时间分辨率，包括柱综合水分预算的七个组成部分：存储变化、水平和垂直平流、水平和垂直收敛以及相关的水分通量收敛项。这些分量是使用中心有限差分法和垂直积分以及表面压力从压力水平变量（包括比湿度和纬向、经向和垂直风分量）导出的。针对 ERA5 单级输出（例如总柱水蒸气和垂直积分水分散度）的验证证明了物理一致性和可靠性。该诊断框架只需稍作代码更改即可适应其他再分析数据集和气候模型输出，并且适用于任何地区。 ERA5moistIN 支持水分过程的高分辨率分析，适用于季风研究、极端事件归因、模型评估和预测工具开发等应用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A gridded dataset of atmospheric moisture budget components constructed from ERA5 reanalysis over the Indian subcontinent and surrounding ocean regions for the period 1940–2024, referred to as ERA5moistIN. Available at 0.25 degree spatial and hourly temporal resolution, the dataset includes seven components of the column integrated moisture budget: change in storage, horizontal and vertical advection, horizontal and vertical convergence, and associated moisture flux convergence terms. These components are derived from pressure level variables including specific humidity and zonal, meridional, and vertical wind components using central finite difference methods and vertical integration, along with surface pressure. Validation against ERA5 single level outputs, such as total column water vapor and vertically integrated moisture divergence, demonstrates physical consistency and reliability. The diagnostic framework can be adapted to other reanalysis datasets and climate model outputs with minor code changes and is applicable to any region. ERA5moistIN supports high resolution analysis of moisture processes and is suitable for applications including monsoon studies, extreme event attribution, model evaluation, and predictive tool development.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06044-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6044_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>