<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 02:16:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 未来极端降水因中尺度水汽辐合加剧而加剧</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01859-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Future extreme precipitation amplified by intensified mesoscale moisture convergence&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ping Chang; Dan Fu; Xue Liu; Frederic S. Castruccio; Andreas F. Prein; Gokhan Danabasoglu; Xiaoqi Wang; Julio Bacmeister; Qiuying Zhang; Nan Rosenbloom; Teagan King; Susan C. Bates&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;极端降水事件是由复杂的多尺度大气动态相互作用驱动的，并由可用水分推动。预计它们将随着气候变化而加剧，给人类社区和生态系统带来越来越大的风险。然而，当前的低分辨率气候模型难以准确表示关键的极端降水现象，限制了我们生成稳健可靠的未来预测的能力。在这里，我们提出了一组分辨率为 10 至 25 公里的气候模拟，并改进了中尺度对流系统的表示，以评估每日极端降水及其驱动因素的未来变化。与 100 公里分辨率的模拟相比，我们的高分辨率模拟更真实地捕捉了历史时期每日极端降水的观测空间分布和强度。在未来二氧化碳排放量较高的情况下，到 2100 年，陆地上的每日极端降水量可能会增加约 41%，这主要是由于中尺度水分收敛的增加。在低分辨率模型中，这种动力学贡献对极端降水的影响被低估了三倍。这些结果凸显了高分辨率气候模型在限制未来极端事件以及为更有效的气候风险评估和适应策略提供信息方面的关键作用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Extreme precipitation events are driven by complex multiscale atmospheric dynamic interactions, fuelled by available moisture. They are expected to intensify with climate change, posing increasing risks to human communities and ecosystems. However, current low-resolution climate models struggle to accurately represent key extreme precipitation-generating phenomena, limiting our ability to generate robust and reliable future projections. Here we present an ensemble of climate simulations with a 10-to-25-km resolution and an improved representation of mesoscale convective systems to assess future changes in daily extreme precipitation and its drivers. Our high-resolution simulations more realistically capture the observed spatial distribution and intensity of daily extreme precipitation over the historical period than the 100-km resolution counterparts. In a future scenario with high carbon dioxide emissions, daily extreme precipitation over land could increase by about 41% by 2100, mainly as a result of increased mesoscale moisture convergence. The impact of this dynamical contribution to extreme precipitation is underestimated by a factor of three in the low-resolution model. These results highlight the crucial role of high-resolution climate modelling in constraining future extremes and informing more effective climate risk assessments and adaptation strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01859-1/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1859_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 安第斯山脉南部未来大干旱期间冰川水量减少</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02845-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Less water from glaciers during future megadroughts in the Southern Andes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Álvaro Ayala; Eduardo Muñoz-Castro; Daniel Farinotti; David Farías-Barahona; Pablo A. Mendoza; Shelley MacDonell; James McPhee; Ximena Vargas; Francesca Pellicciotti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;干旱期间，冰川融化维持山区盆地的水排放，但持续的冰川退缩威胁着这一基本能力。在这里，我们评估了安第斯山脉南部冰川对南美洲有记录以来最严重、持续和广泛的干旱之一（2010 年至今）以及预计的本世纪末特大干旱的反应。通过冰川水文数值模拟，我们发现，尽管年平均降水量赤字为 36%，但 2010-2019 年的冰川径流与前十年（2000-2009 年）相比几乎没有变化，总冰量减少了 10%。然而，对未来冰川演化的模拟表明，与 2010 年之前的水平相比，在本世纪末的特大干旱期间，年度和夏季冰川径流可能分别下降 20 ± 11% 和 48 ± 6%。我们的研究结果预测，在极端干旱期间，冰川对降水不足的缓冲作用会减弱，从而加剧南美洲山区生态系统和生计的水资源短缺。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glacier melt sustains water discharge from mountain basins during droughts, but ongoing glacier retreat threatens this fundamental capacity. Here, we assess the response of glaciers in the Southern Andes to one of the most severe, persistent, and extensive droughts on record in South America (2010-present), and to projected end-of-century megadroughts. Using glacio-hydrological numerical simulations, we show that despite a mean annual precipitation deficit of 36%, glacier runoff in 2010-2019 remained almost unaltered compared to the preceding decade (2000-2009), sustained by a 10% loss of total ice volume. However, simulations of future glacier evolution indicate that annual and summer glacier runoff could decline by up to 20 ± 11% and 48 ± 6%, respectively, during end-of-century megadroughts compared to pre-2010 levels. Our results project a weakening of the glacier’s buffering role against precipitation deficits during extreme droughts, increasing water scarcity for ecosystems and livelihoods in the mountain regions of South America.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02845-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2845_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 基于多模型的全球大气水分源汇关系和大气盆地数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06123-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A multi-model based dataset of global atmospheric moisture source-sink relationships and atmospheric basins&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yu Zhang; Deyu Zhong; Rongrong Cai; Mingxi Zhang; Yinglin Tian; Di Xie; Yuan Cao; Yuantao Mei&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全面了解大气水文循环对于研究气候和人为变化对全球水资源的跨境影响至关重要。本研究提出了 AMSSRAB，这是蒸发和降水位置之间的大气水分源汇关系 (AMSSR) 的全球数据集，以及对全球大气水文循环进行区域化的衍生大气盆地 (AB)。通过集成三个大气水分跟踪模型（WAM2layers、UTrack 和 WaterSip），AMSSRAB 提供了大气水分流的多模型集合表示。该数据集以 1° 分辨率提供了 40 年（1979-2018）的季节性大气水分源汇关系。衍生的大气盆地确定了准独立的水分循环系统，其特征是高内部循环。 AMSSRAB 与偏差校正重建数据和之前发布的数据集表现出强烈的一致性，同时提供了补充现有蒸发-降水框架的区域视角。该数据集使研究人员能够在多个尺度上研究水分源汇关系，分析区域水分循环模式，并检查地球大气水系统内大气水分对气候变化的响应。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A comprehensive understanding of the atmospheric hydrological cycle is crucial for studying the transboundary impacts of climate and anthropogenic changes on global water resources. This study presents AMSSRAB, a global dataset of atmospheric moisture source-sink relationships (AMSSRs) between evaporation and precipitation locations, and the derived atmospheric basins (ABs) that regionalize the global atmospheric hydrological cycle. By integrating three atmospheric moisture tracking models (WAM2layers, UTrack, and WaterSip), AMSSRAB provides a multi-model ensemble representation of atmospheric moisture flows. The dataset provides seasonal atmospheric moisture source-sink relationships at 1° resolution over 40 years (1979–2018). The derived atmospheric basins identify quasi-independent moisture circulation systems characterized by high internal recycling. AMSSRAB demonstrates strong agreement with bias-corrected reconstruction data and previously published datasets while offering a regional perspective that complements existing evaporationshed-precipitationshed frameworks. This dataset enables researchers to investigate moisture source-sink relationships at multiple scales, analyze regional moisture recycling patterns, and examine atmospheric moisture responses to climate variability within the Earth’s atmospheric water system.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06123-0/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6123_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>