<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 02:13:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Water | 观察到的水文过程中的全球模式</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00407-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Global patterns in observed hydrologic processes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hilary McMillan; Ryoko Araki; Lauren Bolotin; Dong-Hyun Kim; Gemma Coxon; Martyn Clark; Jan Seibert&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;为了管理水资源和预测河流，水文学家试图了解水从降水，流域，流向河道的流动。但是，我们缺乏有关全球水文过程的空间分布和物理控制的基本信息。需要此信息来为大域模型模拟提供理论支持。在这里，为了解决这个问题，我们介绍了400个研究流域的全球，可搜索的数据库，其中包含对主要水文流道的发表描述。这种知识综合方法利用了数十年的赠款资金，现场工作和当地专业知识。我们使用数据库来测试有关气候，生物群体和地形在控制水文过程中的作用的长期假设。我们表明，干旱预测了水流通路的深度，并且地形和生物群落预测了侧向流动途径的流行。这些新数据和搜索功能支持有效的假设检验，以研究将景观组织与水文功能相关的新兴模式。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To manage water resources and forecast river flows, hydrologists seek to understand how water moves from precipitation, through watersheds, into river channels. However, we lack fundamental information on the spatial distribution and physical controls on global hydrologic processes. This information is needed to provide theoretical support for large-domain model simulations. Here, to address this issue, we present a global, searchable database of 400 research watersheds with published descriptions of dominant hydrologic flow pathways. This knowledge synthesis approach leverages decades of grant funding, fieldwork effort and local expertise. We use the database to test longstanding hypotheses about the roles of climate, biomes and landforms in controlling hydrologic processes. We show that aridity predicts the depth of water flow pathways and that terrain and biomes predict the prevalence of lateral flow pathways. These new data and search capabilities support efficient hypothesis testing to investigate emergent patterns that relate landscape organization to hydrologic function.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00407-w/MediaObjects/44221_2025_407_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>