<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 02:07:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 森林砍伐和森林火的拦截减少增加了大规模的河流洪水风险</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02748-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Interception reduction from deforestation and forest fire increases large-scale fluvial flooding risk&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Tae-Ho Kang; Ashish Sharma; Lucy Marshall; Young-Oh Kim&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;森林砍伐后，灾难性洪水的发生频率更高，但是在大空间尺度上可以测试这种连接有限的观察结果。在这里，我们使用了影响澳大利亚25,000公里&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;区域的巨型森林大火的数据，在森林冠层中表现出快速损失，在那里，在半个多世纪以来，已经仔细观察了径流产生，并具有最小的人为影响。这提供了一个独特的机会来评估森林冠层损失对大规模河流洪水的影响。国家控制的假设检验具有气候和流域的控制以增强鲁棒性，显示出森林损失疗法导致的年度最大流量的统计学显着增加。这种自然实验的推理是，森林损失对森林冠层，叶片落叶和宽区域土壤的拦截潜力的影响可能会对河流洪水产生可识别的影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Catastrophic flooding has been noted to occur with greater frequency following deforestation, but limited observations have been available to test this connection over large spatial scales. Here we used the data of mega forest fires impacting a region of 25,000 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; in Australia exhibiting rapid loss in forest canopy, where the runoff generation has been carefully observed with minimum anthropogenic influences for more than half a century. This provides a unique opportunity to assess the impact of the forest canopy loss on large-scale fluvial flooding. A state-controlled hypothesis test, with the climate and watershed states controlled to enhance robustness, shows a statistically significant increase in annual maximum flows resulting from the forest loss treatment. The reasoning for this natural experiment is that the forest loss impact on the interception potential of forest canopy, fallen leaves, and root-zone soils in wide region could have a recognizable impact on the fluvial flood.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02748-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2748_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 粉末区域中断的地貌和生物流连通性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02812-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Disrupted geomorphic and biotic stream connectivity in paraglacial regions&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lina E. Polvi; Lovisa Lind&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;生态和地貌理论假定纵向连通性；在这里，我们测试这些概念是否适用于带有湖泊和粗冰川沉积物的自然断开的冰川流网络。我们确定了用于通道宽度的下游液压几何关系（DHG）；河岸植被跨越过程域（急流，公寓，湖泊）在两个北部瑞典北部的集水区（急流，公寓，湖泊）上进行了库存，一个北部的集水区（FHC）以上一个，一个以上是一个。在FHC下方，海洋/三角洲沉积中的较细沉积物可能允许更多的溪流自我调整。 DHG的关系总体较弱，局部宽度变化较大，但在FHC-BELOW集水区中发现了湖面效应，湖泊下游的湖泊下游较宽。沿河岸植被物种密度并没有像连接的流网络那样在下游，并且覆盖范围之间的植被相似性与距离无关，这表明分散障碍。这些发现表明，以前的冰川流域高度分散，局部因素主导着地貌和生态模式。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ecological and geomorphic theory assume longitudinal connectivity; here, we test whether these concepts apply in naturally disconnected paraglacial stream networks with lakes and coarse glacial sediment. We determined downstream hydraulic geometry relationships (DHG) for channel width; riparian vegetation was inventoried across process domains (rapids, flats, lakes) over 10 km in two northern Swedish catchments—one above and one below the former highest coastline (FHC). Below the FHC, finer sediment from marine/deltaic deposition may allow more stream self-adjustment. DHG relationships were weak overall, with large local width variation, but slightly stronger in the FHC-below catchment, where a lake-effect was found, with wider channels downstream of lakes. Riparian vegetation species density did not substantially increase downstream as in connected stream networks, and vegetation similarity between reaches was weakly related to distance, suggesting disrupted dispersal. These findings indicate that formerly glaciated catchments are highly fragmented, with local factors dominating geomorphic and ecological patterns.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02812-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2812_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 质量控制，可靠的地下水水平数据具有相应的特定收益印度</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05899-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Quality controlled, reliable groundwater level data with corresponding specific yield over India&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Satish Kumar Kuruva; Maya Raghunath Suryawanshi; Amin Shakya; Chethan VA; Balaram Shaw; Vandana Sukumaran; Retinder Kour; Aayushi Kochar; Shard Chander; Bhaskar R. Nikam; Nagesh Kumar Dasika; Bramha Dutt Vishwakarma&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;地下水是国内，农业和工业用途的重要资源，由于人口增长和气候变化，其需求增长。几项研究已经确定印度的地下水在西北部以不可持续的速度耗尽，但在印度南部观察到了一种对比的趋势。为了更好地研究地下水动力学质量控制和可靠的井数据，这是必不可少的。在这里，我们处理来自印度32,299口井的季节性地下水水平，以获取可靠的井数据并提供各自的特定收益率。最初，没有数据和负值的井被删除。后来对每个井进行了三个sigma方法，以消除异常值。最后，保留了每年至少两个值的井，没有价值重复两次以上，并保留了2,759个可靠的井。我们使用基于矢量化的方法对含水层类型进行分类和基于水文地质图的估计特定收益率。我们还提供了对数据和脚本的开放访问，以便研究人员可以研究地下水的变化，比较宽限期和基于模型的地下水估计，以与原位井数据进行比较。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Groundwater is a vital resource for domestic, agricultural, and industrial use, with its demand growing due to population growth and climate change. Several studies have identified groundwater depleting in India at unsustainable rate over North-west part, but a contrasting trend is observed in the southern India. To better study groundwater dynamics quality-controlled and reliable well data is essential, which is missing. Here we process seasonal groundwater levels from 32,299 wells across India to obtain reliable well data and provide respective specific yields. Initially, wells with no data and negative values are removed. Later three-sigma method is imposed on each well to eliminate outliers. Finally, wells with at least two values per year, with no value repeating more than twice consecutively, are retained, resulting in 2,759 reliable wells. We used vectorization-based method to classify aquifer types and estimated specific yields based on hydrogeological map. We also provide open access to data and scripts so that researchers can study groundwater variations, compare GRACE and model-based groundwater estimates against in-situ well data.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05899-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5899_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>