<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 02:20:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 时空变异性的差异和印度东西方海岸之间复合沿海极端的风险</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01045-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Disparity in spatiotemporal variability and risk of compound coastal extremes between India’s East-West coasts&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Diljit Dutta; V. V. Srinivas; Govindasamy Bala&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;印度东海岸在6月至11月期间的极端风暴浪涌降落（SS-RF）容易受到季风和季风后孟加拉湾的不同强度的驱动。相反，西海岸主要见证了这些极端，主要是在季风期间，由阿拉伯海的抑郁症和沿海地区的低压槽驱动。当印度洋偶极子与厄尔尼诺南部振荡的中性（LaNiña或中性）阶段共同发生时，西部（东）海岸的较高频率是在西部（东）海岸的。此外，东海岸（孟买以外的西海岸）的SS-RF极端是风暴潮（降雨）占主导地位，在Haldia（孟买）的风险较高。另一方面，由于潮汐范围的差异和沿海潮流的季节性，在东部（西）海岸看到了较高（较低）的同时海平面降落极端频率。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Indian East Coast is susceptible to concurrent storm surge-rainfall (SS-RF) extremes during June–November, driven by low-pressure systems of varying intensity from the Bay of Bengal during monsoon and post-monsoon seasons. Contrarily, the West Coast witnesses these extremes primarily during monsoon, driven by depressions in the Arabian Sea and troughs of low pressure along the coast. Higher frequency of these extremes was witnessed on the West (East) Coast when the positive (negative) phase of the Indian Ocean Dipole co-occurred with the Neutral (La Niña or Neutral) phase of El Niño Southern Oscillation. Further, the SS-RF extremes on the East Coast (West Coast except Mumbai) were storm surge (rainfall) dominant, with higher risk at Haldia (Mumbai). On the other hand, a higher (lower) frequency of concurrent sea level-rainfall extremes was witnessed on the East (West) Coast due to disparity in tidal ranges and seasonality of coastal currents.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01045-5/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1045_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 跨县的节水策略应针对中国的制造业和农业部门</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02292-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Water-saving strategies across prefectures should target the manufacturing and agriculture sectors in China&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zongyong Zhang; Yuli Shan; Martin R. Tillotson; Philippe Ciais; Xu Zhao; Dandan Zhao; Hong Yang; Jingwen Huo; Zhao Zeng; Xian Li; Heran Zheng; Bofeng Cai; Wanqing Wang; Wang Kai; Guanlin Li; Geng Niu; Dabo Guan; Junguo Liu; Yu Hao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在包括中国在内的许多新兴经济体中，缺水是全球挑战。中国是最广泛的淡水使用者之一，在县级设定了2030年的水效率提高目标。但是，在各个部门和部门之间没有系统的用水和储蓄比较。在这里，我们使用了10,608个工业和1715个农业子行业的水的水抽水数据集用于343个县，并探索了减少用水量的机会。结果表明，最低水效率的工业子行业中有10％代表着不成比例的46％用水。可以实现18.9公里&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; （±3.2％）行业的节水和50.3公里&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; （±2.3％）的农业，相当于俄罗斯的年度需求。少数部门，包括布料（ING）和化学制造，米饭，蔬菜和水果培养，可能对节水最大的贡献。我们的研究对于识别用于单个各个部门的用水和效率信息至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water scarcity is a global challenge in many emerging economies, including China. China is one of the most extensive freshwater users and has set water efficiency improvement goals for 2030 at the prefecture level. However, no systematic water use and savings comparison exists across prefectures and sectors. Here, we used datasets of water withdrawal for 10,608 industrial and 1715 agricultural sub-sectors for 343 prefectures, and explored the opportunities to reduce water use. Results show that 10% of the least water-efficient industrial sub-sectors represent a disproportionate 46% water use. 18.9 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; (±3.2%) water saving in industry and 50.3 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; (±2.3%) in agriculture could be achieved, equivalent to Russia’s annual demand. A minority of sectors, including cloth(ing)- and chemical-manufacturing, rice-, vegetable- and fruit-cultivation, could contribute the most to water savings. Our study is essential for identifying water use and efficiency information for individual prefectures and sectors.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02292-3/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2292_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 降雨和失败的大坝有多极端</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-59261-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;How extreme rainfall and failing dams unleashed the Derna flood disaster&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ayman Mokhtar Nemnem; Ahad Hasan Tanim; Audrika Nahian; Sadik Khan; Erfan Goharian; Jasim Imran&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2023年9月11日，丹尼尔（Daniel）在瓦迪·德纳（Wadi Derna）流域释放了前所未有的降雨，引发了现代历史上最毁灭性的洪水之一，这是利比亚沿海城市的德尔纳（Derna）。这项研究使用综合建模方法重建了灾难，该方法结合了卫星图像，水文，液压和岩土技术模拟，机器学习，目击者帐户和数字高程数据，以评估层叠大坝故障的影响。我们的发现表明，该地区的大坝即使在结构上是合理的，也将为极端的径流提供最小的保护。但是，他们的失败释放了破坏性的浪潮，扩大了灾难的幅度和破坏。在这里，我们表明，老化洪水控制基础设施的崩溃，风险评估和应急准备不足，使灾难的影响升级。我们的发现强调了对系统的大坝安全评估，增强洪水预测以及适应性风险管理策略的迫切需求，这些策略应对极端气候和基础设施脆弱性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;On September 11, 2023, Storm Daniel unleashed unprecedented rainfall over the Wadi Derna watershed, triggering one of the most devastating floods in modern history, striking Derna, a coastal city in Libya. This study reconstructs the disaster using an integrated modeling approach that combines satellite imagery, hydrologic, hydraulic, and geotechnical simulations, machine learning, eyewitness accounts, and digital elevation data to assess the impact of cascading dam failures. Our findings reveal that the region’s dams, even if structurally sound, would have provided minimal protection against the extreme runoff. However, their failure unleashed a destructive surge wave, amplifying the disaster’s magnitude and devastation. Here, we show that the collapse of aging flood control infrastructures, compounded by inadequate risk assessment and emergency preparedness, dramatically escalated the disaster’s impact. Our findings underscore the urgent need for systematic dam safety evaluations, enhanced flood forecasting, and adaptive risk management strategies that address climate extremes and infrastructure vulnerabilities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-59261-9/MediaObjects/41467_2025_59261_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>