<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 02:19:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 调和追踪的大气水流以关闭全球淡水周期</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02289-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Reconciling tracked atmospheric water flows to close the global freshwater cycle&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Elena De Petrillo; Simon Felix Fahrländer; Marta Tuninetti; Lauren Seaby Andersen; Luca Monaco; Luca Ridolfi; Francesco Laio&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;大气水分流在水文循环中起着至关重要的作用，将蒸发源连接到降水量。尽管高分辨率跟踪模型提供了有价值的见解，但比较跟踪流与大气再分析数据的差异会出现差异。在这里，我们通过在国家和海洋边界内汇总的UTRACK数据集（2008  -  2017年间平均）应用于UTRACK数据集的迭代比例拟合（平均2008  -  2017年），将跟踪的大气流与重新分析数据调和。它纠正了降水量高达275％和蒸发225％的国家规模差异，平均将双侧流量调节约0.07％。所得的数据集可确保总跟踪的水分与水槽处的总降水量与每年源蒸发匹配。值得注意的是，此过程可以应用于任何跟踪模型输出和分析规模。和解的数据集增强了跨界大气水流的分析，表明总陆地降水量的45％（〜1.5举 10 &lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;年&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ）起源于土地蒸发（ &lt;sup&gt;9.8Å104&lt;/sup&gt; km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;年&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ）。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Atmospheric moisture flows play a vital role in the hydrological cycle, connecting evaporation sources to precipitation sinks. While high-resolution tracking models provide valuable insights, discrepancies arise comparing tracked flows to atmospheric reanalysis data. Here we reconcile tracked atmospheric flows with reanalysis data by means of the Iterative Proportional Fitting applied to the UTrack dataset (averaged over 2008–2017) aggregated within countries and ocean boundaries. It corrects country-scale discrepancies of up to 275% in precipitation and 225% in evaporation, adjusting bilateral flows by ~ 0.07 %, on average. The resulting dataset ensures that the total tracked moisture matches total precipitation at the sink and evaporation at the source annually. Remarkably, this procedure can be applied to any tracking model output and scale of analysis. The reconciled dataset enhances transboundary atmospheric water flows analysis, revealing that 45% of total terrestrial precipitation (~1.5 ⋅ 10&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;) originates from land evaporation (9.8 ⋅ 10&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02289-y/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2289_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>