<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 02:11:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 在解冻的季节，北锡高原的100 m分辨率表面土壤水分数据</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04831-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;100-m-resolution surface soil moisture data during the thawing season on the Qinghai‒Tibet Plateau&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zhibin Li; Lin Zhao; Lingxiao Wang; Guangyue Liu; Erji Du; Defu Zou; Guojie Hu; Zanpin Xing; Chong Wang; Shibo Liu; Minxuan Xiao; Luhui Yin; Yiwei Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;由于缺乏高空间分辨率的SM数据集，因此尚不清楚在Qinghai – Tibet Plateau（QTP）上表面土壤水分（SM）的空间分布的特征。为了改善这种情况，我们首先在QTP的区域中补充了659个SM数据集，其中包含2021  -  2022年稀疏监视站和集成已发布的SM数据集。基于Sentinel-1和2和测量的SM数据，我们为上升和下降轨道开发了SM检索算法。然后，在2017  -  2023年的QTP上的SAR信号可施加的区域中生成了100 m分辨率的SM空间数据。根据测量数据的验证，上升和降轨的检索结果的相关系数分别为0.72和0.69，两者的偏置达到0.07m³/m³和0.07m³/m³的偏差。这些SM数据集表现出明显的希望，可以提高我们对QTP不同环境的生态和水文的理解和分析。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The characteristics of the spatial distribution of surface soil moisture (SM) on the Qinghai‒Tibet Plateau (QTP) on a fine scale are unclear due to the lack of high-spatial-resolution SM datasets. To improve this situation, we first supplemented 659 SM datasets in areas on the QTP containing sparse monitoring stations from 2021–2022 and integrated published SM datasets. Based on Sentinel-1&amp;amp;2 and measured SM data, we developed an SM retrieval algorithm for the ascending and descending orbits. Then, 100-m-resolution SM spatial data were generated for the thawing season of 2017–2023 in the SAR signal-applicable area on the QTP. As validated by the measured data, the correlation coefficients of the retrieval results for the ascending and descending orbits were 0.72 and 0.69, respectively, and the bias reached 0.07 m³/m³ and an RMSE of 0.07 m³/m³ for both. These SM datasets exhibit notable promise for improving our understanding and analysis of the ecology and hydrology of different environments on the QTP.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04831-1/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4831_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>