<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 02:16:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 大数据显示了特质模式和地貌河流的速率</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-58427-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Big data show idiosyncratic patterns and rates of geomorphic river mobility&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Richard J. Boothroyd; Richard D. Williams; Trevor B. Hoey; Gary J. Brierley; Pamela L. M. Tolentino; Esmael L. Guardian; Juan C. M. O. Reyes; Cathrine J. Sabillo; Laura Quick; John E. G. Perez; Carlos P. C. David&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;大数据提供了前所未有的机会，可以测试有关地貌河流调整的模式和速度的长期理论。在这里，我们使用从Landsat Imagery（1988-2019）得出的位置概率来量化10个菲律宾集水区中600 km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;的动力学。对横向调节的分析揭示了地貌河流迁移率沿谷化模式的空间不均匀变化，相对稳定性的区域散布在相对不稳定的区域。移动性热点的大小，大小和集水区之间的位置各不相同。我们无法确定局部因素（主动通道宽度，山谷地板宽度和限制比）和移动性之间的单调关系。通道模式类型和调整速率之间没有关系。我们认为，卫星衍生的位置概率提供了一种空间连续的动态度量，可以帮助解开和上下文的地形河流调节形式和上下文形式和速率，从而有助于在动态景观中洞悉河流行为的特质。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Big data present unprecedented opportunities to test long-standing theories regarding patterns and rates of geomorphic river adjustments. Here, we use locational probabilities derived from Landsat imagery (1988-2019) to quantify the dynamics of 600 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; of riverbed in 10 Philippine catchments. Analysis of lateral adjustments reveals spatially non-uniform variability in along-valley patterns of geomorphic river mobility, with zones of relative stability interspersed with zones of relative instability. Hotspots of mobility vary in magnitude, size and location between catchments. We could not identify monotonic relationships between local factors (active channel width, valley floor width and confinement ratio) and mobility. No relation between the channel pattern type and rates of adjustment was evident. We contend that satellite-derived locational probabilities provide a spatially continuous dynamic metric that can help unravel and contextualise forms and rates of geomorphic river adjustment, thereby helping to derive insights into idiosyncrasies of river behaviour in dynamic landscapes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-58427-9/MediaObjects/41467_2025_58427_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>