<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:13:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 最近刚果盆地中部严重干旱与沃克环流减弱和大西洋变暖有关</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01225-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Recent significant drying in Central Congo Basin linked to weakened Walker circulation and warmer Atlantic&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Sly Wongchuig; Fabrice Papa; Ayan Santos Fleischmann; Juan Pablo Sierra; Julien Boucharel; Jhan Carlo Espinoza; Benjamin Kitambo; Rômulo Jucá Oliveira; Adrien Paris; Rodrigo Paiva; Pauline Casas; Raphael Tshimanga&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;刚果河流域 (CRB) 拥有地球上第二大热带森林，对水和碳循环具有全球意义。其人口和生态系统也强烈依赖于淡水的供应，而淡水的供应日益受到当前气候变化和森林砍伐的威胁。据报道，CRB 存在持续干旱状况，但其驱动因素和对该流域水文的影响仍然未知。在这里，我们分析了 42 年（1981 年至 2022 年）的大气和水文变化，以表明刚果中部的干燥趋势与大气水分辐合和降水减少有关，主要是在最多雨期间。这一趋势与沃克环流的减弱和中东部热带大西洋海面温度的升高有关，这影响了刚果中部的水汽汇聚，滞后约3个月。我们的研究结果强调需要采取综合的大气和水文方法来解决 CRB 的淡水和森林对气候变化的脆弱性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Congo River Basin (CRB), hosting the second-largest tropical forest on Earth, is of global significance for the water and carbon cycles. Its population and ecosystems are also strongly dependent on freshwater availability, which is increasingly threatened by current climate change and deforestation. Persistent drought conditions in CRB have been reported, but their drivers and impacts on the basin’s hydrology remain unknown. Here, we analyze 42 years (1981–2022) of atmospheric and hydrological variability to show that the drying trend in Central Congo is linked to reduced atmospheric moisture convergence and precipitation, primarily during the rainiest period. This trend correlates with a weakening of the Walker circulation and an increase in Sea Surface Temperature in the Central Eastern Tropical Atlantic Ocean which influences moisture convergence over the Central Congo with a ~3-month lag. Our findings emphasize the need for integrative atmospheric and hydrological approaches to address CRB’s freshwater and forest vulnerability to climate change.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01225-3/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1225_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | DAM-IN：印度大坝安全研究的综合大坝流域属性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05954-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;DAM-IN: Comprehensive Dam Catchment Attributes for Dam Safety Studies in India&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Mayank Tiwari; Saran Aadhar&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;印度次大陆在不同河流上拥有约5715座水坝，这些水坝对该国各个经济部门的增长发挥着关键作用。在本研究中，我们利用观测数据、再分析数据和遥感数据开发了印度次大陆 5715 座水坝的流域属性数据集。综合大坝数据集由六大属性组成，包括地形、气候、地质和地下水、土壤、土地利用和土地利用控制以及人类活动。利用 30 米 SRTM 数据，我们使用自动出水口重新定位算法描绘了每个水坝的流域，并估计了每个流域的各种地形属性。考虑到现有的全球和区域数据集，我们为每个大坝流域开发了地质、土壤和土地利用和土地利用控制属性。我们还包含了每个大坝流域的人类活动数据集，这有助于研究人类活动对大坝安全和水资源的影响。总体而言，综合大坝数据集由每个大坝的高质量流域属性组成，可用于进行各种科学研究、大坝安全分析以及对印度大坝的影响研究。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Indian subcontinent has around 5715 dams across different rivers, which play a pivotal role in the growth of various economic sectors in the country. In this study, we developed a dataset of catchment attributes for 5715 dams over the Indian subcontinent using observed, reanalysis, and remote sensing data. The comprehensive dam dataset consists of six major attributes, including topography, climate, geology and groundwater, soil, LULC, and human-induced activities. Using the 30-m SRTM data, we delineated the watershed for each dam using the automatic outlet relocation algorithm and estimated various topographic attributes for each catchment. We developed geological, soil, and LULC attributes for each dam catchment, considering existing global and regional datasets. We also included human-induced activities datasets for each dam catchment, which can be useful in studying the impact of human activities on dam safety and water resources. Overall, the comprehensive dam dataset consists of high-quality catchment attributes for each dam, which can be used to conduct various scientific studies, dam safety analyses, and impact studies on Indian dams.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05954-1/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5954_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>