<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 03:35:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Water | 将来预测中的大气干旱指数</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00416-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Atmospheric drought indices in future projections&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Sergio M. Vicente-Serrano; Fernando Domínguez-Castro; Santiago Beguería; Ahmed El Kenawy; Luis Gimeno-Sotelo; Magí Franquesa; Cesar Azorin-Molina; Miguel Andres-Martin; Amar Halifa-Marín&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;从这个角度来看，我们批判性地讨论了未来的干旱预测，重点是与干旱概念及其经常与干旱混淆有关的关键问题。我们解决了干旱指标和干旱指数之间的共同误解，以及对干旱指数所代表的误解。我们的分析强调了大气蒸发需求在塑造未来干旱严重程度的作用，以及其驱动因素，影响过程以及对全球变暖的反应，同时强调相关的观察和理论挑战。我们还阐明了地球系统模型（ESM）在评估未来干旱严重性时的不确定性和局限性。我们在准确地代表植物生理和水文过程中探讨了ESM的复杂性，这对于评估干旱严重程度至关重要。我们的讨论还深入研究了大气CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;浓度对这些过程和ESM中水动力学的细微影响，有助于阐明与大气干旱指数有关的概念问题。最后，我们主张对干旱指标进行平衡评估，强调考虑干旱预测中多种大气过程的重要性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In this Perspective we critically discuss future drought projections, focusing on key issues related to the concept of drought and its frequent confusion with aridity. We address the common misunderstanding between drought metrics and drought indices, as well as misconceptions about what drought indices represent. Our analysis emphasizes the role of atmospheric evaporative demand in shaping future drought severity, along with its drivers, impact processes, and responses to global warming, while highlighting related observational and theoretical challenges. We also shed light on the uncertainties and limitations of Earth system models (ESMs) in assessing future drought severity. We explore the complexities of ESMs in accurately representing plant physiological and hydrological processes, which are crucial for evaluating drought severity. Our discussion also delves into the nuanced effects of atmospheric CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; concentrations on these processes and on water dynamics within ESMs, helping to clarify conceptual issues related to atmospheric drought indices. Finally, we advocate for a balanced evaluation of drought metrics, emphasizing the importance of considering multiple atmospheric processes in drought projections.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00416-9/MediaObjects/44221_2025_416_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>