<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 02:06:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 前所未有的英国热浪统一的燃油水分驱动器造成了极端的温带野火风险</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02746-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Unprecedented UK heatwave harmonised drivers of fuel moisture creating extreme temperate wildfire risk&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Katy Ivison; Kerryn Little; Alice Orpin; Claire M. Belcher; Gareth D. Clay; Stefan H. Doerr; Thomas E. L. Smith; Roxane Andersen; Laura J. Graham; Nicholas Kettridge&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候变化导致主要热浪期间更加极端的火灾天气。在温带欧洲，灌木景观占据了燃烧的区域，在这些事件中，燃料的水分含量决定了构成的威胁。当前对温带燃料成分的水分含量的控制及其对未来极端热浪的反应尚不清楚。我们对整个英国的现场和死亡Heather（Calluna vulgaris）和有机土壤水分含量进行了3年的现场测量，其中包括2022年7月的Heatwave进行的密集抽样运动。在这里，我们表明，活燃料的燃料水分含量与物候变量显着相关，仅与天气变量相关，而有机富的地面燃料与景观变量更相关。但是，在创纪录的2022 Heatwave期间，跨不同燃料成分的燃油湿度控制有一致，仅天气就会驱动这些控制。这导致在所有燃料成分的当前季节性规范之外的同步极度干燥同时和地点。因此，可以预期未来强烈的夏季热浪会使传统上无火的易火力点火，传播和影响最严重的条件保持一致，从而产生潮湿的温带景观，易受极端野火事件的影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate change is resulting in more extreme fire weather during major heatwaves. Across temperate Europe, shrub landscapes dominate the area burned, with the moisture content of fuels during these events determining the threat posed. Current controls on the moisture content of temperate fuel constituents and their response to future extreme heatwaves are not known. We took field measurements of live and dead heather (Calluna vulgaris) and organic soil moisture content across the UK over 3 years, including an intensive sampling campaign during the July 2022 heatwave. Here, we show that the fuel moisture content of live fuel is associated significantly with phenological variables, dead fuel only with weather variables, whilst organic-rich ground fuels are more associated with landscape variables. However, during the record 2022 heatwave there was a harmonisation in fuel moisture controls across different fuel constituents, with those controls being driven by weather alone. This caused synchronised extreme dryness outside of current seasonal norms across all fuel constituents at the same time and place. Future intense summer heatwaves can therefore be expected to align the most severe conditions for fire ignition, spread and impact in traditionally non-fire prone regions, producing humid temperate landscapes susceptible to extreme wildfire events.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02746-8/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2746_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 在气候变化下，地表水稀缺性的跨界冲突</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-63568-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Transboundary conflict from surface water scarcity under climate change&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ruijie Jiang; Hui Lu; Deliang Chen; Kun Yang; Dabo Guan; Guangwei Huang; Fuqiang Tian&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;跨界河流盆地（TRB）面临缺水引起的冲突的风险，尤其是考虑到气候变化的供水需求不断上升和影响。尽管做出了广泛的努力和一些进展，但将水稀缺与TRB冲突联系起来的机制仍然不足以理解，并且确定有效的缓解和适应策略仍然是一个挑战。在这项研究中，我们介绍了一个框架，以根据水依赖性的概念来预测很容易受到水稀缺引起的冲突的框架，这是由每月的水稀缺性定义的。该框架成功地解释了超过80％的TRB，经历了2005  -  2014年间经历水稀缺引起的冲突。我们的预测表明，在不缓解和适应措施的情况下，将近40％的全球TRB可能会面临2041  -  2050年缺水驱动的潜在冲突，而在非洲，南部和中亚，中东，中东和北美的热点处的热点。但是，积极的措施，例如巴碱内合作可以将这一比例降低到不到10％。这项研究强调了增加投资和积极利益相关者参与的紧迫性，以促进巴辛内部合作并避免潜在的冲突。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Transboundary river basins (TRBs) are at risk of water scarcity-induced conflicts, especially given the rising water demand and impacts of climate change. Despite extensive efforts and some progress, the mechanisms linking water scarcity to conflicts in TRBs remain insufficiently understood, and identifying effective mitigation and adaptation strategies remains a challenge. In this study, we introduce a framework for predicting TRBs vulnerable to water scarcity-induced conflicts, based on the concept of water dependency, defined by monthly water scarcity. This framework successfully explains over 80% of the TRBs experiencing water scarcity-induced conflicts during 2005–2014. Our projections indicate that, without mitigation and adaptation measures, nearly 40% of global TRBs could face potential conflicts driven by water scarcity in 2041–2050, with hotspots in Africa, southern and central Asia, the Middle East, and North America. However, proactive measures such as intra-basin cooperation could reduce this proportion to less than 10%. This study underscores the urgency of increased investment and active stakeholder engagement to foster intra-basin cooperation and avert potential conflicts.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-63568-y/MediaObjects/41467_2025_63568_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>