<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 02:09:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 未来排放和灌溉导致的湿热应激加剧加剧</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-64375-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Compounding future escalation of emissions- and irrigation-induced increases in humid-heat stress&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yi Yao; Yusuke Satoh; Nicole van Maanen; Sabin Taranu; Jessica Keune; Steven J. De Hertog; Seppe Lampe; David M. Lawrence; William J. Sacks; Yoshihide Wada; Agnès Ducharne; Benjamin I. Cook; Sonia I. Seneviratne; Laibao Liu; Jonathan R. Buzan; Jonas Jägermeyr; Wim Thiery&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;灌溉已作为一种重要的历史气候强迫进行了研究，但没有研究考虑其范围和效率可能发生的变化来探索其未来的气候影响。在这里，我们通过根据共享社会经济路径 (SSP) 开发灌溉效率情景来解决这些问题，在社区地球系统模型中实施这些情景，并应用它们来生成 2015-2074 年期间的预测。我们预计，在SSP1-2.6下，年灌溉用水量会减少（从约2100 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ），但在SSP3-7.0下会增加（约2400 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ），同时会出现一些新的灌溉热点，特别是在非洲。灌溉预计会减少这两种情景下干热胁迫的发生，但无法扭转由于温室气体排放造成的变暖趋势（例如，在两种情景下，在强灌溉地区，从约90小时yr &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;增加到约600和1200小时yr -1 ）。此外，湿热极端事件频率大幅增加（热带地区在SSP3-7.0下增加≥1600小时yr &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ），灌溉进一步延长了暴露时间（例如，在南亚增加≥100小时yr &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ），从而增加了暴露社区患湿热相关疾病和死亡的风险。我们的研究结果强调了减少温室气体排放、限制灌溉扩张和提高灌溉效率的重要性，以保护水资源并减缓不断升级的干湿热胁迫。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Irrigation has been investigated as an important historical climate forcing, but there is no study exploring its future climatic impacts considering possible changes in both extent and efficiency. Here, we address these issues via developing irrigation efficiency scenarios in line with the Shared Socioeconomic Pathways (SSPs), implementing these in the Community Earth System Model, and applying them to generate projections over the period 2015–2074. We project that annual irrigation water withdrawal decreases under SSP1-2.6 (from  ~2100 to  ~1700 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;) but increases under SSP3-7.0 (to  ~2400 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;), with some new irrigation hot spots emerging, especially in Africa. Irrigation is projected to reduce the occurrence of dry-heat stress under both scenarios, but cannot reverse the warming trend due to greenhouse gas emission (e.g., increasing from  ~90 to around 600 and 1200 hours yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; in intensely irrigated areas, under two scenarios). Moreover, moist-heat extreme event frequency increases more substantially (by ≥1600 hours yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; under SSP3-7.0 in tropical regions), and irrigation further amplifies the hours of exposure (for example, by ≥100 hours yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; in South Asia), thereby raising the risk of moist-heat-related illnesses and mortality for exposed communities. Our results underscore the importance of reducing greenhouse gas emissions, limiting irrigation expansion and improving irrigation efficiency to preserve water resources and decelerate escalating exposure to dry- and moist-heat stress.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-64375-1/MediaObjects/41467_2025_64375_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>