<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 02:17:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 在悬浮沉积物上作用的阻力增加了微生物定植</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01679-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Drag acting on suspended sediment increased by microbial colonization&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Naiyu Zhang; Haochen Li; Fan Xu; Charlotte E. L. Thompson; Ian H. Townend; Qing He&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;微生物群落和沉积物传输形状之间的动态相互作用会影响大陆景观，并影响地球表面上的颗粒物通量。微生物定植将单个沉积物晶粒转化为具有复杂和多样化的形态和复杂沉积物传输的聚集体。但是，当前的模型通常简化了这种形态的复杂性，假设聚集体经历流体阻力等于光滑球或理想化的形状。在这里，我们应用了一种X射线微型计算层析成像方法，结合了计算流体动力学模拟，以高空间分辨率分析聚集体形态，并确定与阻力的关系。我们发现微生物定殖在阻力上的主要控制量不是骨料大小或总体形状，而是改变了细尺度的聚集形态，而与平滑表面相比，较高的骨料形态增加了1-3的阻力。我们提出了一种以形态校正的阻力法，该法律解释了这种复杂性，并调解了各种聚集体的阻力差异。我们的发现表明，从关注总体量表变化（尺寸或总形状）转变为高尺度的形态可以使运输预测的准确性更高，并提高对河流，沿海和海洋系统中微生物定植的聚集体的理解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The dynamic interplay between microbial communities and sediment transport shapes continental landscapes and influences particulate matter fluxes across the Earth’s surface. Microbial colonization transforms individual sediment grains into aggregates with intricate and varied morphologies, complicating sediment transport. However, current models often simplify this morphological complexity, assuming that aggregates experience fluid drag equal to that of smooth spheres or idealized shapes. Here we apply an X-ray micro-computed tomography method combined with computational fluid dynamics simulations to analyse aggregate morphology at high spatial resolution and determine the relationship with drag. Instead of aggregate size or gross shape being the primary controls on drag, we find that microbial colonization alters the fine-scale aggregate morphology and increases drag by factors of 1–3 compared with smooth surfaces. We propose a morphology-corrected drag law that accounts for this complexity, reconciling the differences in drag across diverse aggregates. Our findings suggest that a shift from focusing on gross scale variabilities (size or gross shape) to fine-scale morphologies could enable greater accuracy in transport predictions, and improve understanding of microbially colonized aggregates in fluvial, coastal and oceanic systems.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01679-3/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1679_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 碳酸盐风化可增强全球河流中氮的同化吸收</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01680-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Carbonate weathering enhances nitrogen assimilatory uptake in rivers globally&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hongkai Qi; Yi Liu; Haoran Wang; Xingxing Kuang; Aditya Nugraha Putra; Jiu Jimmy Jiao; Jianping Gan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;基岩组成，尤其是碳酸盐的比例，可以影响溶解的无机碳浓度以及河流的碳酸盐化学，但其对河流中氮循环的影响通常被忽略。在这里，我们介绍了中国珍珠河盆地河流的地球化学组成测量结果，表明溶解的有机氮（DON）与溶解的无机氮正相吻合，并随后遵循潮湿季节的碳酸酯区域太阳辐射的变化，但在潮湿的季节中，但不是在非碳酸盐含量的区域。原位孵育表明，在高溶解的无机碳，高温和太阳辐射的区域中，有机氮的产生得到了增强。由于低温对氮同化的限制，在干旱季节的DON分区并不明显。我们还报告了印度尼西亚马朗以碳酸盐为主和非碳酸盐为主的区域的类似DON对比。此外，从对全球发布的数据的分析中，我们发现，纳入碳限制的修改后的Michaelis -Menten模型为DON全球的全球纬度分布提供了更好的拟合。因此，我们提出，有机氮产生的碳酸盐风化会普遍存在。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Bedrock composition, in particular the proportion of carbonate, can influence the dissolved inorganic carbon concentration and also the carbonate chemistry of rivers, but its effects on the nitrogen cycle in rivers are usually overlooked. Here we present geochemical composition measurements of rivers across the Pearl River Basin in China that show that dissolved organic nitrogen (DON) is positively correlated with dissolved inorganic nitrogen and follows the variation in solar radiation in the carbonate-dominated region during the wet season, but not in the non-carbonate-dominated region. In situ incubations show that organic nitrogen production is strengthened in the regions with high dissolved inorganic carbon and high temperature and solar radiation. DON zonation in the dry season is not obvious owing to the limitation of low temperature on nitrogen assimilation. We also report a similar DON contrast in carbonate-dominated and non-carbonate-dominated regions in Malang in Indonesia. Furthermore, from an analysis of global published data, we find that a modified Michaelis–Menten model incorporating carbon limitation provides a much better fit to the global latitudinal distribution of DON globally. Hence, we propose that carbonate weathering enhancement of organic nitrogen production occurs ubiquitously.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01680-w/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1680_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>