<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 02:06:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Reviews Earth &amp; Environment | 人为对黄河盆地的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43017-025-00718-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Anthropogenic impacts on the Yellow River Basin&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Shuai Wang 
            (王帅); Shuang Song 
            (宋爽); Haoyu Zhang 
            (张皓宇); Lu Yu 
            (于璐); Chentai Jiao 
            (焦晨泰); Changjia Li 
            (李长嘉); Xutong Wu 
            (武旭同); Wenwu Zhao 
            (赵文武); Jim Best; Patrick Roberts; Bojie Fu 
            (傅伯杰)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;黄河盆地支持2亿人口，并占中国可耕地的15％。气候变化和人类活动加剧了该地区的缺水。在这篇综述中，我们讨论了自1950年代以来对黄河的水文周期和沉积物动力学的影响。黄河是世界上最大的沉积物负荷之一，1958年在2.1 gt yr &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;达到顶峰。这种高泥沙负载升高了洪水危险。因此，自1980年代以来，实施了水库，保护和植被项目，将沉积物运输降低了90％。但是，这些努力也影响了黄河盆地的水文学，导致蒸散通量的增加（1.79 mm yr &lt;sup&gt;-2，1980-2020&lt;/sup&gt; ）和减少的径流。此外，自1980年代以来，人类用水增长了15.8％。土壤储水的减少和垂直水周期的强化预示了潜在的资源危机，并有可能导致不可逆的生态系统降解。由于反馈循环以及人类活动与水文变化之间的相互作用，预测水管理政策和工程项目的结果至关重要，但非常复杂。解决这些挑战，这些挑战也面临着其他干旱地区河流，将需要动态监测水存储，并改善对人类水性相互作用的理解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Yellow River Basin supports a population of 200 million people and contains 15% of arable land in China. Water scarcity in the region is being exacerbated by climate change and human activities. In this Review, we discuss anthropogenic impacts on the hydrological cycle and sediment dynamics of the Yellow River since the 1950s. The Yellow River had one of the largest sediment loads in the world, peaking at 2.1 Gt yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; in 1958. Such high sediment loads elevated flood risk; therefore, reservoirs, conservation and revegetation projects were implemented, reducing sediment transport by 90% since the 1980s. However, these efforts also impacted the hydrology of the Yellow River Basin, leading to an increase in evapotranspiration fluxes (1.79 mm yr&lt;sup&gt;−2&lt;/sup&gt;, 1980–2020) and reduced runoff. In addition, human water use has increased by 15.8% since the 1980s. The resulting reductions in soil water storage and intensification of the vertical water cycle foreshadow potential resource crises and will potentially lead to irreversible ecosystem degradation. Predicting the outcomes of water management policies and engineering projects is essential but highly complex owing to feedback loops and interactions between human activities and hydrological changes. Addressing these challenges, which are also faced by other arid-region rivers, will require dynamic monitoring of water storage and improved understanding of human–hydrological interactions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43017-025-00718-2/MediaObjects/43017_2025_718_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>