<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 02:07:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | UAS水文测定法：非接触式水位，测深和流速 - RӧNneRiver Dataset</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04611-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;UAS hydrometry: contactless river water level, bathymetry, and flow velocity – the Rӧnne river dataset&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zhen Zhou; Laura Riis-Klinkvort; Emilie Ahrnkiel Jørgensen; Daniel Haugård Olesen; Alexander Rietz Vesterhauge; Monica Coppo Frías; Makar Lavish; Sune Nielsen; David Gustafsson; Daniel Wennerberg; Jenny Axén; Viktor Fagerstrӧm; Peter Bauer-Gottwein&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;对河流的高分辨率监测变得很重要，因为由于气候变化，预计将来会发生更频繁和严重的洪水和干旱事件。一些关键的水文变量（水面高程，测深量和水面速度）可以在高空间分辨率和使用无接触式的空中空中系统（UAS）的情况下以无接触式和非侵入性的方式获取。 This paper presents a large publicly available UAS hydrometric dataset surveyed within a 10 km stretch of Rönne Å in Sweden from 28 August to 1 September 2023. The data were acquired using UAS radar altimetry for water surface elevation mapping, UAS water penetrating radar and UAS sonar for bathymetric mapping, and UAS Doppler radar for surface velocity monitoring.所有数据均分为三个处理级别：原始数据（级别1），处理点数据（级别2）以及引用参考河中心线/参考横截面线（第3级）的点数据。现场地面真相和传统UAS湿度测量负载数据包括用于比较和验证。良好的一致性表明，新的UAS水文有效载荷提供令人满意的数据集。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;High-resolution monitoring of rivers becomes important because more frequent and severe flooding and drought events are expected in the future, caused by climate change. Some key hydrometric variables (water surface elevation, bathymetry, and water surface velocity) can be acquired at high spatial resolution and in a contactless and noninvasive way using Unoccupied Aerial Systems (UAS). This paper presents a large publicly available UAS hydrometric dataset surveyed within a 10 km stretch of Rönne Å in Sweden from 28 August to 1 September 2023. The data were acquired using UAS radar altimetry for water surface elevation mapping, UAS water penetrating radar and UAS sonar for bathymetric mapping, and UAS Doppler radar for surface velocity monitoring. All data are divided into three processing levels: the raw data (Level 1), processed point data (Level 2), and point data referenced to a reference river centerline/reference cross section line (Level 3). In-situ ground truth and legacy UAS hydrometry payload data are included for comparison and validation. Good consistency indicates that the new UAS hydrometry payloads provide satisfactory datasets.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-90146-5/MediaObjects/41598_2025_90146_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 全球未来的干旱层基于缩小的CMIP6模型和多种社会经济途径</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04612-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Global Future Drought Layers Based on Downscaled CMIP6 Models and Multiple Socioeconomic Pathways&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Diogo S. A. Araujo; Brian J. Enquist; Amy E. Frazier; Cory Merow; Patrick R. Roehrdanz; Gabriel M. Moulatlet; Alex Zvoleff; Lei Song; Brian Maitner; Efthymios I. Nikolopoulos&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;干旱是一种日益关注的自然危害，因为预计世界许多地区的频率和严重程度会增加。对干旱及其未来特征的识别对于建立对潜在干旱变化轨迹的地理和幅度的理解至关重要，这反过来又是管理多个部门和学科的干旱韧性的关键信息。除此之外，我们开发了一个数据集，其中包括1980  -  2100年期间的全球历史和预计未来的干旱指数，基于多个共享社会经济途径（SSP）的缩写的CMIP6模型。该数据集由两个指数组成：标准化降水指数（SPI）和标准降水蒸发指数（SPEI），用于23个缩小的全球气候模型（GCMS）（0.25度分辨率）（1980- 2014年），包括（1980-2014）和未来的投影（2015-2100）（2015-2100）（2015-2100）（2015-2100）。 SSP3-7.0和SSP5-8.5。计算出3个，6个月和12个月的累积时间标准的干旱指数，并以每月时间分辨率以常规的纬度长度格式作为网格空间数据集使用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Droughts are a natural hazard of growing concern as they are projected to increase in frequency and severity for many regions of the world. The identification of droughts and their future characteristics is essential to building an understanding of the geography and magnitude of potential drought change trajectories, which in turn is critical information to manage drought resilience across multiple sectors and disciplines. Adding to this effort, we developed a dataset of global historical and projected future drought indices over the 1980–2100 period based on downscaled CMIP6 models across multiple shared socioeconomic pathways (SSP). The dataset is composed of two indices: the Standardized Precipitation Index (SPI) and Standardized Precipitation Evapotranspiration Index (SPEI) for 23 downscaled global climate models (GCMs) (0.25-degree resolution), including historical (1980–2014) and future projections (2015–2100) under four climate scenarios: SSP1-2.6, SSP2-4.5, SSP3-7.0, and SSP5-8.5. The drought indices were calculated for 3-, 6- and 12-month accumulation timescales and are available as gridded spatial datasets in a regular latitude-longitude format at monthly time resolution.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-90363-y/MediaObjects/41598_2025_90363_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature | 回复：大西洋干旱不会威胁亚洲水塔</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08358-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Reply to: Atlantic oceanic droughts do not threaten Asian water tower&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Qiang Zhang; Zexi Shen; Yadu Pokhrel; Daniel Farinotti; Vijay P. Singh; Chong-Yu Xu; Wenhuan Wu; Gang Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文没有摘要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This article has no abstract.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04612-w/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4612_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 一个用于监测欧洲农业干旱的数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-024-04199-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A dataset for monitoring agricultural drought in Europe&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Guido Fioravanti; Andrea Toreti; Carmelo Cammalleri; Carolina Arias Muñoz; Davide Bavera; Alfred De Jager; Arthur Hrast Essenfelder; Chiara Di Ciollo; Dario Masante; Diego Magni; Juan Acosta Navarro; Marco Mazzesch; Willem Maetens&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文介绍了合并的干旱指标数据集，这是欧洲欧洲干旱天文台生成的栅格地图集合，用于监测欧洲的农业干旱。在计算上，CDI涉及三个指标：标准化降水指数，土壤水分异常和光合有效辐射异常的比例。这些用作物和雪面剂补充。 CDI数据集的空间分辨率为1/24个十进制度（约5 km），时间分辨率为10天，从2012年开始就可以使用。随着干旱影响在时空上的变化，CDI提供了一种有效的工具，可以评估农业干旱及其空间范围的不同阶段。此外，CDI地图为那些私人和公共参与者（水资源机构，农民，土地管理者等）提供了相关信息，既准备干旱，又计划减轻干旱影响。用户可以从哥白尼欧洲干旱天文台网站门户访问和下载数据集，在线MapViewer和可单击的地图可促进其交互式探索。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This paper introduces the Combined Drought Indicator dataset, a collection of raster maps generated by the Copernicus European Drought Observatory for monitoring agricultural drought in Europe. Computationally, the CDI involves three indicators: the Standardized Precipitation Index, the Soil Moisture Anomaly and the Fraction of the Photosyntetically Active Radiation anomaly. These are complemented by the use of crop and snow masks. The CDI dataset has a spatial resolution of 1/24 decimal degrees (∼5 km), a temporal resolution of 10 days and is available from 2012 onward. As drought effects are variegated both in space and time, the CDI provides an effective instrument for assessing the different stages of propagation of agricultural drought and their spatial extent. Furthermore, the CDI maps provide relevant information for those private and public actors (water resource agencies, farmers, land managers and so on) involved both in drought preparedness and planning to mitigate drought impacts. Users can access and download the dataset from the Copernicus European Drought Observatory web portal, where an online mapviewer and clickable maps facilitate its interactive exploration.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-024-08358-0/MediaObjects/41586_2024_8358_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 瀑布通过使溶解的甲烷绕过微生物氧化来增强区域甲烷排放</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02060-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Waterfalls enhance regional methane emissions by enabling dissolved methane to bypass microbial oxidation&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Rebecca L. Rust; Annastasia Frizzell; John D. Kessler&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河水是大气甲烷的重要来源，其局部排放随河流和湍流而增加。但是，当在区域上进行整合时，当不存在其他损失机制时，驱动的局部变化不影响释放到大气的溶解甲烷量。在这里，我们检验了以下假设：如果微生物甲烷氧化在河水中显着，瀑布会增强局部和区域大气的甲烷排放。在纽约西部的河水中测量了净大气排放和净氧甲烷氧化的速率，发现甲烷氧化会减少湍流时会减少大气排放。然而，在瀑布下，溶解的甲烷过饱和的88±1％被释放到大气中，净甲烷排放率基本上超过了氧化（0.1-16.2×10 &lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; nm d &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ，用于瀑布排放； 10–39 nm d &lt;sup&gt;-1的氧化d -1&lt;/sup&gt;用于氧化），并最终增强了氧化的氧化氧化氧化物的氧化氧化量。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;River waters are significant sources of atmospheric methane whose local emissions increase with river slope and turbulence. However, when integrated regionally, the amount of dissolved methane released to the atmosphere is uninfluenced by local changes in turbulence when no additional loss mechanisms are present. Here we tested the hypothesis that waterfalls enhance both local and regional atmospheric methane emissions if microbial methane oxidation is significant in river waters. Rates of net atmospheric emission and net aerobic methane oxidation were measured in river waters containing waterfalls across western New York revealing that methane oxidation can diminish atmospheric emissions when turbulence is less. However, at waterfalls, 88 ± 1% of the dissolved methane supersaturation was released to the atmosphere, increasing net methane emission rates substantially beyond oxidation (0.1–16.2 × 10&lt;sup&gt;6 &lt;/sup&gt;nM d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; for waterfall emission; 10–39 nM d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; for oxidation), and ultimately enhancing regional methane emissions by enabling dissolved methane to bypass an oxidative sink.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-90490-6/MediaObjects/41598_2025_90490_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 150年的河水质量记录显示磷负荷减少，但没有藻类生长潜力</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-024-01978-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A 150-year river water quality record shows reductions in phosphorus loads but not in algal growth potential&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Helen P. Jarvie; Fred Worrall; Tim P. Burt; Nicholas J. K. Howden&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在全球范围内，促进和有害藻华的富营养和增殖是造成水质损害的主要原因。在这里，我们分析了英国泰晤士河（包括生物氧需求，氯化物，磷和二氧化硅）的世界最长的连续（150年）河水质量数据集，以探索城市化，废水排放和农业强化的影响。在过去的40年中，废水处理和农业管理的改善已降低了约80％的磷载荷。但是，由于营养浓度保持在极限水平以上，因此这不足以减少河流藻类的开花。在过去的50  -  60年中，水温的升高增加了有利于硅藻开花的水温的数量，三月 -  4月和7月8月的蓝细菌生长。这些结果强调了在温暖的气候下富营养化管理的挑战，以及战略需要加倍努力，以进一步减少营养排放以控制滋扰和日益有害的藻华。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Eutrophication and proliferation of nuisance and harmful algal blooms are a major cause of water-quality impairment globally. Here, we analyze the world’s longest continuous (150-year) river water-quality dataset for the River Thames, U.K. (including biological oxygen demand, chloride, phosphorus and silica), to explore the impacts of urbanization, wastewater discharges and agricultural intensification. Over the last 40 years, improvements in wastewater treatment and agricultural management have reduced phosphorus loads by ~80%. However, this has been insufficient to curtail river algal blooms because nutrient concentrations remain above limiting levels. Over the last 50–60 years, rising water temperatures have increased the number of days with water temperatures favourable for diatom blooms in March-April and for cyanobacterial growth in July-August. These results highlight the challenges of eutrophication management in a warming climate and a strategic need to redouble efforts in further reducing nutrient emissions to control nuisance and increasingly harmful algal blooms.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02060-3/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2060_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 印度的基于车站的0.1度每日网格集合降水数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04474-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A station-based 0.1-degree daily gridded ensemble precipitation dataset for India&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Anagha Peringiyil; Manabendra Saharia; Sreejith O. P.; Andrew W. Wood; Mrutyunjay Mohapatra; Bharti Sabde; Aradhana Kumari; Bhushan Phadkar; Sabeerali C. T.; Rohini P.; Hosalikar K. S.; M. Rajeevan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;网格降水产物本质上是不确定的，主要是确定性的，这限制了其在数据同化系统和水文建模中的适用性。在印度等发展中国家，观察网络稀疏且不均匀，地形很复杂，并且氢气学极端频繁。目前的0.25°官方观察到的印度气象部（IMD）的降水数据集是确定性的，并且基于Shephard的插值技术。为了应对这些挑战，我们开发了印度降水集合数据集（IPED），利用印度各地最大的降水量表网络网络，并使用当地加权的空间回归方法。 IPED是每日30人的集合沉淀产品，分辨率为0.1°，分辨率为0.25°（1991– 2020），占高度，斜率和方面的地形变化。对于包括季风期间极端99 &lt;sup&gt;％&lt;/sup&gt;降水的所有阈值，开发的集合产品均表现出更高的歧视和可靠性。这是印度上第一个基于观察的集合降水产品，预计将具有广泛的水文学应用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Gridded precipitation products are inherently uncertain and predominantly deterministic, which limits their applicability in data assimilation systems and hydrologic modeling. This limitation is significant in developing countries such as India, where the observation network is sparse and non-uniform, topography is complex, and hydrometeorological extremes are frequent. The current official 0.25° observed precipitation dataset of the Indian Meteorological Department (IMD) is deterministic and based on Shephard’s interpolation technique. To address these challenges, we have developed the Indian Precipitation Ensemble Dataset (IPED) leveraging the largest network of precipitation gauge stations across India and using a locally weighted spatial regression approach. IPED is a daily 30-member ensemble precipitation product available at 0.1° and 0.25° resolution (1991–2020), accounting for topographical variation in elevation, slope, and aspect. For all thresholds, including the extreme 99&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile precipitation during monsoon, the developed ensemble product exhibits higher discrimination and reliability. This is the first observation-based ensemble precipitation product over India and is expected to have widespread hydrometeorological applications.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-91011-1/MediaObjects/41598_2025_91011_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 十年（2012-2021）的精细分辨率（每小时1公里）降水数据集越过东南藏族高原</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04654-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A ten-year (2012–2021) fine-resolution (1 km, hourly) precipitation dataset over southeastern Tibetan Plateau&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Dayang Li; Ye Shen; Xianyi Ye; Xiaohua Fu; Yang Yang; Tinghai Ou; Deliang Chen; Fuqiang Tian; Long Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;藏族高原（TP）上强烈的下天降水会触发一系列自然灾害（山洪，碎屑流等），从而造成重大的环境影响。 TP的当前降水产物通常缺乏足够的空间或时间分辨率，阻碍了与降水有关的危害的准确表征和缓解。在这里，我们根据天气研究和预测（WRF）模型在TP上进行了10年（2012-2021，6月至9月）的对流模型模型。我们采用了四个单向嵌套域，最内向的域在东南TP上提供了1公里的小时分辨率。使用光谱纽约方案增强了模型性能。将我们的模拟降水数据与东南TP上的原地雨量计观测值和最先进的降水产物（即，HAR V2，ERA5-LAND和IMERG）进行了比较。与其他三种产品相比，我们的沉淀数据集在平均绝对误差，均方根误差和偏置方面表现出较高的精度。它有效地捕获了昼夜降水循环的关键特征以及降水对东南TP上复杂地形的非单调依赖性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Intense sub-daily precipitation on the Tibetan Plateau (TP) can trigger a cascade of natural hazards (flash floods, debris flows, etc.), causing significant environmental impacts. Current precipitation products for the TP often lack sufficient spatial or temporal resolution, hindering accurate characterization and mitigation of precipitation-related hazards. Here, we carry out 10-year (2012–2021, June to September) convection-permitting model simulations based on the Weather Research and Forecasting (WRF) model over the TP. We adopt four one-way nested domains, with the innermost domain providing a 1-km, hourly resolution over the southeastern TP. Model performance is enhanced using a spectral nudging scheme. Our simulated precipitation data are compared against in-situ rain gauge observations and state-of-the-art gridded precipitation products (i.e., HAR v2, ERA5-Land, and IMERG) over the  southeastern TP. Our precipitation dataset demonstrates superior accuracy in mean absolute error, root mean square error, and bias, compared to the other three products. It effectively captures the key feature of the diurnal precipitation cycle and the non-monotonic dependence of precipitation on complex topography over the southeastern TP.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44304-025-00076-5/MediaObjects/44304_2025_76_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature | 流量随着降雪的下降而变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08523-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Streamflow shifts with declining snowfall&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Wouter R. Berghuijs; Kate Hale&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文没有摘要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This article has no abstract.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-024-80100-2/MediaObjects/41598_2024_80100_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature | 回复：流降雪随着降雪而下降</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08524-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Reply to: Streamflow shifts with declining snowfall&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Juntai Han; Ziwei Liu; Yuting Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文没有摘要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This article has no abstract.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-024-08523-5/MediaObjects/41586_2024_8523_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>