<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 02:19:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 加拿大西部支持西部 - 美国互连电力系统研究的每月水电生成数据</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05098-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Monthly hydropower generation data for Western Canada to support Western-US interconnect power system studies&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Youngjun Son; Cameron Bracken; Daniel Broman; Nathalie Voisin&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;加拿大西部的水力发电发电显着促进了北美西部的互连的电网操作，其中一些出口到美国（美国）。但是，缺乏公开可用的水电生成数据集为未来的市场预测和资源充足性评估带来了挑战。我们提出了一个基于模拟的每月电力系统模型的水力发电生成数据集，可在1981年至2019年间为不列颠哥伦比亚省和艾伯塔省提供110个设施。这些每月的水电生成估计是从径流和储层流量的集成水文模型模拟流量的基于水力流入式构造的缩放量基于Hydropower Wlidepower Watlic witchers的信息。为了解决缺乏类似的水电记录，我们使用可用的观察值或估计值进行了逐步评估，用于模拟径流，调节流量和水电生成。提出的水力发电数据集旨在增强加拿大西部水力发电资源的代表，从而为美国和加拿大的西部互连提供支持电网系统研究。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hydroelectric power generation in Western Canada significantly contributes to power grid operations of the North American Western Interconnection through substantial generation, some of which is exported to the United States (U.S.). However, the lack of publicly available hydropower generation datasets poses challenges for future market projections and resource adequacy evaluations. We present a simulation-based monthly power system model-ready hydropower generation dataset for 110 facilities in British Columbia and Alberta from 1981 to 2019. These monthly hydropower generation estimates are developed from integrated hydrologic model simulations of runoff and reservoir-operated streamflow, followed by scaling that considers diversion inflow constraints based on hydropower water license information. To address the lack of comparable hydropower generation records, we conduct step-by-step evaluations for simulated runoff, regulated streamflow, and hydropower generation using available observations or estimates. The presented hydropower dataset aims to enhance the representation of hydropower resources in Western Canada, supporting power grid system studies for the Western Interconnection of the U.S. and Canada.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05098-2/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5098_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | Godeeep-Hydro：美国的历史和投影电力系统准备的水电数据</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05097-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;GODEEEP-hydro: Historical and projected power system ready hydropower data for the United States&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Cameron Bracken; Youngjun Son; Daniel Broman; Nathalie Voisin&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水力发电是美国的关键电力资源，除了低成本发电外，还提供了有价值的辅助电网服务，并支持不可匹配的可依赖天气的资源（例如，风和太阳能）的整合。尽管它具有对电网的价值，但很少有可用的全面数据集研究气候，天气驱动的能源干旱以及其他天气驱动的一代的历史和未来影响。在本文中，我们提出了一个水力发电生成数据集，该数据集涵盖了连续美国的1,452台水力发电植物。数据集包含历史（1982- 2019年）和未来（2020-2099）时期的每月和每周水力发电生成估算值，其中包括4种未来的气候风光。此外，该数据集提供每周和每月的约束，例如最小和最大功率，这些功率在用于研究网格可靠性，传输计划和容量扩展的电力系统模型中特别有用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hydropower is a critical electricity resource in the United States which, in addition to low-cost electricity generation, provides valuable ancillary grid services, and supports the integration of nondispatchable weather-dependent resources (e.g., wind and solar). Despite its value to the grid, there are very few comprehensive datasets available from which to study both historical and future impacts of climate, weather driven energy droughts, and integration of other weather driven generation. In this paper, we present a hydropower generation dataset covering 1,452 hydroelectric plants in the contiguous U.S. The dataset contains monthly and weekly hydropower generation estimates for both historical (1982–2019) and future (2020–2099) periods which includes 4 future climate scenarios. In addition, this dataset provides weekly and monthly constraints such as minimum and maximum power which are particularly useful in power system models which are used to study grid reliability, transmission planning and capacity expansion.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05097-3/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5097_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature | 季节性在塑造湖面表面扩展动态中的全球主导地位</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09046-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Global dominance of seasonality in shaping lake-surface-extent dynamics&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Luoqi Li; Di Long; Yiming Wang; R. Iestyn Woolway&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;湖泊对于生态系统&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; ，温室气体排放&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;和水资源&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;至关重要，但是由于卫星观测的局限性&lt;sup&gt;4,5&lt;/sup&gt; ，它们的表面扩展动态，尤其是季节性，在大陆上对全球尺度的了解仍然很差。尽管以前的研究集中在长期变化&lt;sup&gt;6,7,8&lt;/sup&gt;上，但单源卫星数据中的空间分辨率和时间分辨率之间的权衡，对季节性的全面评估受到限制。在这里，我们表明季节性是全球湖面延伸的主要驱动力。通过利用基于MODI和Landsat的数据集的深度学习时空融合，再加上高性能计算，我们每月达到140万个湖泊（2001–2023）。当针对全球地表水数据集&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;验证时，我们的方法分别产生了盆地级中位用户和生产商的准确性93％和96％。以季节性为主的湖泊占全球湖区的66％，约占湖泊总数的60％，全球90％以上的人口居住在这样的湖泊盛行的地区。在季节性引起的极端事件中，影响可以超过23年的长期变化和常规季节性变化的综合幅度，使42％的收缩湖泊的收缩增加了一倍，并充分抵消了45％的生长湖泊的扩张。这些结果发现了先前隐藏的季节性动力学，这些动力学对于理解对环境变化的水圈反应至关重要&lt;sup&gt;。9&lt;/sup&gt; ，保护湖泊系统&lt;sup&gt;10,11,12&lt;/sup&gt;并改善全球气候模型&lt;sup&gt;13,14&lt;/sup&gt; 。我们的发现强调了将季节性纳入未来研究的重要性，并表明在多源遥控数据融合中的进步为前进的途径提供了有希望的途径。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lakes are crucial for ecosystems&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, greenhouse gas emissions&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; and water resources&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;, yet their surface-extent dynamics, particularly seasonality, remain poorly understood at continental to global scales owing to limitations in satellite observations&lt;sup&gt;4,5&lt;/sup&gt;. Although previous studies have focused on long-term changes&lt;sup&gt;6,7,8&lt;/sup&gt;, comprehensive assessments of seasonality have been constrained by trade-offs between spatial resolution and temporal resolution in single-source satellite data. Here we show that seasonality is the dominant driver of lake-surface-extent variations globally. By leveraging a deep-learning-based spatiotemporal fusion of MODIS and Landsat-based datasets, combined with high-performance computing, we achieved monthly mapping of 1.4 million lakes (2001–2023). Our approach yielded basin-level median user’s and producer’s accuracies of 93% and 96%, respectively, when validated against the Global Surface Water dataset&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;. Seasonality-dominated lakes constitute 66% of the global lake area and approximately 60% of total lake counts, with over 90% of the world’s population residing in regions where such lakes prevail. During seasonality-induced extreme events, the impacts can exceed the combined magnitude of 23-year long-term changes and regular seasonal variations, doubling the contraction of 42% of shrinking lakes and fully offsetting the expansion of 45% of growing lakes. These results uncover previously hidden seasonal dynamics that are crucial for understanding hydrospheric responses to environmental changes&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;, protecting lacustrine systems&lt;sup&gt;10,11,12&lt;/sup&gt; and improving global climate models&lt;sup&gt;13,14&lt;/sup&gt;. Our findings underscore the importance of incorporating seasonality into future research and suggest that advancements in the fusion of multisource remote-sensing data offer a promising path forward.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-025-09046-3/MediaObjects/41586_2025_9046_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>