<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 02:21:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 罗宾：国际水文气候变化检测盆地的参考天文台</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04907-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;ROBIN: Reference observatory of basins for international hydrological climate change detection&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; S. Turner; J. Hannaford; L. J. Barker; G. Suman; A. Killeen; R. Armitage; W. Chan; H. Davies; A. Griffin; A. Kumar; H. Dixon; M. T. D. Albuquerque; N. Almeida Ribeiro; C. Alvarez-Garreton; E. Amoussou; B. Arheimer; Y. Asano; T. Berezowski; A. Bodian; H. Boutaghane; R. Capell; H. Dakhaoui; J. Daňhelka; H. X. Do; C. Ekkawatpanit; E. M. El Khalki; A. K. Fleig; R. Fonseca; J. D. Giraldo-Osorio; A. B. T. Goula; M. Hanel; S. Horton; C. Kan; D. G. Kingston; G. Laaha; R. Laugesen; W. Lopes; S. Mager; M. Rachdane; Y. Markonis; L. Medeiro; G. Midgley; C. Murphy; P. O’Connor; A. I. Pedersen; H. T. Pham; M. Piniewski; B. Renard; M. E. Saidi; P. Schmocker-Fackel; K. Stahl; M. Thyer; M. Toucher; Y. Tramblay; J. Uusikivi; N. Venegas-Cordero; S. Visessri; A. Watson; S. Westra; P. H. Whitfield&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;人类引起的变暖正在改变水周期。适应构成的威胁需要了解对气候变异性的水文反应。尽管可以对这些进行计算建模，但观察到的流量数据对于约束模型以及理解和量化水周期中新兴趋势至关重要。迄今为止，在全球范围内对此类趋势的识别受到数据限制的阻碍，特别是，直接人类对水流的影响的流行率可能掩盖了气候驱动的变异性。通过消除这些影响，流量数据的趋势可以更自信地归因于气候变化。在这里，我们描述了国际水文气候变化检测盆地的参考天文台（Robin） - 来自国家参考水文网络（RHNS）的全球流量数据网络的首次迭代，该网络由几乎是天然或人类影响力有限的集水集成。这项合作已建立了一个可免费获得的全球RHN数据集，其中包括3,000多个集水区和代码库，可用于基础新科学努力和提前变化检测研究，以支持国际气候政策和适应。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Human-induced warming is modifying the water cycle. Adaptation to posed threats requires an understanding of hydrological responses to climate variability. Whilst these can be computationally modelled, observed streamflow data is essential for constraining models, and understanding and quantifying emerging trends in the water cycle. To date, the identification of such trends at the global scale has been hindered by data limitations – in particular, the prevalence of direct human influences on streamflow which can obscure climate-driven variability. By removing these influences, trends in streamflow data can be more confidently attributed to climate variability. Here we describe the Reference Observatory of Basins for INternational hydrological climate change detection (ROBIN) – the first iteration of a global network of streamflow data from national reference hydrological networks (RHNs) – comprised of catchments which are near-natural or have limited human influences. This collaboration has established a freely available global RHN dataset of over 3,000 catchments and code libraries, which can be used to underpin new science endeavours and advance change detection studies to support international climate policy and adaptation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04907-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4907_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>