<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 02:18:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 关于障碍阵列流动流的实验：用于湍流和波转换建模的数据库</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05783-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Experiments on flow over obstacle arrays: a database for turbulent flow and wave transformation modeling&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Francisco Nicolás Cantero-Chinchilla; Oscar Castro-Orgaz; Sk Zeeshan Ali; Subhasish Dey&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;该数据描述符介绍了一个详细的数据集，该数据集与障碍阵列相互作用的开放通道流，源自实验室实验活动，该活动涉及高斯和对数正态形的障碍，并在fl段中依次排列，以及孤立的沙丘概况。测试了六个不同的数组配置。稳定和不稳定的流动条件均被实施，导致了广泛的实验。使用专门为此目的设计的方法系统提取自由表面流量水平，水槽床位和头压数据的数据。数据集补充了实验的数据和全景图像的示意图，包括湍流和波动转化现象的特征。据我们所知，这是文献中的第一个数据库，可以全面研究流动与稳定和不稳定流程条件下各种障碍阵列的相互作用。结合对所采用方法的详细描述，该数据描述符有望促进数据集的大量使用，从而使开放通道流程建模社区受益。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This data descriptor presents a detailed dataset of open-channel flow interacting with arrays of obstacles, originating from a laboratory experimental campaign involving Gaussian- and log-normal-shaped obstacles arranged sequentially in a flume, as well as a solitary dune profile. Six different array configurations were tested. Both steady and unsteady flow conditions were implemented resulting in a wide range of experiments. Data on free surface flow level, flume bed level, and head pressure data were systematically extracted using a methodology specifically designed for this purpose. The dataset is supplemented with schematic representations of the data and panoramas images of the experiments, including characteristics of turbulence and wave transformation phenomena. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first database in the literature to comprehensively examine the interaction of flow with various obstacle arrays under both steady and unsteady flow conditions. Combined with the detailed description of the employed methodology, this data descriptor is expected to promote significant usage of the dataset, benefiting the open-channel flow modeling community.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05783-2/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5783_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 在持续的全球气候变化下，大规模地面沉降漏斗放大了洪水淹没</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02669-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Flood inundation amplified by large-scale ground subsidence funnel under the ongoing global climate change&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Liming He; Yanzhuang Yin; Jiuyang Cai; Lixin Wu; Yongliang Tang; Ronghua He; Zhenglin Qu; Yu Liu; Panke Pei; Qiao Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球气候变化导致更严重的降雨，这极大地加剧了全球大规模沉降漏斗的淹没风险。在这里，我们在2022年在中国利亚霍平原的一个大型地面沉降渠道中提出了一例洪灾灾难，这是由于不断发生的全球气候变化而引发的。我们通过全面利用卫星遥感，数值模拟和风险评估技术进行了回顾性调查和分析及其影响。我们观察了近50年的沉降漏斗规模，定量分析了沉降对洪水灾难的影响，并评估了洪水灾害风险。结果表明，地面沉降部分损害了河流的防洪能力，使该地区的洪水风险提高了28.24％。此外，沉降还破坏了洪水控制大坝，导致违反和次要洪水灾难。我们的工作表明，有可能表征通过Spaceborne遥感的大规模沉降漏斗的淹没风险。这种方法可以增强应付全球类似地面沉降地区极端天气事件的能力。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Global climate change is leading to more severe rainfalls, greatly exacerbating the inundation risk of large-scale subsidence funnels worldwide. Here, we present a case of flood disaster in a large ground subsidence funnel at the Liaohe plain of China in 2022, triggered by continuous heavy rainfall under the ongoing global climate change. We conducted a retrospective investigation and analysis of the disaster event and its impacts through the comprehensive utilization of satellite remote sensing, numerical simulation, and risk assessment techniques. We observed the scale of the subsidence funnel for nearly 50 years, quantitatively analyzed the impact of subsidence on the flood disaster, and assessed the flood disaster risk. The results indicated that the ground subsidence has partially compromised the flood protection capacity of rivers, elevating flood risk in this region by 28.24%. Additionally, the subsidence has also damaged the flood control dam, leading to a breach and a secondary flooding disaster. Our work demonstrates that it’s possible to characterize the inundation risk of large-scale subsidence funnels by spaceborne remote sensing in advance. This approach could enhance the capacity to cope with extreme weather events in similar ground subsidence regions worldwide.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02669-4/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2669_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 在温暖的气候下，欧洲大洪水的趋势分歧</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02734-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Diverging trends in large floods across Europe in a warming climate&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Beijing Fang; Oldrich Rakovec; Emanuele Bevacqua; Rohini Kumar; Jakob Zscheischler&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;同时影响多个地区的大洪水对生活和经济构成了重大风险。在温暖的气候下，预计极端降水量和融雪减少将改变洪水特征，但是在气候变化下，欧洲大洪水的动态如何发展。通过共同评估较温暖的世界中的时间，空间范围和大洪水数量的预计变化，我们在这里表明，较早的融雪通常会导致较早的洪水，同时增加降水贡献会减轻洪水的季节性。尽管大陆尺度的平均值表明变化有限，但它们掩盖了实质性的区域异质性。在西欧，预计大量降水的增加会导致洪水量更大和体积。相比之下，融雪的减少主导着北欧最大的洪水的变化，其本地化从雪融合驱动到降雨驱动的洪水的局部变化。在欧洲跨国洪水风险管理中，应考虑大量洪水对气候变化的区域多样性的反应。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Large floods, which affect multiple regions simultaneously, pose substantial risks to lives and economies. In a warmer climate, increased precipitation extremes and reduced snowmelt are expected to alter flood characteristics, but how the dynamics of large floods across Europe will evolve under climate change remains unclear. By jointly assessing projected changes in the timing, spatial extent and volume of large floods in a warmer world, here we show that earlier snowmelt generally leads to earlier floods, while increasing precipitation contributions attenuate flood seasonality. Although continental-scale averages suggest limited change, they mask substantial regional heterogeneity. In western Europe, projected increases in heavy precipitation result in larger flood extents and volumes. In contrast, reduced snowmelt dominates changes in the largest floods in northern Europe, with localized shifts from snowmelt-driven to rainfall-driven floods. These regionally diverse responses of large floods to climate change should be considered in transnational flood risk management across Europe.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02734-y/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2734_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>