<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 02:10:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 全球土壤湿度-降水耦合的因果路径</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-63999-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Causal pathways underlying global soil moisture–precipitation coupling&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jing Sun; Kun Yang; Xiaogang He; Guiling Wang; Yong Wang; Yan Yu; Hui Lu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;表层土壤水分-降水（SSM-P）耦合涉及复杂的过程，其中显热（SH）和蒸散量是重要的介质。然而，全球范围内的这些耦合途径及其潜在机制仍不清楚，限制了水文气象预测和预测。在这里，我们采用信息流技术进行卫星观测和再分析，揭示了局部 SSM 对约 16% 分析的全球土地降水的强烈影响。在八个已确定的耦合热点中，除两个非洲热点以蒸散介导的途径为主外，SH 介导的途径是一个关键机制。这些路径差异与远程水分可用性和边界层高度变化有关。强耦合优先发生在 SSM 变异较大的区域，特别是对于 SSM-SH-P。大多数 CMIP6 模型无法重现这些耦合模式，只有四个模型成功捕获了 ERA5 衍生的变异性-因果关系。我们的研究提供了对陆地-大气耦合的更多见解，并提出了基于过程的模型评估指标。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Surface soil moisture–precipitation (SSM–P) coupling involves complex processes, with sensible heat (SH) and evapotranspiration as important mediators. However, these coupling pathways and their underlying mechanisms across the globe remain unclear, limiting hydrometeorological predictions and projections. Here, we employ an information flow technique to satellite observations and reanalysis, revealing strong local SSM impacts on precipitation across ~16% of analyzed global land. Among the eight identified coupling hotspots, the SH-mediated pathway emerges as a crucial mechanism, except for two African hotspots dominated by the evapotranspiration-mediated pathway. These pathway differences are linked to remote moisture availability and boundary layer height variability. Strong coupling preferentially occurs over regions with large SSM variability, particularly for SSM–SH–P. Most CMIP6 models fail to reproduce these coupling patterns, with only four successfully capturing the ERA5-derived variability–causality relationship. Our study offers additional insights into land–atmosphere coupling and proposes process-based metrics for model evaluation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-63999-7/MediaObjects/41467_2025_63999_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 3D-LAKES：来自 ICESat-2 高度测量和陆地卫星图像的三维全球湖泊和水库测深</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05911-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;3D-LAKES: Three-Dimensional Global Lake and Reservoir Bathymetry from ICESat-2 Altimetry and Landsat Imagery&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Chi Hsiang Huang; Shuai Zhang; Deep Shah; Anshul Yadav; Yao Li; Gang Zhao; Huilin Gao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球湖泊和水库蓄水动态的量化对于了解地表水在区域气候学、减轻自然灾害和保护生态系统中的作用至关重要。然而，由于缺乏可靠且具有成本效益的全球测深信息，准确理解这些存储动态的能力受到严重阻碍。本研究引入了 3D-LAKES 数据集，该数据集包含全球 510,530 个湖泊和水库的面积-高程 (AE) 关系和三维 (3D) 测深信息，占全球地表水储存容量的 98.9%。该数据集使用从现场测量收集的 214 个 AE 关系和 12 个测深图进行了验证，显示出很强的一致性。 AE 关系得出 RMSE 为 0.60 m、NRMSE 为 0.14、R &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;为 0.61；而 3D 测深图的 RMSE 为 1.37 m，NRMSE 为 0.26。该数据集有潜力支持许多应用，从监测湖泊/水库蓄水变化到参数化水力/水文模型。这种整合为全球水文研究、水资源管理计划和减灾提供了重要信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Quantification of the water storage dynamics in global lakes and reservoirs is pivotal for understanding the roles of surface water in regional climatology, mitigating natural disasters, and preserving ecosystems. However, the ability to accurately comprehend these storage dynamics is significantly hindered by the lack of reliable and cost-effective global bathymetry information. This study introduces the 3D-LAKES dataset, which contains the area-elevation (A-E) relationship and three-dimensional (3D) bathymetry information for 510,530 global lakes and reservoirs, representing 98.9% of global surface water storage capacity. This dataset was validated using 214 A-E relationships and 12 bathymetry maps collected from in-situ measurements, showing strong agreement. The A-E relationships yield an RMSE of 0.60 m, a NRMSE of 0.14, and an R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; of 0.61; while the 3D bathymetry maps have an RMSE of 1.37 m and a NRMSE of 0.26. This dataset has the potential to support many applications, from monitoring lake/reservoir storage variations to parameterizing hydraulic/hydrological models. Such integration provides essential information for global hydrological studies, water management programs, and disaster mitigation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05911-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5911_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>