<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 02:36:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 美国大坝概率的历史变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-59536-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Historical changes in overtopping probability of dams in the United States&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Eunsaem Cho; Ebrahim Ahmadisharaf; Gabriele Villarini; Amir AghaKouchak&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;由于担心水肿极端的衰老和非平稳性变化（例如，洪水），关于现有大坝是否可能面临失败的风险和对社会构成威胁的问题。在这里，我们分析了整个美国的33个大坝，以研究年度最大水位水位的大坝超大概率的时间趋势。选择了这些大坝，因为公共领域的长期时间序列是不受控制的水位（50年或更长时间）。我们在1973年至2022年的30年滚动期间使用广义的极值分布应用了更新的固定频率分析。结果表明，表现出关键超级概率的大坝数量的总体趋势（即，低，低，中度和高）以及非临界超级概率的数量减少（IE，低点）。这种方法发现了仅基于大坝水位的传统分析无法揭示的超出概率。我们确定了六个水坝，其概率最大，其中一些位于大人口中心附近，给下游社区带来了潜在的风险。所有六个水坝都被归类为大而高危的潜力。这项研究提供了有关大坝管理和风险评估的见解，强调了对减轻潜在威胁的积极措施的需求。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;With concerns about aging dams and nonstationary changes in hydrologic extremes (e.g., flooding), questions arise about whether existing dams may be at risk of failure and pose threats to society. Here, we analyzed 33 dams across the United States to investigate temporal trends in dam overtopping probabilities of annual maximum dam water levels. These dams were selected because of the availability of public domain long-term time series of uncontrolled water levels (50 years or longer). We applied updated stationary frequency analyses using generalized extreme value distributions on 30-year rolling periods from 1973 to 2022. The results revealed an overall increasing trend in the number of dams exhibiting critical overtopping probabilities (i.e., low, moderate and high) alongside a decline in the number of non-critical overtopping probabilities (i.e., very low) over time. This approach uncovered overtopping probabilities that traditional analyses based solely on dam water levels could not reveal. We identified six dams having the greatest overtopping probability, with several being located near large population centers, posing potential risks to the downstream communities. All six dams are classified as large and high-hazard potential. This study provides insights into dam management and risk assessment, emphasizing the need for proactive measures to mitigate potential threats.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-59536-1/MediaObjects/41467_2025_59536_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 巴西沿海和内陆水域水质遥感的生物光学数据库（Braza）</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05609-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A bio-optical database for the remote sensing of water quality in BRAZil coAstal and inland waters (BRAZA)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Daniel Andrade Maciel; Claudio Clemente Faria Barbosa; Evlyn Márcia Leão de Moraes Novo; Raianny Leite do Nascimento Wanderley; Pedro Bacellar; Lohan Barbosa Baia; Henrique Bernini; Rafael G. Chasles; Aurea Ciotti; Alice Fassoni-Andrade; Rogério Flores Júnior; Thainara Lima; Fernando Lopes; Rogério Ribeiro Marinho; André Martinelli; Vitor S. Martins; Marcela Miranda; Gabriel Moiano Cesar; David da Motta Marques; Maurício Almeida Noernberg; Fernanda Helena Oliveira da Silva; Felipe Pacheco; Rejane S. Paulino; Waterloo Pereira Filho; Júlio César Pimenta dos Santos; Lino Augusto Sander de Carvalho; Marcio Sousa da Silva; Matheus Henrique Tavares; Marta Ummus; Aline de Matos Valério; Pedro Walfir M. e Souza Filho; Fernanda Sayuri Yoshino Watanabe; Rafaela Cristine Zem&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;了解水质（WQ）对于抓住生物地球化学周期和评估人类影响，例如森林砍伐，气候变化，大坝建设，非法采矿和城市化至关重要。但是，监视整个巴西大量水生系统的WQ需要大量资源。遥感通过提供高分辨率和大规模观察来改善此过程。然而，基于遥感需求的需求，生产可靠的遥感WQ产品，可以同时使用水生反射率和原位测量值（例如，叶绿素-A，secchi磁盘深度，悬浮沉积物）。这样的数据使高级半分析和机器学习模型可以捕获巴西的生物光学水复杂性。协作工作和开放数据共享对于构建这些数据集至关重要。在这里，我们在巴西不同水生系统中介绍了一个新的策划，高质量的生物光学数据集，称为Braza（用于巴西沿海和内陆水域水质的生物光水平数据库）。通过利用来自17个机构的数据，涵盖了 + 128个湖泊，河流，水库和巴西五个行政区域的沿海地区的2,895个站点，我们的数据集为支持基于WQ的远程感知基于WQ的分析提供了重要的贡献。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understanding water quality (WQ) is essential for grasping biogeochemical cycles and assessing human impacts such as deforestation, climate change, dam construction, illegal mining, and urbanization. However, monitoring WQ across Brazil’s vast aquatic systems requires significant resources. Remote sensing improves this process by offering high-resolution and large-scale observations. Nevertheless, to produce reliable remote-sensing WQ products based on remote sensing demands comprehensive datasets with concurrent aquatic reflectance and in situ measurements (e.g., Chlorophyll-a, Secchi Disk Depth, Suspended Sediments). Such data enables advanced semi-analytical and machine learning models to capture Brazil’s bio-optical water complexity. Collaborative efforts and open-data sharing are essential for building these datasets. Here, we introduce a new curated, high-quality bio-optical dataset across different aquatic systems in Brazil, called BRAZA (Bio-optical aquatic database for remote sensing of water quality in BRAZil coAstal and inland waters). By leveraging data from 17 institutions, covering 2,895 stations across + 128 lakes, rivers, reservoirs, and coastal areas of Brazil’s five administrative regions our dataset presents an important contribution to support remote sensing WQ-based analysis in Brazil.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05609-1/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5609_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>