<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 02:17:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Water | 气候变化加剧了灌溉引起的陆地水资源枯竭</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00529-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Irrigation-induced land water depletion aggravated by climate change&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yi Yao; Wim Thiery; Agnés Ducharne; Benjamin I. Cook; Anxin Ding; Steven J. De Hertog; Petra Sieber; Kjetil Schanke Aas; Pedro F. Arboleda-Obando; Jeanne Colin; Maya Costantini; Bertrand Decharme; David M. Lawrence; Peter Lawrence; L. Ruby Leung; Min-Hui Lo; Narayanappa Devaraju; Ren-Jie Wu; Tian Zhou; Jonas Jägermeyr; Sonali Shukla McDermid; Yadu Pokhrel; Yusuke Satoh; Tokuta Yokohata; Lukas Gudmundsson; Sonia I. Seneviratne&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;农业灌溉迅速扩张，其不断增长的淡水消耗可能会加剧水资源短缺问题。以前的研究主要依赖于观测或仅限陆地的模拟，往往忽略了陆地与大气的相互作用或未能捕捉到长期的演化。因此，我们使用七个地球系统模型分析了历史灌溉扩张对水通量和资源的影响。在这里，我们发现许多地区的灌溉扩张大大减少了从大气到陆地的净水流入量，进一步加剧了气候变化造成的现有干旱趋势。例如，1960年后南亚的灌溉扩张使这一净流入量的趋势从-0.664 (±0.283)改变为-1.461 (±0.261) mm yr &lt;sup&gt;-2&lt;/sup&gt; 。因此，当地陆地水储量枯竭率因灌溉扩张而大幅扩大(例如，从-2.559 (±0.094)到-16.008(± 0.557) 毫米·年&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; )。我们的研究结果将土地水资源流失归因于灌溉扩张和气候变化，呼吁立即采取解决方案来应对负面趋势。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Agricultural irrigation has experienced rapid expansion, and its growing freshwater consumption is potentially exacerbating water scarcity issues. Previous studies predominantly relied on observations or land-only simulations, often neglecting land–atmosphere interactions or failing to capture long-term evolution. We therefore analyse the effects of historical irrigation expansion on water fluxes and resources using seven Earth system models. Here we show that irrigation expansion in many regions substantially decreases the net water influx from the atmosphere to land, further aggravating the existing drying trends caused by climate change. For example, irrigation expansion changed the trend of this net influx from −0.664 ( ± 0.283) to −1.461 ( ± 0.261) mm yr&lt;sup&gt;−2&lt;/sup&gt; in South Asia after 1960. Consequently, the local terrestrial water storage depletion rate is substantially enlarged by irrigation expansion (for example, from −2.559 ( ± 0.094) to −16.008 ( ± 0.557) mm yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;). Our results attribute the land water loss to irrigation expansion and climate change, calling for immediate solutions to tackle the negative trends.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00529-1/MediaObjects/44221_2025_529_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>