<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 08:39:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Reviews Earth &amp; Environment | 地球变暖导致的水文气候波动</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43017-024-00624-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Daniel L. Swain; Andreas F. Prein; John T. Abatzoglou; Christine M. Albano; Manuela Brunner; Noah S. Diffenbaugh; Deepti Singh; Christopher B. Skinner; Danielle Touma&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水文气候波动是指非常干燥和非常潮湿的条件之间突然、大幅度和/或频繁的转变。在这篇综述中，我们研究了水文气候波动预计将如何随着人为变暖而演变。使用基于标准化降水蒸散指数的“水文气候鞭打”指标，全球平均次季节（3 个月）和年际（12 个月）鞭打自二十世纪中叶。随着持续变暖，预计气温将进一步上升，其中升温 3°C 的陆地地区，次季节气温上升 113%，年际气温上升 52%；这些变化在高纬度地区以及从北非向东进入南亚的地区最为明显。大量证据表明，这些增加主要与热力学有关，即大气中水蒸气保持能力的增加和潜在的蒸发需求。水文气候波动性的增加将加剧与潮湿和干燥状态之间快速波动相关的危害（包括山洪、野火、山体滑坡和疾病爆发），并可能加速水管理向干旱和洪水风险共同管理的转变。要更清楚地了解水文气候波动的未来可能轨迹，需要使用大型集合气候模型模拟、风暴解析高分辨率模型和新兴的机器学习方法。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hydroclimate volatility refers to sudden, large and/or frequent transitions between very dry and very wet conditions. In this Review, we examine how hydroclimate volatility is anticipated to evolve with anthropogenic warming. Using a metric of ‘hydroclimate whiplash’ based on the Standardized Precipitation Evapotranspiration Index, global-averaged subseasonal (3-month) and interannual (12-month) whiplash have increased by 31–66% and 8–31%, respectively, since the mid-twentieth century. Further increases are anticipated with ongoing warming, including subseasonal increases of 113% and interannual increases of 52% over land areas with 3 °C of warming; these changes are largest at high latitudes and from northern Africa eastward into South Asia. Extensive evidence links these increases primarily to thermodynamics, namely the rising water-vapour-holding capacity and potential evaporative demand of the atmosphere. Increases in hydroclimate volatility will amplify hazards associated with rapid swings between wet and dry states (including flash floods, wildfires, landslides and disease outbreaks), and could accelerate a water management shift towards co-management of drought and flood risks. A clearer understanding of plausible future trajectories of hydroclimate volatility requires expanded focus on the response of atmospheric circulation to regional and global forcings, as well as land–ocean–atmosphere feedbacks, using large ensemble climate model simulations, storm-resolving high-resolution models and emerging machine learning methods.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43017-024-00624-z/MediaObjects/43017_2024_624_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Water | 由于人类活动导致全球旱地地表水储存与降水脱钩</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-024-00367-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Gang Zhao; Huilin Gao; Yao Li; Qiuhong Tang; R. Iestyn Woolway; Julian Merder; Lorenzo Rosa; Anna M. Michalak&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球旱地地表水的供应对于人类社会和生态系统都至关重要。然而，地表水储存变化的长期驱动因素，特别是与人类活动相关的因素，仍不清楚。在这里，我们使用多任务遥感数据构建了全球旱地 105,400 个湖泊和水库从 1985 年到 2020 年的月水储量变化时间序列。地表水储存量每年增加 2.20 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; ，这主要是由于新水库的建设。相反，对于湖泊和老水库（1983 年之前建成）来说，全球范围内的蓄水趋势较小，但它们在 91% 的全球旱地盆地中主导着地表水蓄水趋势。进一步的分析表明，这些水体的长期储存变化主要与人为因素有关，包括人类引起的变暖和水管理实践，而不是像以前认为的那样与降水变化有关。这些发现揭示了全球旱地地表水储存与降水的脱钩，引发了人们对社会和生态系统可持续性的担忧。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The availability of surface water in global drylands is essential for both human society and ecosystems. However, the long-term drivers of change in surface water storage, particularly those related to anthropogenic activities, remain unclear. Here we use multi-mission remote sensing data to construct monthly time series of water storage changes from 1985 to 2020 for 105,400 lakes and reservoirs in global drylands. An increase of 2.20 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; per year in surface water storage is found primarily due to the construction of new reservoirs. For lakes and old reservoirs (constructed before 1983), conversely, the trend in storage is minor when aggregated globally, but they dominate surface water storage trends in 91% of individual global dryland basins. Further analysis reveals that long-term storage changes in these water bodies are primarily linked to anthropogenic factors—including human-induced warming and water-management practices—rather than to precipitation changes, as previously thought. These findings reveal a decoupling of surface water storage from precipitation in global drylands, raising concerns about societal and ecosystem sustainability.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-024-00367-7/MediaObjects/44221_2024_367_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Water | 通过 SWOT 重新审视地球的水和能源</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-024-00372-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Nadya T. Vinogradova; Tamlin M. Pavelsky; J. Thomas Farrar; Faisal Hossain; Lee-Lueng Fu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;随着地球向新的气候过渡，适应地球不断变化的水循环仍然是人类面临的首要挑战之一。过去几千年气候和水资源的相对稳定使人类能够建立复杂的社会，拥有成熟的农业、基础设施和经济，如今维持着 80 亿人的生计。随着地球变暖，水运动的这种稳定状态正在被改变，全球水循环的海洋和陆地部分正在经历可测量的变化，并且可能会持续下去。预测气候变暖时地球水的新轨迹首先要观察整个地球的整个水供需链，从地球最大的水库海洋到陆地上的水储存、使用和循环利用。最近发射的一个名为地表水和海洋地形（SWOT）的空间观测站正在及时进入并补充水观测网络，通过提供对水高度和几乎所有水体体积的直接、高分辨率测量。地球表面。在这里，我们将宽幅卫星测高技术的进步和 SWOT 对全球水量的新颖测量与地球水循环的科学创新联系起来，包括对全球湖泊和河流的水储存和动态、海平面上升、海洋能量学的变化的研究以及陆地-海洋交换，对水资源管理者和气候适应力工作的实用信息具有影响。我们还讨论了 SWOT 创新如何为水科学界内的未来任务和综合地球系统方法奠定基础。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As the planet transitions to a new climate, adapting to the Earth’s changing water cycle remains among the top challenges faced by humanity. The relative stability of climate and water resources over the past millennia allowed humans to build complex societies with established agriculture, infrastructure and economies that today sustain the livelihood of eight billion people. As the planet warms, this steady state of water movement is being altered, and both oceanic and terrestrial components of the global water cycle are undergoing measurable changes that will probably continue. Predicting the new trajectory of Earth’s water in a warming climate begins with observing the entire water supply–demand chain across the planet, from Earth’s largest water reservoir, the ocean, to water storage, use and recycling on land. A recently launched space observatory, called the Surface Water and Ocean Topography (SWOT), is making a timely entrance and addition to the water-observing networks, by providing direct, high-resolution measurements of the water height and volume of nearly all water on the Earth’s surface. Here we link technological advances in wide-swath satellite altimetry and SWOT’s novel measurements of water volume across the planet to scientific innovations for Earth’s water cycle, including studies of changes in the water storage and dynamics in global lakes and rivers, rising seas, ocean energetics and land–ocean exchange, with implications for practical information for water resource managers and climate resilience efforts. We also discuss how SWOT innovations set the stage for future missions and integrated Earth-system approaches within the water science community.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-024-00372-w/MediaObjects/44221_2024_372_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 早期火星上由地壳水合作用引发的间歇性温暖气候</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-024-01626-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Danica Adams; Markus Scheucher; Renyu Hu; Bethany L. Ehlmann; Trent B. Thomas; Robin Wordsworth; Eva Scheller; Rob Lillis; Kayla Smith; Heike Rauer; Yuk L. Yung&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;地质记录表明，古代火星表面蕴藏着大量液态水，这种资源随着地壳物质因水合作用而发生化学变化和大气逃逸等过程而逐渐减少。然而，早期火星上相对温暖的气候如何在较暗的年轻太阳下维持液态水仍存在争议。富含CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;的大气中的诸如H &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;等温室气体可能通过碰撞引起的吸收而导致变暖，但是否有足够的H &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;来维持变暖仍不清楚。在这里，我们使用气候和光化学相结合的模型来模拟早期火星上的大气化学如何在现有观测的限制下对水-岩石反应和气候变化做出反应。我们发现，地壳水合和氧化所释放的 H &lt;sub&gt;2 气体&lt;/sub&gt;，加上短暂的火山活动，可能会产生足够的 H &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;通量，从而短暂地促进温暖、潮湿的气候。我们估计火星经历了总持续时间约为 4000 万年的间歇性温暖期，每次事件持续≥10 &lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;年，与山谷网络的形成时间尺度一致。通过表面氧化剂汇或地球轴倾斜的变化导致大气中CO &lt;sub&gt;2 的&lt;/sub&gt;减少可能导致地球氧化还原状态的突然变化并过渡到以CO为主的大气和寒冷气候。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Geological records indicate that the surface of ancient Mars harboured substantial volumes of liquid water, a resource gradually diminished by processes such as the chemical alteration of crustal materials by hydration and atmospheric escape. However, how a relatively warm climate existed on early Mars to support liquid water under a fainter young Sun is debated. Greenhouse gases such as H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in a CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-rich atmosphere could have contributed to warming through collision-induced absorption, but whether sufficient H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; was available to sustain warming remains unclear. Here we use a combined climate and photochemical model to simulate how atmospheric chemistry on early Mars responded to water–rock reactions and climate variations, as constrained by existing observations. We find that H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; outgassing from crustal hydration and oxidation, supplemented by transient volcanic activity, could have generated sufficient H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; fluxes to transiently foster warm, humid climates. We estimate that Mars experienced episodic warm periods of an integrated duration of ~40 million years, with each event lasting ≥10&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; years, consistent with the formation timescale of valley networks. Declining atmospheric CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via surface oxidant sinks or variations in the planet’s axial tilt could have led to abrupt shifts in the planet’s redox state and transition to a CO-dominated atmosphere and cold climate.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-024-01626-8/MediaObjects/41561_2024_1626_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 极端水文气候威胁地下水质量和稳定性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-55890-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Simon A. Schroeter; Alice May Orme; Katharina Lehmann; Robert Lehmann; Narendrakumar M. Chaudhari; Kirsten Küsel; He Wang; Anke Hildebrandt; Kai Uwe Totsche; Susan Trumbore; Gerd Gleixner&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;与过去的气候参考期（1961-1990）相比，强降水、干旱和其他极端水文气候发生的频率更高。鉴于它们对地下水补给动态的强烈影响，这些现象增加了地下水数量和质量的脆弱性。在过去的十年中，我们记录了地下水中溶解有机物成分的变化。我们发现，随着地下水位下降，进入表面的有机分子的比例显着增加，而溶解的有机碳的浓度保持不变。 2018 年夏季极端干旱后，分子组成的转变加速。这些发现表明，极端水文气候促进地表生态系统和地下水之间的快速运输，从而使外源物质能够逃避微生物处理，在地下水中积累更多，并可能损害这些饮用水源的安全性。地下水质量受近期气候异常影响的程度远比目前认识的要严重，溶解有机物的分子组成可以作为地下水质量恶化的综合指标。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Heavy precipitation, drought, and other hydroclimatic extremes occur more frequently than in the past climate reference period (1961–1990). Given their strong effect on groundwater recharge dynamics, these phenomena increase the vulnerability of groundwater quantity and quality. Over the course of the past decade, we have documented changes in the composition of dissolved organic matter in groundwater. We show that fractions of ingressing surface-derived organic molecules increased significantly as groundwater levels declined, whereas concentrations of dissolved organic carbon remained constant. Molecular composition changeover was accelerated following 2018’s extreme summer drought. These findings demonstrate that hydroclimatic extremes promote rapid transport between surface ecosystems and groundwaters, thereby enabling xenobiotic substances to evade microbial processing, accrue in greater abundance in groundwater, and potentially compromise the safe nature of these potable water sources. Groundwater quality is far more vulnerable to the impact of recent climate anomalies than is currently recognized, and the molecular composition of dissolved organic matter can be used as a comprehensive indicator for groundwater quality deterioration.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-55890-2/MediaObjects/41467_2025_55890_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 考虑作物和地区之间的差异可以减少对氮肥土壤中硝酸盐淋失的估计</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02001-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yan Wang; Yihong Liu; Longlong Xia; Hiroko Akiyama; Xinli Chen; Ji Chen; Yunying Fang; Tony Vancov; Yongfu Li; YuanZhi Yao; Dianming Wu; Bing Yu; Scott X. Chang; Yanjiang Cai&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;施氮 (N) 肥料的土壤中的硝酸盐 (NO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; ) 浸出是全球关注的重大问题，影响环境和公众健康。然而，不同地区或作物的 NO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;淋滤因子 (LF) 存在很大的不确定性和变异性，这阻碍了对 NO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;淋滤的准确评估。在这里，我们综合了全球 2500 个实地观测结果，表明不同地区和作物的 LF 有一个数量级的差异，主要是由水文气候和土壤条件驱动，而不是氮肥管理。通过空间明确的 (15.4, 14.8–16.1 Tg N yr &lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt; ) 和特定作物 (12.9, 11.0–14.8 Tg N yr &lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt; ) LF 计算的全球农田 NO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt;合成氮肥淋失量比 41% 低政府间气候变化专门委员会一级全球清单。超过47%的浸出量集中在中国、印度和美国，其中玉米、小麦、稻米和蔬菜占其中近一半。改进的区域和特定作物的 LF 将通过查明潜在的全球热点为 NO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;浸出减排提供基准。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Nitrate (NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt;) leaching from nitrogen (N) fertilized soils is a significant global concern, affecting both the environment and public health. However, substantial uncertainties and variabilities in NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; leaching factors (LFs) among regions or crops impede accurate assessments of NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; leaching. Here we synthesize 2500 field observations worldwide and show that LFs vary by an order of magnitude across regions and crops, primarily driven by hydroclimatic and edaphic conditions rather than N fertilizer management. Global cropland NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; leaching from synthetic N fertilization, calculated through spatially explicit (15.4, 14.8–16.1 Tg N yr&lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt;) and crop-specific (12.9, 11.0–14.8 Tg N yr&lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt;) LFs, is 41% lower than the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change Tier 1 global inventory. Over 47% of this leaching is concentrated in China, India, and the United States, with maize, wheat, rice and vegetables accounting for nearly half of it. Improved regional and crop-specific LFs will provide a benchmark for NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; leaching abatement by pinpointing potential global hotspots.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02001-0/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2001_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 初级生产力对加速干旱更加敏感</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02013-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yangyang Jing; Shuo Wang; Pak Wai Chan; Zong-Liang Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;突发干旱的特点是发生迅速，严重影响陆地生态系统。然而，人们对不同植被条件下生态系统生产力对突发干旱快速发展的敏感性仍知之甚少。在这里，我们考虑了根区土壤水分的下降率和标准化总初级生产力异常，研究了不同植物功能类型的生态系统对突发干旱发生速度的响应。我们的研究结果显示，2001 年至 2018 年期间，导致标准化总初级生产力负异常的 1 候和 2 候（5 天和 10 天）突发突发干旱的比例显着增加了约 10%。此外，虽然标准化总初级生产力异常下降速度较高，但与发生较慢的突发干旱相比，它们不能在更短的时间内对发生较快的突发干旱做出迅速反应。根系较浅的植被类型对快速发生的突发干旱表现出更高的敏感性，这表明气候变化对陆地生态系统的威胁不断升级。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Flash droughts, characterized by their rapid onset, substantially affect terrestrial ecosystems. However, the sensitivity of ecosystem productivity to the rapid development of flash droughts under varying vegetation conditions remains poorly understood. Here we investigate the ecosystem response to the speed of flash drought onset for different plant functional types, considering the decline rate of root-zone soil moisture and standardized gross primary productivity anomaly. Our findings reveal a significant increase of approximately 10% in the proportion of 1- and 2-pentad (5 and 10 days) onset flash droughts leading to negative standardized gross primary productivity anomalies during 2001–2018. Furthermore, while standardized gross primary productivity anomalies decline at higher rates, they do not promptly respond on a shorter timescale to faster-onset flash droughts compared to slower-onset flash droughts. Vegetation types with shallower root systems exhibit higher sensitivities to faster-onset flash droughts, suggesting an escalating threat to terrestrial ecosystems in a changing climate.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02013-w/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2013_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 抵消温室气体和气溶胶的影响加剧了过去一个世纪的全球水季节性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02025-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Fubo Zhao; Wenbo Shi; Yiping Wu; Yanqing Lian; Qiang Li&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水资源供应季节性的变化对社会和生态系统产生重大影响。虽然许多研究都集中在平均或极端降水量上，但水供应季节性对人类引起的气候变化的影响仍然没有得到充分探索，这种季节性影响超出了个别极端情况下的年度水分布。在这里，我们研究了 1915 年至 2014 年全球和区域可用水量的季节性变化，利用耦合模型比对项目第 6 阶段的重新分析和模拟，量化人为温室气体和气溶胶如何影响这些变化。尽管由于区域变异性和模型假设而存在很大的时空不确定性，我们发现温室气体显着放大了季节性，而气溶胶则减少了季节性。鉴于温室气体的积极影响超过了气溶胶的消极影响，其平衡影响导致过去一个世纪水资源供应季节性的整体增强。随着温室气体引起的变暖持续上升和气溶胶水平下降，预计这种趋势未来将持续下去。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Variations in water availability seasonality significantly impact society and ecosystems. While many studies have focused on mean or extreme precipitation, the response of water availability seasonality, influencing yearly water distribution beyond individual extremes, to human-induced climate change remains underexplored. Here we examine global and regional water availability seasonality changes from 1915 to 2014, quantifying how anthropogenic greenhouse gases and aerosols have influenced these variations using reanalysis and simulations from Coupled Model Intercomparison Project Phase 6. Despite large spatiotemporal uncertainties due to regional variability and model assumptions, we find that greenhouse gases significantly amplify the seasonality, while aerosols reduce it. Given that the positive effects of greenhouse gases surpass the aerosols’ negative effects, the counterbalancing influences have led to an overall enhancement in seasonality of water availability over the past century. This trend is expected to continue in the future as greenhouse gases-induced warming continues to rise and aerosol levels decline.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02025-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2025_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 伏伊伏丁那（塞尔维亚）第一个灌溉田地理空间数据集（2020-2024 年）</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04443-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Mirjana Radulović; Miljana Marković; Sanja Brdar; Ioannis Athanasiadis; Gordan Mimić&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;灌溉是全球粮食安全的基石，可实现可持续农业生产，并有助于确保世界各地的人们现在和将来都能获得粮食。绘制灌溉田地图为可持续水资源管理、农业发展和环境保护工作提供了宝贵的信息。然而，准确灌溉绘图所必需的高质量培训数据的收集仍然是昂贵且劳动密集型的。为了解决这个问题，我们创建了一个地理参考区域数据集，其中包括位置、作物类型和灌溉设备的出现情况，这些是绘制灌溉田地图的基本信息。考虑了四种主要灌溉作物：玉米、大豆、甜菜和小麦。该数据集总共包含 1256 个地块，是为塞尔维亚主要农业区伏伊伏丁那创建的，时间跨度五年（2020-2024 年）。这项研究的目标是提供我们的数据集的可访问性，该数据集可以进一步探索和用于构建或微调机器学习和深度学习模型，以便使用卫星图像自动检测灌溉田。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Irrigation is a cornerstone of global food security, enabling sustainable agricultural production and helping to ensure that food is available for people around the world, now and in the future. Mapping irrigated fields provides valuable information for sustainable water management, agricultural development, and environmental conservation efforts. However, the collection of high-quality training data, which is necessary for accurate irrigation mapping remains costly and labour-intensive. To address this, we created a georeferenced regional dataset consisting of location, crop type, and occurrence of the irrigation equipment which are essential information for mapping irrigated fields. Four main irrigated crops were considered: maize, soybean, sugar beet, and wheat. The dataset, consisting of a total of 1256 parcels, is created for Vojvodina, the main agricultural area in Serbia, spanning the period of five years (2020–2024). This study’s goal is to give accessibility to our dataset which further can be explored and used for building or fine-tuning machine learning and deep learning models for the automatic detection of irrigated fields using satellite imagery.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04443-9/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4443_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 仪器时代之前的洪水模型显示 1931 年长江洪水的震级有限</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00908-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ling Zhang; Zhongshi Zhang; Lu Li; Xiaoling Chen; Xijin Wang; Entao Yu; Pratik Kad; Odd Helge Otterå; Chuncheng Guo; Jianzhong Lu; Mingna Wu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球洪水风险促使人们更好地了解洪水强度及其机制，这需要从仪器前的洪水调查中获得见解。由于数据稀缺，重建仪器仪表前洪水震级依赖于统计降尺度，无法捕捉非线性和动态特征。我们开发了一种动态方法 NorESM-WRF-SWAT，整合了全球气候、区域和水文模型来调查 1931 年长江洪水（世界上最致命的一次），并将其与 1998 年进行了比较。通过验证，我们的方法在模拟降水和河流流量方面优于统计方法。我们首次对 1931 年洪水的强度和持续时间进行了详细分析，结果显示，与 1998 年相比，洪水的规模较小，但损失却更大，这可能是由于社会脆弱性和社会复原力下降所致。虽然成功的模拟可能会受到模型变异性的干扰，但我们的动力学方法显示出模拟仪器仪表前洪水和建立长期仪器仪表前水文数据库的希望。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The global flood risk urges an improved understanding of flood magnitude and its mechanism, which needs insights from pre-instrumental flood investigations. Due to data scarcity, reconstructing pre-instrumental flood magnitudes relies on statistical downscaling, failing to capture nonlinear and dynamic characteristics. We developed a dynamical approach, NorESM-WRF-SWAT, integrating a global climate, a regional, and a hydrologic model to investigate the 1931 Yangtze River flood (the deadliest in the world) and compared it with the 1998’s. Through validation, our method outperforms the statistical method in simulating precipitations and river discharges. For the first time, we presented detailed insights into the intensity and duration of the 1931 flood, revealing a smaller magnitude but associated with an amplified loss, likely due to social vulnerability and reduced societal resilience compared to the 1998’s. While successful simulation can be interfered with by model variability, our dynamical method shows promise for simulating pre-instrumental flood and building a long-term pre-instrumental-hydrology database.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00908-1/MediaObjects/41612_2025_908_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>