<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hydrology in Nature journals</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 08:28:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Accounting for differences between crops and regions reduces estimates of nitrate leaching from nitrogen-fertilized soils</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02001-0</link><description>Nitrate (NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt;) leaching from nitrogen (N) fertilized soils is a significant global concern, affecting both the environment and public health. However, substantial uncertainties and variabilities in NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; leaching factors (LFs) among regions or crops impede accurate assessments of NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; leaching. Here we synthesize 2500 field observations worldwide and show that LFs vary by an order of magnitude across regions and crops, primarily driven by hydroclimatic and edaphic conditions rather than N fertilizer management. Global cropland NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; leaching from synthetic N fertilization, calculated through spatially explicit (15.4, 14.8–16.1 Tg N yr&lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt;) and crop-specific (12.9, 11.0–14.8 Tg N yr&lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt;) LFs, is 41% lower than the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change Tier 1 global inventory. Over 47% of this leaching is concentrated in China, India, and the United States, with maize, wheat, rice and vegetables accounting for nearly half of it. Improved regional and crop-specific LFs will provide a benchmark for NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; leaching abatement by pinpointing potential global hotspots.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gross primary productivity is more sensitive to accelerated flash droughts</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02013-w</link><description>Flash droughts, characterized by their rapid onset, substantially affect terrestrial ecosystems. However, the sensitivity of ecosystem productivity to the rapid development of flash droughts under varying vegetation conditions remains poorly understood. Here we investigate the ecosystem response to the speed of flash drought onset for different plant functional types, considering the decline rate of root-zone soil moisture and standardized gross primary productivity anomaly. Our findings reveal a significant increase of approximately 10% in the proportion of 1- and 2-pentad (5 and 10 days) onset flash droughts leading to negative standardized gross primary productivity anomalies during 2001–2018. Furthermore, while standardized gross primary productivity anomalies decline at higher rates, they do not promptly respond on a shorter timescale to faster-onset flash droughts compared to slower-onset flash droughts. Vegetation types with shallower root systems exhibit higher sensitivities to faster-onset flash droughts, suggesting an escalating threat to terrestrial ecosystems in a changing climate.</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Counteracting greenhouse gas and aerosol influences intensify global water seasonality over the past century</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02025-6</link><description>Variations in water availability seasonality significantly impact society and ecosystems. While many studies have focused on mean or extreme precipitation, the response of water availability seasonality, influencing yearly water distribution beyond individual extremes, to human-induced climate change remains underexplored. Here we examine global and regional water availability seasonality changes from 1915 to 2014, quantifying how anthropogenic greenhouse gases and aerosols have influenced these variations using reanalysis and simulations from Coupled Model Intercomparison Project Phase 6. Despite large spatiotemporal uncertainties due to regional variability and model assumptions, we find that greenhouse gases significantly amplify the seasonality, while aerosols reduce it. Given that the positive effects of greenhouse gases surpass the aerosols’ negative effects, the counterbalancing influences have led to an overall enhancement in seasonality of water availability over the past century. This trend is expected to continue in the future as greenhouse gases-induced warming continues to rise and aerosol levels decline.</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>