<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 02:57:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 沿海含水层通过溶质通量来促进海洋化学的主要贡献者</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-62411-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Coastal aquifers key contributors to ocean chemistry through solute fluxes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yael Kiro&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;了解海洋的化学成分是评估碳循环及其气候影响的关键，尤其是通过控制碳酸钙饱和钙和保存。尽管河流和水热系统是海洋化学的贡献者，但沿海含水层的作用被低估了。这项研究表明，长期海底地下水排放（SGD）是海洋溶质通量的主要来源，尤其是钙和碱度，同时去除钠和钾。通过对元素和同位素海洋预算的分析，我们发现长期SGD的通量与河流相抗衡。这些通量影响主要要素的停留时间，并显着影响全球碳预算。此外，它们与海平面变化动态有关：下降的海平面增强了SGD驱动的溶质输入，而海平面上升会抑制它们。这些模式表明，SGD通量可能调节长期气候趋势，包括全球冷却或变暖的速度。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understanding the ocean’s chemical composition is key to assessing the carbon cycle and its climate impact, especially through its control on calcium carbonate saturation and preservation. While rivers and hydrothermal systems are recognized contributors to ocean chemistry, the role of coastal aquifers has been underestimated. This study shows that long-term submarine groundwater discharge (SGD) is a major source of solute fluxes to the ocean, especially of calcium and alkalinity, while removing sodium and potassium. Through analysis of elemental and isotopic ocean budgets, we find that fluxes from long-term SGD rival those from rivers in magnitude. These fluxes influence the residence times of major elements and significantly affect the global carbon budget. Moreover, they are dynamically linked to sea-level changes: falling sea levels enhance SGD-driven solute inputs, whereas rising sea levels suppress them. These patterns suggest that SGD fluxes may regulate long-term climate trends, including rates of global cooling or warming.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-62411-8/MediaObjects/41467_2025_62411_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>