<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 02:20:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | Yarlung-Tsangpo大峡谷中的水电系统可以减轻由于气候变化造成的洪水灾难</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02247-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Hydropower system in the Yarlung-Tsangpo Grand Canyon can mitigate flood disasters caused by climate change&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Fengbo Zhang; Qin Yang; Jianhua Wang; Huan Liu; Qinghui Zeng; Long Yan; Baolong Zhao; Jiaxuan Tang; Kang Zhao; Yining Zang; Wei Liu; Peng Hu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;世界上最大的转移型水电系统将在Yarlung-Tsangpo大峡谷上创建。峡谷是水力发电开发和生态保护的关键地区，在气候变化下面临挑战。在这里，我们使用大型河流盆地模型中的水和能量转移过程和非主导的分类遗传算法III模型评估了该水力发电系统中的水能生态系统Nexus。主要发现表明，在干旱期间具有中等补充流量（1000m³s &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ）的储层操作每年在水力发电时期（2231×10 &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; kWh），洪水缓解（峰值削减率为22.8％）和最小的生态系统影响（Eco-Index 0.45）之间达到最佳平衡。水力发电开发稳定了径流机制，在气候场景下增强了洪水控制能力（例如，在共享社会经济途径126下，峰值降低29.2％），并减轻下游洪水风险，同时支持旱季灌溉和导航。值得注意的是，在低强度的气候变化情景下（共享的社会经济途径126），生态系统稳定性主要是通过稳定的积雪和冰川储备的逐渐且一致地补充水资源来维持的。通过自适应储层管理，确保中国能源安全和下游国家的洪水保护，可以加强跨界合作。这种综合方法强调了将可持续水电扩展与国际河流盆地的生态和地缘政治弹性相吻合的潜力。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The world’s largest diversion-type hydropower system will be created on the Yarlung-Tsangpo Grand Canyon. The canyon, a critical region for hydropower development and ecological conservation, faces challenges under climate change. Here we evaluate the water-energy-ecosystem nexus in this hydropower system using the Water and Energy Transfer Processes in Large River Basins model and the Non-Dominated Sorting Genetic Algorithm III model. Key findings reveal that reservoir operations with medium replenishment flow (1000 m³ s&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;) during dry periods achieve an optimal balance among hydropower generation annually (2231 × 10&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; kWh), flood mitigation (peak clipping rate 22.8%), and minimal ecosystem impact (eco-index 0.45). Hydropower development stabilizes runoff regimes, enhances flood control capacity under climate scenarios (e.g., 29.2% peak reduction under Shared Socioeconomic Pathway 126), and mitigates downstream flood risks while supporting dry-season irrigation and navigation. Notably, under low-forcing climate change scenarios (Shared Socioeconomic Pathway 126), ecosystem stability is sustained primarily through the gradual and consistent replenishment of water resources from stabilized snowpack and glacial reserves. Transboundary cooperation is strengthened through adaptive reservoir management, ensuring energy security for China and flood protection for downstream nations. This integrated approach highlights the potential for harmonizing sustainable hydropower expansion with ecological and geopolitical resilience in international river basins.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02247-8/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2247_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>