<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 02:10:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 人类世史上前所未有的全球水稀缺的首次出现</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-63784-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;The first emergence of unprecedented global water scarcity in the Anthropocene&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Vecchia P. Ravinandrasana; Christian L. E. Franzke&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;获得水对于生活的各个方面至关重要。人为的全球变暖预计将破坏水文周期，导致水稀缺。但是，尚不清楚空前的水稀缺的时机和热点区域。在这里，我们估计了由干旱驱动的水短缺事件的首次出现（TOFE）的时间，该事件被称为“零天的干旱”（DZD），这是由水文化合物极端产生的，包括长时间的降雨缺陷，减少河流流量和增加水量。使用概率框架和大量的气候模拟集合，我们将DZD事件的时机和可能性归因于人类影响力。包括主要水库在内的许多地区可能面临2020年代和2030年代DZD的高风险。尽管模型和场景不确定性，但在地中海，南部非洲和北美部分地区都出现了一致的DZD热点。在1.5°C的变暖水平上，城市人口特别容易受到伤害。连续的DZD事件之间的时间长度短于DZD持续时间，限制了恢复期和加剧水稀缺风险。因此，迫切需要更加主动的水战略，以避免DZD对社会的严重影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Access to water is crucial for all aspects of life. Anthropogenic global warming is projected to disrupt the hydrological cycle, leading to water scarcity. However, the timing and hotspot regions of unprecedented water scarcity are unknown. Here, we estimate the Time of First Emergence (ToFE) of drought-driven water scarcity events, referred to as “Day Zero Drought” (DZD), which arises from hydrological compound extremes, including prolonged rainfall deficits, reduced river flow, and increasing water consumption. Using a probabilistic framework and a large ensemble of climate simulations, we attribute the timing and likelihood of DZD events to human influence. Many regions, including major reservoirs, may face high risk of DZD by the 2020s and 2030s. Despite model and scenario uncertainties, consistent DZD hotspots emerge across the Mediterranean, southern Africa, and parts of North America. Urban populations are particularly vulnerable at the 1.5 °C warming level. The length of time between successive DZD events is shorter than the duration of DZD, limiting recovery periods and exacerbating water scarcity risks. Therefore, more proactive water strategies are urgently needed to avoid severe societal impacts of DZD.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-63784-6/MediaObjects/41467_2025_63784_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 气候变化对河流和地下水养分投入到沿海海洋的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02594-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Effects of climate change on river and groundwater nutrient inputs to the coastal ocean&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Christina M. Richardson; Bernhard Peucker-Ehrenbrink; Shea Wyatt; Annie Bourbonnais; Vanessa Hatje; Claudia Frey; Tina Sanders; Diana E. Varela; Adina Paytan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流和地下水是全球沿海海洋营养的主要来源。预计气候变化会影响河流盆地和沿海含水层的营养通量，从而改变水文和营养循环过程。在这篇综述中，我们确定并总结了气候变化的影响，例如降水的变化，冰冻层融化的变化以及海平面上升，将影响河流和沿海地下水中的水和养分浓度，最终控制对沿海海洋的营养输入。我们还记录了当前对气候与养分通量变化的理解的关键局限性，尤其是在沿海地下水盆地中。气候变化的影响将与当地的人类影响相互作用，这突出了跨越本地量表的研究的需求，以更好地理解和改善这些水文途径对未来营养通量的预测。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Rivers and groundwater are major sources of nutrients to the global coastal ocean. Climate change is expected to impact nutrient fluxes from river basins and coastal aquifers through alterations to both hydrological and nutrient cycling processes. In this Review, we identify and summarize how climate change impacts, such as changes in precipitation, increased cryosphere melt, and sea level rise, will affect water discharge and nutrient concentrations in rivers and coastal groundwater, which ultimately control nutrient inputs to the coastal ocean. We also document key limitations in the current understanding of climate-related changes to nutrient fluxes, especially in coastal groundwater basins. The impacts of climate change will interact with local human impacts, highlighting the need for studies spanning local to global scales to better understand and improve predictions of future nutrient fluxes from these hydrological pathways.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02594-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2594_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>