<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:17:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 地形控制的雪崩对 21 世纪冰川质量平衡的贡献</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-65608-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Topographically-controlled contribution of avalanches to glacier mass balance in the 21st century&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Marin Kneib; Fabien Maussion; Fanny Brun; Guillem Carcanade; Daniel Farinotti; Matthias Huss; Marit van Tiel; Achille Jouberton; Patrick Schmitt; Lilian Schuster; Amaury Dehecq; Nicolas Champollion&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;冰川通常位于陡峭的山区，周围斜坡的雪崩会强烈影响其表面的积雪模式。然而，这种效应从未对少数冰川进行过量化，而且对冰川未来演化的影响尚不清楚。我们将雪崩和冰川模型结合起来，估计雪崩对世界上所有冰川堆积的贡献，以及这如何影响它们在整个 21 世纪的演变。全球范围内，冰川上积雪的 3% 来自雪崩，1% 则因雪崩而消失。这一净贡献因地区和冰川而异，新西兰最高为 15%。考虑雪崩会改变冰川质量平衡的海拔模式和单个冰川的预计演化。主要影响包括（1）小冰川的持续时间更长，例如，在低排放情景下，中欧小于 1 km &lt;sup&gt;2 的&lt;/sup&gt;冰川保留的冰量增加了三倍，以及（2）高海拔积累区对未来变暖的敏感性增加。我们预计雪崩的相对影响在未来会增加，并主张更好地监测这一过程并在冰川模型中表示。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glaciers are often located in steep mountain settings and avalanches from surrounding slopes can strongly influence snow accumulation patterns on their surface. This effect has however never been quantified for more than a few glaciers and the impact on the future evolution of glaciers is unclear. We coupled an avalanche and a glacier model to estimate the contribution of avalanches to the accumulation of all glaciers in the world and how this affects their evolution throughout the 21st century. Globally, 3% of the snow accumulation on glaciers comes from avalanches and 1% is removed by avalanches. This net contribution varies between regions and glaciers, with a maximum of 15% for New Zealand. Accounting for avalanches modifies the altitudinal pattern of glacier mass balance and the projected evolution of individual glaciers. The main effects include (1) a longer persistence of small glaciers, with for example three times more ice retained by glaciers smaller than 1 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; in Central Europe under a low-emission scenario, and (2) an increased sensitivity of high-elevation accumulation zones to future warming. We anticipate the relative influence of avalanches to increase in the future and advocate for a better monitoring of this process and representation in glacier models.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-25966-6/MediaObjects/41598_2025_25966_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>