<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 02:14:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 通过增加的营养供应减少了最近沉积泥炭中碳的积累</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-59387-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Carbon accumulation in recently deposited peat is reduced by increased nutrient supply&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Betty Ehnvall; Joshua L. Ratcliffe; Carolina Olid; Jacob Smeds; Kevin Bishop; Jonatan Klaminder; Chuxian Li; Carl-Magnus Mörth; Mats B. Nilsson; Mats G. Öquist&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;高纬度米尔斯存储了全球土壤碳的相当一部分。当前的理解表明，湿润的条件会促进碳的积累。该范式主要基于温带的浮雕沼泽，并忽略了集水区域中矿物质水的影响，尽管大多数北方的米尔斯都是矿物源性卵子。在这里，我们表明，矿源性水是对过去世纪碳积累的主要负面影响。在上一千年中形成的米尔斯中，这种效果最为明显。除了在刺激衰减和生产力的高架中，矿化水没有提高生产率，而是刺激有机物衰减。这些发现重塑了我们对碳循环在高宽容下的理解，强调了降水 - 蒸发的变化如何影响芬斯的碳固执，而碳则在阳离子中广泛存在。与对温带地区的期望相反，我们认为，亚北极泥炭地的流域输入增加不太可能增强泥浆碳的积累。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;High-latitude mires store a considerable part of the global soil carbon. Current understanding suggests that wetter conditions promote carbon accumulation. This paradigm is based primarily on temperate ombrogenic bogs and overlooks the influence of minerogenic water from the catchment area, despite most northern mires being minerogenic fens. Here we show that minerogenic water is the main negative influence on past century carbon accumulation in boreal fens. This effect is most pronounced in mires formed during the last millennia. Rather than enhancing productivity, minerogenic water stimulates organic matter decay, apart from in elevated hummocks where both decay and productivity were stimulated. These findings reshape our understanding of carbon cycling at high-latitudes, highlighting how shifts in precipitation-evapotranspiration may impact carbon sequestration in fens, which are widespread in the circum-arctic. Contrary to expectations for temperate regions, we argue that increased catchment water input in sub-arctic peatlands is unlikely to enhance mire carbon accumulation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-59387-w/MediaObjects/41467_2025_59387_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 极端和平均降水对土地使用和土地覆盖变化的不同反应</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01049-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Different responses of extreme and mean precipitation to land use and land cover changes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Meng Zhang; Yanhong Gao; Jun Ge&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;土地利用和土地覆盖变化（LULCCS）可以通过表面能量，水通量和大规模大气循环的变化来影响降水，这对自然和社会的可持续发展产生了很大的影响。但是，与平均变化相比，这些贡献者对极端降水变化的影响和机制仍需要研究。在这里，我们使用水分预算方程将基于CMIP6-LUMIP实验的三个主要因素（蒸散量，大气平均循环和水蒸气）分解为三个主要因素（蒸散量，大气平均循环和水蒸气）。由于历史（1995- 2014年）和未来（2080-2099）时期，由于LULCCS引起的平均降水量的全球减少可以归因于蒸散和大气平均循环的贡献相对较高。相反，在最高干燥月份，降水减少大约是多年平均变化的2-3倍。代表平均循环变化的动态贡献者超过蒸散量，因为驱动大多数景观的主要降水量减少的主要因素。 LULCCS引起的极端降水变化的社会经济影响大于平均状态的社会经济影响，尤其是将来。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Land use and land cover changes (LULCCs) can influence precipitation via changes in surface energy, water flux, and large-scale atmospheric circulation, with great implications for the sustainable development of nature and society. However, the impacts and mechanisms of these contributors to extreme precipitation changes compared with mean changes still need to be investigated. Here, we used the moisture budget equation to decompose precipitation changes into three primary contributing factors (evapotranspiration, atmospheric mean circulation, and water vapor) based on CMIP6-LUMIP experiments. A global reduction in mean precipitation due to LULCCs can be attributed to relatively equal contributions of changes in evapotranspiration and atmospheric mean circulation over the historical (1995–2014) and future (2080–2099) periods. In contrast, during the top drying month, the precipitation reduction is approximately 2–3 times greater than the multi-year mean change. The dynamic contributor representing the mean circulation change surpasses evapotranspiration as the primary contributor driving the extreme precipitation decrease in the majority of the landscape. The socioeconomic impacts of LULCCs-induced extreme precipitation changes are greater than those of the mean state, especially in the future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01049-1/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1049_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>