<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 01:39:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 跨越1940  -  2023年的地表水质的全面数据集用于经验和ML采用的研究</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04715-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A Comprehensive Dataset of Surface Water Quality Spanning 1940-2023 for Empirical and ML Adopted Research&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Md. Rajaul Karim; M. M. Mahbubul Syeed; Ashifur Rahman; Khondkar Ayaz Rabbani; Kaniz Fatema; Razib Hayat Khan; Md Shakhawat Hossain; Mohammad Faisal Uddin&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;对地表水质的评估和监测对于粮食安全，公共卫生和生态系统保护至关重要。尽管水质监测是一种已知现象，但在全球范围内为地表水提供了全面且协调的数据集的努力。这项研究提出了一个全面的地表水质数据集，可保留数据的时空变异性，完整性，一致性和数据深度，以促进经验和数据驱动的评估，预测和预测。该数据集由来自世界五个著名国家，例如美国，美国，加拿大，爱尔兰，英国和中国的各种来源组装，包括区域和全球水质数据库，水管理组织以及个人研究项目。最终的数据集由跨越1940年至2023年的八个水质参数的282万个测量值组成。该数据集可以支持水质模型的荟萃分析，并可以促进基于机器的数据（ML）数据以及基于模型的空间和时间驱动器研究的研究，并促进了空间和时间驱动因素的调查，以及在整体规模的交叉范围的地表水质的模式。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Assessment and monitoring of surface water quality are essential for food security, public health, and ecosystem protection. Although water quality monitoring is a known phenomenon, little effort has been made to offer a comprehensive and harmonized dataset for surface water at the global scale. This study presents a comprehensive surface water quality dataset that preserves spatio-temporal variability, integrity, consistency, and depth of the data to facilitate empirical and data-driven evaluation, prediction, and forecasting. The dataset is assembled from a range of sources, including regional and global water quality databases, water management organizations, and individual research projects from five prominent countries in the world, e.g., the USA, Canada, Ireland, England, and China. The resulting dataset consists of 2.82 million measurements of eight water quality parameters that span 1940 - 2023. This dataset can support meta-analysis of water quality models and can facilitate Machine Learning (ML) based data and model-driven investigation of the spatial and temporal drivers and patterns of surface water quality at a cross-regional to global scale.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04715-4/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4715_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>