<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 02:14:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 北美东部纬度的全新世湿度变异性的模式和驱动因素</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-58685-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Patterns and drivers of Holocene moisture variability in mid-latitude eastern North America&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; J. Sakari Salonen; Frederik Schenk; John W. Williams; Bryan Shuman; Ana L. Lindroth Dauner; Sebastian Wagner; Johann Jungclaus; Qiong Zhang; Miska Luoto&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;东部北美氢化气候的代理数据表明，全新世期间强烈而持久的多千禧一代干旱，但气候模型模拟通常无法再现替代性的干旱。诊断数据 - 模型不匹配可以提供有关水文变异性驱动因素以及对氢化气候强迫的不同敏感性的有价值的见解。在这里，我们提出了一个代理 - 模型合成，用于在北美中部纬度地区全新世气候，包括基于机器的水平平衡重建和高分辨率气候模拟。这些数据模型结果解决了先前的不一致之处，显示了全新世氢化变化的时空模式，并能够评估驾驶机制。该协议表明，世俗的夏季日光照射趋势与劳伦德冰片回发展及其对大气循环的影响相结合，共同解释了较干燥的气候的程度和持续时间。此外，我们的高分辨率代理数据和瞬态模拟揭示了明显的多年气候变化。在我们的模拟中，温度驱动的蒸散量的增加超过了区域降水的增长，在全新世中期大部分地区干燥。这表明，与本世纪中期北美预测的干燥轨迹相比，中新世多千禧一代的干旱是由类似过程驱动的，该过程也主要由变暖驱动。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Proxy data for eastern North American hydroclimate indicate strong and persistent multi-millennial droughts during the Holocene, but climate model simulations often fail to reproduce the proxy-inferred droughts. Diagnosing the data–model mismatch can offer valuable insights about the drivers of hydrological variability and different regional sensitivities to hydroclimate forcing. Here we present a proxy–modeling synthesis for Holocene climates in the eastern North American mid-latitudes, including machine-learning-based water balance reconstructions and high-resolution climate simulations. These data-model results resolve prior-generation inconsistencies, show consistent spatiotemporal patterns of Holocene hydroclimate change, and enable assessment of the driving mechanisms. This agreement suggests that the secular summer insolation trend, combined with the Laurentide Ice Sheet deglaciation and its effect on atmospheric circulation, together explain the extent and duration of drier-than-present climates. In addition, our high-resolution proxy data and transient simulations reveal clear multi-centennial climate variability. In our simulations, temperature-driven increases in evapotranspiration exceed regional precipitation gains, drying much of the region during the mid Holocene. This suggests that the mid-Holocene multi-millennial drought was driven by similar processes compared to the drying trajectory projected for mid-latitude North America over this century, which is also primarily driven by warming.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-58685-7/MediaObjects/41467_2025_58685_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 细胞尺度的大气水分流量数据集与ERA5重新分析对帐</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04964-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Cell-scale atmospheric moisture flows dataset reconciled with ERA5 reanalysis&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Elena De Petrillo; Luca Monaco; Marta Tuninetti; Arie Staal; Francesco Laio&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;大气中的水蒸气流是水文循环的基础，将蒸发源与降水量下水道联系起来。最近的大气跟踪模型提供了宝贵的见解，使人们可以追踪降水的来源，并确定特定地区的蒸发水最终将沉淀。尽管改善了模型的准确性，但重建和观察到的蒸发和重新分析的降水数据之间仍然存在显着差异。为了解决这些差异并提高跟踪模型估计的可靠性，我们提出了一个基于迭代比例拟合（IPF）的程序。使用这种方法，我们通过Lagrangian Model Utrack与ERA5重新分析数据重建大气水分流。这样可以确保追踪的大气水与每年的总蒸发和降水匹配。和解的双边连接提供了一个以2008-2017期为中心的新数据集（RECON），该数据集促进了在全球尺度上以0.5°的空间分辨率在全球尺度上蒸发和降水量之间的大气蒸气流的探索。此外，提出的框架适用于任何大气水分跟踪的细胞尺度数据集。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water vapour flows in the atmosphere are fundamental to the hydrological cycle, linking evaporation sources to precipitation sinks. Recent atmospheric tracking models have provided valuable insights, allowing one to trace the sources of precipitation and determine where evaporated water from specific regions will eventually precipitate. Despite improvements in model accuracy, there remain significant discrepancies between reconstructed and observed evaporation and precipitation data from reanalysis. To address these discrepancies and enhance the reliability of tracking models’ estimates, we propose a procedure based on Iterative Proportional Fitting (IPF). Using this approach, we reconcile atmospheric moisture flows reconstructed by the Lagrangian model UTrack with ERA5 reanalysis data. This ensures that the traced atmospheric water matches the total evaporation and the precipitation annually. The reconciled bilateral connections provide a new dataset (RECON) centred on the period 2008-2017 that facilitates the exploration of atmospheric vapour flows between evaporation and precipitation basins at the global scale with a spatial resolution of 0.5°. Further, the proposed framework applies to any cell-scale dataset of atmospheric moisture tracking.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04964-3/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4964_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>