<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:21:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 伊朗主要含水层水稳定同位素数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06000-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A Dataset of Water Stable Isotopes in Iran’s Main Aquifers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Omid Karimi; Roohollah Noori; Saman Javadi; Changhyun Jun; Sayed M. Bateni; Bahram Choubin; Mojtaba Noury; Mojtaba Heydarizad; Peiman Kianmehr; Qiuhong Tang; Frederic Huneau; Severin Pistre&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;尽管全球水稳定同位素数据库（δ &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt; O和δ &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; H）的数量不断增加，但发展中国家（例如伊朗）的可获取地下水稳定同位素数据却明显缺乏。为了填补这一空白，我们于 2023 年 10 月开展了一次采样活动，测量伊朗 10 个主要含水层的 202 口井、泉水和坎儿井中的 δ &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt; O 和 δ &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; H。我们还计算了所研究的含水层中的二阶水同位素变量，即氘过量（D-过量）和线条件过量（LC-过量），从而深入了解降水产生和动态。此外，我们还确定了每个含水层的当地大气水位线 (LMWL)。研究含水层中的 δ &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; H、δ &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt; O、D-过剩和 LC-过剩值分别为 –79.21 至 –27.81 (‰)、–11.95 至 –4.68 (‰)、–5.99 至 24.26 (‰) 和 –8.18 至 4.37 (‰)。在所研究的含水层计算的 10 个 LMWL 中，有 8 个的坡度低于全球大气水位线。我们的数据集为所研究的含水层中的水文气象和污染途径提供了新的见解，这些含水层满足了伊朗一半以上人口的用水需求。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Although the number of global water stable isotope databases (δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O and δ&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;H) is growing, accessible groundwater stable isotope data on developing countries (e.g., Iran), are conspicuously lacking. To fill this gap, we conducted a sampling campaign during October 2023 to measure δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O and δ&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;H in 202 wells, springs, and qanats across 10 main aquifers in Iran. We also calculated the second-order water isotopic variables, namely deuterium-excess (D-excess) and line-conditioned excess (LC-excess), in the studied aquifers, which provide insight into precipitation production and dynamics. Additionally, we determined the local meteoric water line (LMWL) for each aquifer. δ&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;H, δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O, D-excess, and LC-excess values in the studied aquifers varied from –79.21 to –27.81 (‰), –11.95 to –4.68 (‰), –5.99 to 24.26 (‰), and –8.18 to 4.37 (‰), respectively. Eight out of the 10 calculated LMWLs for the studied aquifers had a lower slope than the global meteoric water line. Our dataset offers new insights into hydro-meteorological and pollution pathways in the studied aquifers, which supply the water needs for over half of Iran’s population.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06000-w/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6000_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 用于近岸波浪破碎类型分类的视频数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06005-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A Video Dataset for Nearshore Wave Breaking Type Classification&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hang Yin; Feng Cai; Hongshuai Qi; Jixiang Zheng; Bipeng Hui; Xi Wu; Kai Liu; Xi Chen&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;破浪类型是近岸水动力过程的基本指标，直接反映波浪能量耗散机制。随着岸基视频监控的进步，遥感已成为识别波浪破碎类型的有效工具。然而，现有的研究主要依赖静态单帧图像，限制了捕捉突发事件动态演变的能力。在这项工作中，我们提出了第一个专门用于波浪破碎类型分类的公开视频数据集。该数据集包含 9,000 个标记的波浪破碎片段，这些片段是从 6 个形态多样的沿海地点的 15 个摄像机收集的，涵盖三种主要破碎类型：溢出、骤降和涌动。为了提高数据集的质量和一致性，实施了严格的数据管理工作流程，包括视频分割、裁剪、标签和帧提取。使用完善的深度学习架构结合 CNN 和 RNN 进行分类实验，取得了最先进的性能。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Wave breaking type is a fundamental indicator of nearshore hydrodynamic processes, directly reflecting wave energy dissipation mechanisms. With the advancement of shore-based video monitoring, remote sensing has emerged as an efficient tool for identifying wave breaking types. However, existing studies predominantly rely on static single-frame imagery, limiting the ability to capture the dynamic evolution of breaking events. In this work, we present the first publicly available video dataset dedicated to wave breaking type classification. The dataset comprises 9,000 labeled wave breaking clips collected from 15 cameras across six morphologically diverse coastal sites, encompassing three primary breaking types: Spilling, Plunging, and Surging. To enhance the dataset’s quality and consistency, a rigorous data curation workflow was implemented, including video segmentation, cropping, labeling, and frame extraction. Classification experiments using a well-established deep learning architecture combing CNN and RNN achieved state-of-the-art performance.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06005-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6005_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>