<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 02:39:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | ECIRA-从2010年至2020年，每年1公里的欧洲作物特异性灌溉面积</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05628-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;ECIRA - European crop-specific irrigated area at 1 km resolution annually from 2010 to 2020&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Wanxue Zhu; Josef Baumert; Hugo Storm; Thomas Heckelei; Stefan Siebert&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;灌溉显着有助于总水抽水，并表现出很大的空间和时间变异性，尤其是在更潮湿的地区。这种变异性是由气候，土壤特性和作物水需求引起的。但是，欧洲的高分辨率，特定于作物的灌溉面积数据的时间序列仍然很少。我们开发了一种方法来协调有关农作物类型和灌溉的投入数据，以获取欧洲作物特异性灌溉面积（ECIRA）数据集，为2010年至2020年的28个欧洲国家提供16种农作物类型的年度1公里网格特定的灌溉面积。 ECIRA数据集有效地确定了特定于农作物的灌溉热点，与次生人口普查数据保持一致，并且与Lucas现场观察和其他基于调查的作物特异性灌溉面积数据集非常吻合。但是，对于特定于地区和位置的研究需要谨慎，因为ECIRA的范围范围需要在当地细节和整体一致性之间进行权衡。它可以用于评估农作物生产力和作物用水，作为土地表面，作物和水文建模，气候影响研究的投入，并支持改善水资源管理。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Irrigation significantly contributes to total water withdrawal and exhibits considerable spatial and temporal variability, particularly in more humid regions. This variability is caused by climate, soil properties, and crop water requirements. However, time series of high-resolution, crop-specific irrigated area data remain scarce in Europe. We developed and applied a method to harmonize input data on crop types and irrigation to obtain the European Crop-specific IRrigated Area (ECIRA) dataset, providing annual 1-km gridded crop-specific irrigated area for 16 crop types across 28 European countries for 2010–2020. The ECIRA dataset effectively identifies crop-specific irrigated hotspots, aligns with subnational census data, and strongly agrees with LUCAS field observations and other survey-based crop-specific irrigation area datasets. However, caution is needed for region- and location-specific studies, as the Europe-wide scope of ECIRA entails a trade-off between local details and overall consistency. It can be used in assessments of crop productivity and crop water use, as input in land surface-, crop-, and hydrological modeling, in climate impact studies and to support improved water resources management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05628-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5628_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 亚洲高山的全面水体数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05659-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A comprehensive water bodies dataset of high-mountain Asia&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yijie Sui; Zhimin Hu; Kuo Zhang; Dezhao Yan; Yanan Su; Jinhao Xu; Ruilin Wang; Min Feng&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;高山亚洲（HMA）拥有许多对气候变化高度敏感的水体。但是，由于该地区的复杂地形和极端的环境条件，其中许多，尤其是小型的人，仍然对其进行了研究。在这项研究中，我们提出了一个多阶段分割 - 分类框架，该框架将光谱 - 纹理特征提取与基于对象的细化结合在一起。该方法表明，即使在复杂的成像条件下，也可以提高检测小至0.001 km &lt;sup&gt;2的&lt;/sup&gt;水体的能力。验证显示，与现有卫星衍生的数据集相比，误差的单位级别错误分类率为0.1％，误报降低了88％，尤其是来自阴影和非水贴的单位分类率。因此，我们在HMA上产生了451,777个水体的全面库存，使以前的记录增加了一倍以上。该数据集包括形态和水文属性（例如，面积，周边，连通性），冰川区域中有83,246个水体（比以前的估计多2-6倍），多年冻土区域中有274,039个水体，其中16.6％是新鉴定的小水体（&amp;lt;3 km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ）。这些结果为理解这个气候脆弱区域的水动态提供了关键的资源。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;High-Mountain Asia (HMA) hosts numerous water bodies that are highly sensitive to climate change. However, many of them, especially small ones, remain understudied due to the region’s complex terrain and extreme environmental conditions. In this study, we propose a multi-stage segmentation–classification framework that combines spectral–textural feature extraction with object-based refinement. This method demonstrates enhanced capabilities for detecting water bodies as small as 0.001 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, even under complex imaging conditions. Validation shows a unit-level misclassification rate of 0.1% and an 88% reduction in false positives, particularly from shadows and non-water patches, compared to existing satellite-derived datasets. Consequently, we generated a comprehensive inventory of 451,777 water bodies across the HMA, more than doubling previous records. The dataset includes morphological and hydrological attributes (e.g., area, perimeter, connectivity), with 83,246 water bodies in glacial regions (2–6 times more than previous estimates) and 274,039 in permafrost regions, 16.6% of which are newly identified small water bodies (&amp;lt;3 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;). These results provide a critical resource for understanding water dynamics in this climatically vulnerable region.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05659-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5659_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>