<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 02:56:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 在当前和将来的情况下，全球南方的城市洪水暴露量比全球北部高</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02585-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Global South shows higher urban flood exposures than the Global North under current and future scenarios&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Qian Zhang; Chunlin Li; Ding Wen; Jieming Kang; Tan Chen; Baolei Zhang; Yuanman Hu; Jiabo Yin; Louise Slater&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;近几十年来，城市化加剧了，引起了人们对增加城市洪水暴露的担忧。在这里，我们评估了城市洪水暴露在建立区域，人口和经济活动中，该地区受100年河流洪水事件影响的区域内。我们使用从2000年到2020年的全球历史数据以及在共享的社会经济途径下从2030年到2100的未来预测。从2000年到2020年，全球城市洪水的暴露量大大增加，东亚最严重的影响是非洲最快的增长。未来的接触持续增长，尤其是在高风险发展方案下。从2030年到2100年，全球南部洪水泛滥的城市地区，人口和经济分别超过两次，近五倍，是全球北部的两倍。在发展中的不平等现象比发达的地区更大。预计这些差异是为了扩大，强调了迫切需要针对针对性的地区特定策略来降低洪水风险的策略。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Urbanization has intensified in recent decades, raising concerns about increasing flood exposure in cities. Here, we assess urban flood exposure in terms of built-up area, population, and economic activity located within zones affected by 1-in-100-year river flood events. We use global historical data from 2000 to 2020 and future projections from 2030 to 2100 under the Shared Socioeconomic Pathways. From 2000 to 2020, global urban flood exposure increased substantially, with the most severe impacts in East Asia and the fastest growth in Africa. Future exposure continues to rise, especially under high-risk development scenarios. From 2030 to 2100, flood-exposed urban area, population, and economy in Global South are more than twice, nearly five times, and over twice those in Global North, respectively. Inequality in exposure is greater within developing regions than developed ones. These disparities are projected to widen, highlighting the urgent need for targeted, region-specific strategies to reduce flood risks.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02585-7/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2585_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | Camelsh：一个小时的水文气象数据集和分水岭的属性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05612-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;CAMELSH: A Large-Sample Hourly Hydrometeorological Dataset and Attributes at Watershed-Scale for CONUS&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Vinh Ngoc Tran; Donghui Xu; Tam Van Nguyen; Taeho Kim; Valeriy Y. Ivanov&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;我们提出了Camelsh（用于大样本研究的流域属性和每小时的水文气象），这是连续美国的小时尺度上的第一个大样本水文学数据集。 Camelsh将每小时的气象时间序列，GAGES-II和Hydroatlas的流域属性和边界融合到各种气候，水文和人为条件下的9,008个集水区。此外，为3,166个流域提供了每小时流量的时间序列。数据集跨越了45年（1980- 2024年），其中有11个来自NLDAS-2的气象变量迫使数据集，我们从中计算出与降水，蒸散量，季节性和降雪分数有关的9个气候指数。此外，Camelsh还包括两组集水属性：GAGES-II的439，从Hydroatlas衍生出195个。这些属性包括与气候，地质，水文学，河流形态，景观，养分，土壤，地形和人为影响有关的因素。 Camelsh是根据公平的（可访问性，互操作性和可重复性）原则开发的，是每小时时间尺度上的第一个大样本数据集，为短期水流（洪水）预测的机器学习应用程序提供了支持，并推进了多个时标的数据驱动的数据驱动的水文研究。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We present CAMELSH (Catchment Attributes and Hourly HydroMeteorology for Large-Sample Studies), the first large-sample hydrometeorological dataset at the hourly scale for the contiguous United States. CAMELSH intergrates hourly meteorological time series, catchment attributes and boundaries from GAGES-II and HydroATLAS for 9,008 catchments across diverse climatic, hydrological, and anthropogenic conditions. In addition, hourly streamflow time series is provided for 3,166 catchments. The dataset spans 45 years (1980–2024) with 11 meteorological variables from the NLDAS-2 forcing dataset, from which we compute nine climate indices related to precipitation, evapotranspiration, seasonality, and snow fraction. Additionally, CAMELSH includes two sets of catchment attributes: 439 from GAGES-II and 195 derived from HydroATLAS. These attributes include factors related to climate, geology, hydrology, river/stream morphology, landscape, nutrient, soil, topography, and anthropogenic influences. Developed in accordance with FAIR (Findability, Accessibility, Interoperability, and Reusability) principles, CAMELSH is the first large-sample dataset at an hourly timescale, supporting machine learning applications for short-term streamflow (flood) prediction and advancing data-driven hydrological research across multiple timescales.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05612-6/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5612_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>