<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 02:13:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 预计近期跨赤道北风涌流的变化及其水文影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01239-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Projected changes in cross-equatorial northerly surges and their hydrological impacts in the near future&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Sandro W. Lubis; Chuan-Chieh Chang; Samson Hagos; Ming Zhao; Ziming Chen; Karthik Balaguru; L. Ruby Leung&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;近几十年来，东南亚一些人口最稠密的地区在寒冬期间出现了前所未有的极端降水和灾难性洪水。这些极端事件经常受到跨赤道偏北气流（CENS）的影响，其特点是西海洋大陆赤道以南偏北潮湿季风的加强。然而，CENS 未来潜在的变化及其水文影响仍未得到充分探索。在这里，我们使用高分辨率气候模型模拟集合（CMIP6 HighResMIP）表明，CENS 对极端降水事件的强度和频率的区域影响预计在不久的将来（2030-2050 年）将显着增加，特别是在印度尼西亚南部和澳大利亚西北部的邻近沿海地区。更具体地说，尽管 CENS 特征在不久的将来没有明显变化，但与季节概率相比，与 CENS 相关的极端降水风险预计将增加高达 39 ± 1.2%。这种更强的影响归因于更潮湿和更温暖的环境导致润湿效率和湿静态不稳定性的增强，从而导致更强烈的CENS对流。我们的结果表明，需要有效的监测和灾害管理，以应对在不久的将来此类事件日益严重的情况。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Recent decades have witnessed unprecedented extreme precipitation and catastrophic flooding in some of the most populated regions in Southeast Asia during boreal winter. These extreme events are often influenced by the cross-equatorial northerly surge (CENS), characterized by a strengthening of northerly moist monsoon winds south of the equator in the western Maritime Continent. However, the potential future changes in CENS and its hydrological impacts remain underexplored. Here, using an ensemble of high-resolution climate model simulations (CMIP6 HighResMIP), we show that the regional impacts of CENS on the intensity and frequency of extreme precipitation events are projected to significantly increase in the near future (2030–2050), particularly over the adjacent coastal regions of southern Indonesia and northwestern Australia. More specifically, the risk of CENS-related extreme precipitation is projected to increase by up to 39 ± 1.2% relative to the seasonal probability, despite no apparent changes in the CENS characteristics in the near future. Such stronger impact is attributed to the enhanced moistening efficiency and moist static instability due to a more humid and warmer environment, which leads to more intense CENS convection. Our results suggest the need for effective monitoring and disaster managements to respond to the increasing severity of such events in the near future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01239-x/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1239_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 阐明美国本土降水和水流对变暖的敏感性之间的松散联系</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01257-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Elucidating the loose tie between precipitation and streamflow sensitivities to warming across the contiguous United States&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Marc Prange; Ming Zhao; Elena Shevliakova; Sergey Malyshev&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;区域降水和径流对变暖的敏感性的关系变得复杂，因为径流通常是降水和蒸散之间平衡中的小残留物。此外，土地水文特性的不均匀性和人类的水文干预（如灌溉和水坝）使得水流敏感性难以用气候模型和观测来约束。在这里，我们使用 GFDL 的中等高分辨率全球气候模型，在反事实的变暖情景中阐明了驱动美国本土地区不同的平均和极端水流对变暖的敏感性的水文过程。我们表明，在美国西海岸和东部，大气河流是当前气候下高流量以及气候变暖时更频繁高流量的主要驱动因素。在美国西部山区，尽管降水量和先前的土壤湿度有所增加，但径流却在减少，因为降雪的减少会加速蒸散，其速度是降水变化速度的两倍。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The relation of regional precipitation and streamflow sensitivities to warming is complicated by runoff often being the small residual in the balance between precipitation and evapotranspiration. In addition, the inhomogeneous nature of land-hydrological properties and hydrological interventions by humans, like irrigation and dams, have made streamflow sensitivities challenging to constrain with both climate models and observations. Here, we elucidate the hydrological processes driving the regionally varying mean and extreme streamflow sensitivities to warming across the contiguous United States in a counter-factual warming scenario using GFDL’s moderately high-resolution global climate model. We show that over the West Coast and eastern US, atmospheric rivers are the dominant driver of high-flows in the present climate and of more frequent high-flows in a warmer climate. Over the mountainous western US, streamflows dwindle despite increases in precipitation and antecedent soil moisture, as loss of snow fuels evapotranspiration at double the rate of precipitation changes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01257-9/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1257_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 孟加拉国水文地貌灾害暴露程度的差异</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-64920-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Disparities in exposure to hydrogeomorphic hazards in Bangladesh&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Amelie Paszkowski; Timothy Tiggeloven; Edoardo Borgomeo; Jim W. Hall&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;自然灾害会损害社会经济发展。虽然人们对各种自然灾害的暴露程度已经被量化，但水文地貌灾害（包括水引起的景观变化）的暴露程度仍然未知。本研究以孟加拉国为案例研究，利用高分辨率水文地貌模型，结合人口和财富数据，对人口和财富群体的水文地貌灾害暴露程度进行了全国范围的空间评估。孟加拉国是一个地质动态极其丰富的国家，这里存在多种灾害，同时人口稠密（每&lt;sup&gt;平方公里&lt;/sup&gt;1300 人）和高贫困率（20%）。在这里，我们显示超过 2200 万人（占人口的 13%）生活在水文地貌不稳定的地区。在这 2200 万人中，86% 属于人口中最低财富群体。鉴于暴露程度如此之大，水文地貌灾害必须纳入孟加拉国及其他地区的灾害风险管理和扶贫工作中。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Natural hazards can impair socio-economic development. While population exposure to various natural hazards has been quantified, the exposure to hydrogeomorphic hazards – involving water-induced landscape changes – remains unknown. Using high-resolution hydrogeomorphic modelling, combined with population and wealth data, this study provides a national-scale spatial assessment of exposure to hydrogeomorphic hazards across population and wealth groups, taking Bangladesh as a case study. Bangladesh is an exceptionally geo-dynamic country, where multiple hazards coincide with a dense population (1300 people per km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;) and a high poverty rate (20%). Here we show that over 22 million people, making up 13% of the population, live within hydrogeomorphically unstable regions. Of the 22 million, 86% are within the lowest wealth groups of the population. Given such a high level of disparity in exposure, hydrogeomorphic hazards must be incorporated into disaster risk management and poverty alleviation efforts in Bangladesh and beyond.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-64920-y/MediaObjects/41467_2025_64920_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 最近由南极放大引发的安第斯山脉中南部水危机是过去八个世纪以来前所未有的</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02858-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Recent south-central Andes water crisis driven by Antarctic amplification is unprecedented over the last eight centuries&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Shijie Wang; Mao Hu; Feng Chen; Xiaoen Zhao; Martín A. Hadad; Fidel A. Roig; David M. Meko; Max C. A. Torbenson; Sergio Piraino; Heli Zhang; Yang Xu; Youping Chen; Weipeng Yue; Honghua Cao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;发源于安第斯山脉的河流是满足南美洲农业和社会需求的重要水源，但日益受到气候变化的威胁。在这里，我们利用安第斯山脉中南部山麓的树木年轮记录重建了过去 827 年巴塔哥尼亚北部内格罗河 (Rió Negro) 的水流。这次重建揭示了近几十年来河流流量前所未有的下降。厄尔尼诺-南方涛动和南方环模产生的水分提供了关键的水源，但气温上升增加了大气水分需求并降低了可用性。南极的放大进一步扰乱了环流模式，加速了变暖，加剧了区域干旱。自 20 世纪以来，内格罗河的流量持续减少，每十年约 10%。各种排放情景下的预测表明排放量持续下降，凸显了迫切需要采取适应性水管理战略，以缓解该地区不断升级的水资源短缺风险。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Rivers originating from the Andes Mountains are vital water sources for agricultural and societal needs in South America, yet are increasingly threatened by climate change. Here we reconstruct streamflow of the Negro River (Rió Negro) in northern Patagonia over the past 827 years using tree-ring records from the south-central Andes foothills. This reconstruction reveals an unprecedented decline in river flow in recent decades. Moisture from the El Niño–Southern Oscillation and the Southern Annular Mode provides a key water source, but temperature rise has increased atmospheric moisture demand and reduced availability. Antarctic amplification has further disrupted circulation patterns and accelerated warming, intensifying regional aridity. Since the 20th century, the Negro River has experienced a sustained flow reduction of approximately 10% per decade. Projections under various emission scenarios indicate continued decline, highlighting the urgent need for adaptive water management strategies to mitigate escalating water scarcity risks in the region.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02858-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2858_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 南加州极端洪水的多尺度驱动因素：ENSO、MJO、北太平洋急流和大气河流</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01242-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Multiscale drivers of extreme southern California flooding: ENSO, MJO, North Pacific jet, and atmospheric rivers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Edoardo Mazza; Shuyi S. Chen; Brandon W. Kerns; Andrew C. Winters&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2024 年 2 月，在 2023 年至 2024 年厄尔尼诺现象期间，由强大的大气河 (AR) 和持续的马登-朱利安振荡 (MJO) 驱动的极端降雨和洪水袭击了南加州，影响了超过 1000 万人。 AR 是造成美国西海岸极端降雨和洪水的主要原因。尽管 AR-MJO 联系已被记录，但其时空变异性仍然是预测和风险管理的主要挑战。结合降水量、流量计和人口数据，我们量化了这一极端事件的物理驱动因素和人口暴露程度。利用拉格朗日 MJO 降水跟踪算法，我们揭示了 AR 发展的多尺度相互作用。厄尔尼诺现象有利于一个大型、寿命长的 MJO，它与北太平洋急流 (NPJ) 相互作用超过三周。 MJO 对流流出通过沿对流层顶引起负位涡平流来调节 NPJ。随后的 NPJ 延伸和加速引发了爆炸性气旋，其 AR 驱动的水分输送导致了极端降雨。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Extreme rainfall and flooding, driven by a powerful atmospheric river (AR) and a persistent Madden-Julian Oscillation (MJO), hit Southern California in February 2024 during the 2023–2024 El Niño, affecting over 10 million people. ARs are key contributors to extreme rainfall and flooding along the U.S. West Coast. Although the AR-MJO link has been documented, its spatio-temporal variability remains a major forecasting and risk-management challenge. Combining precipitation, stream gauge and demographic data, we quantify the physical drivers and population exposure to this extreme event. Leveraging a Lagrangian MJO precipitation tracking algorithm, we unravel the multiscale interactions responsible for the AR’s development. El Niño favored a large, long-lived MJO that interacted with the North Pacific Jet (NPJ) over more than three weeks. The MJO convective outflow modulated the NPJ by inducing negative potential vorticity advection along the tropopause. The ensuing NPJ extension and acceleration induced explosive cyclogenesis, whose AR-driven moisture transport resulted in extreme rainfall.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01242-2/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1242_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>