<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 02:17:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 撒西尔以下非洲地区季节性湖动力学模式的气候基准</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02684-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A climatological baseline for understanding patterns of seasonal lake dynamics across sub-Sahelian Africa&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; M. Amadori; A. J. Greife; L. Carrea; M. Pinardi; R. Caroni; E. Calamita; L. Serrao; R. Maidment; S. Bordoni; C. Giardino; M. Bresciani; F. P. Fava; M. Schmid; M. Ndebele-Murisa; T. Nhiwatiwa; J-F. Crétaux; C. J. Merchant; X. Liu; S. Simis; D. Lomeo; H. Yesou; C. Albergel; R. I. Woolway&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;撒西亚以南非洲的湖泊正面临着气候变化和人类的生态威胁，但大多数研究都集中在少数知名的大湖泊上。这项研究分析了137个以前研究过的湖泊，并确定了气象变量，卫星衍生的湖泊物理和生物地球化学变量以及形态和人为特征的季节性共同可定性模式。我们确定了四个不同的湖泊簇，这是由大气变异性及其与水温季节性同步的塑造。在每个群集中，我们观察到与湿季节有关的三种季节性模式。这些模式与非洲区域气候威胁一致，例如降雨季节性的转变，热带气旋和野火的频率改变，从而将我们的研究定位为评估撒西亚郊区湖泊脆弱性的框架。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lakes in sub-Sahelian Africa are facing growing ecological threats from climate change and human, yet most research has focused on a handful of well-known large lakes. This study analyses 137 lakes, many previously understudied, and identifies consistent seasonal co-variability patterns across meteorological variables, satellite-derived lake physical and biogeochemical variables, and morphological and anthropogenic characteristics. We identify four distinct clusters of lakes, shaped by the atmospheric variability and its synchrony with water temperature seasonality. Within each cluster, we observe three seasonal patterns of chlorophyll-a concentration tied to wet and dry seasons. These patterns align with regional climatic threats in Africa, such as shifts in rainfall seasonality, altered frequency of tropical cyclones and wildfires, thus positioning our study as a framework to assess lake vulnerability across the sub-Sahelian region.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02684-5/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2684_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>