<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 02:11:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 机器学习显示使用近地表气象时雨水分配精度的限制</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-58234-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Machine learning shows a limit to rain-snow partitioning accuracy when using near-surface meteorology&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Keith S. Jennings; Meghan Collins; Benjamin J. Hatchett; Anne Heggli; Nayoung Hur; Sonia Tonino; Anne W. Nolin; Guo Yu; Wei Zhang; Monica M. Arienzo&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;将降水分解为近地面气象的雨水和雪是一个众所周知的挑战。但是，是否存在限制其潜在性能仍然未知。在这里，我们通过将一组基准降水阶段分配方法以及三个机器学习（ML）模型（人工神经网络，随机森林和XGBoost）应用于两个独立数据集来评估这种可能性：38.5万个人群观测和1780万个共宣传气象报告。 ML方法对最佳基准的改进可忽略不计，仅将准确性提高高达0.6％，并使雨水偏见减少高达-4.7％。 ML方法无法鉴定混合降水和亚冻结降雨事件，同时表达其最差的精​​度为1.0°C – 2.5°C。这些缺点的潜在原因是雨水分布中的气温重叠（峰值在1.0°C – 1.6°C之间），该空气温度在分配精度的情况下表达了显着的负关系（P &amp;lt;0.0005）。因此，在略高于冷冻的空气温度下，雨水和雪的气象特征相似，随着与性能降低相关的重叠增加。我们建议研究人员将重点从使用近乎表面气象的固有有限的降水阶段分配方法略微改善，转换为创建吸收新型数据源的新方法 -  EG，众包降水阶段观察。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Partitioning precipitation into rain and snow with near-surface meteorology is a well-known challenge. However, whether a limit exists to its potential performance remains unknown. Here, we evaluate this possibility by applying a set of benchmark precipitation phase partitioning methods plus three machine learning (ML) models (an artificial neural network, random forest, and XGBoost) to two independent datasets: 38.5 thousand crowdsourced observations and 17.8 million synoptic meteorology reports. The ML methods provide negligible improvements over the best benchmarks, increasing accuracy only by up to 0.6% and reducing rain and snow biases by up to -4.7%. ML methods fail to identify mixed precipitation and sub-freezing rainfall events, while expressing their worst accuracy values from 1.0 °C–2.5 °C. A potential cause of these shortcomings is the air temperature overlap in rain and snow distributions (peaking between 1.0 °C–1.6 °C), which expresses a significant negative relationship (p &amp;lt; 0.0005) with partitioning accuracy. Thus, the meteorological characteristics of rain and snow are similar at air temperatures slightly above freezing with increasing overlap associated with decreasing performance. We suggest researchers switch their focus from marginally improving inherently limited precipitation phase partitioning methods using near-surface meteorology to creating new methods that assimilate novel data sources—e.g., crowdsourced precipitation phase observations.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-58234-2/MediaObjects/41467_2025_58234_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>