<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 02:39:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature | 带有侧向水文流的全球湿度指数</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09359-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A global humidity index with lateral hydrologic flows&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Gonzalo Miguez-Macho; Ying Fan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;干旱指数广泛用于指示土地上的水量。平衡气候供水（降水，P）与需求（潜在的蒸发，PET），通常表示为P/PET比率&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;或湿度指数。水也由河流和地下水横向流动，从山丘到山谷，从山到平原，补贴了接收低地&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; 。在这里，我们表明这种横向补贴降低了接收低地的干旱。我们首先通过30英寸全球网格通过全球水文学模型来估计地表和地下水的每月补贴（QLAT）。然后，我们将常规的全局湿度指数（GHI）计算为P/PET和包括（P + QLAT）/PET的新的GHI。后者称为GHI_TOPO，反映了土地地形，在水文收敛的低地中更高。由于延迟和扩散的QLAT到达接收低地，它还表现出延迟且衰减的季节性（相对于P）。 QLAT的这种时空特征是由气候和地形引起的，使Ghi_topo成为降级社会和生态系统中局部用水可用性的更现实指标，从而在干旱的位置和时代实现了生活。 GHI_TOPO≥1的全球土地面积（供应满足或超过需求）比GHI≥1高33％，在干旱和季节ARID气候中高得多。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The aridity index is widely used to indicate water availability on land. Balancing climatic water supply (precipitation, P) against demand (potential evapotranspiration, PET), it is often expressed as the P/PET ratio&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; or humidity index. Water also flows laterally by rivers and groundwater, from hills to valleys and from mountains to plains, subsidizing the receiving lowlands&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;. Here, we show that this lateral subsidy reduces aridity in the receiving lowlands. We first estimate monthly subsidies (Qlat) by surface and groundwater at 30″ global grids with a global hydrology model. We then calculate the conventional global humidity index (GHI) as P/PET and a new GHI including Qlat as (P + Qlat)/PET. Termed GHI_topo, the latter reflects land topography, higher in hydrologically convergent lowlands. It also exhibits a delayed and dampened seasonality (relative to P) owing to delayed and diffused Qlat arrival at the receiving lowlands. Such spatiotemporal features of Qlat, arising from both the climate and the terrain, make GHI_topo a more realistic indicator of local water availability in downgradient societies and ecosystems, enabling life in arid locations and times. Global land area with GHI_topo ≥ 1 (supply meets or exceeds demand) is 33% greater than GHI ≥ 1 and far higher in arid and season-arid climates.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-025-09359-3/MediaObjects/41586_2025_9359_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 脱水驱动了海水渗透并减慢海底地下水排放</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01750-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Deglaciation drove seawater infiltration and slowed submarine groundwater discharge&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; S. ten Hietbrink; H. Patton; B. Dugan; B. Szymczycha; A. Sen; A. Lepland; J. Knies; J.-H. Kim; N.-C. Chen; W.-L. Hong&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;海底地下水排放（地下水流入海洋）在塑造沿海生物地球化学周期中起着重要作用。近端冰川载荷驱动的离岸地下水动力学上没有时间限制，这阻碍了我们评估其循环如何在可能的无冰极区域中变化。在这里，我们估计盐水地下水的盐水地下水的停留时间，在挪威北部海岸附近的大陆架架子上的北部海底和甲烷渗水地点。由于Fennoscandian的冰盖动力学，该领域的地下水文学经历了巨大的变化，从而洞悉了冰川 - 冰间过渡对离岸地下水的后果。使用在向上倾向的地下水中溶解的无机碳的放射性碳年代，我们确定了盐水地下水停留时间为11.5至8.8 kyr和4.8至2.6 kyr，在两个不同的放电地点。沉积物孔隙水中存在陨石水成分，证实了过去冰川载荷驱动的近海地下水清真。这表明，随着冰盖撤退和海平面的上升，海水开始渗透地下，取代了淡水补给。我们的结果提供了观察证据，以指出边缘脱水后海水渗透的发作。这些发现表明，撤退的海洋终止冰川将深刻改变近海地下水组成并降低排放率。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Submarine groundwater discharge—the flow of groundwater into the ocean—plays an important role in shaping coastal biogeochemical cycles. The absence of temporal constraints on offshore groundwater dynamics driven by proximal glacial loading hinders our assessment of how its circulation may vary in conceivable ice-free polar regions. Here we estimate residence times of saline groundwater at an active submarine groundwater discharge and methane seep site off the coast of northern Norway, near the continental shelf break. The subsurface hydrology in this area experienced drastic changes due to Fennoscandian Ice Sheet dynamics, offering insights into the consequences of glacial–interglacial transitions for offshore groundwater. Using radiocarbon dating of dissolved inorganic carbon in the upwards-advected groundwater, we determined saline groundwater residence times of 11.5 to 8.8 kyr and 4.8 to 2.6 kyr at two distinct discharge sites. The presence of a meteoric water component in sediment porewaters confirms offshore groundwater freshening driven by past glacial loading. This indicates that, as the ice sheet retreated and sea levels rose, seawater began to infiltrate the subsurface, replacing freshwater recharge. Our results provide observational evidence pinpointing the onset of seawater infiltration following deglaciation of the margin. These findings suggest that retreating marine-terminating glaciers will profoundly alter offshore groundwater composition and reduce discharge rates.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01750-z/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1750_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 空前的大规模含水层通过人类干预恢复</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-62719-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Unprecedented large-scale aquifer recovery through human intervention&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Di Long; Yuancheng Xu; Yingjie Cui; Yanhong Cui; James J. Butler Jr.; Liang Dong; Longfeng Wang; Dongyong Liu; Yoshihide Wada; Litang Hu; Guoying Bai; Binghua Li; Shufang Wang; Xizhi Nong; Yang Cai; Chunsheng Cheng; Yuhan Mu; Yu Qiao; Jianhua Wang; Hao Wang; Bridget R. Scanlon&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;地下水耗尽是全球的关键挑战，尤其是在深入耕种的旱地，很少有记录的成功恢复案例。在这里，我们报告了中国南部平原的长期地下水下降的惊人逆转，这是世界上最严重枯竭的含水层之一。基于对过去二十年的2000多个监控井的全面分析，我们表明，自2020年以来，地下水水平的平均速度约为0.7 m年&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup&gt;1年&lt;/sup&gt;，到2024年，其恢复是超过2005级的。到2024年，恢复是由大规模的地表水的组合驱动的。从2005年到2023年，这些政策将每年的地下水抽象减少了约12 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; ，并自2021年以来，将环境水分配增加到7 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; ，从而促进了含水层补给并恢复环境流。我们的发现表明，通过综合水管理和广泛地区的有针对性的政策干预措施可以实现快速，大规模的地下水恢复（约130,000公里&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ）。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Groundwater depletion is a critical global challenge, particularly in intensively cultivated drylands, with few documented cases of successful recovery. Here, we report a striking reversal of long-term groundwater decline in the North China Plain, one of the world’s most severely depleted aquifers. Based on a comprehensive analysis of groundwater levels from over 2000 monitoring wells spanning the past two decades, we show that groundwater levels have risen at an average rate of ~0.7 m year&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; since 2020, surpassing 2005 levels by 2024. This recovery is driven by a combination of large-scale surface water diversion from the humid south and stringent groundwater pumping regulations, further amplified by wet years (e.g., 2021). From 2005 to 2023, these policies reduced annual groundwater abstraction by ~12 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; and increased environmental water allocations to over 7 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; since 2021, promoting aquifer recharge and restoring environmental flows. Our findings demonstrate that rapid, large-scale groundwater recovery is achievable through integrated water management and targeted policy interventions across extensive regions (~130,000 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-62719-5/MediaObjects/41467_2025_62719_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 美国河流或沿海洪水危害地区的美国人口的高分辨率估计值</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05717-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;High-resolution estimates of the US population in fluvial or coastal flood hazard areas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Adam C. Gold; Ivy Steinberg-McElroy&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;洪水是美国最常见，最具破坏性的自然灾害（美国），了解有洪水风险的人数是计划的关键信息。此处介绍的数据集使用公开可用的人口普查和构建足迹数据，以改进对频率或沿海洪水危害地区的人数和住房数量的估计。为了计算人口和住房单位的估计，相交高洪水危害区域的住宅建筑占地面积比例乘以2020年十年中的人口普查块数量。这个灵活的框架将使数据集随着时间的推移而更新，并使用额外的洪水风险数据集（例如融合了Pluvial洪水的数据集）。这些对河流或沿海洪水危害地区人和住房的高分辨率估计将为洪水弹性计划工作提供宝贵的信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Flooding is the most common and damaging natural disaster in the United States (US), and understanding the number of people at risk of flooding is critical information for planning. The dataset presented here uses publicly available census and building footprint data to improve upon previous estimates of the number of people and housing units in fluvial or coastal flood hazard areas in the contiguous US. To calculate the population and housing unit estimates, the ratio of total residential building footprint area that intersects high flood hazard areas is multiplied by 2020 Decennial Census block counts. This flexible framework will allow the dataset to be updated over time and with additional flood risk datasets such as those that incorporate pluvial flooding. These high-resolution estimates of people and housing in fluvial or coastal flood hazard areas will provide valuable information to flood resilience planning efforts.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05717-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5717_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>