<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 02:24:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 用于评估对溪流和河流生态影响的水文农业土地利用强度指数</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02933-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A hydrologically informed agricultural land use intensity index for assessing ecological impacts on streams and rivers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Michael Kyei Agyekum; Devanshi Pathak; Alina Kindinger; Rohini Kumar; Dietrich Borchardt; Markus Weitere; Karin Frank; Mechthild Schmitt-Jansen; Olaf Büttner; Mario Brauns; Patrick Fink; Ulrike Scharfenberger&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;土地利用强度的概念已被广泛用于量化人类对陆地系统的影响，但这种方法无法捕捉土地利用对相连河流网络的累积影响。在这里，我们介绍了河流生态系统土地利用强度指数（LUIS），这是一个空间明确、水文信息丰富的指数，它将氮、磷和农药的特定作物投入与河流网络结构相结合。为了评估农业压力与水质之间的关系，我们使用逻辑回归和随机森林分类模型来评估德国各地的整体生态状况和生物质量要素。农药压力与生态状况的关联性最强，在低阶流和高阶流中均表现出最高的效应大小、R² 值和预测因子重要性。这些关联在低阶溪流和中部高地尤其明显，可能是由于它们的稀释能力有限且直接暴露于径流。磷显示出次要的相关性，特别是在高阶流中，而氮的影响不太明显。 LUIS 是评估农业土地利用对河流生态系统的特定化合物和综合压力的重要工具。其机械信息丰富且概念灵活的框架为未来的开发和集成到运营监控和管理环境中提供了坚实的基础。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The concept of land-use intensity has been widely used to quantify human impacts in terrestrial systems, yet such approaches fail to capture the cumulative effects of land use on connected river networks. Here, we introduce the Land Use Intensity Index for Stream Ecosystems (LUIS), a spatially explicit, hydrologically informed index that integrates crop-specific inputs of nitrogen, phosphorus, and pesticides with river network structure. To evaluate the relationship between agricultural pressures and water quality, we used logistic regression and a random forest classification model to assess overall ecological status and biological quality elements across Germany. Pesticide pressure showed the strongest association with ecological status, exhibiting the highest effect sizes, R² values, and predictor importance across both low- and high-order streams. These associations were especially pronounced in low-order streams and the central highlands, likely due to their limited dilution capacity and direct exposure to runoff. Phosphorus showed secondary relevance, particularly in higher-order streams, while nitrogen’s effects were less distinct. LUIS is a valuable tool for assessing the compound-specific and combined pressures of agricultural land use on stream ecosystems. Its mechanistically informed yet conceptually flexible framework provides a solid basis for future development and integration into operational monitoring and management contexts.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-27066-x/MediaObjects/41598_2025_27066_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>