<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 02:24:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 尤卡坦半岛的地下水盐化模式揭示了喀斯特含水层的污染和脆弱性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02456-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Groundwater salinization patterns in the Yucatan Peninsula reveal contamination and vulnerability of the karst aquifer&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Christian Narvaez-Montoya; Rogelio Mondragón Bonilla; Nico Goldscheider; Jürgen Mahlknecht&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;尤卡坦半岛是全球最大的沿海和低地喀斯特地区之一。这个依赖地下水的区域非常容易受到由于喀斯特环境而容易扩散的污染物。在这里，来自政府机构的1528种水样中主要离子的时空模式表明，启用含水层系统的盐分的主要因素。由尺寸降低和基于网络的聚类支持的水力地球化学分析将三分之一的样品与海水侵入，南部的大量石膏溶解以及无处不在的碳酸盐含量含碳酸盐含量的污染相关联。水质的时间变化表明，近几十年来，区域补给趋势的变化和人类影响的增加。此外，来自人类使用来源的水样中约有23％超过了可接受的硫酸盐和硝酸盐限制，以饮用水。该研究强调了对连续水质监测和增强区域知识以支持管理计划的需求。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Yucatan Peninsula is one of the largest coastal and lowland karst regions worldwide. This groundwater-dependent region is highly vulnerable to contaminants that spread easily due to the karst environment. Here, the spatio-temporal patterns of major ions in 1528 water samples sourced from a government institution suggest the main factors triggering salinization in the aquifer system. The hydrogeochemical analysis, supported by dimensional reduction and network-based clustering, linked one-third of the samples to contamination outbreaks from seawater intrusion, extensive gypsum dissolution in the south, and nitrate pollution in the ubiquitous carbonate aquifer matrix. Temporal variations of water quality indicated changes in regional recharge trends and increasing human impact in recent decades. Moreover, ~23% of water samples from human-use sources exceeded acceptable sulfate and nitrate limits for drinking water purposes. The study underscores the need for continuous water quality monitoring and enhanced regional knowledge to support management plans.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02456-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2456_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 跨地球系统模型的水限制频率的巨大偏见</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02426-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Large biases in the frequency of water limitation across Earth system models&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Francesco Giardina; Ryan S. Padrón; Benjamin D. Stocker; Dominik L. Schumacher; Sonia I. Seneviratne&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水的可用性限制了土地上的蒸散量，塑造了能源平衡，陆碳吸收和极端气候。尽管重要性很重要，但地球系统模型仍在努力捕获限制水限制条件的地方和频率。在这里，我们调查了由一致的观察性大气强迫驱动的第六个耦合模型对比项目（CMIP6）的水限制的表示及其与陆上存储能力的联系。利用远程感知的太阳能诱导的植被荧光和陆生储水的观察，以及生态系统通量数据，我们发现CMIP6模型高估了土地上水限制的频率，而在热带地区的频率为26％。模型高估发生在土地面积的57％以上，在热带地区发生78％。这些过于频繁的水限制条件与模型中潜在的土地储水容量的低估没有最终联系，暗示了ESM代表生根深度，植物水吸收和植物水利用策略的差距。我们的研究强调了这些领域模型开发的需求，对未来在土地上的氛围的预测产生了影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water availability limits evapotranspiration on land, shaping the energy balance, land carbon uptake, and climate extremes. Despite its importance, Earth system models struggle to capture where and how often water-limited conditions occur. Here we investigate the representation of water limitation and its link to land water storage capacity in simulations from the Sixth Coupled Model Intercomparison Project (CMIP6) driven by consistent observational atmospheric forcing. Using observations of remotely sensed solar-induced vegetation fluorescence and terrestrial water storage, together with ecosystem flux data, we find that CMIP6 models overestimate the frequency of water limitation by 14% over land and 26% in the tropics. Model overestimation occurs over 57% of the land area, and 78% in the tropics. These too frequent water-limited conditions are not conclusively linked to a potential underestimation of land water storage capacity in the models, hinting at gaps in how ESMs represent rooting depths, plant water uptake, and plant water-use strategies. Our study highlights the need for model development in these areas, with implications for projections of future climate on land.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02426-7/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2426_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>