<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 02:42:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 农村和城市人口的全球差异暴露于复合干旱和热浪事件</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01025-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Global disparities in rural and urban population exposure to compound drought and heatwave events&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Tao Li; Fengjiao Song; Andrée De Cock; Philippe De Maeyer; Jiayu Bao; Ye Yuan; Sulei Naibi; Anming Bao; Long Tuan Ho; Peter Goethals&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在全球气候变化的驱动下，复合干旱和热波事件（CDHW）的高度发生，对人类构成了严重威胁。但是，它们对农村和城市人口的影响尚不清楚。这项研究分析了农村和城市人口中的CDHWS暴露，发现随着时间的流逝，长期暴露于CDHW的人数表现出明显的上升趋势。从1901年到2021年，与城市人口相比，农村人口的总暴露量是CDHWS的2.5倍。然而，在过去的三十年中，城市人口的曝光率显着高于农村人口。在地区，亚洲，北美和非洲的农村人口分别占全球农村人口总敞口的41.06、16.51和13.69％，而亚洲，北美和欧洲的城市人口分别占32.31、18.70，分别占全球城市城市城市暴露的16.85％。气候人口互动效应一直是推动人口暴露最近变化的主要因素。我们的发现有助于全球和区域级别的CDHW的风险评估，并为灾难预防和缓解策略提供可靠的信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The high occurrence of compound drought and heatwave events (CDHWs), driven by global climate change, poses a serious threat to humanity. However, their impacts on rural and urban populations remain unclear. This study analyzed CDHWs exposure in both rural and urban populations and found that the number of people chronically exposed to CDHWs has shown a clear upward trend over time. From 1901 to 2021, rural populations experienced 2.5 times the total exposure to CDHWs compared to urban populations. Over the past three decades, however, urban populations have experienced significantly higher exposure and a faster rate of increase than rural populations. Regionally, rural populations in Asia, North America, and Africa accounted for 41.06, 16.51, and 13.69% of the total global rural population exposure, respectively, while urban populations in Asia, North America, and Europe accounted for 32.31, 18.70, and 16.85% of global urban exposure, respectively. The climate-population interactive effects have been the dominant factors driving recent changes in population exposure. Our findings contribute to the risk assessment of CDHWs at both global and regional levels and provide reliable information for disaster prevention and mitigation strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01025-9/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1025_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | NASA Snowex阿拉斯加竞选期间收集的北极苔原和北方森林的积雪深度测量值</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05170-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Snow depth measurements from Arctic tundra and boreal forest collected during NASA SnowEx Alaska campaign&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Svetlana L. Stuefer; Katherine Hale; Lora D. May; Megan Mason; Carrie Vuyovich; Hans-Peter Marshall; Dragos Vas; Kelly Elder&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;北方森林和北极苔原环境集体拥有全球陆地季节性积雪的最大比例。在这些偏远的北部地区，原地雪量测量网络稀疏且昂贵。在这里，我们通过提供广泛的（64°N – 70°N）雪深度数据集（64°N – 70°N）的雪深度监测以及对地面雪深度测量的描述，并在NASA SNOWEX阿拉斯加强化领域中收集的地面积雪深度测量，并报告了2023年3月7-16日，我们还报告了雪地的准确性，该林中的精确度均可在Alaska密集的田间相同。开发一致且可重复的积雪数据收集程序的考虑。本文描述的积雪深度测量和技术验证可以用作测试雪遥感技术的强大产品，并提供用于气候和水文研究的参考数据集。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Boreal forest and Arctic tundra environments collectively hold the largest percentage of global terrestrial seasonal snow cover. Тhe in-situ snow measurement network is sparse and costly in these remote northern regions. Here, we complement existing snow depth monitoring in Arctic tundra and boreal forest by presenting an extensive (64°N–70°N) snow depth dataset and description of ground-based snow depth measurements collected during the NASA SnowEx Alaska intensive field campaign, March 7–16, 2023. We also report the accuracy of snow depth measurements in shallow boreal forest and Arctic tundra snowpack and share considerations in developing the consistent and repeatable snow depth data collection procedures. Snow depth measurements and technical validation described in this paper can serve as a robust product for testing snow remote sensing techniques, and for providing a reference dataset for climatological and hydrological studies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05170-x/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5170_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>