<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 02:27:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 野火驱动美国西部的多年水质退化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02427-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Wildfires drive multi-year water quality degradation over the western United States&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Carli P. Brucker; Ben Livneh; Fernando L. Rosario-Ortiz; Fangfang Yao; A. Park Williams; William C. Becker; Stephanie K. Kampf; Balaji Rajagopalan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;野火可以极大地改变水质，从而对人类和淡水系统产生严重影响。但是，这些影响的区域评估通常受到数据稀缺的限制。在这里，我们将1984  -  2021年从245个燃烧的分水岭进行的观察结果统一，将火后信号与293个未开枪盆地的基线水平进行了比较。火后1  -  5年，有机碳和磷的水平显着升高（P≤0.05），而氮和沉积物在火后8年显示出显着增加。在火后响应年中，平均碳，氮和磷浓度为火前水平的3-103倍，沉积物为19-286倍射击前浓度。更高的反应与更大的森林和发达区域有关，分别解释了巴蛋白间反应变异性的31％和33％。总体而言，该分析为美国西部野火后多年水质退化提供了有力的证据，并强调了盆地和野火特征的影响。这些见解可能会帮助水管理人员进行准备工作，从而增加水系统对野火影响的弹性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Wildfires can dramatically alter water quality, resulting in severe implications for human and freshwater systems. However, regional-scale assessments of these impacts are often limited by data scarcity. Here, we unify observations from 1984–2021 in 245 burned watersheds across the western United States, comparing post-fire signals to baseline levels from 293 unburned basins. Organic carbon and phosphorus exhibit significantly elevated levels (p ≤ 0.05) in the first 1–5 years post-fire, while nitrogen and sediment show significant increases up to 8 years post-fire. During peak post-fire response years, average carbon, nitrogen, and phosphorus concentrations are 3–103 times pre-fire levels, and sediment 19–286 times pre-fire concentrations. Higher responses are linked with greater forested and developed areas, which respectively explain up to 31 and 33% of inter-basin response variability. Overall, this analysis provides strong evidence of multi-year water quality degradation following wildfires in the western United States and highlights the influence of basin and wildfire features. These insights may aid water managers in preparation efforts, increasing resilience of water systems to wildfire impacts.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02427-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2427_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>