<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 02:24:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 在秘鲁亚马逊的手工黄金开采后，水上可用性的景观控制限制恢复</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02332-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Landscape controls on water availability limit revegetation after artisanal gold mining in the Peruvian Amazon&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Abra Atwood; Shreya Ramesh; Jennifer Angel Amaya; Hinsby Cadillo-Quiroz; Daxs Coayla; Chan-Mao Chen; A. Joshua West&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;来自手工，小规模的金矿开采的森林砍伐正在改变热带地区的大区域，从郁郁葱葱的雨林到贫瘠的尾矿和池塘。天然森林的再生由于土壤的巨大变化而缓慢，现有的造林策略正在失败。在这里，我们将遥感，电阻率成像和土壤特性的测量结合在一起，以表征秘鲁Madre de Dios地区的挖掘区域。我们发现，矿场后的景观已大大改变了水渗透动态，驱动器的地下水可用性减少，并带来了重生的主要障碍。采矿尾矿在液压方面是极端的导电性，可在原代森林土壤中相对于0.074 m天&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;的14.76 m天&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;浸润，从而导致平均土壤水分和极端温度（60°C）。电阻率成像揭示了在采矿景观上的高度电阻，1.5-2 m深层的干砂层。与地形高尾矿相比，靠近地下水位的区域（例如池塘边缘）显示出更高的土壤水分，较低的温度和更大的自然再生。我们的结果表明，在靶向造林地点时应优先考虑使用水，这可能需要大规模的地貌重新配置。由于预计黄金开采将扩大，负责任的做法和补救策略必须说明水的重要作用至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Deforestation from artisanal, small-scale gold mining is transforming large regions of the tropics, from lush rainforest to barren collections of tailings and ponds. Natural forest regeneration is slow due to dramatic soil changes, and existing reforestation strategies are failing. Here we combine remote sensing, electrical resistivity imaging, and measurements of soil properties to characterize post-mining areas in the Madre de Dios region, Peru. We find that the post-mining landscape has dramatically changed water infiltration dynamics, driving decreases in subsurface water availability and presenting a major barrier to revegetation. Mining tailings are extremely hydraulically conductive, allowing for 14.76 m day&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; infiltration relative to 0.074 m day&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; in primary forest soils, leading to lower average soil moisture and extreme temperatures (60 °C). Electrical resistivity imaging reveals a highly resistive, 1.5–2 m deep layer of dry sand across the mining landscape. Areas close to the water table (e.g., pond edges) show higher soil moisture, lower temperatures, and greater natural regeneration compared to topographically elevated tailings. Our results suggest that access to water should be prioritized when targeting reforestation sites, potentially requiring large-scale geomorphological reconfiguration. As gold mining is expected to expand, responsible practices and remediation strategies must account for the critical yet often overlooked role of water.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02332-y/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2332_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 闪存干旱对全球生态系统的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01719-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Flash drought impacts on global ecosystems amplified by extreme heat&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lei Gu; Dominik L. Schumacher; Erich M. Fischer; Louise J. Slater; Jiabo Yin; Sebastian Sippel; Jie Chen; Pan Liu; Reto Knutti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;闪存干旱（因其快速发作而表征）会造成毁灭性的社会经济和农业损害。在此类事件中，土壤水分耗尽不仅是由于降水短缺的驱动，而且还由由于极高的热量引起的大气水分需求升高。但是，极热在塑造闪光干旱的演变中的作用及其生态影响仍然不确定。在这里，我们通过分析1950年至2022年分析全球重新分析数据所涉及的过程。我们发现，当闪光干旱伴随着极高的热量时，它们的严重程度高6.7–90.8％，比没有极高热量的闪光干旱高8.3-114.3％。在闪光干旱期间的极端热量的存在会加速高纬度地区的土壤水分水分，在那里潮湿的土壤和增强的辐射促进了蒸散量。相比之下，由于蒸发节流，它减慢了亚热带过渡气候区域的绝对发作速度。我们的机器学习方法进一步表明，热潮干旱会导致生态系统生产率（尤其是在农田中）的下降，从而威胁着全球粮食安全。这些发现强调了增强基础设施和生态系统对热闪光干旱的抗复力的迫切需求。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Flash droughts—characterized by their rapid onset—can cause devastating socioeconomic and agricultural damage. During such events, soil moisture depletion is driven not only by precipitation shortages but also by the elevated atmospheric moisture demand arising due to extreme heat. However, the role of extreme heat in shaping the evolution of flash droughts and their ecological impacts remains uncertain. Here we investigate the processes involved by analysing global reanalysis data from 1950 to 2022. We find that, when flash droughts are accompanied by extreme heat, they exhibit 6.7–90.8% higher severity and 8.3–114.3% longer recovery time than flash droughts without extreme heat. The presence of extreme heat during flash droughts accelerates soil moisture drawdown over high latitudes, where wet soils and enhanced radiation foster evapotranspiration. By contrast, it slows the absolute onset speed in subtropical transitional climate zones owing to evapotranspiration throttling. Our machine learning approach further reveals that hot flash droughts lead to sharper declines in ecosystem productivity, particularly in croplands, thereby threatening global food security. These findings underscore the pressing need for enhanced infrastructure and ecosystem resilience to hot flash droughts in a warming future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01719-y/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1719_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 陆基传感器揭示了沿海洪水的高频</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02326-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Land-based sensors reveal high frequency of coastal flooding&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Miyuki Hino; Katherine Anarde; Tessa Fridell; Ryan McCune; Thomas Thelen; Elizabeth Farquhar; Perri Woodard; Anthony Whipple&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;除其他因素外，由于全球海平面上升，沿海洪水发生的频率更高。但是，目前对沿海洪水频率和海平面上升影响的理解主要是基于潮汐仪，这不能衡量陆地上的水位。在这里，我们介绍了美国北卡罗来纳州州的新型陆基洪水传感器网络的数据。我们证明，潮汐数据的数据是洪水的不良指标：洪水每年发生26-128天，比区域潮汐仪在某些地方提出的数量级大。提高沿海洪水措施的准确性对于确定海平面上升和制定有效的适应策略的影响至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Coastal flooding is occurring more frequently due to global sea-level rise, among other factors. However, current understanding of coastal flood frequency and sea-level rise impacts is predominantly based on tide gauges, which do not measure water levels on land. Here, we present data from a novel network of land-based flood sensors in the state of North Carolina, USA. We demonstrate that tide-gauge data are poor indicators of flooding: floods occur 26–128 days annually, an order of magnitude greater than what regional tide gauges suggest in some places. Improving the accuracy of coastal flood measures is critical for identifying the impacts of sea-level rise and developing effective adaptation strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02326-w/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2326_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>