<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 02:28:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 重新组合过去的事件降水和先进的集水区会产生前所未有的洪水</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02691-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Recombining past event precipitation and antecedent catchment states generates unprecedented floods&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Li Han; Bruno Merz; Viet Dung Nguyen; Björn Guse; Luis Samaniego; Kai Schröter; Sergiy Vorogushyn&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;超过历史记录的河流经常出乎意料地发生，从而造成广泛的破坏和破坏。为了改善灾难的准备，探索超过过去观察的特殊洪水场景至关重要。在这里，我们介绍了一种完美的风暴方法，该方法重新组合了历史上观察到降水和土壤水分的极端情况，以产生合理的洪水场景，而外行人和洪水风险经理易于理解。我们的分析涵盖了德国记录的十大最具破坏性洪水，另外两个极端降水事件和两个湿润的土壤水分状况。结果表明，这些重新组合的洪水的严重性和损害可以系统地超过观察到的事件的严重性和损害，这表明了完美风暴方法的潜力，即产生了前所未有的洪水的合理情况。在将极端降雨转移到湿土的情况下，始终如一地扩大了洪水的严重性，但移动事件仅1个月也可以加剧洪水，这突显了集水状态和降水量之间时间对齐的关键作用。我们的研究使计划者和政策制定者能够预期超出历史先例的极端洪水场景，并提供了一种简单而强大的策略，用于获得洪水场景以增强灾难的准备。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;River floods that exceed historical records often occur unexpectedly, causing widespread damage and disruption. To improve disaster preparedness, it is crucial to explore exceptional flood scenarios that surpass past observations. Here we introduce a perfect storm approach that recombines historically observed extremes in precipitation and soil moisture to generate plausible flood scenarios that are easy to understand by lay people and flood risk managers. Our analysis covers the ten most damaging floods recorded in Germany, two additional extreme precipitation events and two cases of exceptionally wet soil moisture conditions. The results show that the severity and damage of these recombined floods can systematically exceed those of the observed events, demonstrating the potential of the perfect storm approach to generate plausible scenarios of unprecedented floods. While shifting extreme rainfall to wetter soil consistently amplifies flood severity, moving events by just 1 month can also intensify flooding, which underscores the critical role of temporal alignment between catchment state and precipitation. Our study enables planners and policymakers to anticipate extreme flood scenarios beyond historical precedents, and offers a simple, yet powerful, strategy for obtaining flood scenarios to enhance disaster preparedness.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02691-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2691_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 从1994年至2024年，在里奥格兰德中部的30年同时耕地和土地覆盖土地使用地图</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05771-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;30 Years of simultaneous crop &amp; land cover land use maps for Middle Rio Grande from 1994 to 2024&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Saman Ebrahimi; Mahdis Khorram; Raquel Neri Barranco; Rosario Sanchez; Rocky Talchabhadel; Santosh S. Palmate; Marisol Dominguez-Tuda; Elizabeth F. Racine; Saurav Kumar&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;这项研究介绍了农作物和土地覆盖土地使用（CLCLU）数据集，该数据集是30 m的分辨率产品，可在整个跨国中部里奥格兰德（MRG）地区提供CLCLU的年度地图，从1994年至2024年跨越了美国和墨西哥。该模型在美国方面使用农田数据层（CDL）培训。双月（7月和12月）Landsat复合材料和语义分割模型，具有Resnext-101编码器的MANET，使用四种策略来解决传感器和时间变异性。该模型架构的内在能力是通过其基于注意力的设计和Resnext-101编码器捕获详细的空间模式和上下文依赖性的内在能力的，这表明了强劲的性能，尤其是在墨西哥的数据筛分区域概括。该数据集使用固定的CDL子集实现了97.10％的总体准确性和78.85％的平均交叉点（MIOU）（MIOU）。针对NLCD和MCD12Q1-UMD的验证确认了高协议。早期的数据可用性差异，墨西哥一侧的最小地面真相以及与云相关的伪影导致了一些错误分类。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This study introduces the crop and land cover land use (CLCLU) dataset, a 30 m resolution product providing annual maps of CLCLU across the transnational Middle Rio Grande (MRG) region, spanning both the U.S. and Mexico from 1994 to 2024. The model was trained using the Cropland Data Layer (CDL) on the US side. Dual-month (July and December) Landsat composites and a semantic segmentation model, MANet with ResNeXt-101 encoder, under four strategies were used to address sensor and temporal variability. This model architecture was chosen for its intrinsic ability to capture detailed spatial patterns and contextual dependencies through its attention-based design and ResNeXt-101 encoder, which demonstrated strong performance, particularly in generalizing across data-scarce regions in Mexico. The dataset achieved 97.10% overall accuracy and 78.85% mean Intersection over Union (mIoU), over validation process using a held-out CDL subset. Validation against NLCD and MCD12Q1-UMD confirmed high agreement. Data availability differences, minimal ground truth on the Mexican side, and cloud-related artifacts in early years led to some misclassification.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05771-6/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5771_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>