<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 02:19:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 中国黑土地区日尺度高精度多层土壤湿度生成</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05986-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Generating high accuracy multi-layer soil moisture at daily scale in the black soil region of China&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Liwen Chen; Yangguang Wang; Jingquan Ren; Haiqing Song; Guangxin Zhang; Jingxuan Sun; Lijun Wang; Jia Mu; Cong Liu; Meiyu Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;我国黑土区是世界四大黑土区之一，是重要的粮食生产基地。因此，高精度土壤湿度数据对于了解干旱和涝渍对作物产量的影响机制至关重要。在这里，我们使用社区土地模型 3.5 (CLM3.5) 提供了 16 年（2008-2023）土壤湿度数据集（DMSN），具有高时空分辨率和多层时空一致性（2 km，每天，0-10、10-20、20-50、50-100 cm）。 DMSM表现出优异的性能，经黑土区7个现场监测点验证，相关系数（R）普遍大于0.7，RMSE在0.035~0.07之间变化，MAE在0.03~0.06之间变化，偏差保持在-0.02~0.02之间。 DMSM 有效捕获了每日、年际和季节性土壤湿度变化，为这一关键黑土地区的土壤湿度动态提供了重要见解。这些结果有助于了解干旱和涝渍的潜在驱动因素及其对作物产量的影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The black soil region of China is one of the four major black soil regions in the world and is an important grain production base. High-accuracy soil moisture data are therefore crucial for understanding the mechanisms of drought and waterlogging on crop yields. Here, we present a 16 years (2008–2023) soil moisture dataset (DMSN) with both high spatiotemporal resolution and multi-layer spatiotemporal consistency (2 km, daily, 0–10, 10–20, 20–50, 50–100 cm),using Community Land Model 3.5 (CLM3.5). The DMSM showed excellent performance, with validation at seven field monitoring sites in the black soil region, the correlation coefficient (R) was generally greater than 0.7, the RMSE varied between 0.035 and 0.07, the MAE ranged from 0.03 to 0.06, and the bias remained between −0.02 and 0.02. The DMSM effectively captured daily, inter-annual, and seasonal soil moisture variations, providing important insights into soil moisture dynamics in this critical black soil region. These results help in understanding the potential drivers of drought and waterlogging and their impact on crop yields.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05986-7/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5986_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Water | 全球水文气候极端事件的空间同步结构</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00520-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Spatially synchronized structures of global hydroclimatic extremes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hui-Min Wang; Xiaogang He&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;空间上同步的极端水文气候——干旱、雨雪和干旱——雨雪“跷跷板”偶极子——造成的影响远远超出了它们发生的地方。适应这些并发风险需要进行全球范围的评估，以捕获远程和本地依赖性，但当前的方法通常假设跨位置的独立性，而忽略了导致风险估计偏差的关键空间依赖性。此外，大多数研究孤立地对待干旱和雨雪，忽略了它们的反相共现。在这里，我们使用 67 年降水再分析数据集开发了一个基于多层事件的复杂气候网络，以分析 0.66 万亿个 0.25° 像素对的水文气候冲击的全球同步。我们发现遥连（&amp;gt;2,500 公里）同步存在明显的空间不对称性，主要是海洋地区（90% 的遥连链路）和南部中纬度地区。我们对 91 个全球粮仓区域对进行的区域束分析揭示了这些空间不对称性既是事件特定的，也是半球特定的。三分之二的具有显着干旱或雨雪同步的区域对发生在同一半球内，而 40% 的跨半球对则表现出跷跷板同步，影响至少三分之一的面积。这些发现凸显了对干旱和雨雪及其相互关系进行综合评估的必要性，因为依赖半球多样化的传统农业贸易做法可能在气候变暖、同步化的情况下面临日益严峻的挑战。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Spatially synchronized hydroclimatic extremes—droughts, pluvials and drought–pluvial ‘seesaw’ dipoles—cause impacts far beyond where they occur. Adapting to these concurrent risks requires global-scale assessments that capture both remote and local dependencies, yet current approaches generally assume independence across locations, overlooking critical spatial dependencies that bias risk estimates. Moreover, most research treats droughts and pluvials in isolation, neglecting their antiphase co-occurrences. Here we develop a multilayer event-based complex climate network using a 67-year precipitation reanalysis dataset to analyse global synchronizations of hydroclimatic shocks across 0.66 trillion 0.25° pixel pairs. We find pronounced spatial asymmetries in teleconnected (&amp;gt;2,500 km) synchronizations, dominated by oceanic regions (90% of teleconnection links) and southern mid-latitudes. These spatial asymmetries are both event and hemisphere specific, revealed by our regional bundle analysis of 91 global breadbasket region pairs. Two-thirds of region pairs with significant drought or pluvial synchronization occur within the same hemisphere, while 40% of cross-hemisphere pairs exhibit seesaw synchronizations, affecting at least one-third of their areas. These findings highlight the need for integrated assessments of droughts and pluvials and their interconnections, as traditional agricultural trade practices relying on hemispheric diversification may face growing challenges in a warming, synchronized climate.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00520-w/MediaObjects/44221_2025_520_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>