<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 02:11:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Water | 森林通过大气水分输送支持全球农作物供应</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00518-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Forests support global crop supply through atmospheric moisture transport&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Agnes Pranindita; Adriaan J. Teuling; Ingo Fetzer; Lan Wang-Erlandsson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;与气候变化相关的异常降水模式日益威胁着全球农作物供应。森林作为主要的水分来源，有可能缓冲这些风险，但其在维持农业和全球农作物供应方面的具体作用仍未得到充分探索。我们通过估计从森林到农业区的水分流量并将其与贸易作物流量配对来调查全球森林对农作物生产和出口的贡献。我们发现，155 个国家的农业区高达 40% 的年降水依赖跨境森林，而在 105 个国家，多达 18% 的降水来自全国森林。研究显示，全球森林水分支撑着 18% 的农作物生产和 30% 的农作物出口。我们通过三种类型表明作物生产者、出口商和进口商直接和间接依赖于上风向森林国家。我们的研究表明，可以利用战略性保护位于农业区上风处的森林来保障全球农作物供应。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Anomalous precipitation patterns associated with climate change increasingly threaten global crop supply. Forests, as major moisture source, could potentially buffer these risks, yet their specific role in sustaining agriculture and global crop supply remains underexplored. We investigate global forests’ contribution to crop production and export by estimating moisture flows from forests to agricultural areas and pairing them with traded crop flows. We find that agricultural areas in 155 countries rely on transboundary forests for up to 40% of annual precipitation, whereas in 105 countries, as much as 18% of precipitation is recycled from forests nationally. Moisture from forests globally supports 18% of crop production and 30% of crop export studied. We show that crop producers, exporters and importers are directly and indirectly dependent on upwind forested countries through three typologies. Our study implies that strategically conserving forests located upwind of agricultural areas could be leveraged to safeguard global crop supply.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00518-4/MediaObjects/44221_2025_518_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>