<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 08:37:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 通过校准版本的Gem-Hydro型号在大湖泊上产生的水文产量</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04409-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Étienne Gaborit; Juliane Mai; Daniel Princz; Hongren Shen; Vincent Vionnet; Bryan Tolson; Vincent Fortin&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;该数据集包含来自加拿大环境和气候变化（ECCC）开发的GEM-HYDRO模型的校准版本的输出，可在联合研究数据存储库中获得。数据集涵盖了劳伦斯大湖和渥太华河的盆地，并在2001  -  2018年期间延伸。数据由与Gem-Hydro的土地表面方案（包括降水，表面和地下表面径流，排水，排水，蒸发，雪水等效，土壤水分…）和与Gem-Hydro的水平相关的所有变量（小时通量和状态变量）组成平均每日水流位置位于212号位置。这些输出是用校准版本的GEM-HYDRO模型模拟的，该模型以开环模式（无同化）运行，并以来自ECCC的加拿大加拿大表面重新分析版本2.1的大气强迫驱动。与参考数据集相比，GEM-HYDRO可获得各种水文变量的令人满意的模拟。该数据集可用于例如驱动不同水文变量的任何路由模型，计算气候或统计数据，并研究其变异性作为本地地理形态学的函数，等等。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This dataset contains outputs from a calibrated version of the GEM-Hydro model developed at Environment and Climate Change Canada (ECCC) and is available on the Federated Research Data Repository. The dataset covers the basins of the Laurentian Great Lakes and the Ottawa River and extends over the period 2001–2018. The data consist of all variables (hourly fluxes and state variables) related to the water balance of GEM-Hydro’s land-surface scheme (including precipitation, surface and sub-surface runoff, drainage, evaporation, snow water equivalent, soil moisture…) and mean daily streamflow at 212 gauge locations. These outputs were simulated with a calibrated version of the GEM-Hydro model that was run in open-loop mode (no assimilation) and driven with atmospheric forcings coming from ECCC’s Canadian Surface Reanalysis version 2.1. GEM-Hydro achieves satisfactory simulations of various hydrologic variables when compared to reference datasets. This dataset can be used for example to drive any routing model, compute climatologies or statistics for different hydrologic variables and study their variability as a function of the local geo-morphology, etc.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04409-x/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4409_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 气候温暖的水可用性多方面变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00913-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Binglan Gu; Sha Zhou; Bofu Yu; Kirsten L. Findell; Benjamin R. Lintner&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候变暖改变了地表水利用率（PE）的空间和季节性模式，影响径流和陆地储水。但是，仍然缺乏对各种氢化物质的这些变化的全面评估。我们开发了一种多模型的合奏方法，将全球陆地氢化气候分类为四个不同的政权，基于PE的平均值和季节性。 PE预计在空间和时间之间变化越来越多。季节性低和高季节性的潮湿地区可能会在湿季径流中增加20％的浓度增加，这突出了与洪水有关的脆弱性的潜在增加。低季节性区域表现出更快的湿季增加，土壤水分的干季更快减少，增加了缺水和干旱的可能性。相反，季节性高的干燥区域对气候变化不太敏感。这些发现强调了气候变化对全球水资源的多方面影响，因此需要针对不同氢气气候制度的量身定制策略。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate warming alters spatial and seasonal patterns of surface water availability (P-E), affecting runoff and terrestrial water storage. However, a comprehensive assessment of these changes across various hydroclimates remains lacking. We develop a multi-model ensemble approach to classify global terrestrial hydroclimate into four distinct regimes based on the mean and seasonality of P-E. P-E is projected to become increasingly variable across space and time. Wet regions with low and high seasonality are likely to experience more concentrated increases in wet-season runoff by up to 20%, highlighting potential increases in flood-related vulnerability. Low-seasonality regions exhibit faster wet-season increases and more rapid dry-season decreases in soil moisture, heightening the likelihood of water scarcity and drought. Conversely, dry regions with high seasonality are less sensitive to climate change. These findings underscore the multifaceted impacts of climate change on global water resources, necessitating the need for tailored adaptation strategies for different hydroclimate regimes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00913-4/MediaObjects/41612_2025_913_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | GRAICE：通过复发性神经网络重建地面储水异常</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04403-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Irene Palazzoli; Serena Ceola; Pierre Gentine&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;自2002年以来，重力恢复和气候实验（GRACE）及其后续（GRACE-FO）任务提供了对陆生储存异常（TWSA）的估计，从而可以监测全球水文变化。但是，这些数据集中的时间差距以及2002年之前缺乏TWSA观察限制了我们对长期淡水变异性的理解。在这项研究中，我们使用长期短期记忆（LSTM）和&lt;i&gt;双向&lt;/i&gt;LSTM（BILSTM）神经网络开发了从1984年到2021年的四个全球每月TWSA重建。我们的模型在全球范围内准确地重现了恩典/宽限期观察，并有效地捕获了气候极端的影响。总体而言， &lt;i&gt;GRAI&lt;/i&gt; CE在预测观察到的TWSA方面优于先前的参考TWSA重建，并在河流域量表上提供可靠的水预算估计。通过产生长期连续的TWSA时间序列， &lt;i&gt;Grai&lt;/i&gt; Ce将为气候变异性和变化对淡水资源的影响提供宝贵的见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) and its follow-on (GRACE-FO) missions have provided estimates of Terrestrial Water Storage Anomalies (TWSA) since 2002, enabling the monitoring of global hydrological changes. However, temporal gaps within these datasets and the lack of TWSA observations prior to 2002 limit our understanding of long-term freshwater variability. In this study, we develop GR&lt;i&gt;Ai&lt;/i&gt;CE, a set of four global monthly TWSA reconstructions from 1984 to 2021 at 0.5° spatial resolution, using Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) and Bidirectional LSTM (BiLSTM) neural networks. Our models accurately reproduce GRACE/GRACE-FO observations at the global scale and effectively capture the impacts of climate extremes. Overall, GR&lt;i&gt;Ai&lt;/i&gt;CE outperforms a previous reference TWSA reconstruction in predicting observed TWSA and provides reliable water budget estimates at the river basin scale. By generating long-term continuous TWSA time series, GR&lt;i&gt;Ai&lt;/i&gt;CE will offer valuable insights into the impacts of climate variability and change on freshwater resources.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04403-3/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4403_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 天山地区高山冰川集水区的占主导地位的洪水驱动因素通过可解释的深度学习揭示</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00918-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Wenting Liang; Weili Duan; Yaning Chen; Gonghuan Fang; Shan Zou; Zhi Li; Zewei Qiu; Haodong Lyu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;库马拉克河是天山地区典型的高山冰川集水区，经历了冰川融化，融雪和降雨的驱动的复杂洪水。但是，在气候变化下推动这些过程的机制尚不清楚。为了解决这个问题，使用SWAT-GLACIER水文模型和程度 - 日因子模型用于融雪，冰川融化和降雨计算。使用这些输入开发了两个长的短期记忆（LSTM）模型（LSTM-SG和LSTM-DDF），并应用了加性分解和集成梯度方法来解释洪水机制。发现冰川融水在年度最大洪水（AMF）事件中占主导地位，而融雪驱动了年度春季最大洪水（AMFSP）事件。对于AMF事件（1960- 2018年），融雪的贡献为10.01–12.21％，冰川融合的60.49–60.92％，降雨量为26.86–29.50％。对于AMFSP事件（1961- 2018年），融雪的贡献为48.49-56.08％，冰川融合的16.12–22.08％，降雨量为27.79–29.42％。这些发现为增强洪水预测和优化水资源管理提供了关键见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Kumalak River, a typical alpine glacierized catchment in the Tianshan region, experiences complex flooding driven by glacier meltwater, snowmelt, and rainfall. However, the mechanisms driving these processes under climate change remain unclear. To address this, a SWAT-Glacier hydrological model and a degree–day factor model were used for snowmelt, glacier meltwater, and rainfall calculations. Two Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) models (LSTM-SG and LSTM-DDF) were developed using these inputs, and additive decomposition and integrated gradient methods were applied to interpret flood mechanisms. Glacier meltwater was found to dominate annual maximum flood (AMF) events, while snowmelt drove annual spring maximum flood (AMFSp) events. For AMF events (1960–2018), contributions were 10.01–12.21% from snowmelt, 60.49–60.92% from glacier meltwater, and 26.86–29.50% from rainfall. For AMFSp events (1961–2018), contributions were 48.49–56.08% from snowmelt, 16.12–22.08% from glacier meltwater, and 27.79–29.42% from rainfall. These findings provide critical insights for enhancing flood prediction and optimizing water resource management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00918-z/MediaObjects/41612_2025_918_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 灌溉扩展对基于IRRMIP结果的湿润压力的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-56356-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yi Yao; Agnès Ducharne; Benjamin I. Cook; Steven J. De Hertog; Kjetil Schanke Aas; Pedro F. Arboleda-Obando; Jonathan Buzan; Jeanne Colin; Maya Costantini; Bertrand Decharme; David M. Lawrence; Peter Lawrence; L. Ruby Leung; Min-Hui Lo; Narayanappa Devaraju; William R. Wieder; Ren-Jie Wu; Tian Zhou; Jonas Jägermeyr; Sonali McDermid; Yadu Pokhrel; Maxwell Elling; Naota Hanasaki; Paul Muñoz; Larissa S. Nazarenko; Kedar Otta; Yusuke Satoh; Tokuta Yokohata; Lei Jin; Xuhui Wang; Vimal Mishra; Subimal Ghosh; Wim Thiery&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;灌溉在20 &lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;h&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;世纪迅速扩展，通过水，能量和生物地球化学变化影响气候。对这些影响的先前评估主要依赖于单个地球系统模型，因此遭受了结构模型的不确定性。在这里，我们通过分析参与灌溉模型对比项目（IRRMIP）的六个地球系统模型的模拟结果来量化历史灌溉扩展对气候的影响。结果表明，灌溉的扩张会导致灌溉水抽水的迅速增加，这会导致在大量灌溉区域的2米空气温度极端热量（≥4倍的可能性降低）。但是，由于灌溉引起的空气湿度的增加，灌溉扩展对潮湿压力的冷却效果不太明显甚至逆转，具体取决于热应力度量。总而言之，这项研究表明，灌溉部署并不是在气候变化下升级人类热应激的有效适应措施，呼吁仔细处理当地人增加暴露于潮湿的压力。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Irrigation rapidly expanded during the 20&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;h&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; century, affecting climate via water, energy, and biogeochemical changes. Previous assessments of these effects predominantly relied on a single Earth System Model, and therefore suffered from structural model uncertainties. Here we quantify the impacts of historical irrigation expansion on climate by analysing simulation results from six Earth system models participating in the Irrigation Model Intercomparison Project (IRRMIP). Results show that irrigation expansion causes a rapid increase in irrigation water withdrawal, which leads to less frequent 2-meter air temperature heat extremes across heavily irrigated areas (≥4 times less likely). However, due to the irrigation-induced increase in air humidity, the cooling effect of irrigation expansion on moist-heat stress is less pronounced or even reversed, depending on the heat stress metric. In summary, this study indicates that irrigation deployment is not an efficient adaptation measure to escalating human heat stress under climate change, calling for carefully dealing with the increased exposure of local people to moist-heat stress.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-56356-1/MediaObjects/41467_2025_56356_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 从2002年到2021年，超过60％的降水转化为全球河流盆地的地面储水</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-024-01967-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yulong Zhong; Baoming Tian; Hyunglok Kim; Xing Yuan; Xinyue Liu; Enda Zhu; Yunlong Wu; Lunche Wang; Lizhe Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;降水作为陆生水周期的主要驱动力的关键作用是良好的。但是，量化每日降水向陆地储水的转化仍然是一个挑战。在这里，我们通过引入定量度量标准，平均每日降水量的平均分数转化为陆生水存储，从而通过利用增强的陆地储水统计重建方法和从重力恢复和重力恢复中的水存储数据来实现储水动力学的重要进展。气候实验卫星及其后续任务。这项研究表明，从2002年到2021年，大约64％的土地降水促成了全球121河流盆地的陆地储水，在不同的气候和地理区域中观察到明显的变化。我们的发现加深了人们对降水，地表过程和气候变化之间复杂相互作用的看法，对未来的水资源管理和水文建模具有宝贵的影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The crucial role of precipitation as a primary driver for terrestrial water cycle is well-established. However, quantifying the transformation of daily precipitation into terrestrial water storage remains a challenge. Here we address this by introducing a quantitative metric, average daily fraction of precipitation transformed into terrestrial water storage, providing an important advancement into the dynamics of water storage by utilizing the enhanced terrestrial water storage statistical reconstruction method and water storage data from the Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment satellites and their follow-on mission. This study reveals that approximately 64% of land precipitation contributes to terrestrial water storage in global 121 river basins from 2002 to 2021, with evident variations observed across different climatic and geographical regions. Our findings deepen perception into the complex interactions between precipitation, land surface processes, and climate change, offering valuable implications for future water resource management and hydrological modeling.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-024-01967-7/MediaObjects/43247_2024_1967_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 中国含水层的慢性氮遗产</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02016-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xin Liu; Fu-Jun Yue; Li Li; Feng Zhou; Hang Wen; Zhifeng Yan; Lichun Wang; Wei Wen Wong; Cong-Qiang Liu; Si-Liang Li&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球大约一半的饮用水来自地下水，但地下水质量受到全球含量高硝酸盐的威胁。我们对地下水浓度的理解通常受地下水中的地下水和硝酸盐数据稀缺的无法访问的限制。在这里，我们通过编制来自中国4047个地下水位的硝酸盐浓度和同位素数据来使用机器学习和决策树热图分析，以了解其在地理，气候和人为因素的梯度之间的动态和驱动因素。结果表明，硝酸盐浓度大大差异高，并且在更深的地下水中通常较低，这表明根据硝酸盐同位素模式（例如深度硝化剂），硝酸盐的去除率可能更高。在类似的地下水含水层深度，硝酸盐浓度在人口密度较高的城市地区最高。此外，中国北部干旱的硝酸盐浓度通常高于中国潮湿的南部。有趣的是，虽然在深度深处硝酸盐浓度较低，但缓慢的地下水流量也表明氮的遗产延长。尽管自2016年以来，中国的地下水氮污染总体下降，但持续的污染仍然存在。中国地下水质量保护的未来策略应解决不同含水层中硝酸盐的长期遗产，地下水中的氮水平上升。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;About half of the global drinking water comes from groundwater, yet groundwater quality is threatened by high nitrate concentrations globally. Our understanding of groundwater nitrate concentrations is often limited by inaccessibility of groundwater and scarcity of nitrate data in groundwater. Here we used machine learning and decision tree-heatmap analysis by compiling nitrate concentrations and isotope data from 4047 groundwater sites across China to understand their dynamics and drivers across gradients of geographical, climate, and human factors. Results show that nitrate concentrations vary substantially over depth and are generally lower in deeper groundwater, indicating potentially higher nitrate removal rates according to nitrate isotopic pattern such as denitrification at depth. At similar groundwater aquifer depths, nitrate concentrations are highest in urban regions with high population density. In addition, nitrate concentrations are generally higher in arid northern China than humid southern China. Interestingly, while groundwater nitrate concentrations are lower at deeper depths, slow groundwater flow also indicates prolonged nitrogen legacy. Although there has been an overall decline in groundwater nitrogen pollution in China since 2016, persistent pollution has lingered. Future strategies for groundwater quality protection in China should address the long-term legacy of nitrate in different aquifers and rising nitrogen levels in groundwater.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02016-7/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2016_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 澳大利亚二十年来的澳大利亚水质趋势显示出大堡礁地区的恶化和穆雷 - 达林盆地的恢复</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02044-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Danlu Guo; Qian Zhang; Camille Minaudo; Rémi Dupas; Clément Duvert; Shuci Liu; Kefeng Zhang; Ulrike Bende-Michl; Anna Lintern&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;了解河水质量轨迹和驱动因素对于有效的环境管理至关重要。在这里，我们在澳大利亚进行了全面的全国性水质趋势评估，并从2000年到2019年进行了287个集水区。大约一半的集水区显示了分析的每个参数的流量非正率浓度的显着趋势。这些重大趋势中的大多数是由于浓度流关系的变化而不是流量的长期趋势。澳大利亚的两个主要河流盆地在其重大趋势中表现出相反的区域模式。东北海岸很大程度上流入了大屏障礁泻湖，磷和沉积物增加。这可能反映了自1960年代以来增加土地清理和受精的滞后影响，而该地区的土地改善尚未显示出水质的改善。默里 - 达林盆地的盐度，磷和沉积物的降低，可能是由地区规模盐度管理干预措施的影响以及对集水过程的干旱长期造成的。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understanding river water quality trajectories and drivers is crucial for effective environmental management. Here we present a comprehensive nation-wide water quality trend assessment across Australia with 287 catchments from 2000 to 2019. About half of the catchments show significant trends in the flow-normalised concentration for each parameter analysed. Most of these significant trends are due to changes in concentration-flow relationships rather than long-term trends in flow. Two of Australia’s major river basins show opposing regional patterns in their significant trends. The North East Coast, which largely flows into the Great Barrier Reef lagoon, has increasing phosphorus and sediments. This potentially reflects lagged effects of increasing land clearing and fertilisation since 1960s, while land improvement in the region has not yet demonstrated improvement on water quality. The Murray-Darling Basin has decreasing salinity, phosphorus, and sediment, likely driven by effects of a region-scale salinity management interventions and a prolonged drought on catchment processes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02044-3/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2044_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 人类引起的水损失可能威胁中国沙质地区的可持续发展</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02046-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Runa A; Xinliang Pan; Liudi Zhu; Kelvin T. F. Chan; Zhangcai Qin; Enliang Guo; Yuhai Bao; Song Qing; Tingwei Cui&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水对于可持续的社会经济发展是必不可少的，尤其是在中国的沙质地区。尽管在桑迪地区进行了现有研究，但总储水量变化及其潜在影响的驱动因素仍然不足。在这里，我们通过集成多个数据集发现了2002年至2023年的总储水总存储中净损失559.7亿立方米。水损失主要归因于农田灌溉的增加（495.6亿立方米）和生态恢复（370.4亿立方米）。在接下来的40年中，在低和高排放情况下，供水能力将分别降低6.54％和19.07％，要求将人类用水量减少60％至135％。这种耗竭可能威胁到区域可持续性和国家生态安全。这项研究要求对水资源进行紧急科学法规，包括严格控制当地消费和增强供应能力。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water is indispensable for sustainable socioeconomic development, especially in China’s sandy regions. Despite existing studies in sandy regions, the drivers of changes in total water storage and their potential impacts remain inadequately understood. Here we found a 55.97 billion m³ net loss in total water storage from 2002 to 2023 by integrating multiple datasets. Water loss was primarily attributed to increased farmland irrigation (49.56 billion m³) and ecological restoration (37.04 billion m³). In the coming 40 years, water supply capacity will decrease by up to 6.54% and 19.07% under low and high emission scenarios, respectively, requiring reductions in human water consumption of 60% to 135%. This depletion potentially threatens both regional sustainability and national ecological security. This study calls for urgent scientific regulations on water resources, including strict control of local consumption and enhancement of supply capacity.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02046-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2046_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 未来变暖水平下的全球水间隙</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-56517-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lorenzo Rosa; Matteo Sangiorgio&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;了解气候变化对水资源的影响对于制定有效的适应策略至关重要。我们量化“水间隙”或不可持续的用水量 - 水需求超过供应的短缺，导致稀缺。我们使用多模型分析来量化基线和未来的水间隙，该分析结合了两个合理的未来变暖方案。基线全球水间隙为457.9 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; /yr，预测表明在1.5°C下增加了26.5 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; /yr（+5.8％）和67.4 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; /yr（+14.7％）和3°C的温暖场景， 分别。这些预测强调了变暖水平对水间隙的不均匀影响，强调需要缓解气候变化以减轻对水资源压力的需求。我们的结果还强调了各个国家和盆地之间不平等的适应需求，这些需求受到不同变暖方案的影响，具有重要的区域差异，并模型变异性使未来的预测变得复杂。需要强大的水管理策略来应对全球变暖引起的水稀缺性的升级。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understanding the impacts of climate change on water resources is crucial for developing effective adaptation strategies. We quantify “water gaps”, or unsustainable water use – the shortfall where water demand exceeds supply, resulting in scarcity. We quantify baseline and future water gaps using a multi-model analysis that incorporates two plausible future warming scenarios. The baseline global water gap stands at 457.9 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/yr, with projections indicating an increase of 26.5 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/yr (+5.8%) and 67.4 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/yr (+14.7%) under 1.5 °C and 3 °C warming scenarios, respectively. These projections highlight the uneven impact of warming levels on water gaps, emphasizing the need for continued climate change mitigation to alleviate stress on water resources. Our results also underscore the unequal adaptation needs across countries and basins, influenced by varying warming scenarios, with important regional differences and model variability complicating future projections. Robust water management strategies are needed to tackle the escalating water scarcity caused by global warming.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-56517-2/MediaObjects/41467_2025_56517_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>