<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 02:09:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | Bedmap3更新了南极洲的冰床，表面和厚度网格数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04672-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Bedmap3 updated ice bed, surface and thickness gridded datasets for Antarctica&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hamish D. Pritchard; Peter T. Fretwell; Alice C. Fremand; Julien A. Bodart; James D. Kirkham; Alan Aitken; Jonathan Bamber; Robin Bell; Cesidio Bianchi; Robert G. Bingham; Donald D. Blankenship; Gino Casassa; Knut Christianson; Howard Conway; Hugh F. J. Corr; Xiangbin Cui; Detlef Damaske; Volkmar Damm; Boris Dorschel; Reinhard Drews; Graeme Eagles; Olaf Eisen; Hannes Eisermann; Fausto Ferraccioli; Elena Field; René Forsberg; Steven Franke; Vikram Goel; Siva Prasad Gogineni; Jamin Greenbaum; Benjamin Hills; Richard C. A. Hindmarsh; Andrew O. Hoffman; Nicholas Holschuh; John W. Holt; Angelika Humbert; Robert W. Jacobel; Daniela Jansen; Adrian Jenkins; Wilfried Jokat; Lenneke Jong; Tom A. Jordan; Edward C. King; Jack Kohler; William Krabill; Joséphine Maton; Mette Kusk Gillespie; Kirsty Langley; Joohan Lee; German Leitchenkov; Cartlon Leuschen; Bruce Luyendyk; Joseph A. MacGregor; Emma MacKie; Geir Moholdt; Kenichi Matsuoka; Mathieu Morlighem; Jérémie Mouginot; Frank O. Nitsche; Ole A. Nost; John Paden; Frank Pattyn; Sergey Popov; Eric Rignot; David M. Rippin; Andrés Rivera; Jason L. Roberts; Neil Ross; Antonia Ruppel; Dustin M. Schroeder; Martin J. Siegert; Andrew M. Smith; Daniel Steinhage; Michael Studinger; Bo Sun; Ignazio Tabacco; Kirsty J. Tinto; Stefano Urbini; David G. Vaughan; Douglas S. Wilson; Duncan A. Young; Achille Zirizzotti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;我们提出了Bedmap3，这是最新的网格产品套件，描述了60°S南极南极南极的地面高度，冰厚度以及海底和冰川床升高。 BedMap3均包含并增加了先前用于BedMap2的所有后1950年后数据集，其中包括15个数据提供商的84次新的Aero-Geophysical Surveys，另外5200万个数据点和190万行的测量线。这些努力填补了包括主要山脉和南极洲东部，南极海岸线和南极半岛的显着空白。我们的新Bedmap3/Rings接地线类似地将最近的多个映射整合到一个单一的，空间连贯的功能中。结合更新的表面地貌，冰架厚度，岩石露头和测深的图，Bedmap3揭示了南极冰的冰山下景观和分布，提供了解释大陆规模景观演化的新机会，并为南极冰板的过去和未来的进化提供了新的机会。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We present Bedmap3, the latest suite of gridded products describing surface elevation, ice-thickness and the seafloor and subglacial bed elevation of the Antarctic south of 60 °S. Bedmap3 incorporates and adds to all post-1950s datasets previously used for Bedmap2, including 84 new aero-geophysical surveys by 15 data providers, an additional 52 million data points and 1.9 million line-kilometres of measurement. These efforts have filled notable gaps including in major mountain ranges and the deep interior of East Antarctica, along West Antarctic coastlines and on the Antarctic Peninsula. Our new Bedmap3/RINGS grounding line similarly consolidates multiple recent mappings into a single, spatially coherent feature. Combined with updated maps of surface topography, ice shelf thickness, rock outcrops and bathymetry, Bedmap3 reveals in much greater detail the subglacial landscape and distribution of Antarctica’s ice, providing new opportunities to interpret continental-scale landscape evolution and to model the past and future evolution of the Antarctic ice sheets.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04672-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4672_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | GLEAM4：从1980年到现在为0.1分辨率的全球土地蒸发和土壤水分数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04610-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;GLEAM4: global land evaporation and soil moisture dataset at 0.1 resolution from 1980 to near present&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Diego G. Miralles; Olivier Bonte; Akash Koppa; Oscar M. Baez-Villanueva; Emma Tronquo; Feng Zhong; Hylke E. Beck; Petra Hulsman; Wouter Dorigo; Niko E. C. Verhoest; Shekoofeh Haghdoost&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;陆地蒸发在调节气候和水资源中起着至关重要的作用。在这里，我们提供了一个连续的，每日的数据集，涵盖了1980  -  2023年，其空间分辨率为0.1°，该数据集使用第四代Amsterdam模型（GLEAM）产生。 GLEAM4包含混合建模中的发展，从涡流和SAPFLOW数据中学习蒸发应力。它具有改进的关键因素的代表，例如拦截，大气水需求，土壤水分和植物进入地下水。估计值与现有的全局蒸发产品相互比较，并针对原位测量值进行了验证，包括来自473个涡流协调位点的数据，显示中位相关性为0.73，根平方误差为0.95 mm d- &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;和kling-Gling-Gupta效率为0.49。全球土地蒸发估计为68.5×10 &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;年&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ，归因于蒸腾作用62％。除了实际的蒸发及其成分（蒸腾，截距损失，土壤蒸发等）之外，数据集还提供土壤水分，潜在的蒸发，明智的热通量和蒸发压力，从而促进了广泛的水文，气候和生态研究。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Terrestrial evaporation plays a crucial role in modulating climate and water resources. Here, we present a continuous, daily dataset covering 1980–2023 with a 0.1°spatial resolution, produced using the fourth generation of the Global Land Evaporation Amsterdam Model (GLEAM). GLEAM4 embraces developments in hybrid modelling, learning evaporative stress from eddy-covariance and sapflow data. It features improved representation of key factors such as interception, atmospheric water demand, soil moisture, and plant access to groundwater. Estimates are inter-compared with existing global evaporation products and validated against in situ measurements, including data from 473 eddy-covariance sites, showing a median correlation of 0.73, root-mean-square error of 0.95 mm d&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;, and Kling–Gupta efficiency of 0.49. Global land evaporation is estimated at 68.5 × 10&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;, with 62% attributed to transpiration. Beyond actual evaporation and its components (transpiration, interception loss, soil evaporation, etc.), the dataset also provides soil moisture, potential evaporation, sensible heat flux, and evaporative stress, facilitating a wide range of hydrological, climatic, and ecological studies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04610-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4610_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 驱动旋风，温暖的传送带和大气河的运动学分析</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00942-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A kinematic analysis of extratropical cyclones, warm conveyor belts and atmospheric rivers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Helen F. Dacre; Peter A. Clark&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;中纬度天气系统在造成洪水，风损和相关的社会影响方面起着重要作用。数值建模和观察方法的进步导致了中纬度概要和动态研究的众多概念模型的发展。随着这些模型扩散，将新的见解纳入凝聚力的理解可能是具有挑战性的。本文使用运动学观点来解释中纬度研究，以综合各种概念并创建大气河生命周期的示意图。我们的分析表明，尽管有不同的方法，定义和术语来描述驱动旋风旋风，温暖的输送带气流和大气河流，但推动其形成和发育的基本机制还是一致的。因此，在独立研究这些功能的同时，重要的是要认识到它们都是更大的大气流程模式的一部分。我们希望这种运动学方法将成为联系这些现象研究的桥梁。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mid-latitude weather systems play a significant role in causing floods, wind damage, and related societal impacts. Advances in numerical modeling and observational methods have led to the development of numerous conceptual models in mid-latitude synoptic and dynamical research. As these models proliferate, integrating new insights into a cohesive understanding can be challenging. This paper uses a kinematic perspective to interpret mid-latitude research in a way that synthesises various concepts and create a schematic diagram of an atmospheric river lifecycle. Our analysis demonstrates that, despite varying methods, definitions, and terminology used to describe extratropical cyclones, warm conveyor belt airflows, and atmospheric rivers, the underlying mechanisms driving their formation and development are consistent. Thus, while studying these features independently is valuable, it is important to recognise that they are all part of a larger atmospheric flow pattern. We hope this kinematic approach will serve as a bridge to link research on these phenomena.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00942-z/MediaObjects/41612_2025_942_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>