<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 02:11:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 淡水流入智利，阿根廷和玻利维亚的安第斯高原的封闭盆地</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02130-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Freshwater inflows to closed basins of the Andean plateau in Chile, Argentina, and Bolivia&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Alexander B. Kirshen; Brendan J. Moran; Lee Ann Munk; Aeon A. Russo; Sarah V. McKnight; Jordan Jenckes; Daniel B. Corkran; Magdalen Bresee; David F. Boutt&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在智利，阿根廷和玻利维亚的盐水含水层中发现了世界上一半以上的锂资源。锂盐水加工需要淡水，因此随着锂探索的增加，淡水可用性的准确估计对于该地区的水资源有限的水管理决策至关重要。在这里，我们计算现代的淡水流入，例如地下水充电和流量，用于28个活跃或前瞻性锂的盆地。我们使用区域水预算评估，现场流量测量以及全球气候和地下水补给数据集。使用淡水流入估计，我们使用可用的水剩余方法来计算水的稀缺性。在所有28个盆地中，淡水流入量为2至33毫米&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; 。我们的结果表明，通常使用的全球水文模型高估了流量和淡水的可用性，从而导致水稀缺性分类不准确。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;More than half the world’s lithium resources are found in brine aquifers in Chile, Argentina, and Bolivia. Lithium brine processing requires freshwater, so as lithium exploration increases, accurate estimates of freshwater availability are critical for water management decisions in this region with limited water resources. Here we calculate modern freshwater inflows, such as groundwater recharge and streamflow, for 28 active or prospective lithium-producing basins. We use regional water budget assessments, field streamflow measurements, and global climate and groundwater recharge datasets. Using the freshwater inflow estimates, we calculate water scarcity using the Available Water Remaining methodology. Among all 28 basins, freshwater inflows range from 2 to 33 mm year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;. Our results reveal that commonly used global hydrologic models overestimate streamflow and freshwater availability substantially, leading to inaccurate water scarcity classifications.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02130-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2130_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 从2001年到2022年，北部植被抵抗北部植被抵抗的明显下降</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-58253-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A pronounced decline in northern vegetation resistance to flash droughts from 2001 to 2022&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Miao Zhang; Xing Yuan; Zhenzhong Zeng; Ming Pan; Peili Wu; Jingfeng Xiao; Trevor F. Keenan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候变化导致干旱过渡到被称为闪存干旱的快速和强化现象，对风险管理提出了巨大的挑战，尤其是关于它们对生态系统生产力的影响。量化生态系统在闪光干旱期间维持生产力的能力（称为生态系统抗性）对于评估干旱影响至关重要。但是，尚不确定生态系统生产力对闪存干旱的抵抗力如何随着时间而变化。在这里，我们表明，在2001  -  2022年期间，北半球热点的抗植被抵抗力在北半球热点高达27％（±5％），其中包括东亚，北美西部和北欧。植被耐药性的显着下降主要归因于蒸气压力不足和温度的增加，以及对植被对水利用率的敏感性增强。在生长季节中，闪存干旱构成比缓慢发展的干旱构成更高的生态风险，在这个季节中，生态系统的生产力经历了更快的响应时间下降速度。我们的结果强调了在气候变化下抵抗闪存干旱的有限生态系统能力。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate change has led to the transition of droughts into rapid and intensified phenomena known as flash droughts, presenting considerable challenges for risk management, particularly concerning their impact on ecosystem productivity. Quantifying the ecosystem’s capacity to maintain productivity during flash droughts, referred to as ecosystem resistance, is crucial to assess drought impacts. However, it remains uncertain how the resistance of ecosystem productivity to flash drought changes over time. Here we show that vegetation resistance to flash droughts declines by up to 27% (±5%) over the Northern Hemisphere hotspots during 2001-2022, including eastern Asia, western North America, and northern Europe. The notable decline in vegetation resistance is mainly attributed to increased vapour pressure deficit and temperature, and enhanced vegetation structural sensitivity to water availability. Flash droughts pose higher ecological risks than slowly-developing droughts during the growing seasons, where ecosystem productivity experiences faster decline rates with a shorter response time. Our results underscore the limited ecosystem capacity to resist flash droughts under climate change.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-58253-z/MediaObjects/41467_2025_58253_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>