<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 02:09:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 结合开源水电厂和储层数据的全球数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04975-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Global dataset combining open-source hydropower plant and reservoir data&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jignesh Shah; Jing Hu; Oreane Y. Edelenbosch; Michelle T. H. van Vliet&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水力发电是至关重要的可再生能源，在很大程度上取决于水的可用性。分析干旱和气候变化对水电潜力的影响需要有关水力发电厂属性（例如植物类型和头部）和储层特征（例如面积，深度和体积）的详细数据。但是，现有的开源数据集的整合不足：水电工厂数据集通常缺乏储层信息，而储层数据集通常会错过水力发电工厂信息。本文通过引入GLOHYDRORES来解决这一差距，Glohydreors是一个结合了现有的开源水电厂和储层数据集的全局数据集。 Glohydrores包括植物位置，头部，植物类型以及水库详细信息，例如大坝和水库位置，大坝高度，水库深度，区域和数量，用于128个国家 /地区的7,775种植物。与EIA（2022）和IRENA（2023）报告的安装水力数据相比，Glohydrores占全球安装能力的近79％和81％。开源GLOHYDRORES数据集提供了关键数据，以改善工厂水平的水力发电建模，并可以支持大陆上的能源安全和规划到全球规模。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hydropower is a crucial renewable source that depends heavily on water availability. Analyzing drought and climate change impacts on hydropower potential requires detailed data on both hydropower plant attributes (e.g. plant type and head) and reservoir characteristics (e.g. area, depth and volume). However, existing open-source datasets are poorly integrated: hydropower plant datasets often lack reservoir information, while reservoir datasets commonly miss hydropower plant information. This paper addresses this gap by introducing GloHydroRes, a global dataset that combines existing open-source hydropower plant and reservoir datasets. GloHydroRes includes attributes like plant location, head, plant type as well as reservoir details such as dam and reservoir location, dam height, reservoir depth, area, and volume for 7,775 plants in 128 countries. GloHydroRes covers nearly 79% and 81% of the global installed capacity when compared with installed hydropower data as reported by the EIA(2022) and IRENA (2023), respectively. The open-source GloHydroRes dataset provides crucial data to improve hydropower generation modelling at plant level and can support energy security and planning at continent to global scale.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04975-0/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4975_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 节水灌溉面积的扩张几乎不能提高农作物的产量，同时在中国的气候场景下节省水</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02279-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Water-saving irrigated area expansion hardly enhances crop yield while saving water under climate scenarios in China&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zhiwei Yue; La Zhuo; Xiangxiang Ji; Pengcheng Tian; Jie Gao; Wei Wang; Fubin Sun; Yiduo Duan; Pute Wu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;面对气候变化的水资源短缺和农作物产量损失的风险，在中国尚不清楚灌溉面积的扩张以及如何提高灌溉面积可以通过更少的水增加产量。在这里，我们将2000-2018用作基线，并在75个情况下，在2030年代至2090 s的裁剪模式中模拟了全部作物用水，生产，单位水足迹的网格响应，并考虑了在3种气候变化途径下的两种5级适应措施。与仅气候变化相比，进一步的灌溉膨胀对增加的产量（低于20.8％）和减少水足迹的影响有限（低于3.6％）。合并的两种适应性措施放大了它们各自的影响，技术产量提高了对生产的贡献（37.0-99.6％）和水足迹（90.4-102.3％）。在全面的最佳情况下，随着产量的增加，水足迹将减少。没有水减少绿色水（1.6–1.7％）和蓝色水（6.6–21.6％）节省水。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Facing climate change risks of water shortages and crop yield losses, it is unclear in China that whether and how irrigated area expansion and technological yield improvement can increase production with less water. Here we used 2000–2018 as the baseline and simulated the grid responses of total crop water use, production, unit water footprint by cropping modes in 2030s–2090 s in 75 scenarios with considering each 5 levels of two adaptation measures under 3 climate change pathways. Compared with climate change alone, further irrigation expansion has limited effects on increasing production (below 20.8%) and decreasing water footprint (below 3.6%). Combined two adaptation measures magnifies their respective effects, with technological yield improvement dominating contributions to production (37.0–99.6%) and water footprint (90.4–102.3%). In comprehensive optimal scenario, water footprint will reduce with increased production. No water is saved with reduced green water (1.6–1.7%) and increased blue water (6.6–21.6%).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02279-0/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2279_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 在升高的温度下，特拉华河的增强洪水同步和下游严重程度</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02243-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Enhanced flood synchrony and downstream severity in the Delaware River under rising temperatures&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Matthew G. Cooper; Ning Sun; Mark S. Wigmosta; Hisham Eldardiry; Mithun Deb; Zhaoqing Yang; David R. Judi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流洪水威胁着生活和经济稳定，全球风险在增加，尤其是在人口稠密的沿海地区。在特拉华河流域等山区沿海流域中，预计温度升高以减少积雪，重塑上游 - 下游洪水动态。然而，对高地支流和河口主要系统之间洪水同步的影响仍然很众所周知。使用高分辨率水文模型的多年代流量模拟，我们发现在未来的变暖场景（尤其是严重的洪水）（以上是第75&lt;sup&gt;个&lt;/sup&gt;百分位数）下，同步洪水的频率和幅度显着增加。在较高的温暖场景下，源头subbasins的雪堆和雨后洪水几乎消失了。令人惊讶的是，这种政权转变通过增强历史上积雪的子山糖毒素及其下游对应物之间的同步来扩大河口洪水。尽管同步加强和洪水幅度，但由于降雨的赛车事件较少，冷季洪水风险下降。相反，夏季洪水越来越大，更频繁，更频繁，同步，推动了洪水风险的季节性重新配置，这在未来的缓解策略中应考虑。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;River floods threaten life and economic stability, with risks increasing globally, especially in densely populated coastal areas. In mountainous coastal watersheds like the Delaware River Basin, rising temperature is projected to reduce snowpack, reshaping upstream–downstream flood dynamics. However, the impact on flood synchronization between upland tributaries and estuarine mainstems remains poorly understood. Using multidecadal streamflow simulations from a high-resolution hydrological model, we find significant increases in the frequency and magnitude of synchronized floods under future warming scenarios, particularly severe floods (above the 75&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile). Under higher warming scenarios, snowpack and rain-on-snow floods in headwater subbasins nearly vanish. Surprisingly, this regime shift amplifies estuarine flooding by enhancing synchronization between historically snow-dominated subbasins and their downstream counterparts. Despite intensified synchronization and flood magnitude, cold-season flood risk declines due to fewer rain-on-snow events. Conversely, summer floods grow larger, more frequent, and synchronized, driving a seasonal reconfiguration of flood risk that should be considered in future mitigation strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02243-y/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2243_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 在过去的70年中，变暖会导致早期和更晚的融雪洪水</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-58832-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Warming leads to both earlier and later snowmelt floods over the past 70 years&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yuhan Guo; Yuting Yang; Dawen Yang; Lu Zhang; Hongxing Zheng; Jinghua Xiong; Fangzheng Ruan; Juntai Han; Ziwei Liu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候变暖可减少寒冷地区的雪覆盖，从而改变融雪的洪水状态，并带来重大的水文和生态后果。现有的证据表明，随着气候温暖，融雪往往在本赛季早些时候开始，导致较早的融雪洪水。在这里，我们表明，在变暖下，融雪洪水的时机可以延长或延迟。使用1950  -  2020年以来的流量观测以及基于事件的分析，该分析区分了2339个北半球的洪水生成机制，受雪影响的集水区，我们表明，在温暖下，较早的融雪效应可以实质上被减少，甚至可以被减速的雪速率逆转。这导致大约30％的集水区延迟融雪的洪水泛滥，导致半球量表的总体小转变（每十年-0.87±2.4天）。我们的发现挑战了普遍的“变暖导致早期的融雪洪水”范式，揭示了在温暖世界中融雪洪水变化的更为复杂的模式。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate warming reduces snow cover in cold regions, altering snowmelt flood regimes with significant hydrological and ecological consequences. Existing evidence indicates that as climate warms, snowmelt tends to begin earlier in the season, leading to earlier snowmelt floods. Here we show that the timing of snowmelt floods can be either advanced or delayed under warming. Using streamflow observations from 1950–2020 and an event-based analysis that distinguishes flood-generating mechanisms across 2339 Northern Hemisphere, snow-affected catchments, we show that the earlier snowmelt effect can be substantially offset or even reversed by a decelerated snowmelt rate under warming. This results in delayed snowmelt floods in approximately 30% of the catchments, contributing to an overall minor shift on a hemispheric scale (−0.87 ± 2.4 days per decade). Our findings challenge the prevailing “warming leads to earlier snowmelt floods” paradigm, revealing a more complex pattern of changes in snowmelt flood in a warming world.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-58832-0/MediaObjects/41467_2025_58832_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 评估城市化对中国城市聚集的大雨的一致和不同影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02283-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Assessing the consistent and divergent impacts of urbanization on heavy rainfall in Chinese urban agglomerations&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Fanggang Li; Yingbao Yang; Haider Ali; Jingkai Xie; Yang Dai; Zhiqing Li; Zhenwei Wang; Xin Pan; Hayley J. Fowler&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;了解城市化对极端降水的影响对于在全球变暖和快速的城市扩张的背景下促进可持续的城市发展至关重要。在这里，我们发现在潮湿地区的影响最大，例如长江三角洲和珍珠河三角洲，那里的城市化扩大了极端的降雨强度，随着代表性城市的城市化速度而变化。此外，与潮湿地区的大多数城市的日常规模相比，在3小时的规模上的影响更大。但是，我们发现城市化对北京 - 锡金 - 贝伊等大陆气候地区的极端降雨没有重大影响。此外，我们还发现，城市化会改变白天和夜间大雨的趋势，区域差异与不透水的表面覆盖范围有关。我们的发现提供了基本的科学证据，可以帮助城市设计有针对性的缓解灾难政策，尤其是对于那些具有不同背景和发展模式的人。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understanding the impact of urbanization on extreme precipitation is crucial for promoting sustainable urban development in the context of global warming and rapid urban expansion. Here we found the highest impacts in humid regions such as the Yangtze River Delta and Pearl River Delta, where urbanization amplifies extreme rainfall intensities, varying with the rate of urbanization across the representative cities. Moreover, the impact is greater at the 3-hourly scale compared to the daily scale in most cities in humid regions. However, we found no significant impact of urbanization on extreme rainfall across continental climate regions like the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei. Furthermore, we also found that urbanization alters the trends of heavy rainfall during daytime and nighttime, with significant regional variations linked to impervious surface coverage. Our findings provide essential scientific evidence to assist cities in designing targeted disaster mitigation policies, especially for those with diverse contexts and development patterns.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02283-4/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2283_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>