<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 02:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Water | 尽管湖区在全球范围内增长，但越来越小的冰川湖爆发洪水泛滥</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00388-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Georg Veh; Björn G. Wang; Anika Zirzow; Christoph Schmidt; Natalie Lützow; Frederic Steppat; Guoqing Zhang; Kristin Vogel; Marten Geertsema; John J. Clague; Oliver Korup&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;冰川湖爆发洪水（GLOF）可能起源于较大的湖泊，因为这些湖泊继续随着冰川静修的持续增长。但是，在可用的GLOF数据库中，这种看法仍然受到支持。在这里，我们绘制了1,686个冰川湖泊的区域，就在它们排干之前，在极地地区以外的13个冰川山区，并检查了1990年至2023年之间的湖泊前湖区的趋势。我们发现，湖泊前的湖泊地区几乎没有变化，或者几乎没有变化，或者即使是在整个湖泊区域，甚至在整个湖泊区域，因此危险的潜力也在整体上增长。这一违反直觉的发现反映了不断增长的GLOF幅度的局限性，例如湖泊和父冰川的解耦，宽阔，低梯度的出口或人类管理的发展。在所有地区，前湖泊区域都取决于几个冰堵塞的湖泊，这些湖泊的报道爆发爆发的爆发量是冰龙和基岩塞的湖泊的十倍。后两种水坝类型将继续扣留大量的融合水，从而考虑了大多数整体GLOF危害潜力，而冰烧的湖泊将随着脱水而缩小。由于这些湖泊类型在二十一世纪将有所不同，因此鉴于关键基础设施的暴露越来越大，我们呼吁对GLOF流出和影响进行定制模拟。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glacier lake outburst floods (GLOFs) may originate from larger lakes as these continue to grow with ongoing glacier retreat; however, this perception remains poorly supported in available GLOF databases. Here we mapped the areas of 1,686 glacier lakes, just before they drained, across 13 glaciated mountain regions outside polar regions and examined the trends in pre-GLOF lake areas between 1990 and 2023. We found that pre-GLOF lake areas barely changed, or even decreased, regionally through time, even as the total lake area, and thus hazard potential, grew overall. This counterintuitive finding reflects limits to growing GLOF magnitudes, such as the decoupling of lakes and parent glaciers, the development of wide, low-gradient outlets or human management. Across all regions, pre-GLOF lake areas depend on a few ice-dammed lakes, which have produced ten times more reported outbursts and ten times larger outbursts than moraine- and bedrock-dammed lakes. The latter two dam types will continue to impound growing amounts of meltwater, thereby accounting for most of the overall GLOF hazard potential, while ice-dammed lakes will shrink with deglaciation. As these lake types will evolve differently in the twenty-first century, we call for customized simulations of GLOF outflows and impacts, given the growing exposure of critical infrastructure.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00388-w/MediaObjects/44221_2025_388_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>