<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 02:17:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 将遥感衍生的河流坡度数据集与美国高分辨率水力织物相结合</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05941-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Merging Remote Sensing Derived River Slope Datasets with High-Resolution Hydrofabrics for the United States&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yixian Chen; Sagy Cohen; Anupal Baruah; Dipsikha Devi; Supath Dhital; Dan Tian; Dinuke Munasinghe&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;美国连续尺度 (CONUS) 洪水淹没测绘 Hydrofabric - ICESat-2 河流表面坡度 (FIM HF IRIS) 数据集集成了美国国家海洋和大气管理局 (NOAA) 水预测办公室业务 FIM 预报系统 (OWP HAND-FIM) 内 117,357 个空间对应的主流河段的卫星衍生全球 IRIS 河流坡度。首先开发了一种空间连接方法来对齐 FIM HF 和 IRIS 河段，解决河段流线源的差异。原始 FIM HF 斜率相对于 IRIS 斜率的平均偏差为 76 ± 168%。与 FIM HF 斜坡相比，FIM HF IRIS 应用于 OWP HAND-FIM，在八次洪水事件中将 FIM 精度平均提高了 31 ± 25% (CSI)。使用通用属性，IRIS 数据从 FIM HF IRIS 传输到 CONUS 下一代水资源建模框架 Hydrofabric (NextGen HF)，从而创建 NextGen HF IRIS 数据集。利用共同属性，生成的数据集可以在 OWP HAND-FIM 和 NextGen 中使用 SWOT 矢量数据。提供了空间连接方法，能够通过流线将水力织物与其他水文数据集集成。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The CONtiguous United States scale (CONUS) Flood Inundation Mapping Hydrofabric - ICESat-2 River Surface Slope (FIM HF IRIS) dataset integrates satellite-derived global IRIS river slopes for 117,357 spatially corresponding main-stream reaches within National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) Office of Water Prediction operational FIM forecasting system (OWP HAND-FIM). A spatial joining approach was first developed to align FIM HF and IRIS reaches, addressing differences in reach flowline sources. Original FIM HF slopes had an average bias of 76 ± 168% relative to IRIS slopes. Applying to OWP HAND-FIM, FIM HF IRIS improved FIM accuracy by average 31 ± 25% (CSI) across eight flood events compared to the FIM HF slopes. Using a common attribute, IRIS data were transferred from FIM HF IRIS to the CONUS Next Generation Water Resources Modeling Framework Hydrofabric (NextGen HF), creating the NextGen HF IRIS dataset. Leveraging a common attribute, the resulting datasets enable using SWOT vector data within OWP HAND-FIM and NextGen. The spatial joining approach enabling integrating the hydrofabrics with other hydrologic datasets via flowlines is provided.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05941-6/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5941_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>