<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 02:35:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 不同的地貌过程控制悬挂的沉积物和冰川从冰川出口</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-60776-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Different geomorphic processes control suspended sediment and bedload export from glaciers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ian Delaney; Frédéric Lardet; Matt Jenkin; Davide Mancini; Stuart N. Lane&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;正在进行的冰圈变化已大大改变了冰川化集水区的导出，对生态系统和下游用户（尤其是水电公司）产生了重大影响。沉积物在悬浮液中以更细的沉积物出口，或者是较粗的床，在沉积物和床之间间歇接触。迄今为止，与悬挂载荷相比，观察下冰层床的运输的困难限制了对撤离床负荷相关的物理过程的理解。我们通过将基于物理的基于物理的数值模型的数值模型和悬浮沉积物的悬浮沉积物和连续的床上载排放记录从高山冰川产生，从而阐明了控制沉积物出口的因素。出口大量的悬浮沉积物和床上负载，模型结果表明两者都依赖于沉积物的可用性进行运输。然而，冰川下通道中的床载出口也取决于特定的液压条件，特别是通道形状和液压粗糙度。与细粒沉积物相比，这使出口床尺寸的颗粒效率低下。结果，在检查床载导出过程时应明确考虑冰川液压，并应分别考虑悬挂和床负载的运输。熔融水的效率低下疏散疏散表明，只有在非易流动机制撤离沉积物（例如沉积物夹带到冰中）时，冰川侵蚀才能持续下去。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ongoing cryospheric change has modified sediment export from glacierized catchments substantially, with significant implications for ecosystems and downstream users, notably hydropower companies. Sediment is exported either as finer sediment in suspension or as coarser bedload with intermittent contact between sediment and the bed. To date, the difficulty in observing subglacial bedload transport limits the understanding of the physical processes associated with evacuating bedload compared with suspended load. We elucidate the factors controlling sediment export by inverting a physically-based numerical model of subglacial sediment production and sediment transport with suspended sediment and continuous bedload discharge records from an Alpine glacier. Comparable quantities of suspended sediment and bedload are exported, and model results suggest that both rely on the availability of sediment for transport. Yet, bedload export in subglacial channels also depends on particular hydraulic conditions, notably channel shape and hydraulic roughness. This makes exporting bedload-sized particles inefficient compared to fine-grained sediment. As a result, subglacial hydraulics should be explicitly considered when examining bedload export processes, and suspended and bedload transport should be considered separately. Inefficient bedload evacuation by melt water implies that glacial erosion may only continue when non-fluvial mechanisms evacuate sediment, such as sediment entrainment into the ice.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-60776-4/MediaObjects/41467_2025_60776_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 地球系统模型中的更精细的决议和目标过程表示改善水文投影和氢化气候影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01134-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Finer resolutions and targeted process representations in earth system models improve hydrologic projections and hydroclimate impacts&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Puja Das; Auroop R. Ganguly&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;地球系统模型为水政策和干预提供了信息，但是水文表示的知识差距限制了预测的可信度和影响评估。文献没有提供结论性的证据，表明将更高的决议，全面的过程模型和最新的参数化方案纳入将导致改进。我们比较了两代耦合建模对比项目（CMIP）模型，特别是CMIP5和CMIP6的氢气气候表示和径流预测，以及全球径流重建（Grun）和ECMWF Reanalysis Reanalysis v5（ERA5）的栅格径流（ECMWF）。我们的结果表明，最佳可用过程模型和参数化的系统嵌入方式以及更精细的分辨率，以机械上可以解释的方式改善了全球30条最大河流中30条最大河流中的不确定性特征。更熟练的CMIP6型号表明，在中端SSP370排放方案之后，40％的河流将显示出2100年的径流减少，影响了8.5亿人。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Earth system models inform water policy and interventions, but knowledge gaps in hydrologic representations limit the credibility of projections and impacts assessments. The literature does not provide conclusive evidence that incorporating higher resolutions, comprehensive process models, and latest parameterization schemes, will result in improvements. We compare hydroclimate representations and runoff projections across two generations of Coupled Modeling Intercomparison Project (CMIP) models, specifically, CMIP5 and CMIP6, with gridded runoff from Global Runoff Reconstruction (GRUN) and ECMWF Reanalysis V5 (ERA5) as benchmarks. Our results show that systematic embedding of the best available process models and parameterizations, together with finer resolutions, improve runoff projections with uncertainty characterizations in 30 of the largest rivers worldwide in a mechanistically explainable manner. The more skillful CMIP6 models suggest that, following the mid-range SSP370 emissions scenario, 40% of the rivers will exhibit decreased runoff by 2100, impacting 850 million people.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01134-5/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1134_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 全球城市城市化引起的降水不对称变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-61053-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Asymmetric shifts in precipitation due to urbanization across global cities&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jinghua Xiong; Yuting Yang; Long Yang; Dawen Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;城市化通过修改大气中的热，动态和化学过程来改变降水模式。但是，它对降水制度的影响，尤其是在每日量表下，对降水状态的影响很少。在这项工作中，我们使用高分辨率的，空间连续的卫星降水数据集来检查城市化引起的在全球城市的降水强度的转移。我们表明，城市化通常会导致不对称的偏移，增加较低强度的事件并降低更高强度的事件，在热带季风区域中具有不同的模式。这些转变主要是由于事件频率的变化而驱动的，导致城市地区的降水差异降低，尤其是在温带城市和表现出较高城市化水平的城市。每日分析表明，较低强度的降水最明显在清晨增加，而下午晚些时候较高的强度事件减少，减轻了昼夜降水的可变性。这些发现提供了重要的观察证据，表明城市化如何改变降水制度并强调对自适应城市水管理策略的需求。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Urbanization alters precipitation patterns by modifying thermal, dynamic, and chemical processes in the atmosphere. However, its effect on precipitation regimes, particularly at the sub-daily scale, is poorly understood. In this work, we use a high-resolution, spatially continuous satellite precipitation dataset to examine urbanization-induced shifts across precipitation intensities over global cities. We show that urbanization generally causes asymmetric shifts, increasing lower-intensity events and decreasing higher-intensity ones, with distinct patterns in tropical monsoon regions. These shifts, primarily driven by changes in event frequency, lead to reduced precipitation variability in urban areas, particularly in temperate cities and those exhibiting higher urbanization levels. Sub-daily analysis reveals that lower-intensity precipitation most notably increases in the early morning, while higher-intensity events decrease in the late afternoon, dampening diurnal precipitation variability. These findings offer important observational evidence of how urbanization alters precipitation regimes and highlight the need for adaptive urban water management strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-61053-0/MediaObjects/41467_2025_61053_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 用10年的卫星雷达数据绘制全球洪水</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-60973-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Mapping global floods with 10 years of satellite radar data&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Amit Misra; Kevin White; Simone Fobi Nsutezo; William Straka III; Juan Lavista&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;洪水每年造成广泛的全球损失，从而使有效的监视至关重要。尽管事实证明，卫星观测对于洪水检测和跟踪是无价的，但跨越时间段的全球全球洪水数据集仍然很少。在这项研究中，我们介绍了一个深度学习洪水检测模型，该模型利用了Sentinel-1合成孔径雷达（SAR）卫星图像的云渗透能力，从而使一贯的洪水范围通过云覆盖物以及白天和夜间条件进行映射。通过将该模型应用于10年的SAR数据，我们创建了一个独特的，纵向的全球洪水范围数据集，并没有受到云覆盖范围影响的预测，从而在过去十年中对历史上容易发生洪水的地区提供了全面和一致的见解。我们使用模型预测来确定埃塞俄比亚历史上容易发生洪水的地区，并在2024年5月在肯尼亚的洪水中证明了实时灾难反应能力。此外，我们的纵向分析揭示了随着时间的流逝，全球洪水范围的潜在趋势可能增加，尽管需要进一步验证才能探索与气候变化的联系。为了最大程度地发挥影响力，我们为我们的模型预测和代码存储库提供了公众的访问权限，赋予全球研究人员和从业人员的能力，以推动洪水监测并增强灾难响应策略。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Floods cause extensive global damage annually, making effective monitoring essential. While satellite observations have proven invaluable for flood detection and tracking, comprehensive global flood datasets spanning extended time periods remain scarce. In this study, we introduce a deep learning flood detection model that leverages the cloud-penetrating capabilities of Sentinel-1 Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) satellite imagery, enabling consistent flood extent mapping through cloud cover and in both day and night conditions. By applying this model to 10 years of SAR data, we create a unique, longitudinal global flood extent dataset with predictions unaffected by cloud coverage, offering comprehensive and consistent insights into historically flood-prone areas over the past decade. We use our model predictions to identify historically flood-prone areas in Ethiopia and demonstrate real-time disaster response capabilities during the May 2024 floods in Kenya. Additionally, our longitudinal analysis reveals potential increasing trends in global flood extent over time, although further validation is required to explore links to climate change. To maximize impact, we provide public access to both our model predictions and a code repository, empowering researchers and practitioners worldwide to advance flood monitoring and enhance disaster response strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-60973-1/MediaObjects/41467_2025_60973_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 气候和人为活动控制全球内部水域中铜，锌，镉和铬的浓度</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02508-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Climate and anthropogenic activities control the concentrations of copper, zinc, cadmium and chromium in global inland waters&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xia Jin; Qiqian Wu; Josep Peñuelas; Jordi Sardan; Yan Peng; Zimin Li; Xin Peng; Petr Heděnec; Qiao Yang; Chaoxiang Yuan; Ji Yuan; Zihao Chen; Zemin Zhao; Fuzhong Wu; Kai Yue&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球水域中重金属（CU，Zn，CD，CR）受到的污染对淡水生物多样性和生态系统功能构成了重大威胁，但是重金属的全球模式和驱动因素仍然很探索。在这里，使用从514个同行评审的出版物中收集的11,573个数据点进行评估，主要进步包括：（1）全球内陆水域中平均浓度的量化（CU：8.38，Zn：30.00，CD：0.53：0.53：0.53：0.53和CR：7.00μgL &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ），提供全球规模的参考值，以评估局部水平的局部水平评估。 （2）人为活性，温度，实际蒸散量，降水和径流主要控制内陆水域重金属的浓度，以及（3）建立了全球重金属污染热点，随后是南美，揭示了西亚和南亚和非洲的浓度显着升高。我们的研究对CU，Zn，CD和CR的内陆水提供了全面的分析，为在气候变化下靶向易受伤害地区的污染控制提供了科学基础。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Pollution by heavy metals (Cu, Zn, Cd, Cr) in global inland waters poses significant threats to freshwater biodiversity and ecosystem function, yet the global patterns and drivers of heavy metals remain poorly explored. Here, assessing using 11,573 data points collected from 514 peer-reviewed publications, key advances include: (1) quantification of median concentrations in global inland waters (Cu: 8.38, Zn: 30.00, Cd: 0.53, and Cr: 7.00 μg L&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;), providing global-scale reference values to contextualize local water quality assessments; (2) anthropogenic activities, temperature, actual evapotranspiration, precipitation and runoff dominantly control the concentrations of heavy metals in inland waters, and (3) global heavy metal pollution hotspots were established, revealing significantly elevated concentrations in West and South Asia and Africa, followed by South America. Our study provides a comprehensive analysis of inland water for Cu, Zn, Cd, and Cr, offering a scientific foundation for targeting pollution control in vulnerable regions under climate change.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02508-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2508_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Climate Change | 卫星观察到的冰盖表面融合水的快速增加</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-025-02364-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Rapid increases in satellite-observed ice sheet surface meltwater production&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lei Zheng; Xinyi Shang; Michiel R. van den Broeke; Brice Noël; Xichen Li; Xavier Fettweis; Qi Liang; Kang Wang; Jiping Liu; Xiao Cheng&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;表面融合水的生产会影响冰盖对全球海平面变化的贡献。迄今为止，遍布冰片范围的融合水产量主要是通过区域气候模型来量化的。在这里，我们提出了31年（1992- 2023年）的时间序列，用于每日卫星的表面熔体通量，用于格陵兰和南极冰盖。格陵兰岛的年度融水量显着增加，北部盆地的融化增强了北大西洋振荡的主导，而西部盆地的融化通量升高，这是由于北极海冰的下降而驱动的。在南极洲东部，自2000年以来，高熔体速率归因于南大洋的温暖空气侵入，这是由于与南环模式负相关的异常大气循环以及南极臭氧孔的恢复。该区域以前不太容易表面熔体，已成为熔体热点，可能导致融化岩石和未来的冰架不稳定。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Surface meltwater production influences the contribution of ice sheets to global sea-level change. Ice-sheet-wide meltwater production has thus far primarily been quantified by regional climate models. Here we present a 31-year (1992–2023) time series of daily satellite-observed surface melt flux for the Greenland and Antarctic ice sheets. The annual meltwater volume in Greenland has significantly increased, with intensified melt in the northern basins dominated by a negative North Atlantic Oscillation and elevated melt flux in western basins driven by the decline in Arctic sea-ice. In East Antarctica, high melt rates since 2000 are attributed to warm air incursions from the Southern Ocean due to anomalous atmospheric circulations associated with a negative Southern Annular Mode and the recovery of the Antarctic ozone hole. This region, previously less prone to surface melt, has become a melt hotspot, potentially leading to meltwater ponding and future ice shelf destabilization.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41558-025-02364-4/MediaObjects/41558_2025_2364_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 跨土壤植物 - 大气连续体的水能 - 碳通量的物理一致数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05386-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A physically consistent dataset of water-energy-carbon fluxes across the Soil-Plant-Atmosphere Continuum&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yunfei Wang; Yijian Zeng; Fakhereh Alidoost; Bart Schilperoort; Zengjing Song; Danyang Yu; Enting Tang; Qianqian Han; Zhunqiao Liu; Xiongbiao Peng; Chao Zhang; Bas Retsios; Serkan Girgin; Xiaoliang Lü; Qiting Zuo; Huanjie Cai; Qiang Yu; Christiaan van der Tol; Zhongbo Su&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;陆地大气通量的高质量和长期测量对于气候监测和地表模型（LSMS）基准测试至关重要。 Eddy协方差为理论和LSM评估提供了关键的原位数据，但大多数磁通塔缺乏连续的土壤植物 - 大气测量。在这里，我们介绍了水，能量和碳通量的长期全球数据集，以及相应的上方和下方的水文，光合作用和辐射数据，这些数据来自170个地点的Stemmus-Scope模型模拟。来自Plumber2和FluxNet2015的土壤水分（SM）数据的原位观察到的通量数据用于验证Stemmus-Scope数据集的有效性。 Results demonstrate that, without site-specific model tuning or calibration, and driven solely by global parameters and forcing datasets, simulated net radiation, latent heat flux, sensible heat flux, gross primary production, net ecosystem exchange, and SM datasets consistently agree with available in-situ measurements (median KGE: −0.03 to 0.80; median R &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; : 0.46 to 0.97; median RRMSE：4.09％至29.11％）。该数据集补充了现有的生态系统通量和SM网络，从而增强了我们对生态系统功能的理解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hight-quality and Long-term measurements of land-atmosphere fluxes are vital for climate monitoring and Land Surface models (LSMs) benchmarking. Eddy covariance provides key in-situ data for theory and LSMs evaluation, but most flux towers lack continuous soil-plant-atmosphere measurements. Here, we present a long-term global dataset of water, energy and carbon fluxes, along with the corresponding above and below-ground hydrological, photosynthetic, and radiative data derived from the STEMMUS-SCOPE model simulations at 170 sites. In-situ observed fluxes data from PLUMBER2 and soil moisture (SM) data from FLUXNET2015 are employed to validate the effectiveness of the STEMMUS-SCOPE dataset. Results demonstrate that, without site-specific model tuning or calibration, and driven solely by global parameters and forcing datasets, simulated net radiation, latent heat flux, sensible heat flux, gross primary production, net ecosystem exchange, and SM datasets consistently agree with available in-situ measurements (median KGE: −0.03 to 0.80; median R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;: 0.46 to 0.97; median rRMSE: 4.09% to 29.11%). This dataset supplements the existing ecosystem flux and SM network, enhancing our understanding of ecosystem functioning.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05386-x/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5386_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 三角洲动态系统中的弹性损失的空间传输</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02519-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Spatial transmission of resilience loss in deltaic dynamic systems&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yajun Wang; Jianliang Lin; Yu Yan; Zhenzhong Zeng; Xiaoye Liu; Shuxian Wang; Zhenyan She; Zeqin Huang; Pengnan Sun; Tongtiegang Zhao; Kairong Lin; Giovanni Coco; Huayang Cai&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流和潮汐动力学调节三角洲的水位，以生态和社会经济稳定为基础。在气候和人类压力的增长中，三角洲水位的弹性是从干扰中恢复的能力，这是量化和监测的强大方法。在这里，我们将水位的弹性定义为水平恢复后流动力动力障碍的速率。我们使用自相关来量化弹性趋势，并提出一种基于葡萄藤模型的高维弹性传输方法，以估计子系统遍布弹性损失的空间传播。将此框架应用于中国的珍珠河三角洲，揭示了由人为活动驱动的空间异质性和对弹性损失的传播。尽管流体动力和人类的影响不同，我们的方法仍可以扩展到其他主要三角洲。这些发现强调了针对特定驱动因素和子系统互动的量身定制的管理策略的需求，在不断升级的环境挑战中为全球三角洲保护提供了重要的见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;River and tidal dynamics regulate delta water levels, underpinning their ecological and socio-economic stability. Deltaic water level resilience, the capacity to recover from disturbances, is vital amid growing climate and human pressures, necessitating a robust method to quantify and monitor it. Here we define water level resilience as the rate of water level recovery post-hydrodynamic disturbances. We quantify resilience trends using autocorrelation and propose a high-dimensional resilience transmission method based on a vine Copula model to estimate the spatial propagation of resilience loss across subsystems. Applying this framework to the Pearl River Delta in China reveals spatial heterogeneity and inter-subsystem transmission of resilience loss driven by anthropogenic activities. Our approach can be extended to other major deltas, despite differing hydrodynamic and human impacts. The findings underscore the need for tailored management strategies addressing specific drivers and subsystem interactions, offering critical insights into the global delta preservation amid escalating environmental challenges.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02519-3/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2519_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>