<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 02:20:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 全球雨水的模式及其对从过去到未来预测的径流的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-59855-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Global patterns of rain-on-snow and its impacts on runoff from past to future projections&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Fadji Z. Maina; Sujay V. Kumar&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球变暖引起了寒冷地区的雨水（ROS），从而对生态系统和社会经济发展产生重大影响。但是，目前缺乏在不同排放场景之后对ROS和未来预测的全球分析，目前缺乏对管理策略必不可少的。在这里，我们研究了ROS的变化及其对可用于径流的水的影响，分析自1950年以来的历史状况，并在SSP245和SSP585之前预测未来的趋势。到本世纪末，ROS将主要发生在高纬度和海拔地区，例如高山，高山，北部，北部，北部的欧洲高度，以及三倍的历史范围。尽管如此，尽管降雨量增加，但降雨量的增加将减少ROS对径流的贡献的一半以上。尽管像美国西部这样的地区历史上经历了重要的ROS，但由于降低了积雪和降雨量的加剧，变暖会减少ROS的影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Global warming has induced rain-on-snow (ROS) in cold regions leading to significant consequences on ecosystems and socioeconomic development. However, a global analysis of ROS under historical conditions and future projections following different emissions scenarios, essential for management strategies, is currently lacking. Here, we examine ROS changes and their impacts on the water available for runoff, analyzing historical conditions since 1950 and projecting future trends under SSP245 and SSP585 until 2100. By the end of the century, ROS will predominantly occur in high-latitude and altitude regions such as High Mountain Asia, the Alps, Northern Eurasia, and America with rates up to three times higher than those of the historical conditions. Nonetheless, the increasing rainfall will reduce by more than half the contribution of ROS to the water available for runoff despite its rise. Although regions like the Western United States have historically experienced significant ROS, warming will diminish ROS impacts as they become twice lower due to decreasing snowpack and intensified rainfall.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-59855-3/MediaObjects/41467_2025_59855_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>