<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 02:34:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | AIDA 1公里的分辨率作物特异性雨林和灌溉区域以及对意大利的绿色和蓝色水需求</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05390-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;The AIDA 1 km resolution crop-specific rainfed and irrigated areas and green and blue water demands for Italy&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Nikolas Galli; Harsh Nanesha; Arianna Tolazzi; Davide Danilo Chiarelli; Maria Cristina Rulli&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候和全球变化改变了自然资源的需求和满足社会需求的可用性。农业用水仍然是一个优先事项，因为农业仍然是第一个淡水消费者。准确地灌溉和雨养作物的制图对于水管理和政策的农业流形建模至关重要。以意大利为重要的情况，我们提出了Aida（农业灌溉需求分析仪），这是一套高分辨率的农作物特异性地图和灌溉区和水需求。我们将非常高的分辨率作物特异性土地覆盖数据集与农田地面数据和灌溉强度图相结合，以在整个意大利地区为雨养和灌溉作物提供1公里分辨率的地图。带有最先进的输入的动态，空间分布的农业流水学模型将蒸发需求衍生成绿色的水（从储存为土壤水分的降水）和蓝色水（来自灌溉）。我们的结果在&amp;gt; 80％的区域中具有线性相关性&amp;gt; 75％&amp;gt; 75％，误差&amp;lt;20％的WRT亚国家统计。尽管由于投入，对水文过程和农业实践的假设造成的局限性，AIDA还是补充了意大利的现有水文模型和土地使用数据集。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate and global changes alter natural resources demand and availability for meeting societal needs. Agricultural water use remains a priority, as agriculture remains the first freshwater consumer. Accurate mapping of irrigated and rainfed crops is crucial in agro-hydrological modelling for water management and policy. Taking Italy as prominent case, we present AIDA (Agricultural Irrigation Demand Analyzer), a set of high-resolution crop-specific maps of rainfed and irrigated areas and water demands. We combine very-high resolution crop-specific landcover datasets with cropland ground data and irrigation intensity maps to derive 1km-resolution maps for rainfed and irrigated crops in the entire Italian territory. A dynamic, spatially distributed agro-hydrological model with state-of-the-art inputs derives evapotranspirative demands partitioned into green water (from precipitation stored as soil moisture) and blue water (from irrigation). Our results have a linear correlation &amp;gt;75% and an error &amp;lt;20% w.r.t. subnational statistics in &amp;gt;80% of the areas. Despite limitations due to inputs, assumptions on hydrological processes and agricultural practices, AIDA complements existing hydrological models and land use datasets for Italy.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05390-1/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5390_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Sustainability | 科罗拉多河重新分配的战略环境水权市场</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-025-01585-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A strategic environmental water rights market for Colorado River reallocation&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Philip Womble; Steven M. Gorelick; Barton H. Thompson Jr.; J. Sebastian Hernandez-Suarez&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;科罗拉多河系统是世界上最整体的盆地之一，努力向美国西南部和墨西哥供水。因此，盆地的90％的本地鱼类受到濒危，威胁或灭绝。在一项24年的巨型货币上，美国分配了超过40亿美元的减轻干旱，包括支付农场，城市和行业的水市场交易，以减少整个美国西南地区的水。我们开发了一种模型，该模型是如何在河流水域科罗拉多州内部恢复危险的鱼类栖息地，整合水文学，生态学，经济学和水权。虽然最低成本的水减少量可以改善可再生河栖息地的三分之一，但战略性的支出近三倍，栖息地改善了三倍。十项交易占该成本的1％的26％。不合法保护保守水的水市场比市场的成本效益低29％。总体而言，战略投资和法律改革产生了巨大的生态益处。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Colorado River system is among the world’s most overallocated basins, struggling to supply water to the southwestern United States and Mexico. Consequently, 90% of the basin’s native fish species are endangered, threatened or extinct. Driven by a 24-year megadrought, the United States allocated over US$4 billion for drought mitigation, including water market transactions that pay farms, cities and industries to divert less water across the US Southwest. We developed a model of how strategic water markets can restore imperilled fish habitat, integrating hydrology, ecology, economics and water rights within the river’s headwater state of Colorado. While least-cost water-use reductions improve over one-third of restorable river habitat, strategically spending 8% more nearly triples habitat improvement. Ten transactions attain 26% of that improvement for 1% of the cost. Water markets that do not legally protect conserved water are 29% less cost-effective than markets that do. Overall, strategic investing and legal reforms yield outsized ecological benefits.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41893-025-01585-x/MediaObjects/41893_2025_1585_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 背景气候和植被调节干旱的绿色和蓝色水反应</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02476-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Green and blue water response to drought modulated by background climate and vegetation&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jing Xiao; Fubao Sun; Tingting Wang; Wang Hong&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;干旱通过改变绿色水蒸散和蓝色水径流来影响自然和社会生态系统的健康。但是，绿色和蓝色水反应的全球模式尚不清楚。在这里，我们使用减少根区的土壤水分量化了干旱，并检查了在不同气候和植被条件下产生的水分缺陷。我们表明，干旱通常会在全球范围内降低蒸散量和径流，尽管具有明显的时空变异性。在高纬度潮湿的地区，干旱最初可以增强蒸发量，而径流的反应迅速，并且在整个干旱期间都持续下降。此外，干旱比在潮湿区域中的蒸散量降低了径流，但反向模式发生在干旱地区。与其他植被类型相比，森林表现出较小的干旱引起的蒸散量减少，但径流减少了更大的减少。这些结果强调了在评估干旱的水文影响时考虑背景气候和植被的重要性，这对生态水文理解和水资源管理具有重要意义。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Drought affects the health of natural and socio-ecological systems by altering green water evapotranspiration and blue water runoff. However, the global patterns of green and blue water responses to drought remain unclear. Here we quantified drought using root-zone soil moisture reductions and examined the resulting water deficits across different climatic and vegetation conditions. We show that drought generally reduces both evapotranspiration and runoff globally, though with pronounced spatiotemporal variability. In high-latitude humid regions, drought can initially enhance evapotranspiration, whereas runoff responds more rapidly and declines consistently throughout drought periods. Furthermore, drought reduces runoff more than evapotranspiration in humid regions, but the reverse pattern occurs in arid regions. Compared to other vegetation types, forests exhibit smaller drought-induced reductions in evapotranspiration but greater reductions in runoff. These results underscore the importance of considering background climate and vegetation when assessing drought’s hydrological impacts, with important implications for ecohydrological understanding and water resource management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02476-x/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2476_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>