<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 02:06:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 印度的基于车站的0.1度每日网格集合降水数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04474-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A station-based 0.1-degree daily gridded ensemble precipitation dataset for India&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Anagha Peringiyil; Manabendra Saharia; Sreejith O. P.; Andrew W. Wood; Mrutyunjay Mohapatra; Bharti Sabde; Aradhana Kumari; Bhushan Phadkar; Sabeerali C. T.; Rohini P.; Hosalikar K. S.; M. Rajeevan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;网格降水产物本质上是不确定的，主要是确定性的，这限制了其在数据同化系统和水文建模中的适用性。在印度等发展中国家，观察网络稀疏且不均匀，地形很复杂，并且氢气学极端频繁。目前的0.25°官方观察到的印度气象部（IMD）的降水数据集是确定性的，并且基于Shephard的插值技术。为了应对这些挑战，我们开发了印度降水集合数据集（IPED），利用印度各地最大的降水量表网络网络，并使用当地加权的空间回归方法。 IPED是每日30人的集合沉淀产品，分辨率为0.1°，分辨率为0.25°（1991– 2020），占高度，斜率和方面的地形变化。对于包括季风期间极端99 &lt;sup&gt;％&lt;/sup&gt;降水的所有阈值，开发的集合产品均表现出更高的歧视和可靠性。这是印度上第一个基于观察的集合降水产品，预计将具有广泛的水文学应用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Gridded precipitation products are inherently uncertain and predominantly deterministic, which limits their applicability in data assimilation systems and hydrologic modeling. This limitation is significant in developing countries such as India, where the observation network is sparse and non-uniform, topography is complex, and hydrometeorological extremes are frequent. The current official 0.25° observed precipitation dataset of the Indian Meteorological Department (IMD) is deterministic and based on Shephard’s interpolation technique. To address these challenges, we have developed the Indian Precipitation Ensemble Dataset (IPED) leveraging the largest network of precipitation gauge stations across India and using a locally weighted spatial regression approach. IPED is a daily 30-member ensemble precipitation product available at 0.1° and 0.25° resolution (1991–2020), accounting for topographical variation in elevation, slope, and aspect. For all thresholds, including the extreme 99&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile precipitation during monsoon, the developed ensemble product exhibits higher discrimination and reliability. This is the first observation-based ensemble precipitation product over India and is expected to have widespread hydrometeorological applications.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04474-2/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4474_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 十年（2012-2021）的精细分辨率（每小时1公里）降水数据集越过东南藏族高原</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04654-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A ten-year (2012–2021) fine-resolution (1 km, hourly) precipitation dataset over southeastern Tibetan Plateau&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Dayang Li; Ye Shen; Xianyi Ye; Xiaohua Fu; Yang Yang; Tinghai Ou; Deliang Chen; Fuqiang Tian; Long Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;藏族高原（TP）上强烈的下天降水会触发一系列自然灾害（山洪，碎屑流等），从而造成重大的环境影响。 TP的当前降水产物通常缺乏足够的空间或时间分辨率，阻碍了与降水有关的危害的准确表征和缓解。在这里，我们根据天气研究和预测（WRF）模型在TP上进行了10年（2012-2021，6月至9月）的对流模型模型。我们采用了四个单向嵌套域，最内向的域在东南TP上提供了1公里的小时分辨率。使用光谱纽约方案增强了模型性能。将我们的模拟降水数据与东南TP上的原地雨量计观测值和最先进的降水产物（即，HAR V2，ERA5-LAND和IMERG）进行了比较。与其他三种产品相比，我们的沉淀数据集在平均绝对误差，均方根误差和偏置方面表现出较高的精度。它有效地捕获了昼夜降水循环的关键特征以及降水对东南TP上复杂地形的非单调依赖性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Intense sub-daily precipitation on the Tibetan Plateau (TP) can trigger a cascade of natural hazards (flash floods, debris flows, etc.), causing significant environmental impacts. Current precipitation products for the TP often lack sufficient spatial or temporal resolution, hindering accurate characterization and mitigation of precipitation-related hazards. Here, we carry out 10-year (2012–2021, June to September) convection-permitting model simulations based on the Weather Research and Forecasting (WRF) model over the TP. We adopt four one-way nested domains, with the innermost domain providing a 1-km, hourly resolution over the southeastern TP. Model performance is enhanced using a spectral nudging scheme. Our simulated precipitation data are compared against in-situ rain gauge observations and state-of-the-art gridded precipitation products (i.e., HAR v2, ERA5-Land, and IMERG) over the  southeastern TP. Our precipitation dataset demonstrates superior accuracy in mean absolute error, root mean square error, and bias, compared to the other three products. It effectively captures the key feature of the diurnal precipitation cycle and the non-monotonic dependence of precipitation on complex topography over the southeastern TP.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04654-0/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4654_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>