<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 02:17:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 横跨美国大陆蓄水水库的 ResNet 水坝网络</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06315-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;The ResNet network of dams impounding storage reservoirs across the continental United States&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Aaron A. Hurst; Melissa A. Foster; Abigail C. Eckland&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;ResNet 是美国大陆蓄水水库大坝的国家数据集。大坝从上游到下游布置，在国家水文数据集 (NHD) 流线上创建一个链接网络。该网络能够对沉积物截留以及沉积物和水输送的干扰进行全流域分析。此外，水库与下游主要河口和三角洲相关，提高了量化对特定河流和三角洲影响的能力。国家水库网络 (ResNet) 是通过将自动化工作流程与通过可编辑的用户输入大坝属性文件实施的迭代、手动质量控制检查相结合而创建的，以确保蓄水的大坝捕捉到代表其流域面积的流线，而不是分流。最终产品允许用户创建流域规模的水库网络，跟踪沉积物截留和蓄水潜力，并跟踪小流域内或整个区域内沉积物流域面积随时间的减少。连接的水库网络还可以更好地进行水管理、洪水分析以及水和水力供应研究。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;ResNet is a national dataset of dams impounding storage reservoirs in the continental United States. The dams are routed from upstream to downstream to create a linked network on the National Hydrography Dataset (NHD) flowlines. This network enables basin-wide analyses of sediment trapping and disruptions to sediment and water transport. Further, reservoirs are associated with major downstream river mouths and deltas, improving the ability to quantify impacts to specific rivers and deltas. The national reservoir network (ResNet) was created by combining an automated workflow with iterative, manual quality control checks implemented through an editable user-input dam attributes file to ensure that dams with water storage snapped to the flowline representative of their drainage area, rather than a flow diversion. The final product allows users to create watershed-scale reservoir networks, track sediment trapping and water storage potential, and track the reduction in sediment-contributing drainage area through time within small watersheds or for entire regions. A linked network of reservoirs also allows for better water management, flood analysis, and water and hydropower supply studies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-26562-4/MediaObjects/41598_2025_26562_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 河流干旱迫使哈拉帕变态</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02901-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;River drought forcing of the Harappan metamorphosis&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hiren Solanki; Vikrant Jain; Kaustubh Thirumalai; Balaji Rajagopalan; Vimal Mishra&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水文气候变化是影响印度河流域文明兴衰的因素之一。然而，由于缺乏特定地点的古气候记录，限制这一广阔地区的水资源供应的作用仍然具有挑战性。通过将高分辨率古气候档案与瞬态气候模拟的古水文重建相结合，我们确定了持续数十年至数百年的严重且持续的河流干旱的可能性，这种干旱在距今约 4400 至 3400 年间影响了印度河盆地。流域规模的水流异常进一步表明，持续的河流干旱与区域降雨不足同时发生，共同减少了淡水的供应。我们认为，可用水量的减少，伴随着严重干旱的条件，可能导致人口从主要的哈拉帕中心分散，同时承认社会转型是由气候、社会和经济压力的复杂相互作用形成的。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hydroclimatic variations are among the factors shaping the rise and fall of the Indus Valley Civilization. Yet, constraining the role of water availability across this vast region has remained challenging owing to the scarcity of site-specific paleoclimate records. By integrating high-resolution paleoclimate archives with palaeohydrological reconstructions from transient climate simulations, we identify the likelihood of severe and persistent river droughts, lasting from decades to centuries, that affected the Indus basin between ~4400 and 3400 years before present. Basin-scale streamflow anomalies further indicate that protracted river drought coincided with regional rainfall deficits, together reducing freshwater availability. We contend that reduced water availability, accompanied by substantially drier conditions, may have led to population dispersal from major Harappan centers, while acknowledging that societal transformation was shaped by a complex interplay of climatic, social, and economic pressures.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02901-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2901_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>