<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 02:17:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 2022年2月如何重新定义澳大利亚的极端洪水</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02307-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;How February 2022 redefines extreme floods in Australia&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Julien Lerat; Jai Vaze&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2022年2月，由于强烈的降雨和接近饱和的初始土壤水状况，澳大利亚东部遭受了极端的洪水。这导致了创纪录的水位和洪水量，导致澳大利亚对一次洪水事件的总保险总索赔。在这里，我们分析了该事件的物理因素，并将其与澳大利亚的大量洪水进行比较，其历史可以追溯到1950年。我们的发现表明，2022年2月对设计洪水量的影响最大，年度超高概率为1％，预计该地区的平均地区将增加16％。此外，这种洪水促使国家洪水风险管理的重大变化，包括升级洪水警告网络以及对洪水保险部门的全面审查。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In February 2022, eastern Australia experienced an extreme flood due to a combination of intense rainfall and close to saturation initial soil water conditions. It resulted in record-breaking water levels and flood volumes, leading to Australia’s largest total insurance claim for a single flood event. Here we analyse the physical factors underlying this event and compare them with a large dataset of floods in Australia dating back to 1950. Our findings show that February 2022 had the largest impact on design flood volumes with a 1% annual exceedance probability, which are expected to increase by 16% on average across the affected region. Additionally, this flood prompted major changes in national flood risk management, including upgrades to flood warning networks and a comprehensive review of the flood insurance sector.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02307-z/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2307_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>