<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 02:21:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 秘鲁安第斯山脉中的薄雪形融化和径流动态</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02379-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Thin and ephemeral snow shapes melt and runoff dynamics in the Peruvian Andes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Catriona L. Fyffe; Emily Potter; Evan Miles; Thomas E. Shaw; Michael McCarthy; Andrew Orr; Edwin Loarte; Katy Medina; Simone Fatichi; Rob Hellström; Michel Baraer; Emilio Mateo; Alejo Cochachin; Matthew Westoby; Francesca Pellicciotti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;秘鲁安第斯山脉的雪和冰川在面临缺水和大量冰川变化的地区提供重要的水供应。但是，仍然缺乏对雪过程的了解和对熔体对径流的贡献的量化。在这里，我们将分布式的冰川流学模型在里奥圣诞老人上使用，以解开冰冻圈在安第斯水周期中的作用。只有在最高海拔（&amp;gt; 5000 m ASL）下进行积雪连续。在较低的海拔时，积雪稀薄且短暂，降雪和融化的速度快速。由于较大的集水区受到短暂的降雪的影响，其对集水区投入的贡献是很大的（在潮湿和干旱季节分别为23％和38％）。冰融化在干旱季节至关重要（最多占投入的44％）。我们的结果改善了水通量的估计，并呼吁在安第斯山脉进行进一步的基于过程的建模。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The snow and glaciers of the Peruvian Andes provide vital water supplies in a region facing water scarcity and substantial glacier change. However, there remains a lack of understanding of snow processes and quantification of the contribution of melt to runoff. Here we apply a distributed glacio-hydrological model over the Rio Santa basin to disentangle the role of the cryosphere in the Andean water cycle. Only at the highest elevations (&amp;gt;5000 m a.s.l.) is the snow cover continuous; at lower elevations, the snowpack is thin and ephemeral, with rapid cycles of snowfall and melt. Due to the large catchment area affected by ephemeral snow, its contribution to catchment inputs is substantial (23% and 38% in the wet and dry season, respectively). Ice melt is crucial in the mid-dry season (up to 44% of inputs). Our results improve estimates of water fluxes and call for further process-based modelling across the Andes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02379-x/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2379_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 英国夏季干旱的海洋司机</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02367-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Oceanic drivers of UK summer droughts&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Amulya Chevuturi; Marilena Oltmanns; Maliko Tanguy; Ben Harvey; Cecilia Svensson; Jamie Hannaford&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在气候变化下，英国的干旱预计将变得更加频繁，从而强大了了解其基本原因的需求。我们的研究研究了英国夏季干旱的海洋驱动因素和相关的远程连接途径。具体而言，我们评估了英国和两个北大西洋海面温度（SST）模式的标准化降水和水流指数之间的统计联系，这些模式与以前曾与淡水流入亚极区域相关。我们的发现表明，北大西洋SST通过更改北大西洋电流的位置（与北大西洋夏季喷气流的位置相连），从而提前1。5年的英国水文学会影响英国的水文学。这一遥相关途径的漫长交货时间可以为英国在整个季节性到年际时期标准中的干旱预测，并最终在英国的干旱风险上增加了可持续水资源管理的发展。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;UK droughts are projected to become more frequent under climate change, reinforcing the need to understand their underlying causes. Our study examines oceanic drivers of UK summer droughts and the associated teleconnection pathways. Specifically, we evaluate statistical links between standardized precipitation and streamflow indices for the UK and two North Atlantic Sea surface temperature (SST) patterns which have previously been linked to the influx of freshwater into the subpolar region. Our findings reveal that the North Atlantic SST influences UK hydrology up to 1.5 years in advance by altering the position of the North Atlantic Current, which is coupled to the location of the North Atlantic summer jet stream. The long lead time of this teleconnection pathway can inform UK drought forecasting across seasonal to interannual timescales and ultimately contribute to the advancement of sustainable water resource management in the face of increasing drought risks in the UK.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02367-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2367_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>