<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 02:33:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 在战略位置进行的雪监测可改善供水预测，而不是盆地范围的地图</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02660-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Snow monitoring at strategic locations improves water supply forecasting more than basin-wide mapping&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Mark S. Raleigh; Eric E. Small; Edward H. Bair; Cameron Wobus; Karl Rittger&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在美国西部，由于春季和夏季与水流量的密切相关，因此传统上，供水预测在地面站的雪水等效度量上进行。但是，电台稀疏，并采样了一个小面积，从空间调查或未来的卫星任务中引起了空间完整（但昂贵）的兴趣。在这里，我们表明，在积雪热点（具有未开发的信息以预测流量的本地化区域）上添加战略性测量值 - 始终优于在空间完整的调查中，这些调查提供了提供盆地平均雪堆的空间，无论是在带有和没有现有车站的盆地中。尽管两者都提高了预测技能，但热点监测与流量的相关性增加了390个盆地的11-14％（中位数），而盆地范围内的调查则为4％。这些发现跨越了积雪数据集，技能指标和统计模型。供水预测中最大的收益来自利用现有站点，并将雪测量扩大到正确的地方而不是其他地方。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In the Western United States, water supply forecasting has traditionally relied on snow water equivalent measurements at ground-based stations due to their strong correlations with streamflow volume during spring and summer. However, stations are sparse and sample a small area, prompting interest in spatially complete – but costly – basin-wide mapping from airborne surveys or future satellite missions. Here we show that adding strategic measurements at snow hotspots – localized areas with untapped information for predicting streamflow – consistently outperforms spatially complete surveys that provide basin-average snowpack, both in basins with and without existing stations. While both improve forecast skill, hotspot monitoring increases correlations with streamflow volume by 11-14% (median) across 390 basins, compared to 4% from basin-wide surveys. These findings hold across snowpack datasets, skill metrics, and statistical models. The greatest gains in water supply prediction come from leveraging existing stations and expanding snow measurements to the right places, rather than everywhere.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02660-z/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2660_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | PDSI_CMIP6：一个合奏CMIP6项目的自我校准的Palmer干旱严重性指数数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05790-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;PDSI_CMIP6: an ensemble CMIP6-projected self-calibrated Palmer drought severity index dataset&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jinghua Xiong; Yuting Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;干旱为特征，其特征在于平均水平，深刻影响区域水资源和各种生态系统服务。帕尔默干旱严重程度指数（PDSI）是一种用于干旱监测和气候变化评估的广泛使用的度量，但在气候条件变化的情况下缺乏固有的气候不一致之处，缺乏全面可靠的估计。在这里，我们在1850-2094期间开发了一个每月的自校准PDSI的多模型和多阶段数据集，该数据集源自耦合模型对比项目6中的11个气候模型输出（PDSI_CMIP6）。 PDSI中传统的两层水桶模型被CMIP6型号的直接水文输出取代，从而确保与CMIP6投影保持一致。 PDSI估计值通过相关和回归分析来验证土壤水分模拟。数据集的应用揭示了在整个大陆的长期干旱趋势中明显的空间异质性，全球均值变化有限，但在气候变化下的区域强化显着。该数据集可在不断变化的气候下对陆地水分条件的不确定性约束，忠实地反映了CMIP6项目的水文变化。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Drought, characterized by below-average water supply, profoundly affects regional water resources and various ecosystem services. The Palmer Drought Severity Index (PDSI) is a widely used metric for drought monitoring and climate change assessments but suffers from inherent climatic inconsistencies and lacks comprehensive and reliable estimates under changing climate conditions. Here we develop a monthly multi-model and multi-scenario dataset of self-calibrated PDSI for the period 1850–2094, derived from 11 climate model outputs within the Coupled Model Intercomparison Project 6 (PDSI_CMIP6). The traditional two-layer bucket model in PDSI is replaced with direct hydrological outputs from CMIP6 models, ensuring alignment with CMIP6 projections. The PDSI estimates are validated against soil moisture simulations through correlation and regression analysis. Application of the dataset reveals pronounced spatial heterogeneity in long-term drought trends across continents, with limited global-mean change but notable regional intensification under climate change. This dataset provides uncertainty-constrained quantifications of terrestrial moisture conditions in a changing climate, faithfully reflecting CMIP6-projected hydrological changes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05790-3/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5790_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>