<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 02:10:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 带注释的数据集和基准测试，用于检测内陆水域的浮动碎片</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04594-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;An annotated Dataset and Benchmark for Detecting Floating Debris in Inland Waters&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Guangchao Qiao; Mingxiang Yang; Hao Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;海洋垃圾是对海洋生态系统的严重威胁，及时清除内陆水域的浮动废物可有效防止漂浮的碎片进入大海。准确的对象检测系统是有效清除浮子的先决条件。但是，水中的复杂光条件，小尺寸的物体和其他因素对浮动物体检测构成了巨大挑战。为了促进浮动物体污染问题的解决方案，并促进了AI技术在水行业中的应用，我们提出了基于基于海岸的拍摄设备的iWHR_AI_LABLE_FLOATER_V1从真实水景中收集的第一个浮点数据集。该数据集由3000张图像组成，其中包含准确的注释信息，以支持基于视觉的水面浮点检测任务。我们进行了许多基线实验，以评估该数据集主流对象检测算法的性能。结果表明，包括最先进的模型Yolov9在内的模型的检测准确性都很低，这也表明浮动对象检测是一项具有挑战性的任务。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Marine litter is a serious threat to marine ecosystems, and the timely removal of floating waste from inland waters is effective in preventing floating debris from entering the sea. An accurate object detection system is a prerequisite for efficiently clearing floaters. However, complex light conditions in the water, small size objects and other factors pose a huge challenge for floating object detection. In order to facilitate the solution of the floating object pollution problem and promote the application of AI technology in the water industry, we proposed the first floater dataset of waters collected from real water scenarios based on shore-based filming equipment, IWHR_AI_Lable_Floater_V1. The dataset consists of 3000 images containing accurate annotation information to support vision-based water surface floater detection tasks. We conducted a number of baseline experiments to evaluate the performance of mainstream object detection algorithms on this dataset. The results show that the detection accuracies of the models, including the state-of-the-art model YOLOv9, are all low, which also indicates that floating object detection is a challenging task.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04594-9/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4594_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 干旱指数对历史土地使用和土地覆盖变化的不同反应</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00978-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Divergent response of aridity index to historical land use and land cover change&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Tao Tang; Jun Ge; Haiyun Shi; Junji Cao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;通过使用模型模拟，我们显示自1850年以来的历史土地使用和土地覆盖变化影响了全球的干旱指数（AI），从而在不同地区引起了不同的反应。在本地，AI倾向于在造林区域和大多数潮湿区域中增加（潮湿）。由于这些变化，潮湿区域的面积不足以占全球土地面积的0.22％，牺牲了旱地。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;By using model simulations, we show that historical land use and land cover change since 1850 has impacted aridity index (AI) worldwide, causing divergent responses in different regions. Locally, AI tends to increase (getting humid) in reforestation regions and most humid regions. Owing to these changes, the area of the humid zone expanded insignificantly by 0.22% of the global land area at the expense of drylands.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00978-1/MediaObjects/41612_2025_978_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 跨越1940  -  2023年的地表水质的全面数据集用于经验和ML采用的研究</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04715-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A Comprehensive Dataset of Surface Water Quality Spanning 1940-2023 for Empirical and ML Adopted Research&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Md. Rajaul Karim; M. M. Mahbubul Syeed; Ashifur Rahman; Khondkar Ayaz Rabbani; Kaniz Fatema; Razib Hayat Khan; Md Shakhawat Hossain; Mohammad Faisal Uddin&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;对地表水质的评估和监测对于粮食安全，公共卫生和生态系统保护至关重要。尽管水质监测是一种已知现象，但在全球范围内为地表水提供了全面且协调的数据集的努力。这项研究提出了一个全面的地表水质数据集，可保留数据的时空变异性，完整性，一致性和数据深度，以促进经验和数据驱动的评估，预测和预测。该数据集由来自世界五个著名国家，例如美国，美国，加拿大，爱尔兰，英国和中国的各种来源组装，包括区域和全球水质数据库，水管理组织以及个人研究项目。最终的数据集由跨越1940年至2023年的八个水质参数的282万个测量值组成。该数据集可以支持水质模型的荟萃分析，并可以促进基于机器的数据（ML）数据以及基于模型的空间和时间驱动器研究的研究，并促进了空间和时间驱动因素的调查，以及在整体规模的交叉范围的地表水质的模式。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Assessment and monitoring of surface water quality are essential for food security, public health, and ecosystem protection. Although water quality monitoring is a known phenomenon, little effort has been made to offer a comprehensive and harmonized dataset for surface water at the global scale. This study presents a comprehensive surface water quality dataset that preserves spatio-temporal variability, integrity, consistency, and depth of the data to facilitate empirical and data-driven evaluation, prediction, and forecasting. The dataset is assembled from a range of sources, including regional and global water quality databases, water management organizations, and individual research projects from five prominent countries in the world, e.g., the USA, Canada, Ireland, England, and China. The resulting dataset consists of 2.82 million measurements of eight water quality parameters that span 1940 - 2023. This dataset can support meta-analysis of water quality models and can facilitate Machine Learning (ML) based data and model-driven investigation of the spatial and temporal drivers and patterns of surface water quality at a cross-regional to global scale.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04715-4/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4715_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | Bedmap3更新了南极洲的冰床，表面和厚度网格数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04672-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Bedmap3 updated ice bed, surface and thickness gridded datasets for Antarctica&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hamish D. Pritchard; Peter T. Fretwell; Alice C. Fremand; Julien A. Bodart; James D. Kirkham; Alan Aitken; Jonathan Bamber; Robin Bell; Cesidio Bianchi; Robert G. Bingham; Donald D. Blankenship; Gino Casassa; Knut Christianson; Howard Conway; Hugh F. J. Corr; Xiangbin Cui; Detlef Damaske; Volkmar Damm; Boris Dorschel; Reinhard Drews; Graeme Eagles; Olaf Eisen; Hannes Eisermann; Fausto Ferraccioli; Elena Field; René Forsberg; Steven Franke; Vikram Goel; Siva Prasad Gogineni; Jamin Greenbaum; Benjamin Hills; Richard C. A. Hindmarsh; Andrew O. Hoffman; Nicholas Holschuh; John W. Holt; Angelika Humbert; Robert W. Jacobel; Daniela Jansen; Adrian Jenkins; Wilfried Jokat; Lenneke Jong; Tom A. Jordan; Edward C. King; Jack Kohler; William Krabill; Joséphine Maton; Mette Kusk Gillespie; Kirsty Langley; Joohan Lee; German Leitchenkov; Cartlon Leuschen; Bruce Luyendyk; Joseph A. MacGregor; Emma MacKie; Geir Moholdt; Kenichi Matsuoka; Mathieu Morlighem; Jérémie Mouginot; Frank O. Nitsche; Ole A. Nost; John Paden; Frank Pattyn; Sergey Popov; Eric Rignot; David M. Rippin; Andrés Rivera; Jason L. Roberts; Neil Ross; Antonia Ruppel; Dustin M. Schroeder; Martin J. Siegert; Andrew M. Smith; Daniel Steinhage; Michael Studinger; Bo Sun; Ignazio Tabacco; Kirsty J. Tinto; Stefano Urbini; David G. Vaughan; Douglas S. Wilson; Duncan A. Young; Achille Zirizzotti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;我们提出了Bedmap3，这是最新的网格产品套件，描述了60°S南极南极南极的地面高度，冰厚度以及海底和冰川床升高。 BedMap3均包含并增加了先前用于BedMap2的所有后1950年后数据集，其中包括15个数据提供商的84次新的Aero-Geophysical Surveys，另外5200万个数据点和190万行的测量线。这些努力填补了包括主要山脉和南极洲东部，南极海岸线和南极半岛的显着空白。我们的新Bedmap3/Rings接地线类似地将最近的多个映射整合到一个单一的，空间连贯的功能中。结合更新的表面地貌，冰架厚度，岩石露头和测深的图，Bedmap3揭示了南极冰的冰山下景观和分布，提供了解释大陆规模景观演化的新机会，并为南极冰板的过去和未来的进化提供了新的机会。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We present Bedmap3, the latest suite of gridded products describing surface elevation, ice-thickness and the seafloor and subglacial bed elevation of the Antarctic south of 60 °S. Bedmap3 incorporates and adds to all post-1950s datasets previously used for Bedmap2, including 84 new aero-geophysical surveys by 15 data providers, an additional 52 million data points and 1.9 million line-kilometres of measurement. These efforts have filled notable gaps including in major mountain ranges and the deep interior of East Antarctica, along West Antarctic coastlines and on the Antarctic Peninsula. Our new Bedmap3/RINGS grounding line similarly consolidates multiple recent mappings into a single, spatially coherent feature. Combined with updated maps of surface topography, ice shelf thickness, rock outcrops and bathymetry, Bedmap3 reveals in much greater detail the subglacial landscape and distribution of Antarctica’s ice, providing new opportunities to interpret continental-scale landscape evolution and to model the past and future evolution of the Antarctic ice sheets.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04672-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4672_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | GLEAM4：从1980年到现在为0.1分辨率的全球土地蒸发和土壤水分数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04610-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;GLEAM4: global land evaporation and soil moisture dataset at 0.1 resolution from 1980 to near present&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Diego G. Miralles; Olivier Bonte; Akash Koppa; Oscar M. Baez-Villanueva; Emma Tronquo; Feng Zhong; Hylke E. Beck; Petra Hulsman; Wouter Dorigo; Niko E. C. Verhoest; Shekoofeh Haghdoost&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;陆地蒸发在调节气候和水资源中起着至关重要的作用。在这里，我们提供了一个连续的，每日的数据集，涵盖了1980  -  2023年，其空间分辨率为0.1°，该数据集使用第四代Amsterdam模型（GLEAM）产生。 GLEAM4包含混合建模中的发展，从涡流和SAPFLOW数据中学习蒸发应力。它具有改进的关键因素的代表，例如拦截，大气水需求，土壤水分和植物进入地下水。估计值与现有的全局蒸发产品相互比较，并针对原位测量值进行了验证，包括来自473个涡流协调位点的数据，显示中位相关性为0.73，根平方误差为0.95 mm d- &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;和kling-Gling-Gupta效率为0.49。全球土地蒸发估计为68.5×10 &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;年&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ，归因于蒸腾作用62％。除了实际的蒸发及其成分（蒸腾，截距损失，土壤蒸发等）之外，数据集还提供土壤水分，潜在的蒸发，明智的热通量和蒸发压力，从而促进了广泛的水文，气候和生态研究。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Terrestrial evaporation plays a crucial role in modulating climate and water resources. Here, we present a continuous, daily dataset covering 1980–2023 with a 0.1°spatial resolution, produced using the fourth generation of the Global Land Evaporation Amsterdam Model (GLEAM). GLEAM4 embraces developments in hybrid modelling, learning evaporative stress from eddy-covariance and sapflow data. It features improved representation of key factors such as interception, atmospheric water demand, soil moisture, and plant access to groundwater. Estimates are inter-compared with existing global evaporation products and validated against in situ measurements, including data from 473 eddy-covariance sites, showing a median correlation of 0.73, root-mean-square error of 0.95 mm d&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;, and Kling–Gupta efficiency of 0.49. Global land evaporation is estimated at 68.5 × 10&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;, with 62% attributed to transpiration. Beyond actual evaporation and its components (transpiration, interception loss, soil evaporation, etc.), the dataset also provides soil moisture, potential evaporation, sensible heat flux, and evaporative stress, facilitating a wide range of hydrological, climatic, and ecological studies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04610-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4610_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 驱动旋风，温暖的传送带和大气河的运动学分析</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00942-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A kinematic analysis of extratropical cyclones, warm conveyor belts and atmospheric rivers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Helen F. Dacre; Peter A. Clark&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;中纬度天气系统在造成洪水，风损和相关的社会影响方面起着重要作用。数值建模和观察方法的进步导致了中纬度概要和动态研究的众多概念模型的发展。随着这些模型扩散，将新的见解纳入凝聚力的理解可能是具有挑战性的。本文使用运动学观点来解释中纬度研究，以综合各种概念并创建大气河生命周期的示意图。我们的分析表明，尽管有不同的方法，定义和术语来描述驱动旋风旋风，温暖的输送带气流和大气河流，但推动其形成和发育的基本机制还是一致的。因此，在独立研究这些功能的同时，重要的是要认识到它们都是更大的大气流程模式的一部分。我们希望这种运动学方法将成为联系这些现象研究的桥梁。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mid-latitude weather systems play a significant role in causing floods, wind damage, and related societal impacts. Advances in numerical modeling and observational methods have led to the development of numerous conceptual models in mid-latitude synoptic and dynamical research. As these models proliferate, integrating new insights into a cohesive understanding can be challenging. This paper uses a kinematic perspective to interpret mid-latitude research in a way that synthesises various concepts and create a schematic diagram of an atmospheric river lifecycle. Our analysis demonstrates that, despite varying methods, definitions, and terminology used to describe extratropical cyclones, warm conveyor belt airflows, and atmospheric rivers, the underlying mechanisms driving their formation and development are consistent. Thus, while studying these features independently is valuable, it is important to recognise that they are all part of a larger atmospheric flow pattern. We hope this kinematic approach will serve as a bridge to link research on these phenomena.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00942-z/MediaObjects/41612_2025_942_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | FloodcastBench：用于洪水建模和预测的大型数据集和基础模型</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04725-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;FloodCastBench: A Large-Scale Dataset and Foundation Models for Flood Modeling and Forecasting&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Qingsong Xu; Yilei Shi; Jie Zhao; Xiao Xiang Zhu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;有效的洪水预测对于明智的决策和紧急响应至关重要。现有的洪水数据集主要描述洪水事件，但缺乏适合机器学习（ML）的动态过程数据。 This work introduces the FloodCastBench dataset, designed for ML-based flood modeling and forecasting, featuring four major flood events: Pakistan 2022, UK 2015, Australia 2022, and Mozambique 2019. FloodCastBench details the process of flood dynamics data acquisition, starting with input data preparation (eg, topography, land use, rainfall) and flood measurement data collection (eg, SAR-based maps, surveyed outlines)用于流体动力建模。我们部署了广泛认识的有限差异解决方案，以构建具有30米空间和300秒时间分辨率的高分辨率时空动态过程。洪水测量数据用于校准流体动力模型参数并验证洪水淹没图。 FloodcastBench提供专门针对ML的全面的低保真性和高保真洪水预测数据集。此外，我们建立了使用Floodcastbench进行神经洪水预测的基础模型的基准，从而验证了其在支持时空，跨区域和降低洪水预测的ML模型方面的有效性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Effective flood forecasting is crucial for informed decision-making and emergency response. Existing flood datasets mainly describe flood events but lack dynamic process data suitable for machine learning (ML). This work introduces the FloodCastBench dataset, designed for ML-based flood modeling and forecasting, featuring four major flood events: Pakistan 2022, UK 2015, Australia 2022, and Mozambique 2019. FloodCastBench details the process of flood dynamics data acquisition, starting with input data preparation (e.g., topography, land use, rainfall) and flood measurement data collection (e.g., SAR-based maps, surveyed outlines) for hydrodynamic modeling. We deploy a widely recognized finite difference numerical solution to construct high-resolution spatiotemporal dynamic processes with 30-m spatial and 300-second temporal resolutions. Flood measurement data are used to calibrate the hydrodynamic model parameters and validate the flood inundation maps. FloodCastBench provides comprehensive low-fidelity and high-fidelity flood forecasting datasets specifically for ML. Furthermore, we establish a benchmark of foundational models for neural flood forecasting using FloodCastBench, validating its effectiveness in supporting ML models for spatiotemporal, cross-regional, and downscaled flood forecasting.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04725-2/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4725_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature | 在洪水变化中反映的奥地利每小时大雨增加</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-08647-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Increasing hourly heavy rainfall in Austria reflected in flood changes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Klaus Haslinger; Korbinian Breinl; Lovrenc Pavlin; Georg Pistotnik; Miriam Bertola; Marc Olefs; Marion Greilinger; Wolfgang Schöner; Günter Blöschl&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;预计气候变化会随着洪水的伴随增加而增加大雨&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; 。大降雨增加的原因包括较高的气氛的较高水能和大气循环模式的变化&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ，这可能会转化为欧洲大部分地区的未来大雨&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; 。但是，收集有关过去变化时间演变的证据受到数据限制和测量不确定性的阻碍，尤其是在短降雨期间，例如1小时。在这里，我们显示了过去四十年中每天增加8％，每小时大降雨增加了15％，分析了一个新的数据集，该数据集由1900年到2023年在奥地利的883个站点组成的新数据集增加。这些增加的增加是完全一致的，并且在1960年至1980年之间的稳定阶段之间发生在弱势阶段之后，随着温度的变化而增加。 Clausius – Clapeyron缩放。但是，每天的大雨变化与大气循环指数一致，与空气温度相关，这表明大气循环模式的作用比以前想象的要大。每天的大降雨变化与观察到的洪水大约在大型集水区中的洪水增加约为8％。每小时的大降雨变化与小流域的洪水变化同样是一致的，尽管洪水增加更强（在过去的四十年中25％）。因此，洪水管理中的气候适应措施可能比大河流较小的河流更紧迫。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate change is expected to increase heavy rainfall with concomitant increases in flooding&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;. Causes of increased heavy rainfall include the higher water-holding capacity of a warmer atmosphere and changes in atmospheric circulation patterns&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, which may translate into future heavy rainfall increases in most of Europe&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;. However, gathering evidence on the time evolution of past changes has been hampered by data limitations and measurement uncertainties, in particular for short rainfall durations, such as 1 h. Here we show an 8% increase in daily and 15% increase in hourly heavy rainfall over the last four decades by analysing a new dataset comprising 883 stations in Austria from 1900 to 2023. These increases are fully consistent between two independent networks and occurred after a retarding phase between 1960 and 1980. Hourly heavy rainfall changes are aligned with temperature increases with the sensitivity of a 7% increase per 1 °C of warming, in line with Clausius–Clapeyron scaling. Daily heavy rainfall changes, however, are aligned with atmospheric circulation indices with little correlation to air temperature, which suggests a bigger role of atmospheric circulation modes than previously thought. The daily heavy rainfall changes are remarkably consistent with observed flood increases of about 8% in large catchments. The hourly heavy rainfall changes are similarly consistent with flood changes in small catchments, although the flood increase is stronger (25% over the last four decades). Climate adaptation measures in flood management may therefore be more pressing for rivers draining smaller catchment areas than for large rivers.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-025-08647-2/MediaObjects/41586_2025_8647_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 土壤平均特异性收益的全球数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04742-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A global dataset of average specific yield for soils&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Meizhao Lv; Meixia Lv; Yuanyuan Zha; Lei Wang; Zong-Liang Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;特定的产量（S &lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt; ）是地下水模拟中的关键参数和重要的误差源。但是，仍然缺乏可靠的&lt;sub&gt;全局&lt;/sub&gt;数据集。基于S &lt;sub&gt;Y&lt;/sub&gt;和土壤纹理的三线性图，我们开发了一个全面的全球数据集，该数据集的平均特异性产量（Gasy）针对各种土壤纹理，这些数据集是从全球土壤数据集中获得的，用于地球系统模型，土壤晶格产品和协调的世界土壤数据库。在含水层尺度至全球尺度上，通过实验室和现场方法&lt;sub&gt;估计&lt;/sub&gt;的现有S &lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt;值的验证表明，这种喘气有效地代表了每种土壤质地的可靠平均&lt;sub&gt;水平&lt;/sub&gt;。煤气的深度限制（〜2 m）归因于土壤纹理数据的深度限制，读者可以通过合理地假设土壤纹理的垂直变化具有深度的垂直变化，从而将煤气扩展到更深的土壤中。这种喘息对地下水动态的未来建模和理解地下水资源分配以及缓解气候变化影响的巨大好处。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Specific yield (S&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt;) stands as a critical parameter and a significant source of error in groundwater simulations. However, there is still a lack of reliable global S&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt; datasets. Based on the trilinear graph of S&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt; and soil textures, we develop a comprehensive global dataset of gridded average specific yield (GASY) aimed for various soil textures, which are obtained from the Global Soil Dataset for Earth System Models, the SoilGrids product, and the Harmonized World Soil Database. Validations with existing S&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt; values estimated by laboratory and field methods across different S&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt; concepts, at the aquifer-scale to global-scale, compellingly revealed that the GASY effectively represents reliable average S&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt; for each soil texture. The depth limitation (~2 m) of GASY is attributed to the depth limitations of soil texture data, and readers can expand the GASY into deeper soils by reasonably assuming a vertical variation of soil texture with depth. The GASY holds great benefits for future modeling of groundwater dynamics and understanding the groundwater resources distribution and mitigation of climate change impacts.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04742-1/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4742_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 通过土地初始化增强下季节土壤水分预测</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00987-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Enhancing sub-seasonal soil moisture forecasts through land initialization&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yanan Duan; Sanjiv Kumar; Montasir Maruf; Thomas M. Kavoo; Imtiaz Rangwala; Jadwiga H. Richter; Anne A. Glanville; Teagan King; Musa Esit; Brett Raczka; Kevin Raeder&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;我们利用社区地球系统模型2子对季节性气候预测实验（CESM2-S2S）评估了土地土壤水分（SM）的土地，大气和海洋初始化的相对贡献。使用八个灵敏度实验，我们将这三个组成部分的各个影响及其对连续美国的预测技能的相互作用的各个影响。 CESM2-S2S实验，在该实验中初始化了土地状态，同时大气和海洋仍处于其气候状态，在夏季和冬季，在各种土壤水分条件下，占91±3％。大多数SM可预测性来自土壤水分记忆效应。此外，陆地大气耦合占土地驱动的土壤水分可预测性的50％。对CESM2-S2S SM预测技能与其他两个气候模型的比较分析突出了通过改善土壤水分湿气产生反馈的代表来增强土壤水分预测准确性的潜力。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We assess the relative contributions of land, atmosphere, and oceanic initializations to the forecast skill of root zone soil moisture (SM) utilizing the Community Earth System Model version 2 Sub to Seasonal climate forecast experiments (CESM2-S2S). Using eight sensitivity experiments, we disentangle the individual impacts of these three components and their interactions on the forecast skill for the contiguous United States. The CESM2-S2S experiment, in which land states are initialized while atmosphere and ocean remain in their climatological states, contributes 91 ± 3% of the total sub-seasonal forecast skill across varying soil moisture conditions during summer and winter. Most SM predictability stems from the soil moisture memory effect. Additionally, land-atmosphere coupling contributes 50% of the land-driven soil moisture predictability. A comparative analysis of the CESM2-S2S SM forecast skills against two other climate models highlights the potential for enhancing soil moisture forecast accuracy by improving the representation of soil moisture-precipitation feedback.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00987-0/MediaObjects/41612_2025_987_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>