<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 02:23:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 在不断变化的气候下，从热浪到大雨的加速变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01113-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Accelerated shifts from heatwaves to heavy rainfall in a changing climate&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jian Li; Shuo Wang; Jinxin Zhu; Dagang Wang; Tongtiegang Zhao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在温暖的气候下，连续的热浪和大雨（HW -HR）事件随着频率的增加而发生。时间间隔定义为热浪结束与大降雨开始之间的持续时间，会影响环境条件和两个连续的极端事件之间的区域恢复。但是，连续的HW-HR事件之间过渡的动力学仍然知之甚少。在这项研究中，我们使用来自中国大陆2000多个站点的气象数据，研究了1970年至2019年中国连续HW-HR事件的时间间隔的变化。我们的结果表明，时间间隔在24.1％的电台中显着缩短。这种趋势主要是由短期事件（STE）的比例增加驱动的，该事件（STE）定义为连续事件，在1-2天内以时间间隔定义。从1970年到2019年，STE的比例显着增加，每十年1.4％。我们还发现，在连续的HW-HR事件中，气候变化引起的大气变量异常，尤其是对流可用的势能，2 m温度和相对湿度，可能会导致Stes比例的增加。此外，我们的研究评估了过去二十年来人口接触的变化。我们发现，该国四分之三以上的暴露面积增加了，Ste的增加占总暴露的65.3％。我们的发现强调了连续HW-HR事件期间优先级灾难响应的重要性，并实施有效的风险管理策略来减轻人口暴露于极端事件。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Consecutive heatwave and heavy rainfall (HW‐HR) events are occurring with increasing frequency in a warming climate. The time interval, defined as the duration between the end of a heatwave and the onset of heavy rainfall, affects both environmental conditions and the regional recovery between two consecutive extreme events. However, the dynamics of the transition between consecutive HW-HR events remain poorly understood. In this study, we examine the changes in the time interval of consecutive HW-HR events in China from 1970 to 2019, using meteorological data from over 2000 stations across mainland China. Our results reveal that the time interval has significantly shortened at 24.1% of the stations. This trend is primarily driven by an increased proportion of short-time events (STEs), defined as consecutive events with time intervals within 1–2 days. From 1970 to 2019, the proportion of STEs increased significantly, at a rate of 1.4% per decade. We also find that climate change-induced anomalies in atmospheric variables during the consecutive HW-HR events, especially convective available potential energy, 2 m temperature, and relative humidity, may contribute to this rise in the proportion of STEs. Additionally, our study assesses changes in population exposure to STEs over the past two decades. We find that the area of exposure has increased across more than three-quarters of the country, with the increases in STEs contributing to 65.3% of the overall rise in exposure. Our findings highlight the importance of prioritizing disaster response during consecutive HW-HR events and implementing effective risk management strategies to mitigate population exposure to extreme events.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01113-w/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1113_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | Viking 2着陆点的弗罗斯特（Frost）的高氯酸盐盐水形成</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02411-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Perchlorate brine formation from frost at the Viking 2 landing site&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Vincent F. Chevrier&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;盐水在火星表面的存在和稳定性在行星探索中仍然是一个重要的谜。提出的盐水形成的先前机制包括冰盐混合物和盐差异的融化。然而，熔化缺乏充电机制，而二线会因火星的极端表面干燥而阻碍。这项研究探讨了一个未充分散布的过程：季节性霜在盐水形成中的作用。利用Viking 2 Lander的气象数据（与凤凰城的唯一任务一起观察原位水霜的形成），我证明，作为霜冻的冬季，在冬季结束时，盐水可以在大约30个溶胶中形成。稳定的盐水表现出0.52的水活性上限，对应于高氯酸盐钙的共晶点，这是在各个火星地区检测到的盐，可能包括维京2个着陆点。因此，我得出的结论是，高氯酸钙可以在短时间内与霜接触时产生少量的液态盐水。霜冻的季节性表明这些盐水复发，并可能留下长期的烙印。因此，被霜冻的地区是未来居住能力和天体探索的主要候选人。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The presence and stability of brines on Mars’s surface remain a significant mystery in planetary exploration. Previous mechanisms proposed for brine formation include melting of ice-salt mixtures and salt deliquescence. However, melting lacks a recharge mechanism, and deliquescence is impeded by Mars’s extreme surface aridity. This study explores an underexplored process: the role of seasonal frost in brine formation. Utilizing meteorological data from the Viking 2 lander—the only mission, with Phoenix, to observe in situ water frost formation—I demonstrate that brines can form over approximately 30 sols at the end of winter as frost sublimates. The stable brines exhibit a water activity upper limit of 0.52, corresponding to the eutectic point of calcium perchlorate, a salt detected in various Martian regions, likely including the Viking 2 landing site. Consequently, I conclude that calcium perchlorate can generate small amounts of liquid brine in contact with frost for brief periods. The seasonal nature of frost suggests these brines recur and may leave long-term imprints. Therefore, frost-covered regions are prime candidates for future habitability and astrobiological exploration.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02411-0/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2411_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>