<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 08:38:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 澳大利亚二十年来的澳大利亚水质趋势显示出大堡礁地区的恶化和穆雷 - 达林盆地的恢复</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02044-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Danlu Guo; Qian Zhang; Camille Minaudo; Rémi Dupas; Clément Duvert; Shuci Liu; Kefeng Zhang; Ulrike Bende-Michl; Anna Lintern&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;了解河水质量轨迹和驱动因素对于有效的环境管理至关重要。在这里，我们在澳大利亚进行了全面的全国性水质趋势评估，并从2000年到2019年进行了287个集水区。大约一半的集水区显示了分析的每个参数的流量非正率浓度的显着趋势。这些重大趋势中的大多数是由于浓度流关系的变化而不是流量的长期趋势。澳大利亚的两个主要河流盆地在其重大趋势中表现出相反的区域模式。东北海岸很大程度上流入了大屏障礁泻湖，磷和沉积物增加。这可能反映了自1960年代以来增加土地清理和受精的滞后影响，而该地区的土地改善尚未显示出水质的改善。默里 - 达林盆地的盐度，磷和沉积物的降低，可能是由地区规模盐度管理干预措施的影响以及对集水过程的干旱长期造成的。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understanding river water quality trajectories and drivers is crucial for effective environmental management. Here we present a comprehensive nation-wide water quality trend assessment across Australia with 287 catchments from 2000 to 2019. About half of the catchments show significant trends in the flow-normalised concentration for each parameter analysed. Most of these significant trends are due to changes in concentration-flow relationships rather than long-term trends in flow. Two of Australia’s major river basins show opposing regional patterns in their significant trends. The North East Coast, which largely flows into the Great Barrier Reef lagoon, has increasing phosphorus and sediments. This potentially reflects lagged effects of increasing land clearing and fertilisation since 1960s, while land improvement in the region has not yet demonstrated improvement on water quality. The Murray-Darling Basin has decreasing salinity, phosphorus, and sediment, likely driven by effects of a region-scale salinity management interventions and a prolonged drought on catchment processes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02044-3/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2044_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 人类引起的水损失可能威胁中国沙质地区的可持续发展</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02046-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Runa A; Xinliang Pan; Liudi Zhu; Kelvin T. F. Chan; Zhangcai Qin; Enliang Guo; Yuhai Bao; Song Qing; Tingwei Cui&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水对于可持续的社会经济发展是必不可少的，尤其是在中国的沙质地区。尽管在桑迪地区进行了现有研究，但总储水量变化及其潜在影响的驱动因素仍然不足。在这里，我们通过集成多个数据集发现了2002年至2023年的总储水总存储中净损失559.7亿立方米。水损失主要归因于农田灌溉的增加（495.6亿立方米）和生态恢复（370.4亿立方米）。在接下来的40年中，在低和高排放情况下，供水能力将分别降低6.54％和19.07％，要求将人类用水量减少60％至135％。这种耗竭可能威胁到区域可持续性和国家生态安全。这项研究要求对水资源进行紧急科学法规，包括严格控制当地消费和增强供应能力。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water is indispensable for sustainable socioeconomic development, especially in China’s sandy regions. Despite existing studies in sandy regions, the drivers of changes in total water storage and their potential impacts remain inadequately understood. Here we found a 55.97 billion m³ net loss in total water storage from 2002 to 2023 by integrating multiple datasets. Water loss was primarily attributed to increased farmland irrigation (49.56 billion m³) and ecological restoration (37.04 billion m³). In the coming 40 years, water supply capacity will decrease by up to 6.54% and 19.07% under low and high emission scenarios, respectively, requiring reductions in human water consumption of 60% to 135%. This depletion potentially threatens both regional sustainability and national ecological security. This study calls for urgent scientific regulations on water resources, including strict control of local consumption and enhancement of supply capacity.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02046-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2046_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 未来变暖水平下的全球水间隙</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-56517-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lorenzo Rosa; Matteo Sangiorgio&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;了解气候变化对水资源的影响对于制定有效的适应策略至关重要。我们量化“水间隙”或不可持续的用水量 - 水需求超过供应的短缺，导致稀缺。我们使用多模型分析来量化基线和未来的水间隙，该分析结合了两个合理的未来变暖方案。基线全球水间隙为457.9 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; /yr，预测表明在1.5°C下增加了26.5 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; /yr（+5.8％）和67.4 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; /yr（+14.7％）和3°C的温暖场景， 分别。这些预测强调了变暖水平对水间隙的不均匀影响，强调需要缓解气候变化以减轻对水资源压力的需求。我们的结果还强调了各个国家和盆地之间不平等的适应需求，这些需求受到不同变暖方案的影响，具有重要的区域差异，并模型变异性使未来的预测变得复杂。需要强大的水管理策略来应对全球变暖引起的水稀缺性的升级。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understanding the impacts of climate change on water resources is crucial for developing effective adaptation strategies. We quantify “water gaps”, or unsustainable water use – the shortfall where water demand exceeds supply, resulting in scarcity. We quantify baseline and future water gaps using a multi-model analysis that incorporates two plausible future warming scenarios. The baseline global water gap stands at 457.9 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/yr, with projections indicating an increase of 26.5 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/yr (+5.8%) and 67.4 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/yr (+14.7%) under 1.5 °C and 3 °C warming scenarios, respectively. These projections highlight the uneven impact of warming levels on water gaps, emphasizing the need for continued climate change mitigation to alleviate stress on water resources. Our results also underscore the unequal adaptation needs across countries and basins, influenced by varying warming scenarios, with important regional differences and model variability complicating future projections. Robust water management strategies are needed to tackle the escalating water scarcity caused by global warming.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-56517-2/MediaObjects/41467_2025_56517_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 加拿大偏置校正的高分辨率温度和降水预测</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04396-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hebatallah M. Abdelmoaty; Chandra Rupa Rajulapati; Sofia D. Nerantzaki; Simon Michael Papalexiou&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;高分辨率降水和温度预测对于知情的决策，风险评估和计划是必不可少的。在这里，我们开发了一个广泛的数据库（SPQM-CMIP6-CAN），该数据库的高分辨率（0.1°）降水和温度投影在加拿大的每日规模上延伸至2100。我们采用了一种新型的半参数映射映射（SPQM）方法来偏向于耦合模型对比项目，第6阶段（CMIP6）投影，用于四种共享社会经济途径。 SPQM是简单而强大的，可以根据未来情况再现观测到的边际特性，趋势和可变性，同时保持了从观测到预计模拟的平稳过渡。 SPQM-CMIP6-CAN数据库包含693个模拟，这些模拟来自34种不同的气候模型，用于降水。同样，对于温度投影，我们的数据库包括来自27个气候模型的581个模拟。这些预测对于水文，环境和生态学研究很有价值，为这些领域内的分析提供了全面的资源。此外，这些预测是量化由气候模型，变异配置和未来情况的不确定性的重要工具。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;High-resolution precipitation and temperature projections are indispensable for informed decision-making, risk assessment, and planning. Here, we have developed an extensive database (SPQM-CMIP6-CAN) of high-resolution (0.1°) precipitation and temperature projections extending till 2100 at a daily scale for Canada. We employed a novel Semi-Parametric Quantile Mapping (SPQM) methodology to bias-correct the Coupled Model Intercomparison Project, Phase-6 (CMIP6) projections for four Shared Socio-economic Pathways. SPQM is simple, yet robust, in reproducing the observed marginal properties, trends, and variability according to future scenarios, while maintaining a smooth transition from observations to projected simulations. The SPQM-CMIP6-CAN database encompasses 693 simulations derived from 34 diverse climate models for precipitation. Similarly, for temperature projections, our database comprises 581 simulations from 27 climate models. These projections are valuable for hydrological, environmental, and ecological studies, offering a comprehensive resource for analyses within these domains. Furthermore, these projections serve as a vital tool for the quantification of uncertainties arising from climate models, their variant configurations, and future scenarios.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04396-z/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4396_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Water | 地下水对盐沼泽功能和弹性的隐藏影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-024-00384-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Julia A. Guimond; Emilio Grande; Holly A. Michael; Dannielle Pratt; Elizabeth Herndon; Genevieve L. Noyce; Nicholas D. Ward; Inke Forbrich; Peter Regier; Matthew J. Berens; Bhavna Arora&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;盐沼是营养加工和碳固执的热点。到目前为止，针对盐沼生物地球化学功能，碳储存和弹性的时空变异性的研究集中在海洋驱动的表面水文影响上，通过地下连接忽略陆地水文的影响。在这里，我们使用来自七个沼泽的数据，通过小波分析和信息理论评估了盐沼氧化还原潜力的驱动因素，这是生物地球化学状态的代理。结果指出地下水水平是对所有站点氧化还原变异性的主要控制。因为氧化还原是生物地球化学过程的关键驱动力，是有机物的特殊氧化，可以隔离碳并保持沼泽高度，因此这些陆地影响对于理解沼泽功能和进化至关重要。新近识别的陆上地下水水平与沼泽氧化还原条件之间的联系改变了传统的范式，并表明陆生水文学是盐沼碳碳固隔潜力和弹性的主要控制。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Salt marshes are hotspots of nutrient processing and carbon sequestration. So far, studies addressing spatiotemporal variability in and drivers of salt marsh biogeochemical function, carbon storage and resilience have focused on ocean-driven surface hydrologic influences, neglecting effects of terrestrial hydrology through subsurface connections. Here we evaluate drivers of salt marsh redox potential, a proxy for biogeochemical state, through wavelet analyses and information theory using data from seven marshes. The results point to terrestrial groundwater level as a dominant control on redox variability across all sites. Because redox is a key driver of biogeochemical processes, and specifically oxidation of organic matter that sequesters carbon and maintains marsh elevation, these terrestrial influences are critical to understanding marsh function and evolution. The newly identified links between onshore groundwater levels and marsh redox conditions shift the traditional paradigm and suggest that terrestrial hydrology is a primary control on salt marsh carbon sequestration potential and resilience.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-024-00384-6/MediaObjects/44221_2024_384_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 气候和人口变化在全球洪水暴露和脆弱性中的作用</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-56654-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Justin S. Rogers; Marco M. Maneta; Stephan R. Sain; Luke E. Madaus; Joshua P. Hacker&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;洪水是一种普遍的自然危害，对社会产生了广泛影响。使用高分辨率的全球洪水模型，考虑沿海，河流和泛滥危害，我们阐明了气候影响与人口增长效应在改变洪水暴露中的作用。在2020年至2100年之间，人口可能会暴露于1％的年风险（100年）洪水危害将从1.6亿人口增加到19亿人。从2020年的暴露量开始，我们将21.1％的人归因于气候变化，76.8％的人口变化为2.1％，气候和人口变化均为2.1％。不确定性不确定性的最大驱动力是人口变化，而气候变化仍然是一个较小但仍然重要的驱动因素。 2020年至2100年之间的全球曝光率增加主要是由低GDP地区驱动的，到2100年，最低的GDP地区将占整体和城市地区的63％。在几乎所有全球地区，城市地区都特别容易受到攻击，对极端事件敏感的城市地区预计将使人口敞口增加33％。这项研究强调了洪水暴露的巨大不平等，未来的工作应将资源和策略指导到这些领域的可持续风险降低。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Flooding is a pervasive natural hazard with wide-ranging impacts on society. Using a high-resolution global flood model considering coastal, fluvial, and pluvial hazards, we clarify the role of climate effects versus population growth effects in changing flood exposure. Between 2020 and 2100, the population likely exposed to 1% annual risk (100-year) flood hazard will increase from 1.6 to 1.9 billion people. Of this change from the 2020 exposure, we attribute 21.1% to climate change, 76.8% to population change, and 2.1% to both climate and population change. The largest driver of uncertainty in exposure is population change, while climate change remains a smaller but still important driver. The global increase in exposure between 2020 and 2100 is primarily driven by low-GDP regions, and by 2100 the lowest GDP areas will make up 63% of the exposure both overall and in urban areas. Urban areas are especially vulnerable in nearly all global regions, and urban areas sensitive to extreme events are expected to see a 33% increase in population exposure. This study highlights the vast inequities in flood exposure, and future work should direct resources and strategies toward sustainable risk mitigation in these areas.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-56654-8/MediaObjects/41467_2025_56654_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 在过去的3500年中</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-56687-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yu Liu; Huiming Song; Zhisheng An; Qiang Li; Steven W. Leavitt; Ulf Büntgen; Qiufang Cai; Ruoshi Liu; Congxi Fang; Changfeng Sun; Kerstin Treydte; Meng Ren; Lidong Mo; Yi Song; Wenju Cai; Quan Zhang; Weijian Zhou; Achim Bräuning; Jussi Grießinger; Deliang Chen; Hans W. Linderholm; Ashish Sinha; Hai Cheng; Lu Wang; Ying Lei; Junyan Sun; Wei Gong; Xuxiang Li; Linlin Cui; Liang Ning; Lingfeng Wan; Thomas W. Crowther; Constantin M. Zohner&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;鉴于人们对全球气候变化的关注日益加剧，因此至关重要的是要了解氢气气候的历史和当前转变，尤其是在与全球循环纠缠的地区。藏高原是地球最大和最高的高原，是全球大气过程的联系，通过亚洲季风和西风的协同作用，显着影响了东亚氢化气候动力学。然而，由于短暂的工具观察和部分模棱两可的代理重建，了解历史和最近的氢气候波动及其广泛的生态和社会后果仍然具有挑战性。在这里，我们提出了一个准确的3476年降水重建，该降水重建是从藏藏高原上的树木环&lt;sup&gt;δ11&lt;/sup&gt;数据得出的，这是迄今为止迄今为止少数多米伦尼亚长的陆地甲&lt;sup&gt;δ18O&lt;/sup&gt;记录之一。我们的发现表明，在过去的三千年中， &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;世纪的极端干旱是严重的，可能与由于人为气溶胶的排放而导致的亚洲季风和西风的削弱有关。此外，我们的分析确定了三个不同的阶段（110 BC – AD 280，AD 330-770和AD 950–1300），其特征是向潮湿的社会动荡和王朝倒塌，这对应于干旱的氢气候条件，这强调了严重的社会影响氢化气候变化。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Given growing concerns about global climate change, it is critical to understand both historical and current shifts in the hydroclimate, particularly in regions critically entwined with global circulation. The Tibetan Plateau, the Earth’s largest and highest plateau, is a nexus for global atmospheric processes, significantly influencing East Asian hydroclimate dynamics through the synergy of the Asian Monsoon and the Westerlies. Yet, understanding historical and recent hydroclimate fluctuations and their wide-ranging ecological and societal consequences remains challenging due to short instrumental observations and partly ambiguous proxy reconstructions. Here, we present a precisely-dated 3476-year precipitation reconstruction derived from tree-ring δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O data on the Tibetan Plateau, representing one of the few multi-millennia-long annually-resolved terrestrial δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O records to date. Our findings reveal that the 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century drought extremes are severe within the past three millennia, and likely linked to the weakening of both the Asian Monsoon and Westerlies due to anthropogenic aerosol emissions. Additionally, our analyses identified three distinct stages (110 BC–AD 280, AD 330–770 and AD 950–1300) characterized by shifts toward arid hydroclimate conditions, corresponding to significant social unrest and dynasty collapses, which underscores the potential societal impacts of severe hydroclimatic shifts.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-56687-z/MediaObjects/41467_2025_56687_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 德克萨斯州丛林，玉米蒸散量，增长和收益数据集收集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04539-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Steven R. Evett; Gary W. Marek; Paul D. Colaizzi; Karen S. Copeland; Brice B. Ruthardt; Terry A. Howell&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;提出了一系列数据集，描述了有关玉米（ &lt;i&gt;Zea Mays&lt;/i&gt; ，L。）（玉米）实验的六年实验的集合（1989，1990，1990，1994，2013，2013，2016和2018）。使用四个称重裂解器来确定作物蒸散量（ET）。土壤及以上的地面微气候和ET数据以15分钟的间隔显示，并且一年四季的天气数据也是如此。数据分析以15分钟的基础从溶液表质量数据确定了ET，降水，灌溉和霜冻的积累。校准的中子探针读数的土壤水含量数据定期介绍。农作物种植，收获，受精，控制和其他农艺信息在一年中的农艺日历中介绍。在整个生长季节，最终的作物生物量和产量数据都会定期介绍作物生长数据。该数据适用于分析美国南部高平原地区农作物产量和水生产率的影响，用于模型校准和测试，以及改进模型。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A collection of datasets describing six years of experiments on maize (&lt;i&gt;Zea mays&lt;/i&gt;, L.) (corn) is presented (1989, 1990, 1994, 2013, 2016, and 2018). Four weighing lysimeters were used to determine crop evapotranspiration (ET). In-soil and above ground microclimate and ET data are presented on a 15-minute interval as are weather data for all days of the year. Data analysis determined ET, precipitation, irrigation, and dew and frost accumulation on a 15-minute basis from lysimeter mass data. Soil water content data from calibrated neutron probe readings is presented on a periodic basis. Crop planting, harvest, fertilization, pest control, and other agronomic information are presented in agronomic calendars by day of year. Crop growth data are presented on a periodic basis throughout the growing season, as are final crop biomass and yield data. The data are suitable for analysis of effects of irrigation and other agronomic decisions on crop yield and water productivity in the Southern High Plains region of the USA, for model calibration and testing, and for model improvement.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04539-2/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4539_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 韩国Geum River的高分辨率归化水流数据（1951  -  2020年）</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04486-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Byeong-Hee Kim; Young-Oh Kim; Jonghun Kam&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;高分辨率（小于1 km）的长期流量数据对于氢化气候极端和生态评估至关重要，这在经历了快速的社会经济增长的河流盆地上无法获得。在这里，我们使用可变的渗透能力河流路由模型（VIC-RRM）在1951  -  2020年以上的韩国主要河流之一Geum River（Geum River是90米）分辨率的每日归化。 VIC-RRM表现出较高的时间一致性，相关系数超过了Geum River沿着90个轨距的60％以上的观察到的流量季节性超过0.6。但是，36％的电台显示出低改良的kling-gupta效率（0.2-0.4），这主要是由于径流数据中的不确定性和人类干扰影响（如灌溉和储层存储）。我们模拟的归化数据显示，与1970年代相比，2010年代，2010年代Geum River的日常变异性的变异性变异性衰老。该数据集为参考数据提供了物理上一致的归化水流数据，以评估Geum河的气候变化驱动的流量变化。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Long-term streamflow data at a hyper-resolution (less than 1 km) is essential for hydroclimatic extreme and ecological assessment, which is not available over a river basin where rapid socioeconomic growth have been experienced. Here, we use the Variable Infiltration Capacity-River Routing Model (VIC-RRM) to reconstruct naturalized daily streamflow at 90–meter resolution for the Geum River, one of South Korea’s major rivers, over 1951–2020. VIC-RRM demonstrates high temporal consistency with a correlation coefficient exceeding 0.6 for observed streamflow seasonality at over 60% of the 90 gauge stations along the Geum River. However, 36% of the stations show low modified Kling-Gupta Efficiency (0.2–0.4), primarily due to uncertainties in runoff data and human disturbance impacts like irrigation and reservoir storage. Our simulated naturalized data reveal decadal variability in the 1990s and an increase in day-to-day variability of the Geum River in the 2010s compared to those in the 1970s. This dataset provides physically consistent naturalized streamflow data for reference data to evaluate climate change-driven changes in streamflow for the Geum River.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04486-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4486_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 21世纪的每月灌溉和雨耕区（MIRCA-OS）的全球开源数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-024-04313-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Endalkachew Abebe Kebede; Kevin Ong’are Oluoch; Stefan Siebert; Piyush Mehta; Sarah Hartman; Jonas Jägermeyr; Deepak Ray; Tariq Ali; Kate A. Brauman; Qinyu Deng; Wei Xie; Kyle Frankel Davis&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;作物生产是地球上最广泛的人类活动之一，对于全球粮食安全，土地使用，环境负担和气候至关重要。然而，尽管农田在全球土地使用和地球系统中起着关键作用，但对全球农作物种植的空间模式最近进化，哪些农作物对这些变化做出了最大的贡献。在这里，我们构建了一个新的数据库，该数据库是特定于灌溉和雨水的收获区域统计数据，并将其与全球网格覆盖物产品结合起来，以开发全球栅格（5-二级）灌溉和雨水灌溉和雨水供应区（MIRCA-OS）数据集的数据集2000年至2015年的23种农作物课程。自本世纪初以来，这些全球数据产品支持对灌溉和雨水耕地变化的空间详细模式的关键见解，并为各种全球评估提供了改进的基础，这些全球评估涵盖了农业，水资源管理，土地使用变化，气候影响，气候影响，气候影响，气候影响，气候影响和可持续发展。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Crop production is among the most extensive human activities on the planet – with critical importance for global food security, land use, environmental burden, and climate. Yet despite the key role that croplands play in global land use and Earth systems, there remains little understanding of how spatial patterns of global crop cultivation have recently evolved and which crops have contributed most to these changes. Here we construct a new data library of subnational crop-specific irrigated and rainfed harvested area statistics and combine it with global gridded land cover products to develop a global gridded (5-arcminute) irrigated and rainfed cropped area (MIRCA-OS) dataset for the years 2000 to 2015 for 23 crop classes. These global data products support critical insights into the spatially detailed patterns of irrigated and rainfed cropland change since the start of the century and provide an improved foundation for a wide array of global assessments spanning agriculture, water resource management, land use change, climate impact, and sustainable development.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-024-04313-w/MediaObjects/41597_2024_4313_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>