<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 02:20:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 西风急流波动调节中纬度水文气候变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-65904-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Westerly jet waviness modulates mid-latitude hydroclimate variability&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Liangqing Cheng; Jingran Zhang; Yubin Wu; Jun Cheng; Liang Yi; Zhigang Zhang; Hao Long&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;中纬度地区生态环境十分脆弱，水文气候变率的加剧对其构成重大威胁。然而，由于观测记录较短和气候模型偏差，导致这种变化的机制仍不清楚。在这里，我们展示了过去约 570 万年（Myr）的亚千年分辨率降水记录，源自东亚中纬度（中国北部）300.8 米的河流湖泊沉积岩芯。我们的结果揭示了自上新世以来西风急流对中纬度降水的持续影响，以及约300万年前（Ma）后中纬度降水变率的显着减少以及低纬度变率的放大。基于理想化的敏感性模拟，我们将约 3 Ma 之前中纬度降水变率的放大归因于北极变暖驱动的西风急流波动性增强。鉴于预计未来全球变暖导致急流波度增加，我们预测中纬度地区会出现更频繁的极端水文气候。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The mid-latitude ecological environment is highly vulnerable, and increasing hydroclimate variability poses a significant threat to it. However, the mechanisms driving this variability remain unclear due to short observational records and climate model biases. Here, we present a sub-millennial resolution precipitation record spanning the past ~5.7 million years (Myr), derived from a 300.8-meter fluvio-lacustrine sediment core in mid-latitude East Asia (northern China). Our results reveal a persistent influence of the westerly jet on mid-latitude precipitation since the Pliocene, as well as a marked reduction in mid-latitude precipitation variability alongside amplified low-latitude variability after ~3 million years ago (Ma). Based on idealized sensitivity simulations, we attribute the amplified mid-latitude precipitation variability before ~3 Ma to enhanced westerly jet waviness driven by Arctic warming. Given projected increases in jet waviness under future global warming, we predict more frequent hydroclimate extremes in mid-latitude regions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-25396-4/MediaObjects/41598_2025_25396_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>