<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 02:17:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 自2003年以来，陆生储水的跨际变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02203-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Interdecadal variability of terrestrial water storage since 2003&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Brett Buzzanga; Ben Hamlington; John Fasullo; Felix Landerer; Athina Peidou&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;由于人为的强迫和气候系统中的内部变化，地球的水周期正在发生变化。这些变化导致水周期的强化，在某些地区表现出更频繁，更强大的干旱，而在其他地区则表现出更强的干旱。最终对陆地存储的影响对于水的供应可能至关重要。但是，当前的理解受到观察和模型的局限性以及影响跨时间尺度陆生储水的各种过程的限制。在这里，我们利用重力恢复和气候实验和随后的后续任务中现在两年的长卫星记录，以研究内部变异性存在的持续趋势。我们使用环固化经验正交函数分析来发现可变性的统计模式，这有助于解释2012年左右发生的十年陆地储物储存趋势的变化。主要的统计模式表明，降水记录中也发现了跨期间的周期性。第二个领先模式与太平洋十年际振荡高度相关。隔离这些模式指向区域，由于内部气候变异性，在未来几十年中，陆生储能趋势的大小可能会变平或反向，并降低了多年代线性线性趋势的不确定性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Earth’s water cycle is changing due to anthropogenic forcing and internal variations in the climate system. These changes are leading to an intensification of the water cycle that manifests as more frequent and stronger droughts in some areas, and pluvials in others. The resulting impacts on terrestrial water storage can be crucial for water availability. However, current understanding is hampered by limitations in observations and models, and the variety of processes that influence terrestrial water storage across temporal scales. Here, we leverage the now two-decades long satellite record from the Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment and subsequent Follow-On missions to investigate persistent trends in the presence of internal variability. We use cyclostationary empirical orthogonal function analysis to uncover statistical modes of variability that help explain a shift in decadal terrestrial water storage trends that occurred around 2012. The dominant statistical mode suggests an interdecadal periodicity that is also found in the precipitation record. The second leading mode is highly correlated with the Pacific Decadal Oscillation. Isolating these modes points to regions where the magnitude of the terrestrial water storage trend may flatten or reverse in coming decades due to internal climate variability and reduces uncertainty in multidecadal linear trends.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02203-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2203_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>