<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 02:14:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 欧盟的农药应用率图以250 m的空间分辨率</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05031-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Pesticides application rate maps in the European Union at a 250 m spatial resolution&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; G. M. Porta; L. Casse; A. Manzoni; M. Riva; F. Maggi; A. Guadagnini&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;我们的工作针对欧盟内农药施用率的映射，并以250 m的空间分辨率进行映射。来源数据包括欧洲统计局官方数据报告的农药输入，高分辨率作物图和农药使用情况的全球估计。先前发表的害虫化化剂中的全球农药施用率被用作第一个猜测估计值。然后，使用从农业中使用农药收集的校准数据集对这些进行调整。然后，按国家和农作物类型估计施加的质量与高分辨率作物图结合在一起。该过程通过最大似然估计程序明确说明数据质量和不确定性。该数据产品具有详细的农药输入空间分布，促进了对农药命运和运输的评估，生物地球化学转化以及环境风险评估。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Our work targets mapping of pesticides application rates within the European Union at a 250 m spatial resolution. Source data include global estimates of pesticide inputs, high resolution crop maps and pesticide usage reported by EUROSTAT official figures. Previously published global pesticide application rates in PEST-CHEMGRIDS are used as first guess estimates. These are then adjusted using a calibration dataset gathered from pesticide use in agriculture. The estimation of the applied mass by country and crop type is then combined with high resolution crop maps. The procedure explicitly accounts for data quality and uncertainty through a Maximum Likelihood estimation procedure. This data product features detailed spatial distributions of pesticide inputs, facilitating evaluation of pesticide fate and transport, biogeochemical transformations as well as environmental risk assessment.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05031-7/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5031_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>