<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 01:56:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Reviews Earth &amp; Environment | 陆地 - 海洋北极碳循环</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43017-024-00627-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jorien E. Vonk; Michael Fritz; Niek J. Speetjens; Marcel Babin; Annett Bartsch; Luana S. Basso; Lisa Bröder; Mathias Göckede; Örjan Gustafsson; Gustaf Hugelius; Anna M. Irrgang; Bennet Juhls; McKenzie A. Kuhn; Hugues Lantuit; Manfredi Manizza; Jannik Martens; Matt O’Regan; Anya Suslova; Suzanne E. Tank; Jens Terhaar; Scott Zolkos&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;人为气候变暖在北极地区得到扩增，从而影响北极碳循环及其在调节气候和全球生物地球化学周期中的作用。在这篇综述中，我们提供了整个土地 - 海洋连续体的当今北极碳循环的定量和全面概述。陆地土壤库存总计877±16 pg c，上海洋沉积物包含82±35 pg C.总体而言，北极系统是一个碳汇，由CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; （127±36 Tg C y &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ）的海洋吸收驱动架子海沉积物中的有机碳埋葬（112±41 tg C年&lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt; ）。陆地系统（包括内陆水域和干扰）是CH &lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; （38（21，53）TG C年&lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt; ）和CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; （12（–606，661）TG C年&lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt; ）的净来源。由于沿海侵蚀增加，对河流有机碳的挤压以及近海近海碳转换降低架子沉积物埋葬等因素，北极碳水槽可能会削弱持续变暖。北极绿化和陆生碳水槽的增加将被土壤呼吸的增加，极端事件的干扰以及内陆水域的排放增强所抵消。未来的研究应优先考虑对小流域和近岸地区的增强覆盖范围，并在生物地球化学模型中纳入非线性反应。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Anthropogenic climate warming is amplified in the Arctic, impacting the Arctic carbon cycle and its role in regulating climate and global biogeochemical cycles. In this Review, we provide a quantitative and comprehensive overview of the present-day Arctic carbon cycle across the land–ocean continuum. Terrestrial soil stocks total 877 ± 16 Pg C, with upper marine sediments containing 82 ± 35 Pg C. Overall, the integrated Arctic system is a carbon sink, driven by oceanic uptake of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (127 ± 36 Tg C year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;) and organic carbon burial in shelf sea sediments (112 ± 41 Tg C year&lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt;). Terrestrial systems, including inland waters and disturbance, are a net source of CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; (38 (21, 53) Tg C year&lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt;) and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (12 (–606, 661) Tg C year&lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt;). The Arctic carbon sink will likely weaken under continued warming, owing to factors such as increased coastal erosion, outgassing of riverine organic carbon and enhanced nearshore carbon turnover lowering shelf sediment burial. Arctic greening and increases in terrestrial carbon sinks will be substantially offset by increases in soil respiration, disturbance from extreme events and enhanced emissions from inland waters. Future research should prioritize enhanced coverage of small catchments and nearshore regions, and inclusion of non-linear responses in biogeochemical models.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43017-024-00627-w/MediaObjects/43017_2024_627_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 原始植被状况和降水生长速率分叉沉积物通量趋势趋势</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02075-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jinhao Guo; Yao Yue; Wenxin Huai; Xia Yan; Alistair G. L. Borthwick; Yuanfang Chai; Shuolin Li; Zhiwei Li; Yichu Wang; Chiyuan Miao; Zhonghua Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;青海地基高原上的河流沉积物通量遵循不同源头盆地的单独趋势，因为在全球变暖下途径复杂。在这里，我们使用基于泰勒膨胀的概念多元气候弹性模型成功地从25个水文站的七个途径重建了历史沉积物通量，并揭示了沉积物通量趋势的分叉。显着增加的趋势发生在五个站点，这是由于降水增加（造成-10〜50％）或温度改变基础表面（-12〜100％）引起的径流引起的。在六个站点发现趋势显着下降，这主要是由于植被扩张（11〜100％）。原始植被状况和降水速率增加的组合对于分叉沉积物通量趋势至关重要。将来，随着温度大大升高或原始植被状况较差，植被迅速膨胀可能会减少沉积物的产量，而迅速增加的降水可能会淹没丰富的植被的边际保护作用，因此将来会逐渐增加降水量。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Riverine sediment flux on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau follows separate trends in different headwater basins because of complicated pathways under global warming. Here we successfully reconstructed historical sediment fluxes from seven pathways at 25 hydrological stations during 1982 ~ 2022 using a conceptual Multivariate Climate Elasticity Model based on Taylor expansion and revealed the bifurcation in sediment flux trend. Significantly increasing trends occurred at five stations, caused either by elevated runoff from increased precipitation (contributing -10 ~ 50%) or by temperature modifying the underlying surface (-12 ~ 100%). Significantly decreasing trends were found at six stations, primarily owing to vegetation expansion (11 ~ 100%). Combinations of original vegetation condition and increasing rate of precipitation are pivotal for bifurcating the sediment flux trend. In the future, slowly increasing precipitation with greatly increasing temperature or poor original vegetation condition followed by rapid vegetation expansion may decelerate sediment yield, whereas rapidly increasing precipitation may overwhelm the marginal conservation effect of plentiful vegetation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02075-w/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2075_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 不是随机的：控制浅对流云的稳定动力学</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00924-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ilan Koren; Tom Dror; Elizabeth-Ruth Shehter; Orit Altaratz&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在整个海洋上形成的浅，稀疏，非沉积的对流云被认为是有组织的云场中的。这些云的形成机制与创建浮力包裹的随机局部扰动有关。他们的稀疏表明云之间没有或非常弱的相互作用。在这里，我们表明，这种云在一个组织良好，稳定，密集的对流细胞中形成，它们连续运行，与可见光云的存在无关。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Shallow, sparse, non-precipitating convective clouds forming over the ocean are considered among the least organized cloud fields. The formation mechanism of these clouds is associated with random, local perturbations that create buoyant parcels. Their sparseness suggests no or very weak interactions between clouds. Here, we show that such clouds form within a well-organized, stable, dense mesh of convective cells that operate continuously, independent of the presence of visible clouds.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00924-1/MediaObjects/41612_2025_924_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 由于恢复项目而升高的地下水桌放大了北京地震引起的液化风险</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-56525-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yuan Li; Rui Wang; Hongbo Ma; Jian-Min Zhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;减轻地下水过度开发的地下水恢复越来越普遍，这证明可以有效解决城市水的稀缺性和区域不可持续的发展。中国南到北水转移项目是恢复地下水并解决北京水资源短缺的最大水转移项目之一。然而，这种大小的迅速恢复的地下水在很大程度上尚不清楚。在这里，我们探讨了基于北京的案例，在南到北水转移项目的影响下，地下水桌和地震地面液化之间的关系。我们收集地下水桌深度记录，并使用它们来驱动三维岩土模型，从而产生地面液化危险图。我们发现，由于地下水桌升高而导致的液化覆盖率和严重程度显着增加。在快速城市化过程中建立的基础设施通常在低地下水桌下，因此为这种增加的地震风险做好了准备。这些发现凸显了考虑大规模地下水恢复项目的地震后果的必要性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Groundwater restoration is increasingly common to mitigate groundwater overexploitation, which proves effective in resolving urban water scarcity and regional unsustainable development. China’s South-to-North Water Diversion Project is one of the largest water transfer projects to restore groundwater and resolve water shortage in Beijing. However, how the rapidly restored groundwater of this magnitude changes regional seismic stability is largely unknown. Here, we explore the relation between elevated groundwater table and seismic ground liquefaction based on the case of Beijing under the impact of the South-to-North Water Diversion Project. We collect groundwater table depth records and use them to drive three-dimensional geotechnical models that generate ground liquefaction hazard maps. We find a remarkable increase in coverage and severity of liquefaction due to groundwater table rise. Infrastructures built during the rapid urbanization process are often under low groundwater table and thus illy prepared for this increased seismic risk. These findings highlight the necessity to consider the seismic consequence of large-scale groundwater restoration projects.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-56525-2/MediaObjects/41467_2025_56525_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 野火介导碳转移到北极地区和温带地区</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02070-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Mathilde Bélair; Ian M. McCullough; Christopher T. Filstrup; Jennifer A. Brentrup; Jean-François Lapierre&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;野火可能会破坏从陆地到水的碳运输，但碳循环如何对火灾的反应仍不清楚。在这里，我们分析了魁北克省，加拿大和美国明尼苏达州3个地区的54个湖泊（34烧伤，20个对照）在总碳池中的主要碳形式的浓度和优势（&amp;lt;1  -  3年）。燃烧的流域中的湖泊的控制湖的溶解有机碳浓度增加了两倍，并且在考虑气候和景观驱动因素（例如，集水区与湖泊区域比率）时，火灾效应最为明显。燃烧的湖泊中溶解有机碳的数量和优势比其他碳的周转率和命运不同，这表明在大火后长达几年，在北部森林的流域中尚未确定的命运，对潜在的火灾介导的碳出口具有重要意义，并且对区域符合全球碳预算。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Wildfires can disrupt carbon transport from land to water, but how lake carbon cycling responds to fires remains unclear. Here, we analyzed the concentration and dominance of the main carbon forms in total carbon pools in 54 lakes (34 burned, 20 control) across 3 regions of Quebec, Canada and Minnesota, USA from recent wildfires ( &amp;lt; 1 – 3 years). Lakes in burned watersheds had up to double the dissolved organic carbon concentrations of control lakes, and the fire effect was most apparent when accounting for climate and landscape drivers (e.g., catchment to lake area ratio) of lake carbon cycling. The greater quantity and dominance of dissolved organic carbon in burned lakes over other carbon forms with different turnover rates and fates suggest a potential fire-mediated carbon export up to several years post fire with a yet undetermined fate in northern forested watersheds and with important implications for regional to global carbon budgets.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02070-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2070_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 自动化河流屏障对象检测的带注释的卫星图像数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04590-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jianping Wu; Wenjie Li; Hongbo Du; Yu Wan; Shengfa Yang; Yi Xiao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全世界已经建造了数百万河屏障，用于防洪，水力发电和农业灌溉。缺乏关于河流障碍位置和类型的全面记录，尤其是包括堰在内的小障碍，限制了我们评估其社会和环境影响的能力。将卫星图像与对象检测算法集成在一起，有望自动识别全球范围。但是，实现此目标需要高质量的图像数据集来进行算法培训和测试。因此，本研究提出了一个名为河流屏障对象检测（RBOD）的大规模数据集。它包含4,872个高分辨率卫星图像和11,741个精心注释的定向边界盒（OBB），其中包括五类河流屏障。使用五种典型对象检测算法验证了RBOD数据集的有效性，该算法为将来的应用提供了性能基准。据我们所知，RBOD是第一个用于河流屏障对象检测的公开数据集，为理解和管理河流屏障提供了宝贵的资源。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Millions of river barriers have been constructed worldwide for flood control, hydropower generation, and agricultural irrigation. The lack of comprehensive records on river barriers’ locations and types, particularly small barriers including weirs, limits our ability to assess their societal and environmental impacts. Integrating satellite imagery with object detection algorithms holds promise for the automatic identification of river barriers on a global scale. However, achieving this objective requires high-quality image datasets for algorithm training and testing. Hence, this study presents a large-scale dataset named the River Barrier Object Detection (RBOD). It comprises 4,872 high-resolution satellite images and 11,741 meticulously annotated oriented bounding boxes (OBBs), encompassing five classes of river barriers. The effectiveness of the RBOD dataset was validated using five typical object detection algorithms, which provide performance benchmarks for future applications. To the best of our knowledge, RBOD is the first publicly available dataset for river barrier object detection, providing a valuable resource for the understanding and management of river barriers.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04590-z/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4590_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 紧急约束表明，未来全球蒸散量的增加速度较慢</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00932-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yuanfang Chai; Yao Yue; Louise Slater; Chiyuan Miao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球陆地蒸散量（ET）的预测受到巨大的不确定性的困扰。在这里，我们在SSP126的低排放情况下，在SSP126的低排放趋势下，在SSP126的低排放趋势下，我们发现了预计的全球ET趋势（2015-2100）（2015-2100）（2015-2100）（2015-2100）和历史蒸气压力不足（VPD）趋势之间的双变量紧急约束关系的，我们在28个CMIP6型号中，当水的供应受到限制时，在SSP370和SSP585的高排放方案下。将多个观察数据集结合到分层的紧急约束框架中，我们发现RAW CMIP6模型高估了未来的年度ET增长率。最初的预测为0.233±0.107毫米&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; （SSP126），0.360±0.244毫米年度&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; （SSP370）和0.506±0.365 mm年&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; （SSP585）的原始预测被调整为0.193±0.074 mm y &lt;sup&gt;-1-1，0.193&lt;/sup&gt; ±0.074毫米 - 纽0.184毫米&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; 1年和0.391±0.299毫米&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; 。修订后的预测不确定性减少了18.1–31.1％。这些发现突出了合并观察性约束以提高ET预测的可靠性的价值，这对于理解未来的全球水周期至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Projections of global terrestrial evapotranspiration (ET) are plagued by sizeable uncertainties. Here, we uncover bivariate emergent constraint relationships between projected global ET trends (2015–2100) and historical vapour pressure deficit (VPD) trends (1980–2014) under the low emission scenario of SSP126 when water supply is sufficient, and with historical precipitation trends under the high emission scenarios of SSP370 and SSP585 when water availability is limited, across 28 CMIP6 models. Combining multiple observational datasets into a Hierarchical Emergent Constraint framework, we find the raw CMIP6 models overestimate future annual ET growth rates. The original projections of 0.233 ± 0.107 mm year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; (SSP126), 0.360 ± 0.244 mm year−&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; (SSP370) and 0.506 ± 0.365 mm year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; (SSP585) are adjusted downwards to 0.193 ± 0.074 mm year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;, 0.272 ± 0.184 mm year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; and 0.391 ± 0.299 mm year&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;. The revised projection uncertainties are reduced by 18.1–31.1%. These findings highlight the value of incorporating observational constraints to improve the reliability of ET projections, which are critical for understanding the future global water cycle.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00932-1/MediaObjects/41612_2025_932_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 灌溉和森林砍伐的对比对兰坎·曼旺河流域水文学的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02093-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hao Huang; Junguo Liu; Luca Guillaumot; Aifang Chen; Inge E. M. de Graaf; Deliang Chen&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;灌溉扩展和随后的森林砍伐基本上影响了较大的盆地变异性。但是，鉴于水文变量之间的复杂相互作用，需要对共存土地使用变化内的水文影响更全面地理解。在这里，我们使用历史河流测量值和卫星观测来应用地表水耦合模拟，以评估兰开冈河流域水文学的长期和季节性变化。增加灌溉升高的土壤水分，但地下水储存枯竭。相反，森林砍伐可减少土壤水分，并增加陡峭地形区域的横向流量，以补偿地下水耗尽。灌溉通过增强蒸散和基流的影响影响了径流，这对径流的变化具有相反的影响，从而导致混合的空间模式减少和增加。同时，由于森林砍伐偏移而导致的土壤水分减少，由于灌溉而增加的蒸散量增加，导致径流的范围比减少的降低更大。这些说明了不同土地使用变化和复杂系统评估的途径的独特水文影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Irrigation expansion and subsequent deforestation substantially affect large basin variability. However, given the complex interactions between hydrological variables, a more comprehensive understanding of the hydrological impacts within the coexisting land use changes is needed. Here, we applied surface-groundwater-coupled simulations with historical river gauges and satellite observations to evaluate long-term and seasonal changes in Lancang-Mekong River Basin hydrology. Increasing irrigation elevated soil moisture but depleted groundwater storage. Conversely, deforestation reduced soil moisture, and increased lateral flow in areas with steep terrain compensated for groundwater depletion. Irrigation affected runoff by augmenting evapotranspiration and baseflow, which had opposite implications for runoff changes, causing a mixed spatial pattern of decreases and increases. Meanwhile, decreases in soil moisture due to deforestation offset increases in evapotranspiration due to irrigation, resulting in wider areas of runoff increases than decreases. These illustrate the distinct hydrological impacts of different land use changes and a pathway to complex system assessments.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02093-8/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2093_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 解密蒸散量在降低土地相对湿度趋势中的作用</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02076-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yeonuk Kim; Mark S. Johnson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;近几十年来，土地上的相对湿度有所下降，干旱和野火的增加。先前的解释将这种趋势归因于从海洋中的水分对流不足以维持当前水平，但这忽略了陆地蒸散液提供的大气水分。重要的是，当前的最新气候模型继续低估了观察到的土地相对湿度趋势。在这里，我们表明，相对于给定的基线，特定的湿度的变化（由海洋平流都没有责任）在数量上等同于全球范围内蒸散量的相对变化。尽管存在蒸散趋势差异，但在气候模型和气候重新分析数据集中，这一发现是一致的。蒸散趋势的差异被确定为在气候模型中表达的相对湿度趋势偏见的显着原因。这些结果表明，当前的气候模型可能高估了蒸散量的强化，从而导致大气干燥的低估，对准确预测干旱，野火和气候适应的影响至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In recent decades, relative humidity over land has declined, driving increases in droughts and wildfires. Previous explanations attribute this trend to insufficient moisture advection from the ocean to sustain the current level, but this ignores atmospheric moisture supplied from terrestrial evapotranspiration. Importantly, current state-of-the-art climate models continue to underestimate the observed relative humidity trend over land. Here, we show that changes in specific humidity over land relative to a given baseline, unaccounted for by ocean advection, are quantitatively equivalent to relative changes in evapotranspiration on a global scale. This finding is consistent across climate models and climate reanalysis datasets, despite discrepancies in evapotranspiration trends among them. Differences in evapotranspiration trends are identified as a prominent cause of the bias in relative humidity trend expressed in climate models. These results suggest that current climate models may overestimate evapotranspiration intensifications, leading to an underestimation of atmospheric drying, with critical implications for accurately predicting droughts, wildfires, and climate adaptation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02076-9/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2076_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 使用Daymet的高分辨率，网格的产品用于蒸气压力不足</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04544-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Nicholas K. Corak; Peter E. Thornton; Lauren E. L. Lowman&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;蒸气压力不足（VPD）是评估干旱条件和评估植物水应力的关键变量。全球和区域VPD的网格产品无法从卫星遥感，模型重新分析或地面观察数据集中免费获得。我们以1公里的空间分辨率和每日时间步骤介绍了美国大陆和加拿大北部和加拿大北部（CONUS+）的第一个网格VPD产品的两个版本。我们根据日常每日温度和平均每日蒸气压力得出VPD，并根据（1）由Köppen-Geiger分类确定的气候和（2）由国际地质 - 双聚球计划确定的土地覆盖率的估计值。来自代表不同气候和土地覆盖分类的253个Ameriflux站点的基于地面的VPD数据用于改善CONUS+网格中每个像素的日光衍生的VPD估计值，以生成最终数据集。我们根据独立的观察和重新分析数据评估了Daymet衍生的VPD。 CONUS+ VPD数据集将有助于调查包括干旱和野火在内的骚乱，并为土地管理策略提供信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Vapor pressure deficit (VPD) is a critical variable in assessing drought conditions and evaluating plant water stress. Gridded products of global and regional VPD are not freely available from satellite remote sensing, model reanalysis, or ground observation datasets. We present two versions of the first gridded VPD product for the Continental US and parts of Northern Mexico and Southern Canada (CONUS+) at a 1 km spatial resolution and daily time step. We derived VPD from Daymet maximum daily temperature and average daily vapor pressure and scale the estimates based on (1) climate determined by the Köppen-Geiger classifications and (2) land cover determined by the International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme. Ground-based VPD data from 253 AmeriFlux sites representing different climate and land cover classifications were used to improve the Daymet-derived VPD estimates for every pixel in the CONUS+ grid to produce the final datasets. We evaluated the Daymet-derived VPD against independent observations and reanalysis data. The CONUS+ VPD datasets will aid in investigating disturbances including drought and wildfire, and informing land management strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04544-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4544_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>