<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 02:20:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Sustainability | 全球农田的农作物水源和水文气候脆弱性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-025-01662-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Crop water origins and hydroclimate vulnerability of global croplands&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yan Jiang; Jennifer A. Burney&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水资源供应严重影响作物物候和农业生产力。在这里，我们使用卫星水同位素观测和物理模型来追踪 2003 年至 2019 年全球主要雨养作物的大气水分来源，区分海洋和陆地来源。我们的分析表明，来自陆地的雨水比例 (f) 因地理和季节而异，重要阈值约为 36%。 f 较高的地区，即对陆源水的依赖程度较高的地区，在主要生长季节更容易出现雨水供应不足和土壤水分不足的情况。这些地区的农作物对水文气候表现出更高的敏感性，在降雨量较少的年份生产力下降，并且发生干旱的可能性更高。值得注意的是，全球超过 40% 的玉米和 60% 的冬小麦生长在降雨严重依赖于陆地水分（f ≥ 36%）的地区，这突显了主要主要作物对水文气候胁迫的脆弱性。我们的研究结果强调了管理当地土地水分来源的重要性，并揭示了哪些有针对性的水管理策略最有望增强农业的抵御能力。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water availability critically influences crop phenology and agricultural productivity. Here we use satellite-derived water isotope observations and physical models to trace atmospheric moisture origins for major global rain-fed crops from 2003 to 2019, distinguishing between oceanic and terrestrial sources. Our analysis shows that the fraction of rainwater originating from land (f) varies both geographically and seasonally, with an important threshold at ~36%. Regions with higher f, that is, more dependent on land-originating water, are more prone to insufficient rainwater supply and soil moisture deficits during the main growing season. Crops in these regions show higher sensitivity to hydroclimate—with reduced productivity in lower-rainfall years—and a higher likelihood of drought. Notably, more than 40% of global maize and 60% of winter wheat is grown in regions where rainfall depends heavily on land-originating moisture (f ≥ 36%), underscoring the vulnerability of key staple crops to hydroclimate stress. Our results highlight the importance of managing local land moisture sources and reveal where targeted water management strategies would be most expected to enhance agricultural resilience.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41893-025-01662-1/MediaObjects/41893_2025_1662_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 小气候控制着火星沉积物流的形态</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02879-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Microclimate governs the morphology of sediment flows on Mars&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jacob B. Adler; Frances Rivera-Hernández; Sharissa Thompson; Petr Brož; Matthew E. Sylvest; Zoe S. Emerland; Manish Patel; Mark Fox-Powell&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;流水和沉积物形成的地貌在火星表面留下了沉积物，使研究古代环境成为可能。这些特征可以对地表水活动和过去的宜居性提供限制。然而，只有少数实验室研究调查了相关火星表面条件下富含沉积物的流动的外观和行为。我们在火星环境室中进行了实验，以了解在 5 至 1000 mbar 的大气压力和 248 至 297 K 之间的表面温度下泥浆的流变性和沉积形态。我们发现，大多数水活动发生的诺亚时代的沉积物流的行为可能与地球类似，但仅限于某些气候条件下。然而，在西方和亚马逊时期，由于全球大气损失，主要的物理状况发生了变化。这些时代的沉积物流动与地球上的类似物不同，并且取决于微气候（当地压力和温度），以冻结、蒸发冷却和沸腾为主。因此，区域气候和成分背景是解释火星上这些特征的卫星遥感图像的重要因素。结果表明，我们或许能够通过分析沉积物流形态来发现火星上的古大气压力记录。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Landforms created by flowing water with sediment have left deposits on the surface of Mars, allowing study of the ancient environment. These features could provide constraints on surface water activity and past habitability. However, only a few lab studies have investigated the appearance and behavior of sediment-rich flows at relevant Mars surface conditions. We conducted experiments in a Mars environment chamber to understand the rheology and deposit morphology of mud under atmospheric pressures from 5 to 1000 mbar and surface temperatures between 248 and 297 K. We found that sediment flows in the Noachian era, when most aqueous activity occurred, could behave similarly to Earth analogs, but only under certain climate conditions. However, in the Hesperian and Amazonian periods, the dominant physical regime changed due to global atmospheric loss. Sediment flows during these eras would not have been similar to Earth analogs, and would have been dominated by freezing, evaporative cooling, and boiling depending on the microclimate (local pressure and temperature). Thus, regional climate and compositional context are important factors for interpreting satellite remote sensing images of these features on Mars. The results suggest we may be able to discover the paleo-atmospheric pressure record on Mars by analyzing sediment flow morphology.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02879-w/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2879_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 使用深度学习和气候数据预测孟加拉国北部的水资源短缺</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01030-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Predicting water scarcity in northern Bangladesh using deep learning and climate data&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Md. Alomgir Hossain; Momotaz Begum; Md. Nasim Akhtar; Md Anuwer Hossain; Md. Monirul Islam; Mansour Almazroui; Gowhar Meraj; Muhammad Mubashar Dogar; Mahfuzur Rahman&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候变化和人类活动加剧了水资源短缺，给孟加拉国北部带来了重大挑战。本研究利用先进的深度学习技术整合干旱和地下水潜力图，呈现出全面的水资源短缺图。采用带有优化器的深度学习模型来预测共享社会经济途径（SSP1-2.6、SSP2-4.5 和 SSP5-8.5）下当前和未来的水资源短缺情况。主要重点是如何将这些数据集与深度学习和气候预测相结合，增强对水资源短缺的预测和管理，从而实现创新的资源规划。研究结果表明，SSP1-2.6 显着降低了水资源短缺和干旱风险，特别是在 Kharif-1 和 Rabi 季节，而 SSP5-8.5 则加剧了水资源短缺，特别是在 Rabi 季节。使用总运行特征和曲线下面积指标进行的模型验证证实了强大的预测性能。这项研究推进了水资源短缺评估，为可持续水资源管理和气候适应战略提供了详细且可操作的框架。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water scarcity, exacerbated by climatic variability and human activities, poses a significant challenge in northern Bangladesh. This study presents a comprehensive water scarcity map by integrating drought and groundwater potential maps using advanced deep learning techniques. A deep learning model with optimizer is employed to predict current and future water scarcity under shared socioeconomic pathways (SSP1-2.6, SSP2-4.5, and SSP5-8.5). The primary focus is on how integrating these datasets with deep learning and climate projections enhances the prediction and management of water scarcity, enabling innovative resource planning. Findings reveal that SSP1-2.6 significantly reduces water scarcity and drought risks, particularly during Kharif-1 and Rabi seasons, while SSP5-8.5 intensifies water scarcity, especially in Rabi. Model validation using total operating characteristic and area under the curve metrics confirms strong predictive performance. This study advances water scarcity assessment, offering a detailed and actionable framework for sustainable water resource management and climate adaptation strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01030-y/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1030_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>