<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 02:08:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 全球冰川湖的基于空间限制的基于遥感的库存</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04809-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A spatially constrained remote sensing-based inventory of glacial lakes worldwide&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Chunqiao Song; Chenyu Fan; Jinsong Ma; Pengfei Zhan; Xinyuan Deng&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候变化加速了冰川的广泛撤退，导致冰川湖的广泛发展。全球冰川湖泊空间分布的整体图片是追踪爆发危险的关键基础。通过采用半自动化的映射方法和严格的质量控制，本研究清单117,352冰川湖（≥0.01km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ）全球（南极和格陵兰岛的冰盖/纸盖排除在内），净面积为24,755.84±2,971.33 km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; 。评估结果表明，冰川湖（Giglak）的全球库存分别为89.37％和91.42％。这些冰川湖在不同的海拔高度上广泛分布，从地球的第三杆到海岸。大多数冰川湖泊分布在格陵兰外围，亚洲高山，阿拉斯加，加拿大和山脉。冰川湖的数量在0.01-0.1公里之间&lt;sup&gt;，&lt;/sup&gt;占总计数的77.24％，但面积仅占11.82％。将冰川湖分类为四种类型的分类表明，与冰的冰期湖泊统治了全球的数量（67.07％）和面积（53.04％）。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate change accelerates the extensive retreat of glaciers, leading to the widespread development of glacial lakes. A holistic picture of the spatial distribution of glacial lakes worldwide is a critical base for tracking the outburst hazards. By employing a semi-automated mapping approach and rigorous quality control, this study inventories 117,352 glacial lakes (≥0.01 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;) worldwide (the ice cap/sheet of Antarctic and Greenland excluded), with a net area of 24,755.84 ± 2,971.33 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;. The evaluation result shows this global inventory of glacial lakes (GIGLak) has an overall accuracy of 89.37% and 91.42% in number and area, respectively. These glacial lakes are widely distributed in different altitudes, ranging from the Earth’s third pole to the coasts. Most glacial lakes are distributed in the Greenland periphery, High-Mountain Asia, Alaska, Canada, and the Cordilleras. The number of glacial lakes between 0.01–0.1 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; accounts for 77.24% of the total count but only 11.82% in area. The classification of glacial lakes as four types indicates that the ice-uncontacted proglacial lakes dominate the number (67.07%) and area (53.04%) worldwide.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04809-z/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4809_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>