<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 02:27:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 从2005年到2022年的地下水平水位观测网格数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04799-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Underground well water level observation grid dataset from 2005 to 2022&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Mengran Wang; Jiaqi Yao; Huanyu Chang; Rong Liu; Nan Xu; Zihua Liu; Haiying Gong; Hengliang Zheng; Jinke Wang; Xueer Guo; Yongqiang Cao; Yong Zhao; Hui Lu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;地下水是一种重要的水文循环成分，对于维持生态系统功能和人类生计至关重要。本文介绍的数据集源自中国地质环境监测地下水水平年鉴（2005-2022），由中国地质环境监测研究所编写，该数据集融合了中国地下水监测井的长期观察数据。该数据集包含11,911个监视点和4,275,506个观察记录，每个站点每月提供五个观察结果。为了增强其空间和时间覆盖，使用反向距离加权插值方法处理数据集，以1 km和一个月的空间和时间分辨率生成地下水级别的栅格数据。插值数据的验证证明了高精度，回归系数和R &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;值在多个验证区域接近1，并且根平方误差和均方误差指标仍然可以接受。跨越2005–2022，该数据集以标准的地理格式提供，使其非常适合地理信息系统分析。它为研究地下水动力学，探索与地面生态系统的互动以及支持可持续水管理实践提供了强大的基础。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Groundwater, a vital hydrological cycle component, is essential in sustaining ecosystem functions and human livelihoods. The dataset presented herein, derived from the China Geological Environment Monitoring Groundwater Level Yearbook (2005–2022) compiled by the China Geological Environment Monitoring Institute, integrates long-term observational data from groundwater monitoring wells across China. The dataset comprises 11,911 monitoring points and 4,275,506 observation records, with each site providing five observations per month. To enhance its spatial and temporal coverage, the dataset was processed using the inverse distance weighting interpolation method, generating groundwater level raster data with spatial and temporal resolutions of 1 km and one month, respectively. Validation of the interpolated data demonstrated high accuracy, with regression coefficients and R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; values approaching 1 across multiple validation regions, and root-mean-square error and mean-square error metrics remaining acceptable. Spanning 2005–2022, the dataset is available in standard GeoTIFF format, rendering it ideal for geographic information system analysis. It provides a robust foundation for investigating groundwater dynamics, exploring interactions with surface ecosystems, and supporting sustainable water management practices.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04799-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4799_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 在空间上，中国降水Δ18O对ENSO周期的降水不均匀反应</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01057-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Spatially inhomogeneous response of precipitation δ18O in China to ENSO cycles&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yushuang Cui; Lide Tian; Zhongyin Cai; Shangjie Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水稳定的同位素是必不可少的天然示踪剂，在水循环，大气科学和古气候重建中提供广泛的应用。在这项研究中，我们通过开发融合机学习模型为1961  -  2022年创建了一个降水稳定的同位素数据集，并在过去62年中绘制了整个中国大陆的时间序列降水等等符（ &lt;sup&gt;δ18O&lt;/sup&gt; ）。该数据集允许进一步讨论降水&lt;sup&gt;δ18o&lt;/sup&gt;的空间不同行为与强烈的ENSO事件，并且我们发现，在厄尔尼诺现象中， &lt;sup&gt;δ18o&lt;/sup&gt;值较高，而LaNiña年份在该线的南部大约是从30°N 80°E到40°N 120°E，与北部区域不完全一致。在过去的几十年中，我们还揭示了西部干旱地区和季风东部地区降水&lt;sup&gt;δ18O&lt;/sup&gt;的趋势越来越大，而藏族高原的趋势没有明显的趋势。这些发现增强了我们对影响降水同位素的气候控制机制的理解，并使古气候重建受益。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water stable isotopes serve as essential natural tracers, offering broad applications in water cycle, atmosphere science and paleoclimate rebuilding. In this study, we created a precipitation stable isotope dataset for 1961–2022 by developing a fusion machine learning model, and mapped the time-series precipitation isoscape (δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O) across the mainland of China over the past 62 years. This dataset allows for a further discussion on spatially different behavior of precipitation δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O to the strong ENSO events, and we found that δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O values are higher in El Niño years and lower in La Niña years in the southern of the line roughly from 30°N 80°E to 40°N 120°E, not fully consistent with the northern region. We also revealed an increasing trend in precipitation δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O in the Western arid region and Eastern monsoon region in the past decades, while no significant trend on the Tibetan Plateau. These findings enhance our understanding of the climatic control mechanisms influencing precipitation isotopes and benefit paleoclimate rebuilding.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01057-1/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1057_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 地下水统治着融雪的径流，并控制美国西部的水流效率</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02303-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Groundwater dominates snowmelt runoff and controls streamflow efficiency in the western United States&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Paul D. Brooks; D. Kip Solomon; Stephanie Kampf; Sara Warix; Carleton Bern; David Barnard; Holly R. Barnard; Gregory T. Carling; Rosemary W. H. Carroll; Jon Chorover; Adrian Harpold; Kathleen Lohse; Fabiola Meza; Jennifer McIntosh; Bethany Neilson; Megan Sears; Margaret Wolf&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;季节性积雪的山水集水区的气候变化正在减少供水并降低流量的可预测性。在这里，我们使用Tritium age Edating来表明与融雪迅速有助于径流的普遍假设相反，美国西部集水区的融雪过程中的流量由较旧的地下水主导。融雪径流期间流水的平均年龄（5.7±4.3岁）中间至地下水的平均年龄（10.4±4.5岁）和最近的降水量，表明从地下水中得出了58％（±34％）的融雪径流。水年龄，水流和地下水存储是由基岩地质介导的：低渗透性硬岩/页岩集水集比高渗透性砂岩/碎屑集水集中表现出年轻年龄，更少的存储和更高效的流量产生。我们的结果表明，融雪径流是由地下水储存介导的多年气候的结果。包括这些相互作用包括随着气候和景观变化的加速预测水资源至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate change in seasonally snow-covered mountain catchments is reducing water supply and decreasing streamflow predictability. Here, we use tritium age dating to show that contrary to the common assumption that snowmelt quickly contributes to runoff, streamflow during snowmelt in western US catchments is dominated by older groundwater. The average age of streamwater during snowmelt runoff (5.7 ± 4.3 years) was intermediate to the average age of groundwater (10.4 ± 4.5 years) and recent precipitation, indicating that 58% (±34%) of snowmelt runoff was derived from groundwater. Water ages, streamflow, and groundwater storage were mediated by bedrock geology: low-permeability hard rock/shale catchments exhibited younger ages, less storage, and more efficient streamflow generation than high-permeability sandstone/clastic catchments. Our results demonstrate that snowmelt runoff is the result of multiple prior years of climate mediated by groundwater storage. Including these interactions will be crucial for predicting water resources as climate and landscape changes accelerate.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02303-3/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2303_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>