<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:23:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 基于多传感器遥感观测的全球400米高分辨率土壤湿度数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06356-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A global 400-m high-resolution soil moisture dataset derived from multi-sensor remote sensing observations&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Bin Fang; Venkataraman Lakshmi; Christopher Hain; Vikalp Mishra&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;过去五十年来一直通过卫星遥感监测土壤湿度（SM）。在最近的任务中，由美国国家航空航天局（NASA）发起的土壤湿度主动被动（SMAP）任务一直通过L波段无源微波辐射计提供高质量的全球SM观测，重访时间为1-2天，尽管其空间分辨率仍保持在数十公里量级。为了解决这一限制，开发并应用了一种算法，通过结合可见红外成像辐射计套件 (VIIRS) 中的地表温度 (LST) 和叶面积指数 (LAI) 产品，将 SMAP 增强型 2 级辐射计半轨道 SM 产品的分辨率从 9 km 缩小到 400 m。 400 m 缩小尺寸的 SM 产品根据从国际土壤湿度网络 (ISMN) 获取的现场观测进行了验证，并与 1 km 缩小尺寸和原始 9 km SMAP 产品进行了比较。总体而言，400 m 产品在均方根误差 (RMSE) 和平均绝对误差 (MAE) 方面优于其他两个产品。它还揭示了支持地方和区域水文应用的更精细尺度的 SM 空间模式。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Soil Moisture (SM) has been monitored by satellite remote sensing for the past five decades. Among recent missions, the Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP) mission, launched by the National Aeronautics and Space Administration’s (NASA), has been providing high-quality global SM observations from an L-band passive microwave radiometer with a revisit time of 1-2 days, although its spatial resolution remains on the order of tens of kilometers. To address this limitation, an algorithm was developed and applied to downscale the SMAP enhanced Level-2 radiometer half-orbit SM product from 9 km to 400 m resolution by incorporating land surface temperature (LST) and leaf area index (LAI) products from the Visible Infrared Imaging Radiometer Suite (VIIRS). The 400 m downscaled SM product was validated against in situ observations acquired from the International Soil Moisture Network (ISMN) and compared with both 1 km downscaled and original 9 km SMAP products. Overall, the 400 m product outperformed the other two in terms of Root Mean Square Error (RMSE) and Mean Absolute Error (MAE). It also revealed finer-scale spatial patterns of SM supporting local and regional hydrological applications.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01265-9/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1265_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 基于机器学习的全球长期每日多层土壤湿度数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06436-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A global long-term daily multilayer soil moisture dataset derived from machine learning&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zeyang Wei; Lifei Wei; Ting Wang; Qikai Lu; Shuang Tian; Fei Zhang; Yanfei Zhong&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;土壤水分是地球能量和水循环的重要组成部分。然而，大多数现有产品仅关注表层，深层土壤层的连续高分辨率数据集仍然稀缺。为了解决这一差距，我们利用机器学习方法 (XGBoost) 生成了 2002-2021 年期间的全球每日无缝多层土壤湿度数据集 (SWSM)。 SWSM 数据集提供了三个深度水平的 0.05° 空间分辨率的估计：0-10 厘米、10-30 厘米和 30-60 厘米。针对现场观测的严格验证证明了该数据集的高精度，所有深度的皮尔逊相关系数超过 0.90，均方根误差低于 0.05。特征重要性评估验证了数据集的物理一致性，揭示了与已建立的水文理解相一致的深度依赖模式。 SWSM数据集具有长期的时间覆盖、精细的空间分辨率和多层结构，是水文建模、农业用水管理和气候变化研究应用的宝贵资源。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Soil moisture is a critical component of the Earth’s energy and water cycles. However, most existing products focus solely on surface layers, and continuous, high‐resolution datasets for deep soil horizons remain scarce. To address this gap, we generated a global, daily, seamless multilayer soil moisture dataset (SWSM) for the period 2002–2021 by leveraging a machine learning approach (XGBoost). The SWSM dataset provides estimates at a 0.05° spatial resolution for three depth horizons: 0–10 cm, 10–30 cm, and 30–60 cm. Rigorous validation against in situ observations demonstrated the dataset’s high accuracy, with Pearson correlation coefficients exceeding 0.90 and root mean square errors below 0.05 across all depths. A feature importance assessment verified the dataset’s physical consistency, revealing depth-dependent patterns aligned with established hydrological understanding. The SWSM dataset, with its long-term temporal coverage, fine spatial resolution, and multi-layer structure, is a valuable resource for applications in hydrologic modeling, agricultural water management, and climate change studies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-27391-1/MediaObjects/41598_2025_27391_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 美国玉米带的湿气加剧了对流风暴</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-03089-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Moisture from US Corn Belt fuels more intense convective storms&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zhe Zhang; Andreas F. Prein; Cenlin He; Changhai Liu; Gonzalo Miguez-Macho; Fei Chen; Ronnie Abolafia-Rosenzweig; Tzu-Shun Lin; Roy Rasmussen&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;美国玉米带是世界上生产力最高的农业地区之一，也是全球中尺度对流系统（MCS）的热点地区，该系统提供了至关重要的生长季节降雨，但也引发了危险的洪水。虽然众所周知，来自浅层地下水、大面积农田和灌溉的蒸散量 (ET) 会影响区域降水，但其在助长对流风暴中的作用仍知之甚少。在这里，我们使用高分辨率区域气候模型和先进的水蒸气示踪剂来跟踪从玉米带 ET 到单个对流风暴的水分。我们发现，地下水-作物-灌溉的综合相互作用将 MCS 频率提高了 24-35%，将风暴寿命延长了 10%，并加速了风暴移动。来自玉米带的湿气增强了暖湿气流的流入，维持了对流单元并增强了风暴中心附近的降水，在更强的风暴中效果更为明显。这些发现凸显了浅层地下水和农业活动在加剧对流风暴、造成威胁水和粮食安全的连锁危害方面的重要作用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The US Corn Belt is among the world’s most productive agricultural regions and a global hotspot for mesoscale convective systems (MCSs), which supply vital growing season rainfall but also drive hazardous flooding. While evapotranspiration (ET) from shallow groundwater, extensive croplands, and irrigation is known to influence regional precipitation, its role in fueling convective storms remains poorly understood. Here we use a high-resolution regional climate model coupled with an advanced water vapor tracer to track moisture from Corn Belt ET into individual convective storms. We find that the integrated groundwater-crop-irrigation interactions amplify MCS frequency by 24-35%, extend storm lifetime by up to 10%, and accelerate storm movement. Moisture from Corn Belt ET enhances the warm-moist inflows, sustaining convective cells and enhancing precipitation near the storm center, with more pronounced effects in stronger storms. These findings highlight the significant role of shallow groundwater and agricultural activities in intensifying convective storms, creating cascading hazards that threaten water and food security.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-28581-7/MediaObjects/41598_2025_28581_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Reviews Earth &amp; Environment | 全球河流流量过去和未来的变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43017-025-00745-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Past and future change in global river flows&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lukas Gudmundsson; Manuela I. Brunner; Petra Döll; Etienne Fluet-Chouinard; Natalia Frolova; Simon N. Gosling; Yukiko Hirabayashi; Maria B. Kireeva; Xiaomang Liu; Hannes Müller Schmied; Dmitriy Magritskiy; Louise J. Slater; Lina Stein; Yves Tramblay; Kaiwen Wang; Conrad Wasko; Dai Yamazaki; Xudong Zhou&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流是全球水循环的重要组成部分。然而，人类对气候和陆地系统的影响正在日益影响河流的流量状况。在这篇综述中，我们总结了目前对全球河流流量过去和预计变化的理解，重点关注年流量、季节动态和突变。河流流量观测揭示了不同的区域趋势，包括高纬度地区流量增加和中纬度和亚热带部分地区流量减少。尤其是以降雪为主的地区，其季节周期呈现出向提前流动的转变。这些模式与历史气候模型模拟大致一致，表明存在人为气候变化信号。然而，由于温室气体排放、CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;驱动的植被响应、土地利用变化和水管理之间的相互作用，归因变得复杂。未来的预测表明变化仍在继续，某些地区将经历更加潮湿的环境，而其他地区则将加剧干燥。季节性变化，特别是由于雪动态变化而引起的变化，预计也会加剧。尽管建模和观测取得了进展，但人为气候变化和人类对陆地系统的直接干预的综合影响仍然存在不确定性。缩小这些差距需要改进监测、改进建模和健全的归因框架，以支持有效管理水资源、维持生态系统和适应不断变化的气候。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Rivers are a vital component of the global water cycle. However, human influence on climate and terrestrial systems is increasingly shaping river flow regimes. In this Review, we summarize the current understanding of past and projected changes in global river flow, focusing on annual volumes, seasonal dynamics and sudden changes. River flow observations reveal distinct regional trends, including increased flows in high-latitude regions and decreased flows in parts of the mid-latitudes and subtropics. Snow-dominated regions in particular show shifts in their seasonal cycle towards earlier flows. These patterns align broadly with historical climate model simulations, suggesting an anthropogenic climate change signal. However, attribution is complicated by the interplay of greenhouse gas emissions, CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-driven vegetation response, land-use change and water management. Future projections indicate continued change, with certain regions experiencing wetter conditions and others intensified drying. Seasonal changes, particularly those due to altered snow dynamics, are also expected to intensify. Despite modelling and observational advances, uncertainties remain regarding the combined effects of anthropogenic climate change and direct human interventions in terrestrial systems. Closing these gaps requires improved monitoring, advances in modelling and robust attribution frameworks, in support of efficiently managing water resources, sustaining ecosystems and adapting to a changing climate.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43017-025-00745-z/MediaObjects/43017_2025_745_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>