<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 02:11:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 北半球多年冻土区域的河流二氧化碳发射最近加剧了</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-58716-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Recent intensified riverine CO2 emission across the Northern Hemisphere permafrost region&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Cuicui Mu; Kun Li; Shaoda Liu; Yuguo Wei; Mei Mu; Xuexue Shang; Fumei Liu; Chunling Zhang; Hebin Liu; Tanguang Gao; Chunlin Song; Liwei Zhang; Jan Karlsson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球变暖会导致永久冻结，将大量土壤碳转移到河流中，这不可避免地加速了Riverine Co &lt;sub&gt;2的&lt;/sub&gt;释放。但是，河流CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;排放的时间和空间上的明显变化尚不清楚，从而限制了土地碳气候反馈的评估。使用新的和已发表的5685 Riverine CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;北极和藏族高原的部分压力数据，我们表明，北半球的当前Riverine CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;发射是200±15 tg &lt;sup&gt;cyr⁻1&lt;/sup&gt; 。排放量的偏移量为28.1±2.1％，占北半球多年冻土带的土地碳吸收的28.1±2.1％，大区域可变性为13.1％至63.1％。我们的发现表明，在2000年至2020年期间，CO &lt;sub&gt;2的&lt;/sub&gt;排放率以0.42±0.16 tg &lt;sup&gt;cyr⁻1&lt;/sup&gt;的速度增加，这主要是由于在气候变化下降水增加和加速永久冻土的加速驱动。这项研究突出了河流碳排放量增加，并在纳入河流中释放碳释放碳后，对气候的多年冻土碳反馈加强。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Global warming causes permafrost thawing, transferring large amounts of soil carbon into rivers, which inevitably accelerates riverine CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; release. However, temporally and spatially explicit variations of riverine CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions remain unclear, limiting the assessment of land carbon-climate feedback. Using new and published 5685 riverine CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; partial pressure data in the Arctic and Tibetan Plateau, we show that current riverine CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emission across the Northern Hemisphere permafrost zone is 200 ± 15 Tg C yr⁻&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;. The emission offsets 28.1 ± 2.1% of the land carbon uptake in the Northern Hemisphere permafrost zone, with large regional variability of 13.1 to 63.1%. Our findings suggest that CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions increased at a rate of 0.42 ± 0.16 Tg C yr⁻&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; during 2000 to 2020, and this is primarily driven by increased precipitation and accelerated permafrost thawing under climate change. This study highlights increased riverine carbon emission and strengthening of the permafrost carbon feedback to climate after incorporating carbon release from rivers.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-58716-3/MediaObjects/41467_2025_58716_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 在全球沿海大城市中，潮湿的热浪提高了极端降雨的可能性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01023-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Increasing probability of extreme rainfall preconditioned by humid heatwaves in global coastal megacities&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Poulomi Ganguli; Bruno Merz&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;热湿复合事件，潮湿的热日的顺序发生，然后是极端降雨，可能会导致灾难性后果，通常超过每个事件孤立发生的影响。城市沿海的微气候与陆地微风循环的复杂相互作用，对流和降雨的城市影响以及水分的水平对流混淆，这可能有利于热湿化合物的发生。我们介绍了全球沿海大城市夏季热潮事件的首次观察评估（1951-2022）。我们发现两个半球的热湿化合物事件的频率显着增加（p &amp;lt;0.001）：平均而言，在2020年代，在1950年代，〜3个事件〜3事件。在热潮复合事件频率上具有向上趋势的城市距离海岸&amp;lt;30公里，南半球的城市显示出比北半球的城市更快的热到效果过渡时间（&amp;lt;3天）。此外，当潮湿的热幅度从50个百分位数上升到90％时，29个地点中有26个地点显示出降水量增加，达到153％。了解世界海岸上的热 - 湿化合物相互作用与气候变化影响评估并告知气候适应性高度相关。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hot–wet compound events, the sequential occurrence of humid hot days followed by extreme rainfall, can cause catastrophic consequences, often exceeding the impacts of the isolated occurrence of each event. The urban-coastal microclimate is confounded by complex interactions of land–sea breeze circulations, urban effects of convection and rainfall, and horizontal advection of moisture, which can favor the hot–wet compound occurrence. We present the first observational assessment (1951–2022) of summertime hot–wet compound events across global coastal megacities. We find a significant (P &amp;lt; 0.001) increase in the frequency of hot–wet compound events in both hemispheres: on average, ~3 events in the 1950s to 43 events in the 2020s. Cities with upward trends in the frequency of hot–wet compound events are situated &amp;lt; 30 km from coasts, with cities in the southern hemisphere showing faster hot-to-wet transition times (&amp;lt;3 days) than cities in the northern hemisphere. Further, 26 out of 29 sites show increased extreme precipitation, reaching 153%, when humid heat amplitude rises from the 50th to 90th percentiles. Understanding hot–wet compound interactions over the world’s coasts is highly relevant for climate change impact assessment and informing climate adaptation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01023-x/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1023_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>