<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 02:08:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 30年（1991-2021）意大利PO河区的雪水量数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04633-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;30-years (1991-2021) Snow Water Equivalent Dataset in the Po River District, Italy&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Matteo Dall’Amico; Stefano Tasin; Federico Di Paolo; Marco Brian; Paolo Leoni; Francesco Tornatore; Giuseppe Formetta; John Mohd Wani; Riccardo Rigon; Gaia Roati&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文介绍了意大利PO河区的长期雪水同等数据集，该数据集跨越1991年至2021年，每天的时间步骤和500 m的空间分辨率部分覆盖了阿尔卑斯山和阿彭宁的山脉。该数据是使用混合建模方法生成的，该方法将与基于物理的Geotop模型进行的水文建模，对气象数据的预处理以及对原位雪测量值和地球观测雪产物的同化，以提高模型估计的质量。基于可靠性，质量和领土分布选择的不同控制点，对数据集进行了严格的质量评估。整个控制点模拟和观察到的积雪之间的点验证表明，数据集分别模拟正常和相对较高的积雪条件的准确性。此外，将卫星雪地图与模拟的积雪深度图进行了比较，这是高程和方面的函数。 2D验证显示了随时间和空间的准确值，该值以沿着基本方向的雪线表示。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This paper presents a long-term snow water equivalent dataset in the Po River District, Italy, spanning from 1991 to 2021 at daily time step and 500 m spatial resolution partially covering the mountain ranges of Alps and Apennines. The data has been generated using a hybrid modelling approach integrating the hydrological modelling conducted with the physically-based GEOtop model, preprocessing of the meteorological data, and assimilation of in-situ snow measurements and Earth Observation snow products to enhance the quality of the model estimates. A rigorous quality assessment of the dataset has been performed at different control points selected based on reliability, quality, and territorial distribution. The point validation between simulated and observed snow depth across control points shows the accuracy of the dataset in simulating the normal and relatively high snow conditions, respectively. Additionally, satellite snow cover maps have been compared with simulated snow depth maps, as a function of elevation and aspect. 2D Validation shows accurate values over time and space, expressed in terms of snowline along the cardinal directions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04633-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4633_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>