<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 02:27:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 美国取水数据库</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06300-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;United States Water Withdrawals Database&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Md. Yunus Naseri; Landon T. Marston&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;美国取水数据库 (USWWD) 提供美国 42 个州用户级取水数据的标准化汇编。 USWWD 以前所未有的空间和时间分辨率提供取水时间序列，涵盖各部门 7,524,266 条记录中的 188,857 个独特用水者、353,694 个分流和使用点以及 58,439,412 个取水量。 USWWD 整合了不同的州级数据源，对用水者、取水地点、水量、水源类型和主要用水类别的信息进行标准化。取水数据结合了直接测量和各种估计技术，反映了不同国家机构在报告用水量时使用的不同方法。 USWWD 解决了国家用水数据的重大差距，使研究人员能够对跨空间、时间和部门的取水模式、趋势和驱动因素进行详细分析。这个精细的数据集支持广泛的应用，包括水资源管理、规划和政策制定。通过提供迄今为止最详细的国家用水数据，USWWD 促进了人们对社会如何用水的新认识。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The United States Water Withdrawals Database (USWWD) provides a standardized compilation of user-level water withdrawal data across 42 US states. USWWD provides time series of water withdrawals at unprecedented spatial and temporal resolutions, encompassing 188,857 unique water users, 353,694 points of diversion and use, and 58,439,412 withdrawal volumes included in 7,524,266 records across various sectors. USWWD integrates diverse state-level data sources, standardizing information on water users, withdrawal locations, volumes, source types, and primary water use categories. The withdrawal data combines both direct measurements and various estimation techniques, reflecting the diverse methods utilized by different state agencies in reporting water usage. USWWD addresses significant gaps in national water use data, enabling researchers to conduct detailed analyses of water withdrawal patterns, trends, and drivers across space, time, and sectors. This granular dataset supports a wide range of applications, including water resource management, planning, and policy development. By providing the most detailed national water use data to date, USWWD facilitates new understanding of how society uses water.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06178-z/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6178_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>