<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 02:23:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Water | 河流热浪是气候变化的一个新风险</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00541-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Riverine heatwaves are an emergent climate change risk&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Amber van Hamel; Giulia Bruno; Corentin Chartier-Rescan; Corinna Frank; Maria H. Grundmann; David M. Hannah; Cornelia W. Twining; Manuela I. Brunner&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河水温度持续异常温暖（称为河流热浪）会对河流生态系统和社会经济活动产生负面影响。随着气候变化，这些热浪可能会变得更加严重和频繁。尽管水温的主要驱动因素已被充分了解，但我们对驱动河流热浪的不同水文气候过程如何相互作用的了解有限。鉴于预计河流热浪频率和严重程度的增加可能会逐渐增加生态和人为系统的脆弱性，这种知识的缺乏尤其令人震惊。为了更好地了解河流热浪如何在气候变化中演变，我们建议重点研究开发大样本数据集，增强我们对河流热浪发展过程的理解，并改进水温模型。这些努力需要一个强大的社区，并将支持针对这些日益频繁的极端事件采取的缓解和适应措施。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sustained periods of anomalously warm river water temperature, known as riverine heatwaves, can negatively impact river ecosystems and socioeconomic activities. With climate change, these heatwaves are likely to become more severe and frequent. Even though the main drivers of water temperature are well understood, we only have a limited understanding of how the different hydro-climatic processes that drive riverine heatwaves interact. This lack of knowledge is particularly striking given that anticipated increases in the frequency and severity of riverine heatwaves may progressively increase the vulnerability of ecological and anthropogenic systems. To better understand how riverine heatwaves may evolve in a changing climate, we propose focused research efforts to develop large-sample datasets, enhance our understanding of the processes involved in riverine heatwave development, and improve water temperature models. Such efforts require a strong community and will support mitigation and adaptation measures in relation to these increasingly frequent extreme events.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00541-5/MediaObjects/44221_2025_541_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>