<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 02:12:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 整个美国大陆的统一合奏土壤水分数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04657-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A unified ensemble soil moisture dataset across the continental United States&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lingcheng Li; Xinming Lin; Yilin Fang; Z. Jason Hou; L. Ruby Leung; Yaoping Wang; Jiafu Mao; Yaping Xu; Elias Massoud; Mingjie Shi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在美国大陆（CONUS）上已经开发了统一的整体土壤水分（SM）。数据包包括19种来自地表模型，遥感，重新分析和机器学习模型的产品。所有数据集统一到0.25度和每月的时空分辨率，从而综合了表面SM动力学。数据集的统计分析利用Koppen-Geiger气候分类来探索Surfore SM的时空变异性。提取的SM特性突出了不同的模式，西部圆锥显示了更大的变异值系数，而东部圆锥则显示出更高的SM值。遥感数据集往往更干燥，而重新分析产品呈现湿润的条件。原位SM观测是小波功率分析的基础，以解释跨数据集中促进每日SM记录的时间尺度的差异。这项研究提供了一个全面的土壤水分数据包和一个分析框架，可用于地球系统模型评估和不确定性量化，量化干旱影响和土地 - 大气相互作用，并为干旱反应计划提出建议。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A unified ensemble soil moisture (SM) package has been developed over the Continental United States (CONUS). The data package includes 19 products from land surface models, remote sensing, reanalysis, and machine learning models. All datasets are unified to a 0.25-degree and monthly spatiotemporal resolution, providing a comprehensive view of surface SM dynamics. The statistical analysis of the datasets leverages the Koppen-Geiger Climate Classification to explore surface SM’s spatiotemporal variabilities. The extracted SM characteristics highlight distinct patterns, with the western CONUS showing larger coefficient of variation values and the eastern CONUS exhibiting higher SM values. Remote sensing datasets tend to be drier, while reanalysis products present wetter conditions. In-situ SM observations serve as the basis for wavelet power spectrum analyses to explain discrepancies in temporal scales across datasets facilitating daily SM records. This study provides a comprehensive soil moisture data package and an analysis framework that can be used for Earth system model evaluations and uncertainty quantification, quantifying drought impacts and land–atmosphere interactions and making recommendations for drought response planning.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04657-x/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4657_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>