<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 02:27:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Sustainability | 由不可持续的地下水灌溉驱动的三角洲淡水短缺</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-025-01566-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Deltaic freshwater scarcity driven by unsustainable groundwater-fed irrigation&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Augusto Getirana; Nishan Kumar Biswas; Sujay Kumar; Wanshu Nie; Shahryar Ahmad; Fadji Maina; Nazmus Sakib; Md Sazzad Hossain; Robin Kumar Biswas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;南亚通过提高该地区农作物生产率和季风含水层补给率，从地下水抽水中受益于旱季灌溉。根据数据驱动的集成建模系统，我们提供了数值证据，表明不可持续的地下水灌溉对地表淡水的可用性的影响远远超出了以前的理解。我们的结果证实了先前研究的发现表明，在2002  -  2021年间潮湿季节期间的地下水充电率提高，但是这些速率不足以使含水层恢复，逐渐耗尽了恒河 - 恒河 - 布拉赫马普拉 - 梅格纳三角洲的地下水。主要发现是，这种增加的充值会导致季风期间的地表径流和基础流的产生下降，从而导致洪水危险降低（有益的结果），但可用于耕种的地表淡水较少，这可能会触发额外的地下水需求。内陆地下水喂养的灌溉引起的沿海洪水风险下降超过了海平面上升约五到十倍。减少的径流也可能会增加海水的侵入，这是由于淡水较少以推动海水驱动的驱动，从而进一步增加了淡水稀缺性。这尤其令人担忧，因为该地区一直处于海平面上升和沉没土地的下降。我们对这一三角洲的发现具有全球影响，因为人类和气候在全球范围内越来越压力沿海和三角洲生态系统。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Southern Asia benefits from groundwater pumping for dry-season irrigation by increasing both crop productivity and monsoon aquifer recharge rates in the region. On the basis of a data-driven integrated modelling system, we provide numerical evidence that the impacts of unsustainable groundwater-fed irrigation on surface freshwater availability go beyond what was previously understood. Our results confirm findings from previous studies showing increased groundwater recharge rates during wet seasons over 2002–2021, but these rates are insufficient for aquifers to recover, gradually depleting groundwater across the Ganges–Brahmaputra–Meghna delta. The main findings are that this increased recharge causes a drop in surface runoff and baseflow generation during the monsoons, resulting in lower flood risk (a beneficial outcome), but also less surface freshwater available for farming, which may trigger additional groundwater demand. The drop in coastal flood risk induced by inland groundwater-fed irrigation exceeds the increase caused by sea level rise by about five- to tenfold. Reduced runoff may also increase seawater intrusion, driven by less freshwater to push ocean water away, further increasing freshwater scarcity. This is particularly concerning, since the region has been under rising sea levels and sinking lands. Our findings over this delta have global implications, as humans and climate are increasingly pressuring coastal and deltaic ecosystems worldwide.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41893-025-01566-0/MediaObjects/41893_2025_1566_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>