<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 02:52:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 定量地下表征阐明了第四纪密西西比河河谷的起源</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02545-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Quantitative subsurface characterization illuminates the origin of the Quaternary Mississippi River Valley alluvial aquifer&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yuqi Song; Frank T.-C. Tsai; Burke J. Minsley; Chenliang Wu; Essam Heggy&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;密西西比河河谷冲积含水层（MRVA）对于美国粮食安全和全球农业供应至关重要。但是，对其第四纪起源，结构和水文功能的定量理解仍然不完整。在这里，我们开发了一个三维水学位模型，以表征粘土和淤泥，细中等砂和碎石沙子的沉积，并使用来自密西西比州下部山谷的75,000个钻孔的岩石学数据和geestatitions方法 -  Interval kriging。我们发现，循环冰川固定在遗迹前 - 冰川后沉积物的残留物以及地球动力学活动塑造了MRVA基础构型。断层和盐遗传学的层降低，增强了冰川切口，从而产生了突然的含水层增厚。我们将碎石沙的顶部划定为更新世 - 近代过渡的区域标记。 MRVA水文学揭示了关于地下水储存和质量的水文功能和地质控制，从而在气候变化下对含水层可持续性进行了评估，对全球冲积含水层的影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Mississippi River Valley alluvial aquifer (MRVA) is vital to U.S. food security and global agricultural supply. However, quantitative understanding of its Quaternary origin, architecture, and hydrologic function remains incomplete. Here we develop a three-dimensional hydrostratigraphic model to characterize the deposition of clay and silt, fine-medium sands, and graveliferous sands using lithologic data from 75,000 boreholes compiled across the Lower Mississippi Valley and a geostatistical method—interval kriging. We find that cyclic glacial entrenchments, evidenced by remnants of pre-Wisconsinan postglacial sediments, alongside geodynamic activities shaped the MRVA basal configuration. Stratal weakening from faulting and salt diapirism enhanced glacial incision and thereby produced abrupt aquifer thickening. We demarcate the top of graveliferous sands as the regional marker of the Pleistocene-Holocene transition. The MRVA hydrostratigraphy reveals hydrologic function and geologic controls on groundwater storage and quality, advancing the assessment of aquifer sustainability under a changing climate, with implications for alluvial aquifers globally.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02545-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2545_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>