<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 09:24:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 解密蒸散量在降低土地相对湿度趋势中的作用</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02076-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Deciphering the role of evapotranspiration in declining relative humidity trends over land&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yeonuk Kim; Mark S. Johnson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;近几十年来，土地上的相对湿度有所下降，干旱和野火的增加。先前的解释将这种趋势归因于从海洋中的水分对流不足以维持当前水平，但这忽略了陆地蒸散液提供的大气水分。重要的是，当前的最新气候模型继续低估了观察到的土地相对湿度趋势。在这里，我们表明，相对于给定的基线，特定的湿度的变化（由海洋平流都没有责任）在数量上等同于全球范围内蒸散量的相对变化。尽管存在蒸散趋势差异，但在气候模型和气候重新分析数据集中，这一发现是一致的。蒸散趋势的差异被确定为在气候模型中表达的相对湿度趋势偏见的显着原因。这些结果表明，当前的气候模型可能高估了蒸散量的强化，从而导致大气干燥的低估，对准确预测干旱，野火和气候适应的影响至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In recent decades, relative humidity over land has declined, driving increases in droughts and wildfires. Previous explanations attribute this trend to insufficient moisture advection from the ocean to sustain the current level, but this ignores atmospheric moisture supplied from terrestrial evapotranspiration. Importantly, current state-of-the-art climate models continue to underestimate the observed relative humidity trend over land. Here, we show that changes in specific humidity over land relative to a given baseline, unaccounted for by ocean advection, are quantitatively equivalent to relative changes in evapotranspiration on a global scale. This finding is consistent across climate models and climate reanalysis datasets, despite discrepancies in evapotranspiration trends among them. Differences in evapotranspiration trends are identified as a prominent cause of the bias in relative humidity trend expressed in climate models. These results suggest that current climate models may overestimate evapotranspiration intensifications, leading to an underestimation of atmospheric drying, with critical implications for accurately predicting droughts, wildfires, and climate adaptation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02076-9/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2076_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 使用Daymet的高分辨率，网格的产品用于蒸气压力不足</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04544-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A high resolution, gridded product for vapor pressure deficit using Daymet&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Nicholas K. Corak; Peter E. Thornton; Lauren E. L. Lowman&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;蒸气压力不足（VPD）是评估干旱条件和评估植物水应力的关键变量。全球和区域VPD的网格产品无法从卫星遥感，模型重新分析或地面观察数据集中免费获得。我们以1公里的空间分辨率和每日时间步骤介绍了美国大陆和加拿大北部和加拿大北部（CONUS+）的第一个网格VPD产品的两个版本。我们根据日常每日温度和平均每日蒸气压力得出VPD，并根据（1）由Köppen-Geiger分类确定的气候和（2）由国际地质 - 双聚球计划确定的土地覆盖率的估计值。来自代表不同气候和土地覆盖分类的253个Ameriflux站点的基于地面的VPD数据用于改善CONUS+网格中每个像素的日光衍生的VPD估计值，以生成最终数据集。我们根据独立的观察和重新分析数据评估了Daymet衍生的VPD。 CONUS+ VPD数据集将有助于调查包括干旱和野火在内的骚乱，并为土地管理策略提供信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Vapor pressure deficit (VPD) is a critical variable in assessing drought conditions and evaluating plant water stress. Gridded products of global and regional VPD are not freely available from satellite remote sensing, model reanalysis, or ground observation datasets. We present two versions of the first gridded VPD product for the Continental US and parts of Northern Mexico and Southern Canada (CONUS+) at a 1 km spatial resolution and daily time step. We derived VPD from Daymet maximum daily temperature and average daily vapor pressure and scale the estimates based on (1) climate determined by the Köppen-Geiger classifications and (2) land cover determined by the International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme. Ground-based VPD data from 253 AmeriFlux sites representing different climate and land cover classifications were used to improve the Daymet-derived VPD estimates for every pixel in the CONUS+ grid to produce the final datasets. We evaluated the Daymet-derived VPD against independent observations and reanalysis data. The CONUS+ VPD datasets will aid in investigating disturbances including drought and wildfire, and informing land management strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04544-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4544_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 气候变化对朝鲜半岛海底地下水排放和区域变化的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02084-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Climate change effects on submarine groundwater discharge and regional variations along the Korean Peninsula&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hahn Chul Jung; Yeosang Yoon&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候变化会影响朝鲜半岛的新鲜海底地下水排放，从而增加了沿海地区对环境退化和经济后果的脆弱性。在这里，我们使用已建立的水平衡方法对整个海岸的新鲜海底地下水排放进行区域估计。我们的发现表明，与北朝鲜半岛相比，由于净降水量更高，朝鲜半岛南部的西部和南部海岸表现出更高的新鲜海底地下水排放率。东海岸和西海岸之间的排水长度差异以及大量的潮汐公寓，显着影响海底地下水排放率。气候变化导致新鲜海底地下水排放的变化，春季和冬季朝鲜半岛的趋势不断上升，而北部沿海流域在所有季节中均显示出一致的增加。沿海地区因土地使用开发而造成近海污染的脆弱性影响了海岸线的15％。值得注意的是，在1990年至2020年之间，朝鲜半岛南部沿海流域的风险增加了38％。我们的分析还凸显了朝鲜半岛西南部盐水入侵的脆弱性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate change impacts fresh submarine groundwater discharge on the Korean Peninsula, increasing the vulnerability of coastal regions to environmental degradation and economic consequences. Here, we provide regional estimates of fresh submarine groundwater discharge along the entire coast using established water balance methods. Our findings reveal that the western and southern coasts of the southern Korean Peninsula exhibit higher fresh submarine groundwater discharge rates due to greater net precipitation compared to the northern Korean Peninsula. Differences in drainage length between the east and west coasts, along with substantial tidal flats, significantly influence submarine groundwater discharge rates. Climate change drives variations in fresh submarine groundwater discharge, with rising trends in the southern Korean Peninsula during spring and winter, while the northern coastal watersheds show consistent increases across all seasons. Coastal vulnerability to offshore contamination from land use development affects 15% of the coastline. Notably, between 1990 and 2020, the risk in the southern Korean Peninsula’s coastal catchments increased by 38%. Our analysis also highlights heightened vulnerability to saltwater intrusion in the southwestern Korean Peninsula.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02084-9/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2084_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 水健康知识图</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04537-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;The Water Health Open Knowledge Graph&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Anna Sofia Lippolis; Giorgia Lodi; Andrea Giovanni Nuzzolese&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球可持续发展挑战最近导致人们对水和卫生资源的管理产生了越来越多的兴趣。因此，有效，有意义和开放的数据的可用性对于在联合国针对的清洁水和卫生目标的更广泛背景下解决这些问题至关重要。在本文中，我们介绍了水健康知识图（WHOW-KG）及其设计方法和影响分析。 Whow-KG是在欧盟资助的WHOW（水健康知识）项目的背景下开发的，是一个语义知识图，该图形模拟了有关用水量，污染，极端天气事件，传染病率和药物分布的数据。确实，它旨在支持广泛的应用：从知识发现到决策，使其成为水和健康领域中研究人员，政策制定者和从业者的宝贵资源。 WHOW-KG由一个由五个本体和链接的开放数据组成的网络，该网络根据这些本体进行建模。作为一个完全分布的系统，它会随着时间的流逝而可持续，可以处理大型数据集，并允许数据提供商完全控制，并将其确定为在用水和污染领域中的重要欧洲资产。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Global sustainability challenges have recently led to an increasing interest in the management of water and health resources. Thus, the availability of effective, meaningful and open data is crucial to address those issues in the broader context of the Sustainable Development Goals of clean water and sanitation as targeted by the United Nations. In this paper, we present the Water Health Open Knowledge Graph (WHOW-KG) along with its design methodology and analysis on impact. Developed in the context of the EU-funded WHOW (Water Health Open Knowledge) project, the WHOW-KG is a semantic knowledge graph that models data on water consumption, pollution, extreme weather events, infectious disease rates and drug distribution. Indeed, it aims at supporting a wide range of applications: from knowledge discovery to decision-making, making it a valuable resource for researchers, policymakers, and practitioners in the water and health domains. The WHOW-KG consists of a network of five ontologies and related linked open data, modelled according to those ontologies. As a fully distributed system, it is sustainable over time, can handle large datasets, and allows data providers full control, establishing it as a vital European asset in the fields of water consumption and pollution.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04537-4/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4537_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Water | 尽管湖区在全球范围内增长，但越来越小的冰川湖爆发洪水泛滥</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00388-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Progressively smaller glacier lake outburst floods despite worldwide growth in lake area&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Georg Veh; Björn G. Wang; Anika Zirzow; Christoph Schmidt; Natalie Lützow; Frederic Steppat; Guoqing Zhang; Kristin Vogel; Marten Geertsema; John J. Clague; Oliver Korup&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;冰川湖爆发洪水（GLOF）可能起源于较大的湖泊，因为这些湖泊继续随着冰川静修的持续增长。但是，在可用的GLOF数据库中，这种看法仍然受到支持。在这里，我们绘制了1,686个冰川湖泊的区域，就在它们排干之前，在极地地区以外的13个冰川山区，并检查了1990年至2023年之间的湖泊前湖区的趋势。我们发现，湖泊前的湖泊地区几乎没有变化，或者几乎没有变化，或者即使是在整个湖泊区域，甚至在整个湖泊区域，因此危险的潜力也在整体上增长。这一违反直觉的发现反映了不断增长的GLOF幅度的局限性，例如湖泊和父冰川的解耦，宽阔，低梯度的出口或人类管理的发展。在所有地区，前湖泊区域都取决于几个冰堵塞的湖泊，这些湖泊的报道爆发爆发的爆发量是冰龙和基岩塞的湖泊的十倍。后两种水坝类型将继续扣留大量的融合水，从而考虑了大多数整体GLOF危害潜力，而冰烧的湖泊将随着脱水而缩小。由于这些湖泊类型在二十一世纪将有所不同，因此鉴于关键基础设施的暴露越来越大，我们呼吁对GLOF流出和影响进行定制模拟。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glacier lake outburst floods (GLOFs) may originate from larger lakes as these continue to grow with ongoing glacier retreat; however, this perception remains poorly supported in available GLOF databases. Here we mapped the areas of 1,686 glacier lakes, just before they drained, across 13 glaciated mountain regions outside polar regions and examined the trends in pre-GLOF lake areas between 1990 and 2023. We found that pre-GLOF lake areas barely changed, or even decreased, regionally through time, even as the total lake area, and thus hazard potential, grew overall. This counterintuitive finding reflects limits to growing GLOF magnitudes, such as the decoupling of lakes and parent glaciers, the development of wide, low-gradient outlets or human management. Across all regions, pre-GLOF lake areas depend on a few ice-dammed lakes, which have produced ten times more reported outbursts and ten times larger outbursts than moraine- and bedrock-dammed lakes. The latter two dam types will continue to impound growing amounts of meltwater, thereby accounting for most of the overall GLOF hazard potential, while ice-dammed lakes will shrink with deglaciation. As these lake types will evolve differently in the twenty-first century, we call for customized simulations of GLOF outflows and impacts, given the growing exposure of critical infrastructure.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00388-w/MediaObjects/44221_2025_388_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature | 从2000年到2023年的全球冰川质量变化的社区估计</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08545-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Community estimate of global glacier mass changes from 2000 to 2023&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; The GlaMBIE Team&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;冰川是正在进行的人为气候变化的指标&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; 。它们的融化导致当地的地球扎下&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ，影响海洋&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;和陆地&lt;sup&gt;4,5&lt;/sup&gt;生态系统，区域淡水资源&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;以及全球水和能源周期&lt;sup&gt;7,8&lt;/sup&gt; 。与格陵兰和南极冰盖一起，冰川是当前&lt;sup&gt;9,10&lt;/sup&gt;和未来&lt;sup&gt;11,12,13&lt;/sup&gt;海平面上升的必不可少的驱动因素。对全球冰川质量变化的先前评估受到空间和时间限制以及现有数据系列&lt;sup&gt;14,15,16&lt;/sup&gt;的异质性的阻碍。在这里，我们在比对练习中表明，从2000年到2023年，全球冰川每年在全球群体中损失273±16 Gigatonnes，从第一次（2000- 2011年）到第二个（2012-201-201-2023），增加了36±10％时期。自2000年以来，冰川在区域上损失了2％至39％，全球约5％。冰川质量损失比格陵兰冰盖的损失大约18％，是南极冰盖&lt;sup&gt;17&lt;/sup&gt;的两倍以上。我们的结果源于科学社区的努力，以收集，同质化，结合和分析冰川质量的变化，从原位和遥感观察结果发生了变化。尽管我们的估计值与以前评估的发现一致&lt;sup&gt;14,15,16&lt;/sup&gt;在全球范围内，但由于观察方法之间的系统差异，我们发现了一些较大的区域偏差。我们的结果为更好地理解观察差异和校准模型合奏&lt;sup&gt;12,16,18&lt;/sup&gt;提供了精致的基准，这将有助于缩小二十一世纪&lt;sup&gt;11,12,18&lt;/sup&gt;的投影不确定性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glaciers are indicators of ongoing anthropogenic climate change&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;. Their melting leads to increased local geohazards&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, and impacts marine&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; and terrestrial&lt;sup&gt;4,5&lt;/sup&gt; ecosystems, regional freshwater resources&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;, and both global water and energy cycles&lt;sup&gt;7,8&lt;/sup&gt;. Together with the Greenland and Antarctic ice sheets, glaciers are essential drivers of present&lt;sup&gt;9,10&lt;/sup&gt; and future&lt;sup&gt;11,12,13&lt;/sup&gt; sea-level rise. Previous assessments of global glacier mass changes have been hampered by spatial and temporal limitations and the heterogeneity of existing data series&lt;sup&gt;14,15,16&lt;/sup&gt;. Here we show in an intercomparison exercise that glaciers worldwide lost 273 ± 16 gigatonnes in mass annually from 2000 to 2023, with an increase of 36 ± 10% from the first (2000–2011) to the second (2012–2023) half of the period. Since 2000, glaciers have lost between 2% and 39% of their ice regionally and about 5% globally. Glacier mass loss is about 18% larger than the loss from the Greenland Ice Sheet and more than twice that from the Antarctic Ice Sheet&lt;sup&gt;17&lt;/sup&gt;. Our results arise from a scientific community effort to collect, homogenize, combine and analyse glacier mass changes from in situ and remote-sensing observations. Although our estimates are in agreement with findings from previous assessments&lt;sup&gt;14,15,16&lt;/sup&gt; at a global scale, we found some large regional deviations owing to systematic differences among observation methods. Our results provide a refined baseline for better understanding observational differences and for calibrating model ensembles&lt;sup&gt;12,16,18&lt;/sup&gt;, which will help to narrow projection uncertainty for the twenty-first century&lt;sup&gt;11,12,18&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-024-08545-z/MediaObjects/41586_2024_8545_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | UAS水文测定法：非接触式水位，测深和流速 - RӧNneRiver Dataset</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04611-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;UAS hydrometry: contactless river water level, bathymetry, and flow velocity – the Rӧnne river dataset&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zhen Zhou; Laura Riis-Klinkvort; Emilie Ahrnkiel Jørgensen; Daniel Haugård Olesen; Alexander Rietz Vesterhauge; Monica Coppo Frías; Makar Lavish; Sune Nielsen; David Gustafsson; Daniel Wennerberg; Jenny Axén; Viktor Fagerstrӧm; Peter Bauer-Gottwein&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;对河流的高分辨率监测变得很重要，因为由于气候变化，预计将来会发生更频繁和严重的洪水和干旱事件。一些关键的水文变量（水面高程，测深量和水面速度）可以在高空间分辨率和使用无接触式的空中空中系统（UAS）的情况下以无接触式和非侵入性的方式获取。本文提出了一个大型公开的UAS水文数据集，该数据集于8月28日至2023年8月28日至8月1日在瑞典的RönneÅ延伸10公里内进行了调查。使用UAS Radar Altimetry用于水面高程图，UAS水面雷达和UAS Sonar radar和UAS Sonar进行了数据用于测深的映射，以及用于表面速度监测的UAS多普勒雷达。所有数据均分为三个处理级别：原始数据（级别1），处理点数据（级别2）以及引用参考河中心线/参考横截面线（第3级）的点数据。现场地面真相和传统UAS湿度测量负载数据包括用于比较和验证。良好的一致性表明，新的UAS水文有效载荷提供令人满意的数据集。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;High-resolution monitoring of rivers becomes important because more frequent and severe flooding and drought events are expected in the future, caused by climate change. Some key hydrometric variables (water surface elevation, bathymetry, and water surface velocity) can be acquired at high spatial resolution and in a contactless and noninvasive way using Unoccupied Aerial Systems (UAS). This paper presents a large publicly available UAS hydrometric dataset surveyed within a 10 km stretch of Rönne Å in Sweden from 28 August to 1 September 2023. The data were acquired using UAS radar altimetry for water surface elevation mapping, UAS water penetrating radar and UAS sonar for bathymetric mapping, and UAS Doppler radar for surface velocity monitoring. All data are divided into three processing levels: the raw data (Level 1), processed point data (Level 2), and point data referenced to a reference river centerline/reference cross section line (Level 3). In-situ ground truth and legacy UAS hydrometry payload data are included for comparison and validation. Good consistency indicates that the new UAS hydrometry payloads provide satisfactory datasets.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04611-x/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4611_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 全球未来的干旱层基于缩小的CMIP6模型和多种社会经济途径</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04612-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Global Future Drought Layers Based on Downscaled CMIP6 Models and Multiple Socioeconomic Pathways&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Diogo S. A. Araujo; Brian J. Enquist; Amy E. Frazier; Cory Merow; Patrick R. Roehrdanz; Gabriel M. Moulatlet; Alex Zvoleff; Lei Song; Brian Maitner; Efthymios I. Nikolopoulos&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;干旱是一种日益关注的自然危害，因为预计世界许多地区的频率和严重程度会增加。对干旱及其未来特征的识别对于建立对潜在干旱变化轨迹的地理和幅度的理解至关重要，这反过来又是管理多个部门和学科的干旱韧性的关键信息。除此之外，我们开发了一个数据集，其中包括1980  -  2100年期间的全球历史和预计未来的干旱指数，基于多个共享社会经济途径（SSP）的缩写的CMIP6模型。该数据集由两个指数组成：标准化降水指数（SPI）和标准降水蒸发指数（SPEI）（SPEI），用于23个缩小的全球气候模型（GCMS）（0.25度分辨率）（包括历史分辨率），包括历史（1980- 2014年）和未来的预测（未来的预测（ 2015–2100）在四种气候方案下：SSP1-2.6，SSP2-4.5， SSP3-7.0和SSP5-8.5。计算出3个，6个月和12个月的累积时间标准的干旱指数，并以每月时间分辨率以常规的纬度长度格式作为网格空间数据集使用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Droughts are a natural hazard of growing concern as they are projected to increase in frequency and severity for many regions of the world. The identification of droughts and their future characteristics is essential to building an understanding of the geography and magnitude of potential drought change trajectories, which in turn is critical information to manage drought resilience across multiple sectors and disciplines. Adding to this effort, we developed a dataset of global historical and projected future drought indices over the 1980–2100 period based on downscaled CMIP6 models across multiple shared socioeconomic pathways (SSP). The dataset is composed of two indices: the Standardized Precipitation Index (SPI) and Standardized Precipitation Evapotranspiration Index (SPEI) for 23 downscaled global climate models (GCMs) (0.25-degree resolution), including historical (1980–2014) and future projections (2015–2100) under four climate scenarios: SSP1-2.6, SSP2-4.5, SSP3-7.0, and SSP5-8.5. The drought indices were calculated for 3-, 6- and 12-month accumulation timescales and are available as gridded spatial datasets in a regular latitude-longitude format at monthly time resolution.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04612-w/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4612_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature | 回复：大西洋干旱不会威胁亚洲水塔</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08358-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Reply to: Atlantic oceanic droughts do not threaten Asian water tower&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Qiang Zhang; Zexi Shen; Yadu Pokhrel; Daniel Farinotti; Vijay P. Singh; Chong-Yu Xu; Wenhuan Wu; Gang Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文没有摘要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This article has no abstract.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-024-08358-0/MediaObjects/41586_2024_8358_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 一个用于监测欧洲农业干旱的数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-024-04199-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A dataset for monitoring agricultural drought in Europe&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Guido Fioravanti; Andrea Toreti; Carmelo Cammalleri; Carolina Arias Muñoz; Davide Bavera; Alfred De Jager; Arthur Hrast Essenfelder; Chiara Di Ciollo; Dario Masante; Diego Magni; Juan Acosta Navarro; Marco Mazzesch; Willem Maetens&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文介绍了合并的干旱指标数据集，这是欧洲欧洲干旱天文台生成的栅格地图集合，用于监测欧洲的农业干旱。在计算上，CDI涉及三个指标：标准化降水指数，土壤水分异常和光合有效辐射异常的比例。这些用作物和雪面剂补充。 CDI数据集的空间分辨率为1/24个十进制度（约5 km），时间分辨率为10天，从2012年开始就可以使用。随着干旱影响在时空上的变化，CDI提供了一种有效的工具，可以评估农业干旱及其空间范围的不同阶段。此外，CDI地图为那些私人和公共参与者（水资源机构，农民，土地管理者等）提供了相关信息，既准备干旱，又计划减轻干旱影响。用户可以从哥白尼欧洲干旱天文台网站门户访问和下载数据集，在线MapViewer和可单击的地图可促进其交互式探索。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This paper introduces the Combined Drought Indicator dataset, a collection of raster maps generated by the Copernicus European Drought Observatory for monitoring agricultural drought in Europe. Computationally, the CDI involves three indicators: the Standardized Precipitation Index, the Soil Moisture Anomaly and the Fraction of the Photosyntetically Active Radiation anomaly. These are complemented by the use of crop and snow masks. The CDI dataset has a spatial resolution of 1/24 decimal degrees (∼5 km), a temporal resolution of 10 days and is available from 2012 onward. As drought effects are variegated both in space and time, the CDI provides an effective instrument for assessing the different stages of propagation of agricultural drought and their spatial extent. Furthermore, the CDI maps provide relevant information for those private and public actors (water resource agencies, farmers, land managers and so on) involved both in drought preparedness and planning to mitigate drought impacts. Users can access and download the dataset from the Copernicus European Drought Observatory web portal, where an online mapviewer and clickable maps facilitate its interactive exploration.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-024-04199-8/MediaObjects/41597_2024_4199_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>