<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 02:29:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 在阿拉伯海中加强热带气旋补充耗尽的含水层</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02493-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Intensifying tropical cyclones in the Arabian Sea replenish depleting aquifers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hassan Saleh; Mohamed Sultan; Eugene Yan; Himanshu Save; Hesham Elhaddad; Hadi Karimi; Karem Abdelmohsen; Mustafa K. Emil; Sara Al Qamshouai&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;近几十年来，热带气旋在全球范围内加剧，在内陆更深的内陆降水。尽管许多研究集中在气候变化在热带气旋强化中的作用，但对它们对地下水充电的贡献的了解却少，尤其是在淡水稀缺且含水剂的干旱地区。在这里，我们使用基于卫星的总水存储和流体动力建模来量化2002年至2021年从阿拉伯半岛跨越旋风驱动的地下水充电。研究结果表明，旋风在阿拉伯南部半岛的总降水量占60％。 Cyclone Mekunu（2018）仅提供30 &lt;sup&gt;km&lt;/sup&gt;的内陆降水量，导致NAJD subbasin的净地下水补给3.2±1.2 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; 。这些发现表明，热带气旋在补充干旱地区的地下水中起着至关重要的作用。我们的方法提供了一个框架，可在全球范围内量化未加州干旱盆地的充值，为气候硫化的水资源管理提供了宝贵的见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tropical cyclones intensified globally in recent decades, delivering extreme precipitation deeper inland. While much research has focused on the role of climate change in tropical cyclone intensification, less is known about their contribution to groundwater recharge, especially in arid regions where freshwater is scarce and aquifers are being depleted. Here we quantify cyclone-driven groundwater recharge across the Arabian Peninsula from 2002 to 2021 using satellite-based total water storage and hydrodynamic modeling. Findings show that cyclones contributed up to 60% of total precipitation in the southern Arabian Peninsula. Cyclone Mekunu (2018) alone delivered 30 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; of precipitation inland, resulting in a net groundwater recharge of 3.2 ± 1.2 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; in the Najd subbasin. These findings reveal that tropical cyclones play a crucial role in replenishing groundwater resources in arid regions. Our approach provides a framework for quantifying recharge in ungauged arid basins worldwide, offering valuable insights for climate-resilient water resource management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02493-w/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2493_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>