<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 02:09:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 印度的基于车站的0.1度每日网格集合降水数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04474-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A station-based 0.1-degree daily gridded ensemble precipitation dataset for India&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Anagha Peringiyil; Manabendra Saharia; Sreejith O. P.; Andrew W. Wood; Mrutyunjay Mohapatra; Bharti Sabde; Aradhana Kumari; Bhushan Phadkar; Sabeerali C. T.; Rohini P.; Hosalikar K. S.; M. Rajeevan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;网格降水产物本质上是不确定的，主要是确定性的，这限制了其在数据同化系统和水文建模中的适用性。在印度等发展中国家，观察网络稀疏且不均匀，地形很复杂，并且氢气学极端频繁。目前的0.25°官方观察到的印度气象部（IMD）的降水数据集是确定性的，并且基于Shephard的插值技术。为了应对这些挑战，我们开发了印度降水集合数据集（IPED），利用印度各地最大的降水量表网络网络，并使用当地加权的空间回归方法。 IPED是每日30人的集合沉淀产品，分辨率为0.1°，分辨率为0.25°（1991– 2020），占高度，斜率和方面的地形变化。对于包括季风期间极端99 &lt;sup&gt;％&lt;/sup&gt;降水的所有阈值，开发的集合产品均表现出更高的歧视和可靠性。这是印度上第一个基于观察的集合降水产品，预计将具有广泛的水文学应用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Gridded precipitation products are inherently uncertain and predominantly deterministic, which limits their applicability in data assimilation systems and hydrologic modeling. This limitation is significant in developing countries such as India, where the observation network is sparse and non-uniform, topography is complex, and hydrometeorological extremes are frequent. The current official 0.25° observed precipitation dataset of the Indian Meteorological Department (IMD) is deterministic and based on Shephard’s interpolation technique. To address these challenges, we have developed the Indian Precipitation Ensemble Dataset (IPED) leveraging the largest network of precipitation gauge stations across India and using a locally weighted spatial regression approach. IPED is a daily 30-member ensemble precipitation product available at 0.1° and 0.25° resolution (1991–2020), accounting for topographical variation in elevation, slope, and aspect. For all thresholds, including the extreme 99&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile precipitation during monsoon, the developed ensemble product exhibits higher discrimination and reliability. This is the first observation-based ensemble precipitation product over India and is expected to have widespread hydrometeorological applications.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-91011-1/MediaObjects/41598_2025_91011_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 十年（2012-2021）的精细分辨率（每小时1公里）降水数据集越过东南藏族高原</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04654-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A ten-year (2012–2021) fine-resolution (1 km, hourly) precipitation dataset over southeastern Tibetan Plateau&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Dayang Li; Ye Shen; Xianyi Ye; Xiaohua Fu; Yang Yang; Tinghai Ou; Deliang Chen; Fuqiang Tian; Long Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;藏族高原（TP）上强烈的下天降水会触发一系列自然灾害（山洪，碎屑流等），从而造成重大的环境影响。 TP的当前降水产物通常缺乏足够的空间或时间分辨率，阻碍了与降水有关的危害的准确表征和缓解。在这里，我们根据天气研究和预测（WRF）模型在TP上进行了10年（2012-2021，6月至9月）的对流模型模型。我们采用了四个单向嵌套域，最内向的域在东南TP上提供了1公里的小时分辨率。使用光谱纽约方案增强了模型性能。将我们的模拟降水数据与东南TP上的原地雨量计观测值和最先进的降水产物（即，HAR V2，ERA5-LAND和IMERG）进行了比较。与其他三种产品相比，我们的沉淀数据集在平均绝对误差，均方根误差和偏置方面表现出较高的精度。它有效地捕获了昼夜降水循环的关键特征以及降水对东南TP上复杂地形的非单调依赖性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Intense sub-daily precipitation on the Tibetan Plateau (TP) can trigger a cascade of natural hazards (flash floods, debris flows, etc.), causing significant environmental impacts. Current precipitation products for the TP often lack sufficient spatial or temporal resolution, hindering accurate characterization and mitigation of precipitation-related hazards. Here, we carry out 10-year (2012–2021, June to September) convection-permitting model simulations based on the Weather Research and Forecasting (WRF) model over the TP. We adopt four one-way nested domains, with the innermost domain providing a 1-km, hourly resolution over the southeastern TP. Model performance is enhanced using a spectral nudging scheme. Our simulated precipitation data are compared against in-situ rain gauge observations and state-of-the-art gridded precipitation products (i.e., HAR v2, ERA5-Land, and IMERG) over the  southeastern TP. Our precipitation dataset demonstrates superior accuracy in mean absolute error, root mean square error, and bias, compared to the other three products. It effectively captures the key feature of the diurnal precipitation cycle and the non-monotonic dependence of precipitation on complex topography over the southeastern TP.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44304-025-00076-5/MediaObjects/44304_2025_76_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature | 流量随着降雪的下降而变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08523-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Streamflow shifts with declining snowfall&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Wouter R. Berghuijs; Kate Hale&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文没有摘要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This article has no abstract.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-024-80100-2/MediaObjects/41598_2024_80100_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature | 回复：流降雪随着降雪而下降</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08524-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Reply to: Streamflow shifts with declining snowfall&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Juntai Han; Ziwei Liu; Yuting Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文没有摘要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This article has no abstract.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-024-08523-5/MediaObjects/41586_2024_8523_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 极端干旱的波动事件威胁着长江生态系统中水生浮游生物社区的生物多样性和稳定性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02143-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Extreme drought-heatwave events threaten the biodiversity and stability of aquatic plankton communities in the Yangtze River ecosystems&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jixuan Lyu; Yong Shi; Tao Liu; Xiaomei Xu; Shengjing Liu; Guang Yang; Dong Peng; Yubing Qu; Shuo Zhang; Chonghao Chen; Yanxu Zhang; Jianhua Gao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流对生物地球化学周期至关重要，连接陆地，海洋和大气系统。但是，他们的生态系统越来越受到极端天气事件的威胁。在这里，我们使用了环境DNA方法来评估极端干旱的事件对长江河水群社区的影响。我们表明，极端干旱的事件减少了社区的α多样性，增加了其β多样性，并同时简化了不稳定的社区网络结构。该事件还将主要的藻类分类单元从芽孢杆菌转移到蓝细菌，并伴随着有机碳和不稳定有机碳含量的增加。在全球范围内，在高纬度地区，在极端干旱的波动事件中，温度升高更为明显，可能会增加对河流生态系统生物多样性和稳定性的影响。我们的发现突出了河流生态系统对极端事件的脆弱性，并强调了减轻气候变化对河流生态系统的影响的必要性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Rivers are crucial to biogeochemical cycles, connecting terrestrial, oceanic, and atmospheric systems. However, their ecosystems are increasingly threatened by extreme weather events. Here we used the environmental DNA approach to assess the impact of extreme drought-heatwave events on the aquatic plankton communities of the Yangtze River. We showed that an extreme drought-heatwave event reduced the α diversity of communities, increased their β diversity, and simultaneously simplified and destabilized community network structure. This event also shifted the dominant algae taxa from Bacillariophyta to Cyanobacteria, accompanied by increases in organic carbon and labile organic carbon contents. Globally, temperature rises during this extreme drought-heatwave event are more pronounced in high-latitude regions, likely amplifying impacts on river ecosystem biodiversity and stability. Our findings highlight the vulnerability of river ecosystems to extreme events and underscore the need to mitigate climate change’s effects on river ecosystems.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02143-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2143_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 30年（1991-2021）意大利PO河区的雪水量数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04633-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;30-years (1991-2021) Snow Water Equivalent Dataset in the Po River District, Italy&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Matteo Dall’Amico; Stefano Tasin; Federico Di Paolo; Marco Brian; Paolo Leoni; Francesco Tornatore; Giuseppe Formetta; John Mohd Wani; Riccardo Rigon; Gaia Roati&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文介绍了意大利PO河区的长期雪水同等数据集，该数据集跨越1991年至2021年，每天的时间步骤和500 m的空间分辨率部分覆盖了阿尔卑斯山和阿彭宁的山脉。该数据是使用混合建模方法生成的，该方法将与基于物理的Geotop模型进行的水文建模，对气象数据的预处理以及对原位雪测量值和地球观测雪产物的同化，以提高模型估计的质量。基于可靠性，质量和领土分布选择的不同控制点，对数据集进行了严格的质量评估。整个控制点模拟和观察到的积雪之间的点验证表明，数据集分别模拟正常和相对较高的积雪条件的准确性。此外，将卫星雪地图与模拟的积雪深度图进行了比较，这是高程和方面的函数。 2D验证显示了随时间和空间的准确值，该值以沿着基本方向的雪线表示。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This paper presents a long-term snow water equivalent dataset in the Po River District, Italy, spanning from 1991 to 2021 at daily time step and 500 m spatial resolution partially covering the mountain ranges of Alps and Apennines. The data has been generated using a hybrid modelling approach integrating the hydrological modelling conducted with the physically-based GEOtop model, preprocessing of the meteorological data, and assimilation of in-situ snow measurements and Earth Observation snow products to enhance the quality of the model estimates. A rigorous quality assessment of the dataset has been performed at different control points selected based on reliability, quality, and territorial distribution. The point validation between simulated and observed snow depth across control points shows the accuracy of the dataset in simulating the normal and relatively high snow conditions, respectively. Additionally, satellite snow cover maps have been compared with simulated snow depth maps, as a function of elevation and aspect. 2D Validation shows accurate values over time and space, expressed in terms of snowline along the cardinal directions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04633-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4633_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature | 亚马逊森林砍伐对季节之间降水逆转的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08570-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Impact of Amazonian deforestation on precipitation reverses between seasons&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yingzuo Qin; Dashan Wang; Alan D. Ziegler; Bojie Fu; Zhenzhong Zeng&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;发现，使用一系列基于观测的数据集&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; ，发现热带森林砍伐会导致降水量大量减少。但是，基于卫星的空间统计分析的局限性阻碍了人们对重塑中尺度大气环流和区域降水回收在不同尺度上的作用的理解。这些作用被认为是非局部效应，这些作用与森林砍伐引起的蒸散量减少（ET）的局部效应不同。在这里，我们显示了整个潮湿和干旱季节对亚马逊森林砍伐的降水反应。在潮湿的季节，森林砍伐的网格值得注意的是降水量增加（0.96 mm月&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;个每百分比森林损失），主要归因于中尺度大气循环的增强（即非局部效应）。这些非局部性随着距离森林砍伐的网格的距离而增加，导致60公里以上的缓冲液的降水量显着减少。相反，在干旱季节，降水量减少，在所有分析缓冲液中都会减少，并且局部效果减少了ET的主导作用。我们的发现突出了局部效应与非局部效应之间的复杂平衡，以推动不同季节和尺度的森林砍伐 - 预测反应，并强调迫切需要解决亚马逊地区森林的快速而广泛的损失。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tropical deforestation was found to cause large reductions in precipitation using a range of observation-based datasets&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;. However, the limitations of satellite-based space-for-time statistical analysis have hindered understanding of the roles of reshaped mesoscale atmospheric circulation and regional precipitation recycling at different scales. These effects are considered nonlocal effects, which are distinct from the local effects governed by deforestation-induced reductions in evapotranspiration (ET). Here we show reversed precipitation responses to Amazon deforestation across wet and dry seasons. During the wet season, deforested grids experienced a noteworthy increase in precipitation (0.96 mm month&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; per percentage point forest loss), primarily attributed to enhanced mesoscale atmospheric circulation (that is, nonlocal effect). These nonlocal increases weaken with distance from deforested grids, leading to significant precipitation reductions in buffers beyond 60 km. Conversely, during the dry season, precipitation decreases in deforested grids and throughout all analysis buffers, with local effects from reduced ET dominating. Our findings highlight the intricate balance between local effects and nonlocal effects in driving deforestation–precipitation responses across different seasons and scales and emphasize the urgent need to address the rapid and extensive loss of forest in the Amazon region.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-024-08570-y/MediaObjects/41586_2024_8570_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 离散断裂网络建模重建裂缝阵列的演化和相关的岩石物理特性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02146-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Discrete fracture network modelling reconstructs fracture array evolution and related petrophysical properties over geological time&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Matthew S. Hodge; Mark Cottrell; Jochen Knies; Giulio Viola&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;破裂的岩石物理研究很少使用时间限制，从而阻碍了与骨折相关的渗透性和过去地理流体迁移期间的连通性估计。在这里，我们提出了一种概念方法，使用一种随机方法，该方法结合了绝对年龄，以重建地质时期的断裂阵列。生成“成年”离散裂缝网络模型，我们通过渐进的裂缝后折射模拟了从晚白垩纪/古代到泥盆纪的断裂岩量的液压行为。我们透露，对于所检查的岩体，最大主渗透率从9.47e-14 m &lt;sup&gt;2 2&lt;/sup&gt;增加到4.44e-13 m &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; （〜3个数量级），以及最大的水平渗透率方向从NEE-SW转移到NW-SE。同样，连通性度量随断裂饱和度增加，在白垩纪中部峰值。为了进行比较，日期的海上烃二次迁移可能与我们的结果相吻合。因此，对时间约束的裂缝集的后置是一种强大的方法，可以通过地质时代研究和量化岩石物理特性的动态演化。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Fractured rock petrophysical studies rarely use temporal constraints, thus hindering fracture-related permeability and connectivity estimation during past geofluid migration. Here we present a conceptual approach, using a stochastic method incorporating absolute ages to reconstruct fracture arrays back in geological time. Generating ‘grown’ discrete fracture network models, we simulate the hydraulic behaviour of fractured rock volumes from the late-Cretaceous/Palaeocene to the Devonian, via progressive fracture back-stripping. We reveal that for the examined rock mass, maximum principal permeability increased through time from 9.47e-14 m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; to 4.44e-13 m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; (~3 orders of magnitude) along with the maximum horizontal permeability orientation shifting from NE-SW to NW-SE. Similarly, the connectivity metric increased with fracture saturation, peaking in the mid-Cretaceous. For comparison, dated offshore hydrocarbon secondary migration potentially coincides with our results. Back-stripping of time-constrained fracture sets is therefore a powerful method to investigate and quantify the dynamic evolution of petrophysical properties through geological time.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02146-y/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2146_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 带注释的数据集和基准测试，用于检测内陆水域的浮动碎片</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04594-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;An annotated Dataset and Benchmark for Detecting Floating Debris in Inland Waters&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Guangchao Qiao; Mingxiang Yang; Hao Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;海洋垃圾是对海洋生态系统的严重威胁，及时清除内陆水域的浮动废物可有效防止漂浮的碎片进入大海。准确的对象检测系统是有效清除浮子的先决条件。但是，水中的复杂光条件，小尺寸的物体和其他因素对浮动物体检测构成了巨大挑战。为了促进浮动物体污染问题的解决方案，并促进了AI技术在水行业中的应用，我们提出了基于基于海岸的拍摄设备的iWHR_AI_LABLE_FLOATER_V1从真实水景中收集的第一个浮点数据集。该数据集由3000张图像组成，其中包含准确的注释信息，以支持基于视觉的水面浮点检测任务。我们进行了许多基线实验，以评估该数据集主流对象检测算法的性能。结果表明，包括最先进的模型Yolov9在内的模型的检测准确性都很低，这也表明浮动对象检测是一项具有挑战性的任务。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Marine litter is a serious threat to marine ecosystems, and the timely removal of floating waste from inland waters is effective in preventing floating debris from entering the sea. An accurate object detection system is a prerequisite for efficiently clearing floaters. However, complex light conditions in the water, small size objects and other factors pose a huge challenge for floating object detection. In order to facilitate the solution of the floating object pollution problem and promote the application of AI technology in the water industry, we proposed the first floater dataset of waters collected from real water scenarios based on shore-based filming equipment, IWHR_AI_Lable_Floater_V1. The dataset consists of 3000 images containing accurate annotation information to support vision-based water surface floater detection tasks. We conducted a number of baseline experiments to evaluate the performance of mainstream object detection algorithms on this dataset. The results show that the detection accuracies of the models, including the state-of-the-art model YOLOv9, are all low, which also indicates that floating object detection is a challenging task.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04594-9/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4594_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 干旱指数对历史土地使用和土地覆盖变化的不同反应</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00978-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Divergent response of aridity index to historical land use and land cover change&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Tao Tang; Jun Ge; Haiyun Shi; Junji Cao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;通过使用模型模拟，我们显示自1850年以来的历史土地使用和土地覆盖变化影响了全球的干旱指数（AI），从而在不同地区引起了不同的反应。在本地，AI倾向于在造林区域和大多数潮湿区域中增加（潮湿）。由于这些变化，潮湿区域的面积不足以占全球土地面积的0.22％，牺牲了旱地。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;By using model simulations, we show that historical land use and land cover change since 1850 has impacted aridity index (AI) worldwide, causing divergent responses in different regions. Locally, AI tends to increase (getting humid) in reforestation regions and most humid regions. Owing to these changes, the area of the humid zone expanded insignificantly by 0.22% of the global land area at the expense of drylands.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00978-1/MediaObjects/41612_2025_978_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>