<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 12:50:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 考虑作物和地区之间的差异可以减少对氮肥土壤中硝酸盐淋失的估计</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02001-0</link><description>Yan Wang; Yihong Liu; Longlong Xia; Hiroko Akiyama; Xinli Chen; Ji Chen; Yunying Fang; Tony Vancov; Yongfu Li; YuanZhi Yao; Dianming Wu; Bing Yu; Scott X. Chang; Yanjiang Cai&lt;br/&gt;施氮 (N) 肥料的土壤中的硝酸盐 (NO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; ) 浸出是全球关注的重大问题，影响环境和公众健康。然而，不同地区或作物的 NO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;淋滤因子 (LF) 存在很大的不确定性和变异性，这阻碍了对 NO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;淋滤的准确评估。在这里，我们综合了全球 2500 个实地观测结果，表明不同地区和作物的 LF 有一个数量级的差异，主要是由水文气候和土壤条件驱动，而不是氮肥管理。通过空间明确的 (15.4, 14.8–16.1 Tg N yr &lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt; ) 和特定作物 (12.9, 11.0–14.8 Tg N yr &lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt; ) LF 计算的全球农田 NO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt;合成氮肥淋失量比 41% 低政府间气候变化专门委员会一级全球清单。超过47%的浸出量集中在中国、印度和美国，其中玉米、小麦、稻米和蔬菜占其中近一半。改进的区域和特定作物的 LF 将通过查明潜在的全球热点为 NO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;浸出减排提供基准。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;原文:&lt;br/&gt;Nitrate (NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt;) leaching from nitrogen (N) fertilized soils is a significant global concern, affecting both the environment and public health. However, substantial uncertainties and variabilities in NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; leaching factors (LFs) among regions or crops impede accurate assessments of NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; leaching. Here we synthesize 2500 field observations worldwide and show that LFs vary by an order of magnitude across regions and crops, primarily driven by hydroclimatic and edaphic conditions rather than N fertilizer management. Global cropland NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; leaching from synthetic N fertilization, calculated through spatially explicit (15.4, 14.8–16.1 Tg N yr&lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt;) and crop-specific (12.9, 11.0–14.8 Tg N yr&lt;sup&gt;–1&lt;/sup&gt;) LFs, is 41% lower than the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change Tier 1 global inventory. Over 47% of this leaching is concentrated in China, India, and the United States, with maize, wheat, rice and vegetables accounting for nearly half of it. Improved regional and crop-specific LFs will provide a benchmark for NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;−&lt;/sup&gt; leaching abatement by pinpointing potential global hotspots.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02001-0/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2001_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 初级生产力对加速干旱更加敏感</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02013-w</link><description>Yangyang Jing; Shuo Wang; Pak Wai Chan; Zong-Liang Yang&lt;br/&gt;突发干旱的特点是发生迅速，严重影响陆地生态系统。然而，人们对不同植被条件下生态系统生产力对突发干旱快速发展的敏感性仍知之甚少。在这里，我们考虑了根区土壤水分的下降率和标准化总初级生产力异常，研究了不同植物功能类型的生态系统对突发干旱发生速度的响应。我们的研究结果显示，2001 年至 2018 年期间，导致标准化总初级生产力负异常的 1 候和 2 候（5 天和 10 天）突发突发干旱的比例显着增加了约 10%。此外，虽然标准化总初级生产力异常下降速度较高，但与发生较慢的突发干旱相比，它们不能在更短的时间内对发生较快的突发干旱做出迅速反应。根系较浅的植被类型对快速发生的突发干旱表现出更高的敏感性，这表明气候变化对陆地生态系统的威胁不断升级。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;原文:&lt;br/&gt;Flash droughts, characterized by their rapid onset, substantially affect terrestrial ecosystems. However, the sensitivity of ecosystem productivity to the rapid development of flash droughts under varying vegetation conditions remains poorly understood. Here we investigate the ecosystem response to the speed of flash drought onset for different plant functional types, considering the decline rate of root-zone soil moisture and standardized gross primary productivity anomaly. Our findings reveal a significant increase of approximately 10% in the proportion of 1- and 2-pentad (5 and 10 days) onset flash droughts leading to negative standardized gross primary productivity anomalies during 2001–2018. Furthermore, while standardized gross primary productivity anomalies decline at higher rates, they do not promptly respond on a shorter timescale to faster-onset flash droughts compared to slower-onset flash droughts. Vegetation types with shallower root systems exhibit higher sensitivities to faster-onset flash droughts, suggesting an escalating threat to terrestrial ecosystems in a changing climate.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02013-w/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2013_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 抵消温室气体和气溶胶的影响加剧了过去一个世纪的全球水季节性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02025-6</link><description>Fubo Zhao; Wenbo Shi; Yiping Wu; Yanqing Lian; Qiang Li&lt;br/&gt;水资源供应季节性的变化对社会和生态系统产生重大影响。虽然许多研究都集中在平均或极端降水量上，但水供应季节性对人类引起的气候变化的影响仍然没有得到充分探索，这种季节性影响超出了个别极端情况下的年度水分布。在这里，我们研究了 1915 年至 2014 年全球和区域可用水量的季节性变化，利用耦合模型比对项目第 6 阶段的重新分析和模拟，量化人为温室气体和气溶胶如何影响这些变化。尽管由于区域变异性和模型假设而存在很大的时空不确定性，我们发现温室气体显着放大了季节性，而气溶胶则减少了季节性。鉴于温室气体的积极影响超过了气溶胶的消极影响，其平衡影响导致过去一个世纪水资源供应季节性的整体增强。随着温室气体引起的变暖持续上升和气溶胶水平下降，预计这种趋势未来将持续下去。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;原文:&lt;br/&gt;Variations in water availability seasonality significantly impact society and ecosystems. While many studies have focused on mean or extreme precipitation, the response of water availability seasonality, influencing yearly water distribution beyond individual extremes, to human-induced climate change remains underexplored. Here we examine global and regional water availability seasonality changes from 1915 to 2014, quantifying how anthropogenic greenhouse gases and aerosols have influenced these variations using reanalysis and simulations from Coupled Model Intercomparison Project Phase 6. Despite large spatiotemporal uncertainties due to regional variability and model assumptions, we find that greenhouse gases significantly amplify the seasonality, while aerosols reduce it. Given that the positive effects of greenhouse gases surpass the aerosols’ negative effects, the counterbalancing influences have led to an overall enhancement in seasonality of water availability over the past century. This trend is expected to continue in the future as greenhouse gases-induced warming continues to rise and aerosol levels decline.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02025-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2025_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>