<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 02:33:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Water | 社会脆弱地区的地表水不成比例地监测到美国南大西洋湾地区的养分</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00460-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Surface waters in socially vulnerable areas are disproportionately under-monitored for nutrients in the US South Atlantic-Gulf region&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Christopher C. Oates; Khara Grieger; Ryan Emanuel; Natalie G. Nelson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;这项研究调查了主动水质监测站是否按比例分布在不同社会脆弱性的社区中。我们特别关注对南大西洋湾地区地表水的养分监测，这是一个富含土地用途的水域，跨越了社会脆弱性谱系。我们使用了来自美国水质门户网站的2018  -  2022年数据，将车站位置与美国疾病控制社会脆弱性指数（SVI）的指标和美国地质调查局的水文图进行比较。统计分析表明，主动监测站位置的分布存在很大的失衡，在较低的脆弱性区域的监测站有更多的监测站，而在高脆弱性区域中的监测站则更少，并且模式随状态而变化。车站聚集在类似的SVI值的区域中。如果区域靠近具有不同SVI值的区域，则不太可能受到监测。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This study investigates whether active water quality monitoring stations are proportionately distributed across communities of varying social vulnerability. We specifically focus on nutrient monitoring of surface waters in the South Atlantic-Gulf region, a water-rich area with wide-ranging land uses and communities that span the social vulnerability spectrum. We used 2018–2022 data from the US Water Quality Portal to compare station locations to metrics from the US Centers for Disease Control Social Vulnerability Index (SVI) and hydrography from the US Geological Survey. Statistical analyses revealed a substantial imbalance in the distribution of active monitoring station placements, with more monitoring stations in lower vulnerability areas and fewer in high vulnerability areas, and patterns that vary by state. Stations were clustered in areas of similar SVI values; areas were less likely to be monitored if they were near tracts with differing SVI values.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00460-5/MediaObjects/44221_2025_460_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>