<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 02:20:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 在气候变化下，人类流动性扩大了沿海城市地区的复合洪水风险</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02406-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Human mobility amplifies compound flood risks in coastal urban areas under climate change&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zhi-Yong Long; Huan-Feng Duan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在气候变化下，沿海城市面临着人类流动模式的复合洪水风险的增加。在这项研究中，我们将动态种群分布模型与数值流体动力模型相结合，以检查香港九龙区域洪水风险的迁移率影响。我们在75个场景中模拟了洪水，在当前条件和2060和2100的气候预测下，在中级和非常高排放的途径下，降雨和风暴潮的回流期（50、100、200年）。我们发现，人类流动性会导致风险分布的暂时变化，而商业区的白天风险较高，而居民区面临夜间风险的增加。洪水风险随着距离海岸线的距离而降低，在工作日和周末之间显示出不同的变化。夜间风险比率显示，工作日的差异从18.7％到20.6％，周末差异很小，在未来的气候预测下加剧。这些见解为沿海城市的城市规划和洪水管理提供了信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Coastal cities face increasing compound flood risks from human mobility patterns under climate change. In this study, we integrated dynamic population distribution models with numerical hydrodynamic modelling to examine mobility effects on flood risk in Hong Kong’s Kowloon area. We simulated flooding across 75 scenarios with matching rainfall and storm surge return periods (50, 100, 200 years) under current conditions and climate projections for 2060 and 2100 under intermediate and very high emission pathways. We found human mobility causes notable temporal shifts in risk distribution, with commercial areas experiencing higher daytime risk while residential areas face increased nighttime risk. Flood risk decreases with distance from coastlines, showing distinct variations between weekdays and weekends. The Night-Day Risk Ratio reveals weekday differentials ranging from 18.7% to 20.6% with minimal weekend variations, intensifying under future climate projections. These insights inform urban planning and flood management in coastal cities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02406-x/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2406_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 将人类决策纳入水文模型，以准确估计农业政策的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02325-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Integrating human decision-making into a hydrological model to accurately estimate the impacts of agricultural policies&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Mahesh R. Tapas; Gregory Howard; Randall Etheridge; Matthew Mair; Ariane L. Peralta&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;农业是营养污染的主要因素，可驱动水生生态系统中的富营养化。这项研究将水文模型与农民行为分析整合在一起，以评估两种农业保护实践的有效性，包括农作物和氮肥的施用降低 - 减少了北卡罗来纳州塔尔 - 帕米洛河盆地田间的硝酸盐损失。来自279名农民的调查反应显示，广泛不愿采取保护措施，特别是严格的肥料减少。水文模型表明，将每种练习应用于25％的农业土地可以大大减少硝酸盐出口，覆盖作物比降低的肥料使用更有效力。然而，一种综合的社会流程模型纳入了农民的行为反应，预测由于有限的自愿采用而导致的硝酸盐损失减少了得多。具体而言，覆盖作物的硝酸盐减少被高估了8倍，当排除行为反应时，施肥的施用量为25。该结果突出了传统建模方法的关键局限性，并强调将人类决策纳入环境政策分析的重要性。通过将政策激励措施与生物物理和社会反应联系起来，本研究为设计具有成本效益和有影响力的农业保护策略提供了更现实的框架。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Agriculture is a major contributor to nutrient pollution that drives eutrophication in aquatic ecosystems. This study integrates hydrological modeling with farmer behavioral analysis to assess the effectiveness of two agricultural conservation practices—cover crops and reduced nitrogen fertilizer application—in reducing nitrate loss from fields in the Tar-Pamlico River Basin of North Carolina. Survey responses from 279 farmers revealed widespread reluctance to adopt conservation practices, particularly strict fertilizer reductions. A hydrological model showed that applying each practice to 25 percent of agricultural land could substantially reduce nitrate export, with cover crops showing greater effectiveness than reduced fertilizer use. However, an integrated socio-hydrological model, which incorporated behavioral responses from farmers, predicted much smaller reductions in nitrate loss due to limited voluntary adoption. Specifically, nitrate reductions were overestimated by a factor of 8 for cover crops and by a factor of 25 for reduced fertilizer application when behavioral responses were excluded. This result highlights a critical limitation of traditional modeling approaches and underscores the importance of integrating human decision-making into environmental policy analysis. By linking policy incentives with both biophysical and social responses, this study offers a more realistic framework for designing cost-effective and impactful agricultural conservation strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02325-x/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2325_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>