<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 02:10:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 印度洋偶极子和西太平洋亚热带的转移影响对东亚南部的年度降水量Δ18O</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01000-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Shifting influences of Indian Ocean Dipole and western Pacific subtropical high on annual precipitation δ18O in southern East Asia&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jingyi Zhang; Wusheng Yu; Lonnie G. Thompson; Stephen Lewis; Alexandre Cauquoin; Martin Werner; Zhaowei Jing; Yaoming Ma; Baiqing Xu; Guangjian Wu; Rong Guo; Pengjie Ren; Zhuanxia Zhang; Qiaoyi Wang; Dongmei Qu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;澄清降水（ &lt;sup&gt;δ18O&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;P&lt;/sub&gt; ）中稳定的氧同位素比与包括印度洋偶极子（IOD）（IOD）和西太平洋亚热带高（WPSH）在内的大气环境中的关系构成了古循环重建的基础。但是，IOD和WPSH是否调制&lt;sup&gt;δ18O&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;P&lt;/sub&gt;的年际变化尚不清楚。在这里，我们揭示了东亚南部的IOD/WPSH与年度&lt;sup&gt;δ18O&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;P&lt;/sub&gt;之间的联系。我们发现，IOD在1999年之前强烈影响了年度&lt;sup&gt;δ18O&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;P，&lt;/sub&gt;这是由于不同的传输途径和对流的水分供应的变化。然而，链接在1999年之后脱钩，这是由于iod从对称模式到不对称模式的过渡而产生的。相反，在1999年之后，对年度&lt;sup&gt;δ18o&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;P&lt;/sub&gt;的重要影响显着增强。因此，IOD和WPSH交替影响1999年左右的&lt;sup&gt;δ18o&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;P&lt;/sub&gt;的年际变化。我们的发现表明，应考虑在不同时期内考虑IOD和WPSH的信号，以更好地解释古生物学记录。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Clarifying relationships between stable oxygen isotope ratios in precipitation (δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;p&lt;/sub&gt;) and atmospheric circulations including the Indian Ocean Dipole (IOD) and western Pacific subtropical high (WPSH) forms the basis of paleocirculation reconstructions. However, whether the IOD and WPSH modulate interannual variations of δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;p&lt;/sub&gt; remains unclear. Here, we reveal the links between the IOD/WPSH and the annual δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;p&lt;/sub&gt; in southern East Asia. We found that the IOD strongly influenced annual δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;p&lt;/sub&gt; before 1999 by changes in moisture supply from different transport pathways and convection. However, the link became decoupled after 1999, resulting from the transition of the IOD from a symmetric to an asymmetric pattern. In contrast, significantly enhanced WPSH emerges as an important influence on annual δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;p&lt;/sub&gt; after 1999. Therefore, the IOD and WPSH alternately influence interannual variation of δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;p&lt;/sub&gt; around 1999. Our findings imply that signals of IOD and WPSH should be considered in different periods to better interpret paleoclimate records.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01000-4/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1000_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Climate Change | 随着气候变暖，全球农业干旱的动态可预测性降低</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-025-02289-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Decreasing dynamic predictability of global agricultural drought with warming climate&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Haijiang Wu; Xiaoling Su; Shengzhi Huang; Vijay P. Singh; Sha Zhou; Xuezhi Tan; Xiaotao Hu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;干旱在世界范围内经常发生在温暖的气候下，对水 - 食品 - 能源生态学的安全产生不利影响，这为干旱可预测性带来了重大挑战。但是，对于全球农业干旱的动态可预测性的未来变化以及造成这种变化的主要混杂因素的未来变化知之甚少。在这里，我们利用贝叶斯模型的平均模型，以合奏葡萄藤模型揭示了在三个预计的全球变暖水平的温暖季节中全球农业干旱可预测性的变化。我们发现，在+2°C和+3°C的世界中，尤其是在北美，亚马逊，欧洲，欧洲，东亚和南亚和澳大利亚的世界中，农业干旱的预计动态可预测性将大大降低全球土地地区的70％以上。这主要归因于土壤湿度记忆，背景干旱和土地 - 大气耦合的削弱。我们的发现强调，利益相关者应采用动态气候适应来应对较温暖的气候下的干旱可预测性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Droughts have been occurring frequently worldwide in a warming climate with an adverse impact on water–food–energy–ecology security, which raises substantial challenges for drought predictability. However, little is known about the future changes in dynamic predictability of agricultural drought over the globe and the dominant confounders causing this change. Here we leveraged Bayesian model averaging ensemble vine copula model to reveal changes in agricultural drought predictability globally in warm seasons at three projected global warming levels. We found that the projected dynamic predictability of agricultural drought would significantly decrease over 70% of the global land areas in +2 °C and +3 °C worlds, especially over North America, Amazonia, Europe, eastern and southern Asia and Australia. This was primarily attributed to the weakening soil moisture memory, background aridity and weakening land–atmosphere coupling. Our findings highlight that stakeholders should employ dynamic climate adaptations to cope with the decreasing drought predictability in a warmer climate.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41558-025-02289-y/MediaObjects/41558_2025_2289_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Reviews Earth &amp; Environment | 西藏高原湖对气候变化的物理和生物地球化学反应</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43017-025-00650-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Physical and biogeochemical responses of Tibetan Plateau lakes to climate change&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Liping Zhu; Jianting Ju; Baojin Qiao; Chong Liu; Junbo Wang; Ruimin Yang; Qingfeng Ma; Linan Guo; Shuyu Pang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;藏族高原（TP）的湖泊，河流和冰川是东亚至关重要的水资源 - 正在发生实质性的环境变化。在这篇综述中，我们检查了TP湖泊的大小以及物理和生物地球化学特性的趋势。自1995年以来，湖泊地区和体积一直在增加，北湖区最快的扩张。在1986年至2022年之间，大于1公里&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;的湖泊总面积从37,109 km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;增加到46,980 km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ，储水量增加了169.7 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; ，这是由变暖和增强的降水驱动的。在大湖区（≥10km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ）中，平均表面温度升高1.33°C，水透明度增加了1 m，盐度从48.76降至23.76 psu。湖泊生物地球化学的反应包括增强的微生物多样性和营养状态，尽管额外的养分投入最少和生产率一致。尽管TP湖泊似乎是大气中CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;的净来源（分别为2000年代，2010年代和2020年代的1.60、6.87和1.16 TG C YR &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ），但长期CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;源源动力学仍然不确定。在SSP5-8.5下，TP湖面积预计将增加9,000 km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;到2050年，并将继续影响和增强区域降水。对TP湖泊水文学和生物地球化学的预测改进了，将有助于对TP的水资源进行可持续管理。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The lakes, rivers and glaciers of the Tibetan Plateau (TP) — a vital water resource for East Asia — are undergoing substantial environmental change. In this Review, we examine trends in the size and the physical and biogeochemical properties of TP lakes. Lake area and volume have consistently increased since 1995, with most rapid expansion in northern lakes. Between 1986 and 2022, the total area of lakes larger than 1 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; increased from 37,109 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; to 46,980 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, and water storage increased by 169.7 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;, driven by warming and enhanced precipitation. In large lakes (≥10 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;), average surface temperatures increased by 1.33 °C, water transparency increased by 1 m, and salinity decreased from 48.76 to 23.76 psu. Responses in lake biogeochemistry include enhanced microbial diversity and trophic status, despite minimal additional nutrient inputs and consistent rates of productivity. Although TP lakes appear to be a net source of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to the atmosphere (1.60, 6.87 and 1.16 Tg C yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; in the 2000s, 2010s and the 2020s, respectively), long-term CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; source-sink dynamics remain uncertain. TP lake area is projected to increase by 9,000 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; by 2050 under SSP5-8.5 and will continue to influence and enhance regional precipitation. Improved prediction of TP lake hydrology and biogeochemistry will aid sustainable management of water resources across the TP.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43017-025-00650-5/MediaObjects/43017_2025_650_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>