<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 02:18:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 第三极径流趋势的加速分化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02854-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Acceleration of diverging runoff trends on the Third Pole&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lei Wang; Xiuping Li; Arthur Lutz; Santosh Nepal; Deliang Chen; Tandong Yao; Fengge Su; Lan Cuo; Zhijun Yao; Yinsheng Zhang; Zhidan Hu; Jingheng Huang; Mei Hou; Ruishun Liu; Junshui Long; Chenhao Chai; Zhaofei Liu; Ahmad Bashir; Sonu Khanal; He Sun; Yong Nie; Yongqiang Zhang; Tao Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;量化脆弱的第三极高山河流径流的长期历史变化对于亚洲水资源规划至关重要，但在气候变化背景下，从一致的区域角度来看，这一问题仍未得到解决。在这里我们发现，在过去的半个世纪里，西风主导的河流（印度河、阿姆河、锡尔河、塔里木河、黑河和疏勒河）的山地出水径流总体上经历了显着的增加，而季风主导的河流（恒河、布拉马普特拉河、湄公河和萨尔温江）的山地出水径流总体上经历了不显着的下降，这主要是由西风增强和印度夏季风减弱驱动的。虽然径流量的变化率主要可以用降水量减去蒸散量的变化来解释，但总水储存量的变化（例如，区域冰川融化、地下水枯竭）也不能忽视。 1997年之后，西风和季风主导地区的对比变化明显加快，需要积极主动地适应以维持区域水、生态和粮食安全。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Quantifying long-term historical changes in river runoff from the vulnerable high-mountain Third Pole is critical for Asia’s water resources planning, but still unresolved from a coherent, regional perspective in the climate change context. Here we show that the mountain-outlet runoff generally experienced significant increases for the westerlies-dominated rivers (Indus, Amu Darya, Syr Darya, Tarim, Heihe, and, Shule) and insignificant declines for the monsoon-dominated rivers (Ganges, Brahmaputra, Mekong, and Salween) in the past half-century, largely driven by the enhanced westerlies and weakened Indian summer monsoon. Although the changing rates of runoff can be mostly explained by the varying precipitation minus evapotranspiration, the total water storage changes (e.g., regional glacier melting, groundwater depletion) cannot be neglected. After the year 1997, the contrasting changes in the westerlies- and monsoon-dominated regions have been remarkably accelerated, necessitating proactive adaptations to sustain regional water, ecology, and food security.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02854-5/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2854_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>