<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 02:19:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 由情节水流形状的南极地面区域环境</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01687-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A West Antarctic grounding-zone environment shaped by episodic water flow&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Huw J. Horgan; Craig Stewart; Craig Stevens; Gavin Dunbar; Linda Balfoort; Britney E. Schmidt; Peter Washam; Mauro A. Werder; Darcy Mandeno; James Marschalek; Christina Hulbe; Nicholas Holschuh; Richard Levy; Benjamin Hurwitz; Stefan Jendersie; Katelyn Johnson; Justin Lawrence; Regine Morgenstern; Andrew D. Mullen; Enrica Quartini; Wilson Sauthoff; Matthew Siegfried; Holly Still; Sam Thorpe-Loversuch; Tina van de Flierdt; Ryan Venturelli; Arran Whiteford&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在南极洲的冰盖下，一个鲜为人知的液态水网络连接了广阔的景观，并有助于压倒冰的运动。当这种亚冰川水到达冰架下的海洋腔时，它将与海水混合，放大熔体，并在冰底部形成深层通道的某些地方。在这里，我们介绍了一个热水钻孔的钻孔，记录了进入Kamb Ice Stream和Ross Ice架子地面的海洋腔的亚冰河水。我们的观察结果表明，熔体已经去除了大约三分之一的冰厚度，但测量结果表明，在浊羽中冰山下排放的速率较低。从通道地板上芯的沉积物显示出更大的排放事件，并从不同的地质领域沉积了材料。我们量化了冰川下排放，并将我们的观察结果与上游的集水区联系起来。我们得出的结论是，离散的排放事件可能会占主导地位的通道熔体和沉积物的运输，并导致坎布冰流下游的广泛冰壳特征。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Beneath Antarctica’s ice sheets, a little-observed network of liquid water connects vast landscapes and contributes to the motion of the overriding ice. When this subglacial water reaches the ocean cavity beneath ice shelves, it mixes with seawater, amplifying melt and in places forming deep channels in the base of the ice. Here we present observations from a hot-water-drilled borehole documenting subglacial water entering the ocean cavity at the grounding zone of Kamb Ice Stream and the Ross Ice Shelf. Our observations show that melt has removed approximately a third of the ice thickness, yet measurements reveal low rates of subglacial discharge in a turbid plume. Sediment cored from the channel floor shows larger discharge events occur and episodically deposit material from distinct geological domains. We quantify subglacial discharge and link our observations to the catchment upstream. We conclude that discrete discharge events are likely to dominate channel melt and sediment transport and result in the extensive ice-shelf features downstream of Kamb Ice Stream.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01687-3/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1687_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Water | 通过全球水模型模拟的水文通量和储藏中的相似性和不同模式</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00435-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Similarities and divergent patterns in hydrologic fluxes and storages simulated by global water models&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Amar Deep Tiwari; Yadu Pokhrel; Julien Boulange; Peter Burek; Luca Guillaumot; Simon N. Gosling; Manolis Grillakis; Naota Hanasaki; Aristeidis Koutroulis; Sebastian Ostberg; Kedar Otta; Hannes Müller Schmied; Yusuke Satoh; Bridget Scanlon; Tobias Stacke; Tokuta Yokohata&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球水模型（GWMS）是在不断变化的气候和加速人类干预措施下了解地球的水周期和水资源管理的关键工具。尽管已经评估了GWM的水文通量（例如，河流排放）和代表人类活动的作用，但了解模型同时再现通量和储藏的能力（例如，陆生储水（TWS））存在持续的差距。在这里，我们表明八个最先进的GWM并不始终繁殖放电，并且在各种地理和气候区域之间具有相同功效的TWS。此外，随着人类影响加剧，排放的模型性能会恶化。尽管在全球主要河流盆地的三分之二中发现了模拟和观察到的TWS趋势之间的一般协议，但模型倾向于低估这两个方向的趋势。同样，在全球主要的河流盆地中，没有任何单一模型能够准确，均匀地模拟TWS趋势和季节性。尽管与以前的报告相比，捕获盆地平均TWS趋势的改善，空间分布和季节性波动已经实现，但仍在准确地重现通量和储藏量的挑战，这主要是由于不足以使人类活动的代表不足，在严重管理的地区。这项研究强调了GWM性能中的关键差异，强调了进一步的模型增强的需求，这对于改善气候变化下的改进和更健壮的水文评估和预测至关重要。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Global water models (GWMs) are critical tools for understanding the Earth’s water cycle and water resource management under a changing climate and accelerating human interventions. Although GWMs have been evaluated for hydrologic fluxes (for example, river discharge) and the role of representing human activities, there is a persistent gap in understanding models’ ability to simultaneously reproduce fluxes and storages (for example, terrestrial water storage (TWS)). Here we show that eight state-of-the-art GWMs do not consistently reproduce discharge and TWS with the same efficacy across varied geographic and climatic regions. Furthermore, model performance for discharge deteriorates as human impacts intensify. While a general agreement between simulated and observed TWS trends is found in two-thirds of major global river basins, models tend to underestimate the trends in both directions. Likewise, no single model simulates TWS trends and seasonality accurately and uniformly across major global river basins. Although improvements in capturing basin-averaged TWS trends, spatial distributions and seasonal fluctuations have been achieved compared with previous reports, challenges remain in accurately reproducing both fluxes and storages, owing primarily to inadequate representation of human activities in heavily managed regions. This study underscores critical disparities in GWM performance, emphasizing the need for further model enhancements, which is crucial for improved and more robust hydrologic assessments and predictions under climate change.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00435-6/MediaObjects/44221_2025_435_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>