<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 02:21:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 直接的人干预措施推动了整个美国长期峰值流趋势的空间变异性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02738-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Direct human interventions drive spatial variability in long-term peak streamflow trends across the United States&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jibin Joseph; Sanjiv Kumar; Venkatesh M. Merwade; David R. Johnson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在气候变化和人类干预措施&lt;sup&gt;1,2&lt;/sup&gt;中，了解年度峰值的非平稳性是关键的。我们分析了在美国大陆的3907个流量场所的峰值趋势，中位数为80年。结果表明，三分之一的地点具有很大的趋势。其中，三分之二的人在全国范围内显示出趋势的下降，而三分之一的趋势显示了东北地区和大湖地区的趋势越来越高。我们发现城市化和水管理是主要驱动因素，农业和气候是次要的。城市化解释了德克萨斯湾差异的62％，加利福尼亚州的44％和中大西洋地区的32％。水管理在田纳西州（37％）和俄亥俄州（30％）地区占主导地位。农业在大湖区（17％）地区最有影响力，而气候在里奥格兰德（15％）和加利福尼亚州（11％）地区贡献。尽管最新的气候模型提供了许多实现，但它不足地捕获了水系统中的直接人力干预措施。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understanding non-stationarity in annual peakflow is critical amid climate change and human interventions&lt;sup&gt;1,2&lt;/sup&gt;. We analyzed trends in peakflow across 3907 streamflow sites with a median record length of 80 years in the continental United States. Results showed that one-third of the sites have significant trends. Of these, two-thirds showed decreasing trends nationwide, while one-third showed increasing trends in the Northeast and Great Lakes regions. We found urbanization and water management as primary drivers, with agriculture and climate as secondary. Urbanization explained up to 62% of the variance in Texas-Gulf, 44% in California, and 32% in the Mid-Atlantic regions. Water management dominated in Tennessee (37%) and Ohio (30%) regions. Agriculture was most influential in the Great Lakes (17%) region, while climate contributed in the Rio Grande (15%) and California (11%) regions. Although the latest climate model provides many realizations, it inadequately captures direct human interventions in the water system.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02738-8/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2738_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 国家土壤水文组映射使用数据驱动和基于专家的方法的环境应用</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05853-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;National soil hydrologic groups map for environmental applications using data-driven and expert-based methods&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Brigitta Szabó; Ronald András Kolcsár; János Mészáros; Annamária Laborczi; Katalin Takács; Gábor Szatmári; András Makó; Kálmán Rajkai; Balázs Benyhe; Károly Barta; László Pásztor; Zsófia Bakacsi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;区域和国家3D土壤液压图增强了对土壤液压特性的理解，这对于环境评估必不可少。但是，在大型模型中通常需要数据聚集，以促进复杂土壤特征的建模。这项研究介绍了匈牙利的土壤水文组映射，通过K-均值聚类和基于专家的规则得出。将聚类应用于100 m分辨率3D HU  - 大号基因组数据库，考虑到六个深度的八个液压参数。这些地图的准确性限制在具有极端特征的稀有土壤类型的情况下，由于其空间范围很小，而且在国家数据集中表示稀疏。为了说明这些代表性不足的土壤类型，我们使用基于专家的规则来完善每个基于统计的群集，这些规则结合了土壤剖面深度，遗传类型，电导率和可兑换的钠含量。最终分类包括68个土壤水文基团，这些基团由不同的液压特性定义，例如范·埃努切滕参数来描述保留水位和饱和的水力传导率。这张国家地图通过始终如一地处理类似的土壤，支持匈牙利的全国水文建模，环境管理和农业规划。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Regional and national 3D soil hydraulic maps enhance understanding of soil hydraulic properties, essential for environmental assessments. However, data aggregation is often necessary in large-scale models to facilitate the modelling of complex soil characteristics. This study presents a soil hydrologic groups map for Hungary, derived through k-means clustering and expert-based rules. Clustering was applied to the 100 m resolution 3D HU-SoilHydroGrids database, considering eight hydraulic parameters across six depths. The accuracy of these maps is limited for rare soil types with extreme characteristics due to their small spatial extent and sparse representation in national datasets. To account for these underrepresented soil types, we refined each statistics-based cluster using expert-based rules incorporating soil profile depth, genetic type, electrical conductivity, and exchangeable sodium content. The final classification includes 68 soil hydrologic groups, defined by distinct hydraulic properties, such as van Genuchten parameters to describe water retention, and saturated hydraulic conductivity. This national map supports country-wide hydrological modelling, environmental management, and agricultural planning in Hungary by enabling consistent treatment of similar soils.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05853-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5853_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 巴西的地下水井数据库（Gwdbrazil）</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05843-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A groundwater well database for Brazil (GWDBrazil)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; José Gescilam S. M. Uchôa; Paulo Tarso S. Oliveira; André S. Ballarin; Didier Gastmans; Jamil A. A. Anache; Bridget R. Scanlon; Clyvihk R. Camacho; Valmor J. Freddo Filho; Edson C. Wendland&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;足够的时空内地下水级测量对于可持续水管理至关重要。尽管它们的重要性，但缺乏协调，质量控制的数据集阻碍了巴西的大规模地下水研究。与巴西地质调查局合作，我们介绍了巴西（Gwdbrazil）的地下水井数据库，该数据库巩固和标准化了来自351,000多个井的信息，记录的历史可追溯到1900年至2024年，其中包括大约450井，包括2010年至2024年的每日连续监测，以确保数据的持续监控。以确保数据的准确性。 Gwdbrazil以表格格式和矢量点都有可用的可用，其中包括位置，深度和井目的等信息。该数据集还提供了支持集成的地表水和地下水管理的数据，例如每个井到最近的河流和含水层信息的距离。该数据集旨在为研究人员，决策者和利益相关者提供宝贵的资源，提供基本信息来支持巴西全面的水管理策略。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sufficient spatiotemporal in-situ groundwater-level measurements are essential for sustainable water management. Despite their importance, lack of harmonized, quality-controlled datasets has hindered large-scale groundwater studies in Brazil. In collaboration with the Geological Survey of Brazil, we present the Groundwater Well Database for Brazil (GWDBrazil), which consolidates and standardizes information from over 351,000 wells, with records dating from 1900 to 2024, including about 450 wells with continuous daily monitoring from 2010 to 2024. Cross-verification steps were applied to ensure data accuracy. GWDBrazil is available in both tabular format and vector points, comprising information such as location, well depth, and well purpose. The dataset also provides data to support integrated surface water and groundwater management, such the distance from each well to the nearest river and aquifer information. This dataset is intended to serve as a valuable resource for researchers, decision-makers, and stakeholders, providing essential information to support comprehensive water management strategies in Brazil.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05843-7/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5843_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 在2026年后，拆除科罗拉多河的气候和政策不确定性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-63635-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Disentangling climate and policy uncertainties for the Colorado River post-2026 operations&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Bowen Wang; Benjamin Bass; Alex Hall; Stefan Rahimi; Lei Huang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;科罗拉多河流域的湖泊米德和鲍威尔是美国西部的水和水力发电供应。尽管目前对盆地进行监管的政策将到2026年到期，但由于气候变化和政策不确定性，计划仍然具有挑战性。基于从10个动态缩小的CMIP6全球气候模型和添加和消除内部变异性的独特方法的流量投影，我们评估了鲍威尔的未来条件，并在现有和替代策略下评估了Mead的未来条件。由于预计流量的下降，根据现有政策，这两个水库将面临2060年之前到达死池的重大风险（&amp;gt; 80％的可能性）。采用最近提议的替代政策减少，但不会消除这种风险。所有政策还表现出临界点，其中储层水平会随着流量的略有变化而迅速变化。可持续的政策可能需要更大的减少，以进一步降低储层的死池风险，并从突然的变化中提供更好的缓冲。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lakes Mead and Powell in the Colorado River Basin underpin water and hydropower supply for the western United States. While the policies currently regulating the basin will expire by 2026, planning remains challenging due to intertwined climate variability and policy uncertainties. Based on streamflow projections from 10 dynamically downscaled CMIP6 global climate models and unique methods that add and remove internal variability, we evaluate future conditions at Powell and Mead under existing and alternative policies. Due to projected streamflow declines, under existing policy, both reservoirs will face substantial risks (&amp;gt;80% likelihood) of reaching dead pool before 2060. Adopting recently proposed alternative policies reduces but doesn’t eliminate such risks. All policies also exhibit tipping points where reservoir levels can change rapidly with a slight change in streamflow. A sustainable policy may require larger reductions to further reduce the reservoirs’ dead pool risks and provide better buffers from sudden changes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-63635-4/MediaObjects/41467_2025_63635_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 机翼大坝对河流中水和床位的影响受床负载类型的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02739-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Wing dam effects on water and bed levels in rivers are influenced by bedload type&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Gergely Tihamér Török; Gary Parker&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在密西西比州和多瑙河等河流中使用的机翼大坝通过在低流动期间增加水深来改善导航。它们的液态效果很复杂，并且对洪水风险的影响仍然存在争议。在这里，我们开发了一种方法，该方法可以从详细的数值计算中识别局部物理模式，从而使较大的河流延伸到较大的河流和以前难以研究的更长时间尺度。我们应用这种数值方法来评估几十年到几个世纪的水和床水平对水和床位的影响。我们的结果表明，床材料容易发生的河流往往会因翼水坝而导致长期水位增加，而其他河流则可能看到减少。对新稳定条件的调整需要数十年，即使在均匀的床中，临时水位也会上升。对于密西西比河，翼水坝可能导致初始水位增加，但随着时间的流逝，效果下降，表明河床的反应不断发展。这些发现有助于设计洪水风险 - 最佳的机翼大坝配置。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Wing dams, used in rivers like the Mississippi and Danube, improve navigation by increasing water depth during low flow. Their hydromorphological effects are complex, and their influence on flood risk remains debated. Here we developed an approach that identifies local physical patterns from detailed numerical calculations, enabling extension to larger river sections and longer time scales previously difficult to study. We apply this numerical method to assess wing dam impacts on water and bed levels over decades to centuries. Our results show that rivers with bed materials prone to armouring tend to experience long-term water level increases due to wing dams, while others may see decreases. Adjustments to new stable conditions take decades, with temporary water level rises even in uniform beds. For the Mississippi River, wing dams likely caused initial water level increases, but effects declined over time, indicating evolving riverbed responses. These findings help design flood risk–optimal wing dam configurations.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02739-7/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2739_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Climate Change | 自1980年代以来全球峰值排放的同步</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-025-02427-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Synchronization of global peak river discharge since the 1980s&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yixin Yang; Long Yang; Gabriele Villarini; Fang Zhao; Danqing Huang; Gabriel A. Vecchi; Qiang Wang; Yida Sun; Fuqiang Tian&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;与个别事件相比，在多个地区同时发生的河流洪水通常会导致社会和环境影响。但是，管理跨空间远处和近端位置的峰值排放峰值排放的全球互连的模式和机制仍然在很大程度上没有探索。在这里，根据来自4,407个观察湿度站的全球年度峰值排放数据库，我们确定了跨越数千公里的远程连接排放峰的枢纽。我们显示了远程连接的流域和总排水面积的趋势不断增加，这表明自1980年代以来，全球峰值排放的同步。海洋 - 大气振荡通过温度和降水异常的扰动决定了排放峰的全局耦合模式和时间演变。我们的发现凸显了在温暖的气候下，全球峰值流的紧急形象，可以使协调的洪水风险管理受益。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Riverine floods that occur simultaneously over multiple regions often lead to amplified societal and environmental impacts compared to individual events. However, the pattern and mechanisms governing the global interconnection of peak river discharge across spatially distant and proximate locations remain largely unexplored. Here, on the basis of a global annual peak discharge database from 4,407 observational hydrometric stations, we identify hubs for remotely linked discharge peaks spanning thousands of kilometres. We show increasing trends in the number of remotely linked watersheds and the total drainage area, pointing to amplified synchronization of global peak river discharge since the 1980s. Ocean–atmosphere oscillations, through the perturbation of both temperature and precipitation anomalies, dictate the global coupling pattern and temporal evolution of discharge peaks. Our findings highlight an emergent profile of global peak river flow in a warming climate that can benefit coordinated flood risk management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41558-025-02427-6/MediaObjects/41558_2025_2427_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>