<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 02:21:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 气候和人为活动控制全球内部水域中铜，锌，镉和铬的浓度</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02508-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Climate and anthropogenic activities control the concentrations of copper, zinc, cadmium and chromium in global inland waters&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xia Jin; Qiqian Wu; Josep Peñuelas; Jordi Sardan; Yan Peng; Zimin Li; Xin Peng; Petr Heděnec; Qiao Yang; Chaoxiang Yuan; Ji Yuan; Zihao Chen; Zemin Zhao; Fuzhong Wu; Kai Yue&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球水域中重金属（CU，Zn，CD，CR）受到的污染对淡水生物多样性和生态系统功能构成了重大威胁，但是重金属的全球模式和驱动因素仍然很探索。在这里，使用从514个同行评审的出版物中收集的11,573个数据点进行评估，主要进步包括：（1）全球内陆水域中平均浓度的量化（CU：8.38，Zn：30.00，CD：0.53：0.53：0.53：0.53和CR：7.00μgL &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ），提供全球规模的参考值，以评估局部水平的局部水平评估。 （2）人为活性，温度，实际蒸散量，降水和径流主要控制内陆水域重金属的浓度，以及（3）建立了全球重金属污染热点，随后是南美，揭示了西亚和南亚和非洲的浓度显着升高。我们的研究对CU，Zn，CD和CR的内陆水提供了全面的分析，为在气候变化下靶向易受伤害地区的污染控制提供了科学基础。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Pollution by heavy metals (Cu, Zn, Cd, Cr) in global inland waters poses significant threats to freshwater biodiversity and ecosystem function, yet the global patterns and drivers of heavy metals remain poorly explored. Here, assessing using 11,573 data points collected from 514 peer-reviewed publications, key advances include: (1) quantification of median concentrations in global inland waters (Cu: 8.38, Zn: 30.00, Cd: 0.53, and Cr: 7.00 μg L&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;), providing global-scale reference values to contextualize local water quality assessments; (2) anthropogenic activities, temperature, actual evapotranspiration, precipitation and runoff dominantly control the concentrations of heavy metals in inland waters, and (3) global heavy metal pollution hotspots were established, revealing significantly elevated concentrations in West and South Asia and Africa, followed by South America. Our study provides a comprehensive analysis of inland water for Cu, Zn, Cd, and Cr, offering a scientific foundation for targeting pollution control in vulnerable regions under climate change.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02508-6/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2508_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>