<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 02:25:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Climate Change | 人为增强地下土壤水分干旱</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-025-02458-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Anthropogenic enhancement of subsurface soil moisture droughts&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yansong Guan; Xihui Gu; Aiguo Dai; Tianjun Zhou; Xing Yuan; Ashok K. Mishra; Jakob Zscheischler; Yadu Pokhrel; Lunche Wang; Jianfeng Li; Shengzhi Huang; Sijia Luo; Liangwei Li; Dongdong Kong; Xiang Zhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;人为气候变化加剧了全球土壤水分干旱，但土壤垂直结构的时空演变仍不清楚。在这里，我们提出了拉格朗日四维跟踪框架来识别一种空间（水平和垂直）-时间连续干旱事件，即以底部重的深层为主的形状为特征的深层干旱，深层土壤比表层土壤有更广泛的水分亏缺。这些深度干旱占总事件的四分之一，在地表土壤湿度监测中被忽略。再分析和气候模型都显示，由于人为气候变化，过去四十年深度干旱的持续时间和强度显着增加。与过去相比，未来全球范围内的深度干旱预计将变得更持久、更严重，在高排放情景下，更深的土壤层会出现更大的增加。这些隐藏在地表以下的深层干旱给基于卫星的农业干旱监测带来了挑战，并导致低估了干旱对生态系统的不利影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Anthropogenic climate change has exacerbated soil moisture droughts globally, yet this exacerbation in their spatiotemporal evolution in terms of soil vertical structure remains unclear. Here we propose a Lagrangian four-dimensional tracking framework to identify a type of spatial (horizontal and vertical)–temporal contiguous drought events, that is, deep droughts characterized by bottom-heavy deep-dominated shapes, with more extensive moisture deficits in deep than surface soils. These deep droughts, accounting for a quarter of total events, are ignored in surface-based soil moisture monitoring. Both reanalyses and climate models show significantly increasing duration and intensity of the deep droughts over the past four decades, attributable to anthropogenic climate change. Relative to the past, future deep droughts are projected to become longer-lasting and more intense globally, with larger increases in deeper soil layers under higher-emission scenarios. These deep droughts hidden below the surface pose challenges for satellite-based agricultural drought monitoring and cause an underestimation of adverse impacts of droughts on ecosystems.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41558-025-02458-z/MediaObjects/41558_2025_2458_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 蒙古高原三年湖泊数据集追踪水域面积和质量动态（1990-2020）</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06059-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A three-decade lake dataset on the Mongolian plateau tracking water area and quality dynamics (1990–2020)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jinkai Guo; Kai Liu; Jiaming Na; Ge Liu; Zhigang Cao; Chenyu Fan; Bin Xue; Junchuan Huang; Chunqiao Song&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;蒙古高原（MP）的湖泊是重要的淡水和生态资源，但缺乏对其面积和水质动态的全面长期记录。为了填补这一空白，我们开发了蒙古高原湖泊数据集 (MPLD)，这是第一个开放获取、空间明确的数据集，提供 1,161 个湖泊（&amp;gt; 1 平方公里，包括人工水库）的湖泊范围年度记录（1990-2020 年）和三个水质指标（塞奇盘深度、总悬浮物和福雷尔-乌勒指数）。该数据集由通过 Google Earth Engine 处理的超过 56,000 个 Landsat 场景构建而成，揭示了湖泊最初收缩然后部分恢复的模式，到 2020 年，湖泊总面积达到 19,592.78 平方公里。到那一年，71.83% 的湖泊被归类为富营养化 (FUI ≥ 10)。数据显示出强烈的时空异质性：西部和北部湖泊扩大和清除，而东部和中部湖泊扩大和清除。内蒙古出现萎缩，水质下降。 MPLD 为整个 MPLD 的水资源管理提供了关键支持，并为全球气候变化和旱地动态研究提供了宝贵的参考。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lakes on the Mongolian Plateau (MP) are vital freshwater and ecological resources, yet comprehensive long-term records of their area and water quality dynamics have been lacking. To fill this gap, we developed the Mongolian Plateau Lake Dataset (MPLD)—the first open-access, spatially explicit dataset providing annual records (1990–2020) of lake extent and three water quality indicators (Secchi Disk Depth, Total Suspended Matter, and Forel–Ule Index) for 1,161 lakes ( &amp;gt; 1 km², including artificial reservoirs). Built from over 56,000 Landsat scenes processed via Google Earth Engine, the dataset reveals a pattern of initial lake shrinkage followed by partial recovery, with total lake area reaching 19,592.78 km² by 2020. By that year, 71.83% of lakes were classified as eutrophic (FUI ≥ 10).The data show strong spatiotemporal heterogeneity: western and northern lakes expanded and cleared, while eastern and central Inner Mongolia saw contraction and water quality decline. The MPLD provides critical support for water resource management across the MP and serves as a valuable reference for global studies on climate change and dryland dynamics.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06059-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6059_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>