<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 02:59:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 从格陵兰冰盖表面爆发的冰川洪水爆发</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01746-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Outburst of a subglacial flood from the surface of the Greenland Ice Sheet&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jade S. Bowling; Malcolm McMillan; Amber A. Leeson; Stephen J. Livingstone; Andrew J. Sole; Felix S. L. Ng; Nanna B. Karlsson; Peter Nienow; Karla Boxall; Brice Noël; Michiel R. van den Broeke; Thomas Slater; Jennifer Maddalena; Louise Sandberg Sørensen; Sebastian B. Simonsen; Jérémie Mouginot; Romain Millan; Laura Melling; Liam Taylor; Angelika Humbert&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;随着地球气候的温暖，格陵兰冰盖的地面融化增强了海平面上升速度。观察和理论表明，在冰盖表面产生的熔融水会沥干到床上，在那里它相对不受限制地流向海洋。对冰盖内部和下面的水运动的理解为基础的理论模型，这些模型用于进行冰盖变化。在这里，我们提供了格陵兰岛融化流水的破坏性模式的证据。我们使用多个卫星来源表明，一个9000万立方米的亚冰块洪水从床上向上迫使其向上，使冰盖骨折并穿过表面。这种现象是由冰山下湖的快速排水触发的，发生在预计冰床被冷冻的区域。由此产生的洪水导致下游海洋末端冰川的快速减速。我们的观察结果揭示了冰盖表面和基础水文系统之间复杂的双向耦合，并证明在预测的基于冷的冰的区域可能会发生极端的水文强迫。这样的过程会影响冰盖的动态和结构完整性，但目前在冰盖模型中尚未考虑。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As Earth’s climate warms, surface melting of the Greenland Ice Sheet has intensified, increasing rates of sea-level rise. Observations and theory indicate that meltwater generated at the ice sheet surface can drain to its bed, where it flows relatively unhindered to the ocean. This understanding of water movement within and beneath ice sheets underpins the theoretical models that are used to make projections of ice sheet change. Here we present evidence of a destructive mode of meltwater drainage in Greenland. Using multiple satellite sources, we show that a 90-million-cubic-metre subglacial flood forced its way upwards from the bed, fracturing the ice sheet, and bursting through the surface. This phenomenon was triggered by the rapid drainage of a subglacial lake and occurred in a region where the ice bed was predicted to be frozen. The resulting flood caused a rapid deceleration of the downstream marine-terminating glacier. Our observations reveal a complex, bi-directional coupling between the ice sheet’s surface and basal hydrological systems and demonstrate that extreme hydrological forcing may occur in regions of predicted cold-based ice. Such processes can impact the ice sheet’s dynamics and structural integrity but are not currently considered in ice sheet models.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01746-9/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1746_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 卫星遥感的非主动湖盐度数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05686-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A non-optically active lake salinity dataset by satellite remote sensing&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Mingming Deng; Ronghua Ma; Lixin Wang; Minqi Hu; Kun Xue; Zhigang Cao; Junfeng Xiong; Zhengyang Yu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水盐度是天然水的理化特性的特征，是评估湖水质量的重要参数。但是，由于盐度是一种非主动的参数，因此遥感反转的遥感反转效率受到限制，导致缺乏像素规模的湖泊盐度数据集。基于盐度示踪剂或单个湖泊的常规功能模型的区域适用性较低，而机器学习算法可以有效地捕获辐射和盐度之间的非线性关系，从而提供大规模的反转机会。我们的研究构建了一种极端的梯度提升（XGB）盐度模型，该模型用于生成具有Sentinel-2遥感反射率的内蒙古湖盐度（IMSAL）数据集。 IMSAL数据集包含928个栅格场景，从2016年到2024年，八个湖泊的空间分辨率为10米。交叉验证和独立验证，具有测量和已发表的文献录制的盐度，证实了良好的一致性和可靠性。该数据集提供了有关空间模式的宝贵信息和盐分的长期变化，可用于防止湖水盐化和促进湖泊管理可持续生态系统发展。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water salinity characterizes the physicochemical properties of natural water, serving as an essential parameter for assessing lake water quality. However, the efficiency of remote sensing inversion of water salinity is limited as salinity is a non-optically active parameter, leading to the lack of a pixel-scale lake salinity dataset. Conventional function models based on salinity tracers or single lakes have low regional applicability, while machine learning algorithms can effectively capture the nonlinear relationship between radiance and salinity, providing large-scale inversion opportunities. Our study constructed an extreme gradient boosting (XGB) salinity model, which was used to generate the Inner Mongolia lake salinity (IMSAL) dataset with Sentinel-2 remote sensing reflectance. The IMSAL dataset contains 928 raster scenes with 10-meter spatial resolution for eight lakes from 2016 to 2024. Cross-validation and independent validation with measured and published literature-recorded salinities confirmed the good consistency and reliability. This dataset provides invaluable information on spatial patterns and long-term variations in lake salinity useful to prevent lake salinization and facilitate the lake management for sustainable ecosystem development.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05686-2/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5686_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>