<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 02:27:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 中国276个城市面板数据揭示气温与河流水质的非线性关系</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02978-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Non-linear relationships between air temperature and river water quality revealed by a panel dataset of 276 Chinese cities&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Kehan Liang; Litiao Hu; Zongwei Ma; Shenyuan Huang; Miaomiao Liu; Wen Fang; Jianxun Yang; Jun Bi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气温对水质的影响通常通过其对水温、蒸发和物理化学过程的影响来调节。全面了解气温对河流污染的影响势在必行，特别是考虑到中国日益严重的水资源短缺和日益频繁的极端气温事件。在这里，我们采用固定效应模型来估计气温对河流水质的影响，并阐明 2014 年至 2020 年中国 276 个城市的倒 U 形响应。我们的研究结果表明，单日高温（&amp;gt;37°C）和热浪（连续四天高于35°C）都会显着增加河流高锰酸盐指数（COD &lt;sub&gt;Mn&lt;/sub&gt; ）浓度，加剧有机污染。此外，这些极端温度事件导致超过 67% 和 10% 的水质短缺，给城市取水带来了巨大挑战。我们的研究结果需要将与温度相关的考虑因素纳入当代和未来的河流治理中，有助于制定有针对性的适应战略并加强水资源管理。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The impact of air temperature on water quality is typically mediated through its influence on water temperature, evaporation, and physicochemical processes. A comprehensive understanding of air temperature’s effects on river pollution is imperative, particularly given rising water scarcity and the increasingly frequent extreme temperature events in China. Here, we employ the fixed effects model to estimate the effects of air temperature on river water quality and elucidate inverted U-shaped responses through 276 Chinese cities from 2014-2020. Our results demonstrate that both single-day high temperatures (&amp;gt;37 °C) and heatwaves (four consecutive days above 35 °C) significantly increase river permanganate index (COD&lt;sub&gt;Mn&lt;/sub&gt;) concentration, worsening organic pollution. Additionally, these extreme temperature events contribute over 67% and 10% to quality-based water scarcity, presenting considerable challenges to water withdrawals in cities. Our findings necessitate incorporating temperature-related considerations into contemporary and prospective river governance, contributing to the development of targeted adaptation strategies and enhancing water resource management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-27615-4/MediaObjects/41598_2025_27615_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>