<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 02:12:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 南亚季风强度上太阳能调制的speleothem证据</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00971-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Speleothem evidence of solar modulation on the south Asia monsoon intensity&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hong-Wei Chiang; Yue-Gau Chen; Shih-Yu Lee; Dung Chi Nguyen; Chuan-Chou Shen; Yin Lin; Lam Dinh Doan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;长期以来，太阳变异对气候的影响一直在辩论。在这里，我们利用越南的十年降解的&lt;sup&gt;speleothemΔ18o&lt;/sup&gt;记录，跨越32.5至27.5 kyr bp，作为区域降水水平的代理。我们的结果表明，总太阳辐照度（TSI）和区域降水之间的一般连贯性，支持与常规季风理论一致的积极气候反应。研究数据集的光谱分析显示，与太阳能活动的DE VRIE周期相吻合了约180年。进一步将我们的记录与其他35个Speleothem记录进行了比较，我们证明了足够的年龄控制点在捕获太阳相关周期时的重要性。模型模拟表明TSI可以增强季风循环和区域降水。还强调了年表控制对检测代理记录中气候事件的影响。新发现强调了相对较小的辐射强迫在季后赛至百年纪念时期对季风亚洲的区域气候动力学中的重要性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The influence of solar variation on climate has long been debated. Here, we utilize a decadal-resolved speleothem δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O record from Vietnam, spanning 32.5 to 27.5 kyr BP, as a proxy for regional precipitation levels. Our results show a general coherence between Total Solar Irradiance (TSI) and regional precipitation, supporting a positive climate response consistent with conventional monsoon theory. Spectral analysis on studied datasets reveals an approximately 180-year periodicity coinciding with the de Vries cycle of solar activity. Further comparing our record with 35 other speleothem records, we demonstrate the importance of sufficient age control points in capturing solar-related periodicities. Model simulation shows that TSI could enhance monsoonal circulation and regional precipitation. Also highlighted are the implications of chronology control for detecting climate events in proxy records. The new findings underscore the significance of relatively minor radiative forcing in regional climate dynamics over monsoonal Asia on decadal to centennial timescales.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00971-8/MediaObjects/41612_2025_971_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 黄河盆地中的生态恢复增强了水电潜力</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-57891-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Ecological restoration in the Yellow River Basin enhances hydropower potential&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xutong Wu; Zihan Yan; Haiyan Yang; Shuai Wang; Haoyu Zhang; Yilin Shen; Shuang Song; Yanxu Liu; Ying Guo; Dawen Yang; Bojie Fu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水力发电是全球重要的可再生能源，受到储层沉积的威胁。生态恢复（ER）可以通过减少上游沉积物来减轻这种情况，从而延长水力发电设施的寿命。但是，ER还可以减少径流，潜在地减少能源的产生，并使其对水电潜力的总体影响变得复杂。在这里，我们使用生态流水学和储层调节模型来研究中国曾经是世界上最充满沉积物的河流的中国黄河，以评估大型ER的影响小南储水库的水电潜力，该水库控制了92.3％的盆地区域。我们的结果表明，除了上游储层的运营和社会经济用水外，Xiaolangdi可能会产生〜2.7×10 &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt; kWh的能量，然后面对降低沉积物储存引起的柔韧性和效率降低，这是由于沉积物储存而导致的耗尽，这是由于不超过ER的57.3％，而不是超过〜100亿亿kWh。尽管平均每年能源产生降低了6.9％，但水力潜力的这种增强主要是延长的寿命。这些发现提高了我们对生态系统 - 水 - 辅助 - 能源Nexus的理解，为全球综合分水岭管理提供了宝贵的见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hydropower, an important renewable energy source worldwide, is threatened by reservoir sedimentation. Ecological restoration (ER) can mitigate this by reducing upstream sediment, thereby extending hydropower facilities’ lifespan. However, ER may also reduce runoff, potentially diminishing energy generation and complicating its overall impact on hydropower potential. Here, we examine China’s Yellow River, once the world’s most sediment-laden river, using eco-hydrological and reservoir regulation models to assess how large-scale ER influences the hydropower potential of the Xiaolangdi Reservoir, which controls 92.3% of the basin area. Our results indicate that, excluding upstream reservoirs’ operations and socioeconomic water use, Xiaolangdi could generate a total of ~2.7×10&lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt; kWh of energy before facing diminished flexibility and efficiency caused by the exhaustion of sediment storage—57.3% more than without ER—equating to an additional ~100 billion kWh. This enhancement in hydropower potential primarily arises from the extended lifespan, despite a 6.9% reduction in average annual energy generation. These findings advance our understanding of the ecosystem-water-sediment-energy nexus, offering valuable insights for integrated watershed management globally.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-57891-7/MediaObjects/41467_2025_57891_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>