<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 02:25:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | Fongyun-3卫星系列的协同合并序列的无缝分辨率土壤水分</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05263-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Seamless finer-resolution soil moisture from the synergistic merging of the FengYun-3 satellite series&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Daniel F. T. Hagan; Seokhyeon Kim; Guojie Wang; Xiaowen Ma; Yifan Hu; Yi Y. Liu; Alexander Barth; Haonan Liu; Waheed Ullah; Isaac K. Nooni; Samuel A. Bhatti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在过去的几年中，已经启动了更多带有微波成像仪的卫星，从而使更多的观察值可用于在全球获得土壤水分估计。中国的努力导致了能够填补全球土壤湿度数据差距的宫山（FY）被动微波观测（FY-3B，C，D）的推出。在这项研究中，我们通过合并技术的合并技术从2011年的空间分辨率开发了一个合并的土壤水分数据集，该空间分辨率为0.15°，该系列跨度（本研究中的2020年），使用输入母产物的信噪比将均方误差（MSE）最小化。在这里，我们结合了从三个卫星观测值中的上升和下降观测值，以获得亚每日估计。最后，我们将合并后的每日FY土壤水分平均为每日估计，并使用深度学习插值方法进行填充，以重建缺失的日子，同时保留合并的FY数据的特征。这项研究的结果旨在提供针对使用全球卫星土壤水分观察的挑战的数据集。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In the last years, more satellites with microwave imagers have been launched, making more observations available to obtain soil moisture estimates globally. China’s endeavour has resulted in the launch of the FengYun (FY) passive microwave observations (FY-3B, C, D) capable of filling in global soil moisture data gaps. In this study, we develop a merged soil moisture dataset at a spatial resolution of 0.15° from the FY series which spans 2011 to present time (2020 in this study) by a merging technique that minimizes mean square error (MSE) using the signal-to-noise ratio of the input parent products. Here, we combine the ascending and descending observations from the three satellite observations to obtain sub-daily estimates. Finally, we averaged the merged sub-daily FY soil moisture into daily estimates and gap-fill it using a deep learning interpolation approach to reconstruct the missing days while preserving the characteristics of the Merged FY data. The results of this study aim to provide datasets that meet challenges in using global satellite soil moisture observations.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05263-7/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5263_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 巴基斯坦纳马山谷的水信网络</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05310-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Hydrometeorological Network of Namal Valley, Pakistan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Muhammad Sheraz; Talha Manzoor; Malik Jahan Khan; Usman Ali; Hamza Tariq; Shabeh ul Hasson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文介绍了从位于巴基斯坦Mianwali区的Namal Lake集水区部署的传感器网络收集的数据。该湖是纳马尔大坝的水库。传感器网络由跨越425平方公里区域的流域中的14个独特的观测点组成。数据包括在所有传感器位置的分辨率为0.246 mm的降水测量以及在7个位置（包括湖泊本身）以1 mm分辨率的水位测量。第一个传感器安装于2020年11月进行，最后一个传感器安装于2022年7月。这两个变量的相关时间序列均以10分钟的采样频率生成。数据集的多个聚合已在每小时，每日和每月的时间表上提供。数据可用于校准各种应用的水文模型，例如洪水预测，分水岭管理和储层运营决策。该数据集还有助于理解季风边缘类似小流域中的水信过程。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This article describes data collected from a sensor network deployed in the catchment of The Namal Lake, situated in Mianwali district, Pakistan. The lake serves as a reservoir for the Namal Dam. The sensor network consists of 14 unique observation points in a watershed spanning a 425 sq km area. The data includes measurements of precipitation at a resolution of 0.246 mm at all sensor locations and measurements of water level at a 1 mm resolution at 7 locations (including the lake itself). The first sensor installation was made in November 2020 with the last one deployed in July 2022. The associated time series for both variables is generated at a 10-minute sampling frequency. Multiple aggregations of the dataset have been made available at hourly, daily, and monthly timescales. The data can be used for calibrating hydrological models for various applications such as flood prediction, watershed management, and decision-making for reservoir operation. The dataset also contributes to understanding the hydrometeorological processes in similar small catchments at the Monsoon Margin.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05310-3/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5310_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>