<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 02:17:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 基于遥感的土壤关键点和永久枯萎点的全球数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05048-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A global dataset of remote sensing-based soil critical point and permanent wilting point&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yawei Xu; Qing He; Hui Lu; Kun Yang; Dara Entekhabi; Daniel J. Short Gianotti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;临界点（CP）和永久性枯萎点（PWP）是控制土地表面能量预算和水平平衡的关键土壤液压特征。在全球范围内，这些参数缺乏可用数据。这项研究通过土壤水分干燥（SMD）提取CP和PWP，并从长期（2002-2023）遥感土壤湿度产品（基于神经网络的土壤水分，NNSM）中提供全球年度土壤液压性能。结果对来自国际土壤水分网络（ISMN）的1334个站进行了验证，结果表明，基于NNSM的CP和PWP的全球中位数随着时间的推移而稳健，并且由于每日时间分辨率的优势，土壤水分的精确度优于准确性。此外，该数据集比现有产品具有优势，因为它源自多年的气候平均状态，仅来自基于卫星的土壤水分观察。派生的数据集对于那些希望将陆地大气特征与他们的利益以及校准陆地表面模型联系起来的人很有用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The critical point (CP) and permanent wilting point (PWP) are key soil hydraulic characteristics that control the land surface energy budget and water balance. There is a lack of available data for these parameters on the global scale. This study extracts CP and PWP through soil moisture drydown (SMD) and provides global yearly soil hydraulic properties from a long-term (2002–2023) remote-sensing soil moisture product (Neural Network-based Soil Moisture, NNsm). Validated against 1334 stations from the International Soil Moisture Network (ISMN), the results show that the global medians of CP and PWP based on the NNsm are robust over time, and outperform the Soil Moisture Active and Passive (SMAP) dataset in accuracy due to the advantage of daily temporal resolution. Furthermore, this dataset holds an advantage over existing products, as it is derived from a multi-year climatological mean state and solely from satellite-based soil moisture observation. The derived dataset is useful for those who wish to connect land-atmosphere characteristics with their interests, as well as calibrate land surface models.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05048-y/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5048_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 高流量在新西兰河流中贡献了很大一部分污染物的收益</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02238-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;High flows contributed a large part of annual contaminant yields in New Zealand’s rivers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Richard W. McDowell; Esther Meenken; Alasdair Noble; Mike Kittridge; Olivier Ausseil; Laura Keenan; Ton Snelder; Crile Doscher&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流中准确的污染物估计对于制定水质政策和随着时间的推移监测其有效性至关重要。我们评估了高流量（≥90％）对新西兰15年（310-325个地点）的每月数据计算得出的高流量（≥90％）对硝酸氮，总氮，总磷和大肠杆菌的总产率，在24个地点以及高频率（30分钟）硝酸盐nInitrate-Nitrate-Nitrate-Nitorgogen和phoserulogen和phoserulogen和phoserulogen and rogengogen和phose in。高流量在长期部位和48％的硝酸硝酸盐氮和高频部位的总磷占48％的年度污染产量的51–74％。根据每月监测数据估计的年收益率的平均不确定性（与高频记录中的真实收率相比，硝酸盐氮的平均收率）为29％，总磷为52％。需要每日采样以将不确定性降低到&amp;lt;10％，尤其是在农业用地比例很高的集水区中。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Accurate contaminant yield estimation in rivers is essential to developing water quality policies and monitoring their effectiveness over time. We assessed the contribution of high-flows (≥90th percentile) to total yields of nitrate-nitrogen, total nitrogen, total phosphorus, and E. coli calculated from monthly data over 15 years (310–325 sites) in New Zealand, and at 24 sites with high-frequency (30-min) nitrate-nitrogen and total phosphorus. High flows contributed 51–74% of annual contaminant yields at long-term sites and 48% of nitrate-nitrogen and 63% of total phosphorus in the high-frequency sites. Mean uncertainties in annual yields estimated from monthly monitoring data (compared to the true yield, calculated from high-frequency records) were 29% for nitrate-nitrogen and 52% for total phosphorus. Daily sampling was needed to reduce uncertainty to &amp;lt;10% especially in catchments with a high proportion of agricultural land use.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02238-9/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2238_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 最近在北部生态系统中碳水耦合的最近削弱</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01059-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Recent weakening of carbon-water coupling in northern ecosystems&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Fubo Zhao; Wenbo Shi; Jingfeng Xiao; Meng Zhao; Xing Li; Yiping Wu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;陆生碳和水周期深深交织在一起，它们的耦合对于塑造生态系统过程和陆地大气反馈至关重要。了解很少探索的碳水偶联（CWC）的变化对于预测对气候变化的生态流水学反应至关重要。在这里，使用来自Eddy协方差塔和遥感的数据，我们证明了CWC强度的大幅下降 - 在过去的二十年中，北部生态系统占据了北部生态系统的大量相关性。这种弱化的主要是由温度，太阳辐射和降水扮演的次要角色驱动的。时尚项目中的陆地表面模型未能捕获这种弱的同步，这主要是由于它们对升高大气CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;水平的影响的表示不足。水和碳之间这种同步变化的弱化可能表明生态系统正在重塑其在北半球的生态流水平衡。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The terrestrial carbon and water cycles are deeply intertwined, and their coupling is critical to shaping ecosystem processes and land-atmosphere feedback. Understanding how the carbon-water coupling (CWC) changes, which remains rarely explored, is essential for predicting eco-hydrological responses to climate change. Here, using data from eddy covariance towers and remote sensing, we demonstrate a substantial decline in the CWC strength—measured as the correlation between gross primary production and evapotranspiration—across northern ecosystems over the past two decades. This weakening is primarily driven by rising CO₂ levels, with temperature, solar radiation, and precipitation playing secondary roles. Land surface models in the TRENDY project fail to capture this weakening synchronization, primarily due to their inadequate representation of the effects of elevated atmospheric CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; levels. The weakening of this synchronous variation between water and carbon may signify that the ecosystems are reshaping their eco-hydrological balances across the Northern Hemisphere.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01059-z/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1059_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 全球内陆水域微塑料分布模式的定量评估</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02320-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Quantitative assessment on the distribution patterns of microplastics in global inland waters&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xia Jin; Zimin Li; Josep Peñuelas; Jordi Sardan; Qiqian Wu; Yan Peng; Petr Heděnec; Zhijie Li; Chaoxiang Yuan; Ji Yuan; Zihao Chen; Zemin Zhao; Fuzhong Wu; Kai Yue&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球内陆水域的微塑料（MPS）污染最近引起了人们的关注。但是，在这些环境中，MP丰度的定量研究仍然有限。在这里，我们在301个出版物中的5365个观察结果中汇编了全球内陆水域中的国会议员全面数据集，揭示了内陆水域的MP丰度分布多样，范围为0.00至4,275,800.70个项目M &lt;sup&gt;-3&lt;/sup&gt; （平均值：25,255.4777777777±1322,132,808.40 MIM -M &lt;sup&gt;-3&lt;/sup&gt; ）。人类发展指数，蒸散量，农田和地表径流是影响水中国会议员水平的主要因素。预测地图显示中国的MP丰度特别高，但在亚洲，欧洲，非洲和美国东部也相对较高。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Microplastics (MPs) contamination in global inland waters has raised concerns recently. However, quantitative research on the abundance of MP in these environments remains limited. Here we compiled a comprehensive dataset of MPs in global inland waters from 5365 observations across 301 publications, revealing a diverse distribution of MP abundance in inland waters, ranging from 0.00 to 4,275,800.70 items m&lt;sup&gt;−3&lt;/sup&gt; (mean: 25,255.47 ± 132,808.40 items m&lt;sup&gt;−3&lt;/sup&gt;). Human development index, evapotranspiration, cropland, and land surface runoff emerged as the primary factors influencing MPs levels in water. The predicting map showed particularly high MP abundance in China, but also relatively high abundance in Asia, Europe, Africa, and the eastern United States.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02320-2/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2320_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 混合方法增强了本地流量预测的水文模型可用性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02324-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Hybrid approaches enhance hydrological model usability for local streamflow prediction&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yiheng Du; Ilias G. Pechlivanidis&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水文模型对于预测水通量动态（包括极端和管理水资源）至关重要，但是传统的基于过程的大规模模型通常由于无法代表复杂的，非线性的水文流程过程而在准确性和过程中挣扎，从而限制了它们在当地条件下的有效性。在这里，我们探讨了结合基于过程的建模和统计或机器学习后处理器的混合方法，以提高欧洲水电气候梯度在内的水流预测准确性，包括极端。我们研究了各种后处理方法，例如随机森林，长期的短期记忆模型，分位数映射和广义线性模型，在减少总体积和极端误差以及在多样化的气候和地理条件下的鲁棒性方面表明了模型性能的显着改善。我们进一步表明，水文相似性是控制杂种方法改进的主要驱动力之一，以及其他盆地特征，例如平均降水量和平均温度。我们的结果还揭示了后处理方法之间的空间互补性，没有从单个方法确定的绝对优势，指向多模型平均方法，用于将来的混合水文建模的未来演变。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hydrological models are essential for predicting water flux dynamics, including extremes, and managing water resources, yet traditional process-based large-scale models often struggle with accuracy and process understanding due to their inability to represent complex, non-linear hydrometeorological processes, limiting their effectiveness in local conditions. Here we explore hybrid methods combining process-based modelling and statistical or machine learning post-processors to improve streamflow predictive accuracy, including extremes, across Europe’s hydro-climatic gradient. We investigate various post-processing methods, such as random forest, long short-term memory model, quantile mapping and generalised linear model, demonstrating notable improvements in model performance, in terms of reducing errors in total volume and extremes and increasing robustness across diverse climatic and geographic conditions. We further show that hydrologic similarity is one of the key drivers that control the hybrid approach’s improvements, together with other basin characteristics, such as mean precipitation and mean temperature. Our results also reveal spatial complementarity among the post-processing methods, with no absolute superiority identified from a single method, pointing towards multi-model averaging approaches for the future evolution of hybrid hydrological modelling.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02324-y/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2324_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | CMIP6驱动的10公里超分辨率的每日气候预测在中国有宠物估算</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05071-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;CMIP6-driven 10 km super-resolution daily climate projections with PET estimates in China&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Fuyao Zhang; Xiubin Li; Xue Wang; Minghong Tan; Liangjie Xin&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全球变暖加剧了极端天气事件，对区域气候和水力生态系统提出了挑战。为了解决当前多气候变量和潜在蒸散量（PET）的低分辨率限制，本研究开发了一个基于深层剩余注意机制的超分辨率融合框架，建立了中国的10公里分辨率分辨率多模型 - 模型 -  scenario-scenario高分辨率高分辨率气候和PET DATASET（SRCPCPCPCN10）。残留的通道注意网络（RCAN）表现出适当的温度，辐射和压力（r &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; /kGE&amp;gt; 0.99）的降低表现，而由于空间不连续性，降水表现出明显较低的精度（R &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; = 0.897）。这些发现揭示了在SSP场景下中国未来气候变量的明显发射措施反应，温度，辐射和降水随着辐射强迫的强化而增加。原始CMIP6和缩小数据之间的年平均差异的比较表明一致性很高，大多数气候指数差异不足1％。这项工作克服了传统的局限性，为水文建模，农业气候风险评估和碳中性途径优化提供了千年规模的多元数据，从而提高了区域适应策略的精度。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Global warming has intensified extreme weather events, posing challenges to regional climate and hydro-ecological systems. To address the low-resolution limitations of current multi-climate variables and potential evapotranspiration (PET), this study develops a super-resolution fusion framework based on deep residual attention mechanisms, establishing China’s 10-km resolution multi-model-multi-scenario high-resolution climate and PET dataset (SRCPCN10). The Residual Channel Attention Network (RCAN) demonstrates exceptional downscaling performance for temperature, radiation, and pressure (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;/KGE &amp;gt; 0.99), while precipitation exhibits significantly lower accuracy (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; = 0.897) due to spatial discontinuity. The findings reveal distinct emission-gradient responses in China’s future climate variables under SSP scenarios, with temperature, radiation, and precipitation increases escalating alongside radiative forcing intensification. The comparison of annual mean differences between original CMIP6 and downscaled data showed excellent agreement, with most climate indices differing by less than 1%. This work overcomes traditional limitations, providing kilometer-scale multivariate data for watershed hydrological modeling, agricultural climate risk assessment, and carbon-neutral pathway optimization, enhancing the precision of regional adaptation strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05071-z/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5071_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>