<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 02:05:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 瀑布通过使溶解的甲烷绕过微生物氧化来增强区域甲烷排放</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02060-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Waterfalls enhance regional methane emissions by enabling dissolved methane to bypass microbial oxidation&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Rebecca L. Rust; Annastasia Frizzell; John D. Kessler&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河水是大气甲烷的重要来源，其局部排放随河流和湍流而增加。但是，当在区域上进行整合时，当不存在其他损失机制时，驱动的局部变化不影响释放到大气的溶解甲烷量。在这里，我们检验了以下假设：如果微生物甲烷氧化在河水中显着，瀑布会增强局部和区域大气的甲烷排放。在纽约西部的河水中测量了净大气排放和净氧甲烷氧化的速率，发现甲烷氧化会减少湍流时会减少大气排放。然而，在瀑布下，溶解的甲烷过饱和的88±1％释放到大气中，增加了净甲烷排放速率，其净甲烷排放率基本上超出了氧化（0.1-16.2×10 &lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; nm d &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ，用于瀑布发射； 10-39 nm d -1 nm d -1 nm d &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;用于氧化），并最终通过使溶解的甲烷绕过氧化水槽来增强区域甲烷的排放。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;River waters are significant sources of atmospheric methane whose local emissions increase with river slope and turbulence. However, when integrated regionally, the amount of dissolved methane released to the atmosphere is uninfluenced by local changes in turbulence when no additional loss mechanisms are present. Here we tested the hypothesis that waterfalls enhance both local and regional atmospheric methane emissions if microbial methane oxidation is significant in river waters. Rates of net atmospheric emission and net aerobic methane oxidation were measured in river waters containing waterfalls across western New York revealing that methane oxidation can diminish atmospheric emissions when turbulence is less. However, at waterfalls, 88 ± 1% of the dissolved methane supersaturation was released to the atmosphere, increasing net methane emission rates substantially beyond oxidation (0.1–16.2 × 10&lt;sup&gt;6 &lt;/sup&gt;nM d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; for waterfall emission; 10–39 nM d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; for oxidation), and ultimately enhancing regional methane emissions by enabling dissolved methane to bypass an oxidative sink.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02060-3/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2060_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 150年的河水质量记录显示磷负荷减少，但没有藻类生长潜力</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-024-01978-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A 150-year river water quality record shows reductions in phosphorus loads but not in algal growth potential&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Helen P. Jarvie; Fred Worrall; Tim P. Burt; Nicholas J. K. Howden&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在全球范围内，促进和有害藻华的富营养和增殖是造成水质损害的主要原因。在这里，我们分析了英国泰晤士河（包括生物氧需求，氯化物，磷和二氧化硅）的世界最长的连续（150年）河水质量数据集，以探索城市化，废水排放和农业强化的影响。在过去的40年中，废水处理和农业管理的改善已减少了约80％。但是，由于营养浓度保持在极限水平以上，因此这不足以减少河流藻类的开花。在过去的50  -  60年中，水温的升高增加了有利于硅藻开花的水温的数量，三月 -  4月和7月8月的蓝细菌生长。这些结果强调了在温暖的气候下富营养化管理的挑战，以及战略需要加倍努力，以进一步减少营养排放以控制滋扰和日益有害的藻华。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Eutrophication and proliferation of nuisance and harmful algal blooms are a major cause of water-quality impairment globally. Here, we analyze the world’s longest continuous (150-year) river water-quality dataset for the River Thames, U.K. (including biological oxygen demand, chloride, phosphorus and silica), to explore the impacts of urbanization, wastewater discharges and agricultural intensification. Over the last 40 years, improvements in wastewater treatment and agricultural management have reduced phosphorus loads by ~80%. However, this has been insufficient to curtail river algal blooms because nutrient concentrations remain above limiting levels. Over the last 50–60 years, rising water temperatures have increased the number of days with water temperatures favourable for diatom blooms in March-April and for cyanobacterial growth in July-August. These results highlight the challenges of eutrophication management in a warming climate and a strategic need to redouble efforts in further reducing nutrient emissions to control nuisance and increasingly harmful algal blooms.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-024-01978-4/MediaObjects/43247_2024_1978_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>