<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 02:24:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 土地用水可随着历史土地使用和土地覆盖的改变而改变</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01111-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Land water availability altered by historical land use and land cover change&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Tao Tang; Jun Ge; Junji Cao; Haiyun Shi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;人为土地使用和土地覆盖变化（LULCC）对通过生物物理途径定义为降水（P）减去蒸发（ET）的土地水的利用率有深远的影响。但是，长期以来，人们一直在争论这种影响，主要是因为在基于观察的研究中循环和背景气候变化引起的大气反馈的考虑不足，或者在基于理想的基于理想的模拟研究中对历史LULCC的不切实际表示。为了克服这些局限性，我们使用来自多个地球系统模型的最新模拟来研究历史（1850- 2014年）和Future（2015-2100）LULCC对P – ET的影响。在这里，我们表明，历史lulcc导致全球P – ET（主要在湿区域）的降低无关。在局部，p – et倾向于减少森林砍伐（造林）区域，这主要是由于降水的主要作用。大约3.8％的全球土地面积（5.1 mkm &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ）甚至经历了相反的政权转移，其中负（正）P – ET变为正（负）。然而，在中等到高温的情况下，预计甚至在重新森林的区域中，重新造林也可以减少P – ET。这项研究不仅阐明了现实的LULCC的水文效应，并充分考虑了大气反馈，而且还强调说，局部效应和大气反馈的相对重要性随背景气候变化而变化。我们强调，在计划造林和其他土地利用政策时，应考虑背景气候变化和反馈。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Anthropogenic land use and land cover changes (LULCC) have profound impacts on land water availability, defined as precipitation (P) minus evapotranspiration (ET), through biophysical pathways. However, such impacts have long been debated mostly due to either the inadequate consideration of the atmospheric feedbacks arising from the changes in circulations and background climate in observation-based studies or unrealistic representation of historical LULCC in idealized-simulation-based studies. To overcome these limitations, we use the latest simulations from multiple Earth system models to investigate the impacts of historical (1850–2014) and future (2015–2100) LULCC on P–ET. Here we show that historical LULCC caused an insignificant reduction in global P–ET, mainly in wet regions. Locally, P–ET tends to decrease (increase) in deforestation (reforestation) regions mainly due to the dominant role of precipitation. Approximately 3.8% of the global land area (5.1 Mkm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;) even has experienced opposite regime shifts, in which negative (positive) P–ET becomes positive (negative). Under a medium-to-high warming scenario, however, reforestation is projected to decrease P–ET even over reforested areas. This study not only elucidates the hydrological effects of realistic LULCC with atmospheric feedbacks being fully considered, but also highlights that the relative importance of the local effects and atmospheric feedbacks varies with background climate changes. We stress that background climate changes and feedbacks due to LULCC should be considered when planning reforestation and other land-use policies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01111-y/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1111_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>