<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 02:24:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Water | 水文气候和景观多样性导致热带和亚热带内陆水域温室气体排放量变化很大</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00522-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Hydroclimate and landscape diversity drive highly variable greenhouse gas emissions from tropical and subtropical inland waters&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Clément Duvert; Alberto V. Borges; Elisa Calamita; Gerard Rocher-Ros; Annika Linkhorst; Judith A. Rosentreter; Shaoda Liu; Pierre Taillardat; Katrin Attermeyer; Tonya DelSontro; Loris Deirmendjian; Alicia A. Dixon; Charlotte Grasset; Allison M. Herreid; Luke C. Jeffrey; Lediane Marcon; Ricky M. Mwanake; José R. Paranaíba; Lishan Ran; Adam T. Rexroade; Vanessa Solano; Francesco Ulloa-Cedamanos; Jilong Wang; Keridwen M. Whitmore; Liwei Zhang; Carla López-Lloreda; Marcia N. Macedo; Diana Oviedo-Vargas; Diego A. Riveros-Iregui; Nicholas S. Marzolf&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;（亚）热带内陆水域是重要的温室气体（GHG）来源，但有限的观测长期以来阻碍了对这一不同地区温室气体变异性的广泛分析。在这里，通过荟萃分析，我们研究了流动和静止（亚）热带内陆水域的温室气体排放率和驱动因素。我们发现通量存在相当大的空间变化，很大程度上与水文气候、地貌、土地覆盖和人类干扰的差异有关。流动的水比静止的水（114）排放更多的二氧化碳（3,387 &lt;sup&gt;5,702&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;2,121&lt;/sub&gt; TgCO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; yr &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ，表示&lt;sup&gt;第三四分位数&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;第一四分位数中&lt;/sub&gt;位数）、甲烷（10.6 &lt;sup&gt;28.8&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;0.1&lt;/sub&gt; TgCH &lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; yr &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ）和一氧化二氮（0.62 &lt;sup&gt;1.10&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;0.35&lt;/sub&gt; TgN &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; O yr &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; ） &lt;sup&gt;219&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;73&lt;/sub&gt; TgCO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;年(分别为&lt;sup&gt;-1、5.4&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup&gt;9.1&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;2.1&lt;/sub&gt; TgCH &lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; yr &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;和0.03 &lt;sup&gt;0.05&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;0.02&lt;/sub&gt; TgN &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; O yr &lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; )。 （亚）热带内陆水域每年排放 4,238 &lt;sup&gt;7375&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sub&gt;2473&lt;/sub&gt; TgCO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;当量，一级至三级溪流占河流排放量的 75%，面积超过 100 km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;的湖泊占死水排放量的 59%。我们的结果表明，（亚）热带水域的排放量比之前的估计低 29-72%，这一向下修正对全球温室气体预算具有重要影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Sub)tropical inland waters are important greenhouse gas (GHG) sources, yet limited observations have long hindered broad analyses of GHG variability across this diverse region. Here, through a meta-analysis, we have examined the rates and drivers of GHG emissions from flowing and standing (sub)tropical inland waters. We find considerable spatial variation in fluxes, largely related to differences in hydroclimate, geomorphology, land cover and human disturbance. Flowing waters emit more carbon dioxide (3,387
&lt;sup&gt;5,702&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;2,121&lt;/sub&gt;
 TgCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;, expressing median
&lt;sup&gt;third quartile&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;first quartile&lt;/sub&gt;
), methane (10.6
&lt;sup&gt;28.8&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;0.1&lt;/sub&gt;
 TgCH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;) and nitrous oxide (0.62
&lt;sup&gt;1.10&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;0.35&lt;/sub&gt;
 TgN&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;) than standing waters (114
&lt;sup&gt;219&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;73&lt;/sub&gt;
 TgCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;, 5.4
&lt;sup&gt;9.1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;2.1&lt;/sub&gt;
 TgCH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; and 0.03
&lt;sup&gt;0.05&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;0.02&lt;/sub&gt;
 TgN&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O yr&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;, respectively). (Sub)tropical inland waters release 4,238
&lt;sup&gt;7375&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;2473&lt;/sub&gt;
 TgCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-equivalents annually, with first- to third-order streams contributing 75% of riverine emissions and lakes larger than 100 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; contributing 59% of standing water emissions. Our results suggest emissions from (sub)tropical waters are 29–72% lower than earlier estimates, a downward revision with important implications for global GHG budgets.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00522-8/MediaObjects/44221_2025_522_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 全面的适应措施组合，以防范气候变化中不断变化的洪水风险</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02779-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Comprehensive portfolio of adaptation measures to safeguard against evolving flood risks in a changing climate&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Mohammed Azhar; Bergen Kane; Farshid Vahedifard; Amir AghaKouchak&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候变化加剧的洪水给世界各地的社区带来了越来越大的风险。尽管对洪水风险进行了广泛的研究，但缺乏对传统和新兴方法的洪水适应措施的批判性分析。在这里，我们编制了 39 项适应措施的综合组合，分为四组：基础设施/技术、制度、行为/文化和基于自然的措施。每项措施都会评估其优点、缺点、协同效益和权衡。我们的分析确定了洪水适应措施演变的四个主要时代。虽然早期的努力主要集中在结构改造上，但最近的项目转向了软适应措施，人们对采用以社区为中心和基于自然的解决方案越来越感兴趣。我们列出了关键的决策属性，以确定社会公正、实际可行且技术可靠的成功适应策略。最后，我们强调了差距并为未来的研究提供了建议，重点是采用跨学科方法来制定和实施气候适应和公平的洪水适应战略。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Flooding exacerbated by climate change presents growing risks to communities worldwide. Despite extensive research on flood risk, there is a lack of critical analysis of flood adaptation measures spanning traditional and emerging methods. Here, we compile a comprehensive portfolio of 39 adaptation measures classified into four groups: infrastructural/technological, institutional, behavioral/cultural, and nature-based measures. Each measure is evaluated for its advantages, disadvantages, co-benefits, and tradeoffs. Our analysis identifies four broad eras in the evolution of flood adaptation measures. While early efforts primarily focused on structural modifications, more recent projects shifted toward soft adaptation measures, with a growing interest in employing community-centered and nature-based solutions. We lay out key decision-making attributes to identify successful adaptation strategies that are socially just, practically feasible, and technically sound. Finally, we highlight gaps and provide recommendations for future research, with an emphasis on a transdisciplinary approach toward developing and implementing climate-resilient and equitable flood adaptation strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02779-z/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2779_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>