<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 02:24:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 温度和降水对水流入藏族高原上最大湖泊的不同影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01017-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Divergent effects of temperature and precipitation on water flow into the largest lake on the Tibetan Plateau&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yuanwei Wang; Lingxiao Wang; Lei Wang; Ting Li; Jing Zhou; Xiaoyu Guo; Zhaoyan Xie; Sichen Lin; Ying Hong; Lin Zhao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;TP上的大多数湖泊都以加速的方式扩展，改变了当地水周期和生态系统的调节。在这里，从1979年至2022年对Selin CO（TP上最大的湖泊）流入的时空变化进行了建模，并探索了变暖和润湿对水量的影响。建模的年平均湖泊流入为2.27 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; ，伴随着0.035 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; /年的显着增长趋势（P &amp;lt;0.01，变暖和润湿的贡献分别为-0.016和0.048 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; /年）。变暖（+0.0386 k/yr）每年湖流入量下降0.33 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; ，占年平均水量的14.5％，而润湿（+4.46 mm/yr）每年润湿的0.91 km &lt;sup&gt;3增加，占湖流入的0.91 km 3&lt;/sup&gt; ，占年平均值的40％。温度升高和降水对湖泊流入的这些不同影响使得预测Selin Co等盆地的未来水资源变得更加困难。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The majority of lakes on the TP have expanded in an accelerated manner, changing the regulation of local water cycles and ecosystems. Here, spatiotemporal changes in inflow to Selin Co (the largest lake on the TP) from 1979 to 2022 were modeled, and the impacts of warming and wetting on water volume were explored. The modeled annual mean lake inflow was 2.27 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;, accompanied by a significant growth trend of 0.035 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/yr (p &amp;lt; 0.01, the contributions of warming and wetting are −0.016 and 0.048 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/yr respectively). Warming (+0.0386 K/yr) caused a decrease of 0.33 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; in lake inflow per year, accounting for 14.5% of the annual mean water volume, while wetting (+4.46 mm/yr) caused an increase of 0.91 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; in lake inflow per year, accounting for 40% of the annual mean value. These divergent effects of increasing temperature and precipitation on lake inflow makes it more difficult to predict the future water resources of basins such as Selin Co.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01017-9/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1017_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>