<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 02:07:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 近年来，降雪减少了西北帕米尔斯的冰川健康和融水资源</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02611-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Snowfall decrease in recent years undermines glacier health and meltwater resources in the Northwestern Pamirs&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Achille Jouberton; Thomas E. Shaw; Evan Miles; Marin Kneib; Stefan Fugger; Pascal Buri; Michael McCarthy; Abdulhamid Kayumov; Hofiz Navruzshoev; Ardamehr Halimov; Khusrav Kabutov; Farrukh Homidov; Francesca Pellicciotti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;中亚拥有世界上最后一个相对健康的山地冰川，尽管尚不清楚这种稳定的冰川状态的原因。我们结合了最新的原位观察结果，气候重新分析和遥感数据，以迫使土地表面模型重建冰川在过去的二十年（1999-2023）中的变化，并在塔吉基斯坦的基准测试冰川集水区中解散了它们的原因。我们表明，自2018年以来，降雪和降雪深度已大大降低，导致冰川健康的下降并减少了径流的产生。遥感观察结果证实了西北帕米尔（Pamirs）的降雪量更大，这表明缺乏降雪可能是区域群众损失的原因。我们的结果为该地区冰川健康最近下降提供了解释，并强化了更好地了解降水的可变性的必要性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Central Asia hosts some of the world’s last relatively healthy mountain glaciers and is heavily dependent on snow and ice melt for downstream water supply, though the causes of this stable glacier state are not known. We combine recent in-situ observations, climate reanalysis and remote sensing data to force a land-surface model to reconstruct glacier changes over the last two decades (1999–2023) and disentangle their causes over a benchmark glacierized catchment in Tajikistan. We show that snowfall and snow depth have been substantially lower since 2018, leading to a decline in glacier health and reduced runoff generation. Remote-sensing observations confirm wider snow depletion across the Northwestern Pamirs, suggesting that a lack of snowfall might be a cause of mass losses regionally. Our results provide an explanation for the recent decline in glacier health in the region, and reinforce the need to better understand the variability of precipitation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02611-8/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2611_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>