<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 02:11:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 波罗的海系统大规模水文地球化学和同位素观测</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06217-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Large scale hydrogeochemical and isotopic observations in the Baltic Sea system&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Tristan McKenzie; Claudia Majtényi-Hill; Linnea Henriksson; Wilma Ljungberg; Gloria M. S. Reithmaier; Luiz C. Cotovicz Jr.; Jannine M. Lencina-Avila; Nico Mitschke; Michael Ernst Böttcher; Beata Szymczycha; Adam Ulfsbo; Aprajita S. Tomer; Tibaud Cardis; Per O. J. Hall; Ceylena Holloway; Júlia Rodriguez-Puig; Solveig Börjesson; Yvonne Y. Y. Yau; Shibin Zhao; Henry L. S. Cheung; Stefano Bonaglia; Tobia Politi; Linda Zetterholm; Nicolai Verbücheln; Iris Schmiedinger; Gregor Rehder; Thorsten Dittmar; Mats Tysklind; Pedro A. Inostroza; Ana Tronholm; Isaac R. Santos&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;我们报告了两次研究考察对波罗的海的水文地球化学和同位素观测：(1) 2023 年在 R/V Skagerak 上进行的约 5000 公里的巡航轨道；(2) 2024 年对陆地端元进行的陆基采样。基于船的观测包括对地表水中的水文参数、pH 和&lt;sup&gt;222&lt;/sup&gt; Rn 的连续监测。此外，我们还从水体、垂直剖面（n = 69 个站点）和气象数据中收集了 542 个离散样本。陆地观测包括来自海滩地下水 (n = 77)、近岸地表水 (n = 47) 和靠近海岸线的河流 (n = 46) 的离散样本。分析离散样品的短寿命镭同位素、营养物、溶解的有机和无机碳、总溶解氮、总碱度、甲烷和稳定同位素（δ &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt; O &lt;sub&gt;H2O&lt;/sub&gt; 、δ &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; H &lt;sub&gt;H2O&lt;/sub&gt; 、δ &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt; C &lt;sub&gt;DIC&lt;/sub&gt; 、δ &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt; C &lt;sub&gt;CO2&lt;/sub&gt; 、δ &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt; C &lt;sub&gt;CH4&lt;/sub&gt; ）。数据产品包括七个开放获取文件。该数据集为即将发表的原始研究出版物奠定了基础。该数据集对于对波罗的海等沿海海洋水文地球化学感兴趣，以及对海底地下水排放和河口生物地球化学感兴趣的研究人员也很有价值。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We report hydrogeochemical and isotopic observations across the Baltic Sea from two research expeditions: (1) a ~5000 km cruise-track onboard the R/V Skagerak in 2023 and (2) a land-based sampling for terrestrial endmembers in 2024. The ship-based observations include continuous monitoring of hydrographic parameters, pH, and &lt;sup&gt;222&lt;/sup&gt;Rn in surface water. In addition, we collected 542 discrete samples from the water column, vertical profiles (n = 69 stations), and meteorological data. Land observations include discrete samples from beach groundwater (n = 77), nearshore surface water (n = 47), and rivers close to the coastline (n = 46). Discrete samples were analyzed for short-lived radium isotopes, nutrients, dissolved organic and inorganic carbon, total dissolved nitrogen, total alkalinity, methane, and stable isotopes (δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;H2O&lt;/sub&gt;, δ&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;H2O&lt;/sub&gt;, δ&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;DIC&lt;/sub&gt;, δ&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;CO2&lt;/sub&gt;, δ&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;CH4&lt;/sub&gt;). Data products include seven open-access files. This dataset forms the deposit for upcoming original research publications. This dataset will also be valuable to researchers interested in the hydrogeochemistry of coastal seas, like the Baltic Sea, and more generally interested in submarine groundwater discharge and estuarine biogeochemistry.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06217-9/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6217_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>