<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:26:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | Sentinel-3 Altimetry主题产品用于水文学，海冰和陆冰</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04956-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Sentinel-3 Altimetry Thematic Products for Hydrology, Sea Ice and Land Ice&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jérémie Aublanc; Julien Renou; Fanny Piras; Karina Nielsen; Stine K. Rose; Sebastian B. Simonsen; Sara Fleury; Stefan Hendricks; Nicolas Taburet; Giovanni D’Apice; Anouk Chamayou; Pierre Féménias; Filomena Catapano; Marco Restano&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;本文介绍了Copernicus-Sentinel-3 Level-2 Altimetry Hydro-Cryo“ Thematic Products”，自2023年9月以来由ESA生成。与以前的产品版本相比，现在通过三个独立的链条执行了三个独立的链条，以产生三个“主题产品”的家族，以跨越水文，冰冰和土地，以相应地获得测量。在运营部署之前，与主题处理器实现了完整的任务重新处理，为用户提供了完整而协调的数据集。在本文中，介绍了地面细分市场处理的新体系结构以及主要的算法开发。还描述了主题产品的主要数据内容，以指示最终用户的关键产品变量。 Sentinel-3 Mission Performance Cluster（MPC）专家对主题产品进行了评估。提出了主要结果和结果，显示了与以前的处理版本相比，取得的显着性能提高。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This paper presents the Copernicus Sentinel-3 level-2 altimetry Hydro-Cryo “Thematic Products”, operationally generated by ESA since September 2023. In comparison to previous product versions, the level-2 processing is now performed through three independent chains, generating three families of “Thematic Products”, for measurements acquired over hydrological, sea ice and land ice areas, respectively. Prior to the operational deployment, a full mission reprocessing was achieved with the thematic processors, providing a complete and harmonised dataset to the users. In this paper, the new architecture of the ground segment processing is presented, along with the major algorithmic developments. The main data content of the Thematic Products is also described, to indicate the key product variables for the end users. The Thematic Products have been evaluated by the Sentinel-3 Mission Performance Cluster (MPC) experts. The major results and outcomes are presented, showing the significant performance improvement achieved in comparison to previous processing versions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04956-3/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4956_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | TSW：基于观测的田山山流域的流量数据集（1901- 2019年）</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05046-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;TSWS: An observation-based streamflow dataset of Tianshan Mountains watersheds (1901–2019)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Shuai Li; Wei Wei; Yaning Chen; Weili Duan; Gonghuan Fang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;由于数据的稀缺性和天山地区的复杂水文条件，因此缺乏长期和完整的流量数据。 This study produced a multi-basin streamflow dataset, named Tianshan watershed streamflow (TSWS) dataset, by comparing the results of Hydrologiska Byråns Vattenavdelning and Long Short-Term Memory models, and analyzed spatiotemporal variation of streamflow.TSWS dataset provides daily streamflow data for 56 watersheds and monthly streamflow data for 89 watersheds in the天山山脉于1901  -  2019年。 40个流域（每日尺度）和70个流域（每月尺度）的流量模拟通过了S检验（Nash-Sutcliffe效率≥0.5，偏差百分比≤25％，并且根平方误差与测量数据≤0.7的标准偏差与标准偏差的比率。该数据集显示出流量的总体上升趋势，尤其是从1990年到2019年；在空间上，它在西部和南部显示出较高的水流，东部和北部的水流较低。该数据集提供了第一个综合模拟，其长期序列将为气候和水文研究提供重要参考。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Due to scarcity of data and complex hydrological conditions in the Tianshan region, long-term and complete streamflow data are lacking. This study produced a multi-basin streamflow dataset, named Tianshan watershed streamflow (TSWS) dataset, by comparing the results of Hydrologiska Byråns Vattenavdelning and Long Short-Term Memory models, and analyzed spatiotemporal variation of streamflow.TSWS dataset provides daily streamflow data for 56 watersheds and monthly streamflow data for 89 watersheds in the Tianshan Mountains in 1901–2019. The streamflow simulations of 40 watersheds (daily scale) and 70 watersheds (monthly scale) passed the S-tests (Nash-Sutcliffe efficiency ≥0.5, percent bias ≤25%, and ratio of the root-mean-square error to the standard deviation of measured data ≤0.7). The dataset showed an overall increasing trend of streamflow, especially from 1990 to 2019; spatially, it showed higher streamflow in the west and south, and lower streamflow in the east and north. The dataset provides the first comprehensive simulation and its long time series will provide an important reference for climatic and hydrological studies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05046-0/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5046_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>