<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 02:27:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 熟练的亚季节土壤水分干旱预测，并具有深度学习模型</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-62761-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Skillful subseasonal soil moisture drought forecasts with deep learning-dynamic models&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Kyle Lesinger; Di Tian&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;从气候重新分析数据中学习的深度神经网络在十天内产生了熟练的天气预报。但是，对于动态模型来说，预测土壤水分，干旱和其他极端事件的挑战仍然是一个巨大的挑战，这些事件超过了两周。在这里，我们结合了递归深度学习模型（即Rise-Unet）和来自动态模型的亚季节预测，并提前四个星期实现对根区土壤水分的熟练预测。 Our hybrid model, combining RISE-UNet and dynamic model forecasts, outperforms reanalysis-driven RISE-UNet models, while both methods show significantly higher performance than the latest European Centre for Medium-Range Weather Forecasts (ECMWF) and Global Ensemble Forecast System (GEFS) dynamic models, the postprocessed ECMWF or GEFS subseasonal forecasts by RISE-UNet, or ensemble model output 统计数据。混合模型显示了预测闪存干旱的技能，在大多数情况下，该模型高于ECMWF和GEFS模型，这是美国，中国和澳大利亚的重大事件所证明的。从第三周到第四周，混合建模方法的预测技能主要是由于首个为期两周的动态模型预测和先前的根部区域土壤水分重新分析。我们的结果表明，将深度学习与动态模型的预测相结合可以大大提高两周以上的季节预测技能，尤其是对于根部区域土壤水分和闪光干旱事件。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Deep neural networks that learn from climate reanalysis data have produced skillful weather forecasts within ten days. However, it is still a great challenge for dynamic models to predict soil moisture, droughts, and other extreme events with lead times beyond two weeks. Here, we combine a recursive deep learning model (namely RISE-UNet) and subseasonal forecasts from dynamic models and achieve skillful forecasts of root zone soil moisture up to four weeks in advance. Our hybrid model, combining RISE-UNet and dynamic model forecasts, outperforms reanalysis-driven RISE-UNet models, while both methods show significantly higher performance than the latest European Centre for Medium-Range Weather Forecasts (ECMWF) and Global Ensemble Forecast System (GEFS) dynamic models, the postprocessed ECMWF or GEFS subseasonal forecasts by RISE-UNet, or ensemble model output statistics. The hybrid model shows skill in predicting flash droughts, which is higher than ECMWF and GEFS models in most cases, as demonstrated for major events in the United States, China, and Australia. The forecast skill of the hybrid modeling approach from weeks three to four is mainly due to the inclusion of the first two-week dynamic model forecasts and antecedent root zone soil moisture reanalysis. Our results indicate that combining deep learning with dynamic model forecasts can substantially improve the skill of subseasonal predictions beyond two weeks, particularly for root zone soil moisture and flash drought events.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-62761-3/MediaObjects/41467_2025_62761_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 国内废水是全球河水溶解碳的被忽视的来源和数量</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-62920-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Domestic wastewater is an overlooked source and quantity in global river dissolved carbon&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xingxing Cao; Shiqin Chen; Yan Liu; Guangxi Long; Y.Jun Xu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河流溶解碳（DC）在全球碳循环中起着至关重要的作用。然而，废水对全球河流DC的贡献仍然没有量化。在这里，我们量化了经过处理和未经处理的家庭废水对溶解的无机碳（DIC）和溶解的有机碳（DOC）载荷的影响。我们表明，在全球范围内，每年的家庭废水排放量约为21.4 tg DC  - 已处理的6.42 TG DIC和1.17 TG DOC，未经处理的9.64 TG DIC和4.21 TG DOC，共同核算，占全球DC Export的3.13±0.46％。在人口稠密的地区，贡献最高。流出的直流水平受到治疗技术，温度，降水，经济增长和城市发展的影响。这强调了将废水衍生的碳纳入全球碳预算评估的需求，并监测和减少废水废水中的碳。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Riverine dissolved carbon (DC) plays a crucial role in global carbon cycle. Yet, the contribution of wastewater to global riverine DC remains unquantified. Here, we quantify the impact of treated and untreated domestic wastewater on dissolved inorganic carbon (DIC) and dissolved organic carbon (DOC) loadings at nation and river basin scales. We show that, globally, domestic wastewater discharges ~21.4 Tg DC annually—6.42 Tg DIC and 1.17 Tg DOC from treated, and 9.64 Tg DIC and 4.21 Tg DOC from untreated, collectively accounting for 3.13 ± 0.46% of the global riverine DC export. Contributions are highest in densely populated regions with high treatment capacity. Effluent DC levels are influenced by treatment technology, temperature, precipitation, economic growth and urban development. This underscores a need to incorporate the wastewater derived carbon into global carbon budget assessment, as well as to monitor and reduce carbon in wastewater effluents.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-62920-6/MediaObjects/41467_2025_62920_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 情节储层洪水转化沉积物汇到来源以及潜在的全球影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02666-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Episodic reservoir flooding transforming sediment sinks to sources and the potential global implications&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Haifei Yang; Min Tian; Shilun Yang; Benwei Shi; Chunpeng Chen; Houjie Wang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;储层被广泛认为是沉积物水槽，但是由于沉积物来源仍然很少了解，淤积的水库的作用仍然很少。这项研究对黄河中水库的情节侵蚀作用进行了定量评估。在这里，我们表明，在Sanmenxia和Xiaolangdi水库中，2019年洪水期间的沉积物侵蚀分别为112和2.65亿吨。几乎所有的Sanmenxia侵蚀都是归因于自然洪水，而仅约40％的小米侵蚀是由于自然洪水造成的，其余的造成的洪水和人造洪水。这些侵蚀贡献了八十叶河流沉积物通量的〜1/4。储层侵蚀使下游悬浮的沉积物浓度增加了两个数量级。研究储层中初始侵蚀的阈值淤积比（沉积量/存储容量）范围为28％至87％，平均为60％±21％。考虑到许多在全球变暖下经历了30％的容量损失和洪水加剧的水库，在全球范围内，水库侵蚀将变得更加频繁。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Reservoirs are widely recognized as sediment sinks, but the role of silted-up reservoirs as sediment sources remains poorly understood. This study presents quantitative assessments on episodic erosion effects of reservoirs in the Yellow River. Here we showed that sediment erosion during the 2019 flooding was 112 and 265 million tons at the Sanmenxia and Xiaolangdi reservoirs, respectively. Nearly all the Sanmenxia erosion was attributable to natural floods, whereas only ~40% of the Xiaolangdi erosion resulted from natural floods with the rest from drawdown and artificial flooding. These erosions contributed ~1/4 of decadal fluvial sediment flux. Reservoir erosion increased downstream suspended sediment concentration by over two orders of magnitude. Threshold siltation ratios (sedimentation volume/storage capacity) for initial erosion in the studied reservoirs ranged from 28% to 87%, averaging 60% ± 21%. Considering many reservoirs experiencing &amp;gt;30% capacity loss and intensifying floods under global warming, reservoir erosion will become more frequent worldwide.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02666-7/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2666_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>