<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 02:53:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 西欧2021年7月的替代降雨故事情节因合奏而洪水泛滥</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02386-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Alternative rainfall storylines for the Western European July 2021 floods from ensemble boosting&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Vikki Thompson; Dim Coumou; Urs Beyerle; Joy Ommer; Hannah L. Cloke; Erich Fischer&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2021年7月，一个截止的低压系统为西欧带来了极端的降雨，导致洪水造成生命损失和基础设施损失。在这里，鉴于观察到的动态情况，我们使用合奏提升来研究事件的替代故事情节。使用完全耦合的自由运行的气候模型，我们在初始条件大集合中确定了2021事件的大气流类似物。这些类似物通过略有干扰的大气初始条件进行了重新定位，以产生物理上合理的替代故事情节。这些故事情节用于研究鉴于相同的大规模动态，可能会如何展开一个可能更糟糕的事件。我们确定持久性和更大程度的降雨事件，但观察到的事件似乎是当前气候中合理的上端。这种故事情节可用于为可能的未来活动做准备，帮助社会想象危险但合理的情况。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In July 2021, a cut-off low-pressure system brought extreme rainfall to Western Europe, leading to flooding that caused loss of life and infrastructure damage. Here, we use ensemble boosting to investigate alternative storylines of the event, given the observed dynamical situation. Using a fully coupled free-running climate model, we identify atmospheric flow analogues of the 2021 event in an initial-condition large ensemble. These analogues are re-initialised with slightly perturbed atmospheric initial conditions to generate physically plausible alternative storylines. The storylines are used to investigate how a potentially worse event could have unfolded given the same large-scale dynamics. We identify rainfall events with longer persistence and larger extent, yet the observed event appears to be towards the upper end of what is plausible in the current climate. Such storylines can be used to prepare for possible future events, helping society to imagine dangerous, but plausible, scenarios.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02386-y/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2386_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 在阿拉伯海中加强热带气旋补充耗尽的含水层</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02493-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Intensifying tropical cyclones in the Arabian Sea replenish depleting aquifers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hassan Saleh; Mohamed Sultan; Eugene Yan; Himanshu Save; Hesham Elhaddad; Hadi Karimi; Karem Abdelmohsen; Mustafa K. Emil; Sara Al Qamshouai&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;近几十年来，热带气旋在全球范围内加剧，在内陆更深的内陆降水。尽管许多研究集中在气候变化在热带气旋强化中的作用，但对它们对地下水充电的贡献的了解却少，尤其是在淡水稀缺且含水剂的干旱地区。在这里，我们使用基于卫星的总水存储和流体动力建模来量化2002年至2021年从阿拉伯半岛跨越旋风驱动的地下水充电。研究结果表明，旋风在阿拉伯南部半岛的总降水量占60％。 Cyclone Mekunu（2018）仅提供30 &lt;sup&gt;km&lt;/sup&gt;的内陆降水量，导致NAJD subbasin的净地下水补给3.2±1.2 km &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; 。这些发现表明，热带气旋在补充干旱地区的地下水中起着至关重要的作用。我们的方法提供了一个框架，可在全球范围内量化未加州干旱盆地的充值，为气候硫化的水资源管理提供了宝贵的见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tropical cyclones intensified globally in recent decades, delivering extreme precipitation deeper inland. While much research has focused on the role of climate change in tropical cyclone intensification, less is known about their contribution to groundwater recharge, especially in arid regions where freshwater is scarce and aquifers are being depleted. Here we quantify cyclone-driven groundwater recharge across the Arabian Peninsula from 2002 to 2021 using satellite-based total water storage and hydrodynamic modeling. Findings show that cyclones contributed up to 60% of total precipitation in the southern Arabian Peninsula. Cyclone Mekunu (2018) alone delivered 30 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; of precipitation inland, resulting in a net groundwater recharge of 3.2 ± 1.2 km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; in the Najd subbasin. These findings reveal that tropical cyclones play a crucial role in replenishing groundwater resources in arid regions. Our approach provides a framework for quantifying recharge in ungauged arid basins worldwide, offering valuable insights for climate-resilient water resource management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02493-w/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2493_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 水下沙丘高度的双峰性表明在高流量时闪烁行为</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-61248-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Bimodality in subaqueous dune height suggests flickering behavior at high flow&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Sjoukje I. de Lange; Roeland C. van de Vijsel; Paul J. J. F. Torfs; Nick P. Wallerstein; Antonius J. F. Hoitink&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;河床形式通过改变床粗糙度来影响河流液压。随着流速的增加，沙床从平床到涟漪，沙丘和上层舞台床的河流过渡。尽管先前的研究注意到，床形高度随着流动强度和床配置之间的快速变化增加了，但后者仍在研究。在这里，我们揭示了基于早期实验的数据和一个互补实验，在低和高的沙丘高度之间的运输阶段闪烁。在此运输阶段之上，沙丘高度分布中的第二种模式变得越来越独特，表明临界过渡。第二种模式的出现可能是由于悬浮沉积物浓度影响湍流的时间变化而引发的，或者可能是由沙丘运动学导致的，使大沙丘能够长得更长。这种闪烁的行为挑战了单个快照以捕获系统的床几何形状，影响现场测量和实验设计，并质疑地貌学中经典的平衡方程。我们的研究要求进一步的研究以了解和量化高运输阶段沉积物床的闪烁行为。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;River bedforms influence fluvial hydraulics by altering bed roughness. With increasing flow velocity, the sand-bedded river transitions from a flat bed to ripples, dunes, and an upper stage plane bed. Although prior research notes increased bedform height variation with flow strength and rapid shifts between bed configurations, the latter remains understudied. Here, we reveal flickering between low and high dune heights for transport stages exceeding 18, based on data from earlier experiments and a complementary experiment. Above this transport stage, the second mode in the dune height distributions becomes increasingly distinctive, suggesting a critical transition. The emergence of the second mode is potentially triggered by temporal changes in suspended sediment concentration impacting turbulence, or might result from dune kinematics enabling larger dunes to grow and persist longer. This flickering behavior challenges the adequacy of a single snapshot to capture the system’s bed geometry, impacting field measurements and experimental designs, and questions a classical equilibrium equation in geomorphology. Our study calls for further research to understand and quantify flickering behavior in sediment beds at high transport stages.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-61248-5/MediaObjects/41467_2025_61248_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | SMRFR：使用来自多源数据的随机森林生成的全球多层土壤水分数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05511-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;SMRFR: A global multilayer soil moisture dataset generated using Random Forest from multi-source data&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yuhan Liu; Yuanyuan Zha; Gulin Ran; Yonggen Zhang; Liangsheng Shi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;对土壤水分（SM）的准确和连续监测对于在农业，水文学和气候建模中的广泛应用至关重要。在这项研究中，我们提出了一个新型机器学习（ML）框架，用于生成连续更新的多层全局SM数据集：SMRFR（通过随机森林回归的土壤水分）。 Leveraging publicly available reanalysis and remote sensing data, SMRFR provides daily SM estimates at five soil layers (0–5, 5–10, 10–30, 30–50 and 50–100 cm) with a spatial resolution of 9 km, covering the period from 2000 to 2023. Evaluation results demonstrate that SMRFR effectively captures both spatial and temporal SM variability.它还表现出强大的概括能力，成功地转移了大陆的知识，并在降雨事件发生后准确捕获了短暂和季节性的SM动态。 SMRFR在验证集上达到了无偏的根平方误差为0.0339 m &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; /m &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; 。我们的小说SM数据集为农业，水文和生态研究提供了基础和宝贵的参考，从而可以改进区域与全球量表的SM动力学的分析和建模。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Accurate and continuous monitoring of soil moisture (SM) is crucial for a wide range of applications in agriculture, hydrology, and climate modelling. In this study, we present a novel machine learning (ML) based framework for generating a continuously updated, multilayer global SM dataset: SMRFR (Soil Moisture via Random Forest Regression). Leveraging publicly available reanalysis and remote sensing data, SMRFR provides daily SM estimates at five soil layers (0–5, 5–10, 10–30, 30–50 and 50–100 cm) with a spatial resolution of 9 km, covering the period from 2000 to 2023. Evaluation results demonstrate that SMRFR effectively captures both spatial and temporal SM variability. It also exhibits strong generalization capacity, successfully transferring knowledge across continents and accurately capturing transient and seasonal SM dynamics following rainfall events. SMRFR achieved an unbiased root mean square error of 0.0339 m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; on the validation set. Our novel SM dataset offers a basis and valuable reference for agricultural, hydrological, and ecological research, enabling improved analysis and modelling of SM dynamics at regional to global scales.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05511-w/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5511_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 从2003年到2018年的全球每日平均无间隙地表温度数据集的合成</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05498-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Synthesis of a global daily average gapless land surface temperature dataset from 2003 to 2018&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xin Pan; Xu Ding; Kevin Tansey; Rufat Guluzade; Penghua Hu; Zi Yang; Suyi Liu; Jie Yuan; Zhanchuan Wang; Ziyu Lv; Wenyi Duan; Yingbao Yang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;土地表面温度（LST）在能量平衡，水文，气象，地理和生态学领域的研究中起着至关重要的作用，它是广泛关注的重要输入指标。遥感LST是使用最广泛和应用的方法之一。但是，由于诸如云之类的因素，遥感LST数据通常会显示出大量缺失值，这可能会对其应用构成挑战。这项研究提出了一种无质量的LST产品，其空间分辨率为1公里，时间分辨率为一天，通过整合了两个遥感数据集（每天1 km每天平均地表温度（DMLST）数据集，由Zhan等人和1 km DMLST数据集和Liu等人的1 km DMLST Dataset由Liu等人。验证结果表明，合成产品的均方根误差（RMSE）约为2 K，比其他四种产品好，RMSE的准确性增加了0.4-0.6 K，并且在干旱和冷区域显示出显着改善。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Land Surface Temperature (LST) plays a crucial role in research in the fields of energy balance, hydrology, meteorology, geography, and ecology, serving as a significant input indicator of widespread interest. Remote sensing LST is one of the most widely used and applied methods. However, due to factors such as cloud, remote sensing LST data often exhibit a significant number of missing values, which can pose challenges to its application. This study proposes a gapless LST product with a spatial resolution of one kilometer and a temporal resolution of one day, generated by integrating two remote sensing datasets (1 km daily mean land surface temperature (DMLST) dataset by Zhan et al. and 1 km DMLST dataset by Liu et al.) and two reanalysis datasets (GLDAS and ERA5-Land). The validation results show that the Root Mean Square Error (RMSE) of the synthesized product is about 2 K, which is better than the other four products, the accuracy of RMSE has increased by 0.4–0.6 K, and it have shown significant improvements in arid and cold regions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05498-4/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5498_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 秘鲁各地的全国性同位素数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05413-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A nationwide dataset of stable isotopes in meteoric and terrestrial water across Peru&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Carol Romero; James Apaéstegui&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水稳定的同位素（ &lt;sup&gt;δ18o&lt;/sup&gt; ， &lt;sup&gt;δ2&lt;/sup&gt;小时）是追踪水周期中的来源和相互作用的有价值的工具，提供了专门用于理解与全球气候相关的物理机制的重要信息。尽管具有重要意义，但南美的同位素研究主题受到有限数据的阻碍。为了解决这一差距，我们启动了一个国家水平的水稳定同位素数据集，其中涵盖了秘鲁（WSI-Perudb）的不同水源。 The dataset contains curated in-house data and incorporates previously published records from various locations collected between 2000 and 2021. The WSIPeruDB dataset is composed of 489 water collection sites and allows a comprehensive use of the dataset by implementing standardized metadata templates containing essential geographical information such as latitude, longitude, and altitude (from sea level to 5000 m asl), and sampling information such as sample type （例如地下水，降水，河流，春季等）和采样频率（例如每两周，每月，每月）。 WSIPERUDB数据集可在Zenodo上公开可用，可促进科学界的访问和使用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water Stable Isotopes (δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O, δ&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;H) are valuable tools for tracing sources and interactions in the water cycle, providing important information dedicated to understanding physical mechanisms related to global climate. Despite their significance, the topic of isotopic research in South America has been hindered by limited data. To address this gap, we launched a national-level water stable isotope dataset covering different water sources in Peru (WSI-PeruDB). The dataset contains curated in-house data and incorporates previously published records from various locations collected between 2000 and 2021. The WSIPeruDB dataset is composed of 489 water collection sites and allows a comprehensive use of the dataset by implementing standardized metadata templates containing essential geographical information such as latitude, longitude, and altitude (from sea level to 5000 m a.s.l), and sampling information such as sample type (e.g. groundwater, precipitation, river, spring, and others) and sampling frequency (e.g. biweekly, daily, monthly). The WSIPeruDB dataset is publicly available on Zenodo, facilitating access and use for the scientific community.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05413-x/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5413_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Water | 社会脆弱地区的地表水不成比例地监测到美国南大西洋湾地区的养分</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00460-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Surface waters in socially vulnerable areas are disproportionately under-monitored for nutrients in the US South Atlantic-Gulf region&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Christopher C. Oates; Khara Grieger; Ryan Emanuel; Natalie G. Nelson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;这项研究调查了主动水质监测站是否按比例分布在不同社会脆弱性的社区中。我们特别关注对南大西洋湾地区地表水的养分监测，这是一个富含土地用途的水域，跨越了社会脆弱性谱系。我们使用了来自美国水质门户网站的2018  -  2022年数据，将车站位置与美国疾病控制社会脆弱性指数（SVI）的指标和美国地质调查局的水文图进行比较。统计分析表明，主动监测站位置的分布存在很大的失衡，在较低的脆弱性区域的监测站有更多的监测站，而在高脆弱性区域中的监测站则更少，并且模式随状态而变化。车站聚集在类似的SVI值的区域中；如果区域靠近具有不同SVI值的区域，则不太可能受到监测。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This study investigates whether active water quality monitoring stations are proportionately distributed across communities of varying social vulnerability. We specifically focus on nutrient monitoring of surface waters in the South Atlantic-Gulf region, a water-rich area with wide-ranging land uses and communities that span the social vulnerability spectrum. We used 2018–2022 data from the US Water Quality Portal to compare station locations to metrics from the US Centers for Disease Control Social Vulnerability Index (SVI) and hydrography from the US Geological Survey. Statistical analyses revealed a substantial imbalance in the distribution of active monitoring station placements, with more monitoring stations in lower vulnerability areas and fewer in high vulnerability areas, and patterns that vary by state. Stations were clustered in areas of similar SVI values; areas were less likely to be monitored if they were near tracts with differing SVI values.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-025-00460-5/MediaObjects/44221_2025_460_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | Landsat-8和Sentinel-2卫星测量的全球多传感器数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05562-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A Global Multi-Sensor Dataset of Surface Water Indices from Landsat-8 and Sentinel-2 Satellite Measurements&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yohei Miura; Mohammad Shamsudduha; Anawat Suppasri; Daisuke Sano&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;地表水范围的时空映射构成了用于管理水资源，监测洪水和干旱影响区域以及湿地和淡水生态系统的宝贵数据集。地表水指数，源自光学卫星数据，是估计地表水覆盖率的有效指标。然而，使用多个水指数的高分辨率地表水图的全球尺度数据集仍然稀缺，并且在时间范围和空间范围内受到限制。在这里，我们介绍了从三个水指数（标准化差异指数（NDWI），修改的NDWI（MNDWI）和水指数2015（WI2015）得出的每月地表水图，利用高分辨率的地球观测卫星数据在2019年1月9日至12月20日的时间为202年1月9日。这些水指数映射为投射地表水资源的分配提供了基准，并在全球气候变化带来的挑战下为地表水资源的可持续管理提供关键信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Spatiotemporal mapping of surface water extent constitutes a valuable dataset for the management of water resources, the monitoring of flood- and drought-affected areas, and the conservation of wetlands and freshwater ecosystems. Surface water indices, derived from optical satellite data, serve as effective indicators for estimating surface water coverage. However, global-scale datasets featuring high-resolution surface water mapping using multiple water indices remain scarce and constrained in temporal and spatial scope. Here, we present monthly surface-water maps derived from three water indices, Normalized Difference Water Index (NDWI), Modified NDWI (MNDWI), and Water Index 2015 (WI2015), utilizing high-resolution earth observation satellite data from Landsat-8 and Sentinel-2 for the period January 2019 to December 2021. These maps will be regularly updated as new satellite data become available. These water index mappings provide a baseline for projecting the distribution of surface-water resources and deliver critical information for the sustainable management of surface water resources under the challenges posed by the global climate change.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05562-z/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5562_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 机器学习的河流排放，温度和热通量的数据集进入北极海洋</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05582-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A Machine Learning-Reconstructed Dataset of River Discharge, Temperature, and Heat Flux into the Arctic Ocean&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Zihan Wang; Fengming Hui; Xiao Cheng&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;北极河流将全球河流排放量的11％带入北极海洋，影响海洋循环，海冰和沿海生态系统。我们对这些模式的理解受到大量数据差距的限制。为了解决这个问题，我们介绍了重建的北极排放的河流排放和温度（RADIT）数据集，这是1950年至2023年25个主要北极河流重建的每日排放，温度和热通量的全面记录。基于机器学习回归方法和ERA5-LOND重新分析数据，我们设计了不同的重新构造框架，以进行分配和温度，以考虑不同的形式。我们实现了高重建精度，纳什– utcliffe效率（NSE）值为0.861，温度为0.906。径向数据集具有广泛的空间和时间覆盖范围，是理解北极水文学及其对气候变化的反应的宝贵资源。它将改善北极淡水预算量化，气候模型校准以及对河流对北极海洋影响的评估，从而增强我们对北极海洋在全球气候系统中作用的理解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Arctic rivers deliver 11% of the global river discharge volume into the Arctic Ocean, influencing ocean circulation, sea ice, and coastal ecosystems. Our understanding of these patterns is limited by substantial data gaps. To address this, we present the Reconstructed Arctic-draining river DIscharge and Temperature (RADIT) dataset, a comprehensive record of reconstructed daily discharge, temperature, and heat flux for 25 major Arctic rivers from 1950 to 2023. Based on machine learning regression methods and ERA5-Land reanalysis data, we designed distinct reconstruction frameworks for discharge and temperature, considering the different characteristics of the observational data. We achieved high reconstruction accuracy, with median Nash–Sutcliffe efficiency (NSE) values of 0.861 for discharge and 0.906 for temperature. The RADIT dataset, with extensive spatial and temporal coverage, is a valuable resource for understanding Arctic hydrology and its response to climate change. It will improve Arctic freshwater budget quantification, climate model calibrations, and assessments of river impacts on the Arctic Ocean, enhancing our understanding of the role of the Arctic Ocean in the global climate system.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05582-9/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5582_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 区域干旱终止对登陆热带气旋的依赖性增加</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02564-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Increased dependency of regional drought termination on landfalling tropical cyclones&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yaxin Liu; Xuezhi Tan; Xinxin Wu; Xuejin Tan; Chengguang Lai; Huabin Shi; Thian Yew Gan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;登陆的热带气旋经常发生在强风和大雨中，提供了大量的水资源。热带气旋对减轻干旱和终止的积极影响尚不清楚。在这里，我们通过频率分析和事件重合分析来估计干旱终止对热带气旋降雨的依赖性。结果表明，从1999年到2021年，受热带气旋降雨终止的热带气旋影响区域中，约有3％的人经历了多次干旱事件。全球，热带气旋终止的干旱事件平均每年1.12，每年显着增加1.92％。在阿拉伯半岛，南亚和澳大利亚西北部，增长尤为明显。由热带气旋产生的降雨量比其他天气系统（例如前线，中尺度对流系统和大气河流）更大程度地减轻了干旱事件。这些发现强调了由于气候下的时机和天气系统的变化而导致的降水变化的适应。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Landfalling tropical cyclones frequently occur with strong winds and heavy rainfall, providing substantial water resources. The positive impacts of tropical cyclones on drought alleviation and termination remain unknown. Here, we estimate the dependency of drought terminations on tropical cyclone rainfall through frequency analyses and event coincidence analysis. Results show that ~3% of the tropical cyclone-affected areas have experienced multiple drought events terminated by tropical cyclone rainfall from 1999 to 2021. Globally, tropical cyclone-terminated drought events averaged 1.12 annually and increased significantly by 1.92% per year. Increases were especially significant in the Arabian Peninsula, South Asia, and the northwest of Australia. Rainfall produced by tropical cyclones alleviates drought events more drastically than that by other weather systems, such as fronts, mesoscale convective systems, and atmospheric rivers. These findings underscore the adaptation of precipitation changes due to shifts in the timing and weather systems under a warming climate.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02564-y/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2564_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>