<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 02:03:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 由于恢复项目而升高的地下水桌放大了北京地震引起的液化风险</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-56525-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yuan Li; Rui Wang; Hongbo Ma; Jian-Min Zhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;减轻地下水过度开发的地下水恢复越来越普遍，这证明可以有效解决城市水的稀缺性和区域不可持续的发展。中国南到北水转移项目是恢复地下水并解决北京水资源短缺的最大水转移项目之一。然而，这种大小的迅速恢复的地下水在很大程度上尚不清楚。在这里，我们探讨了基于北京的案例，在南到北水转移项目的影响下，地下水桌和地震地面液化之间的关系。我们收集地下水桌深度记录，并使用它们来驱动三维岩土模型，从而产生地面液化危险图。我们发现，由于地下水桌升高而导致的液化覆盖率和严重程度显着增加。在快速城市化过程中建立的基础设施通常在低地下水桌下，因此为这种增加的地震风险做好了准备。这些发现凸显了考虑大规模地下水恢复项目的地震后果的必要性。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Groundwater restoration is increasingly common to mitigate groundwater overexploitation, which proves effective in resolving urban water scarcity and regional unsustainable development. China’s South-to-North Water Diversion Project is one of the largest water transfer projects to restore groundwater and resolve water shortage in Beijing. However, how the rapidly restored groundwater of this magnitude changes regional seismic stability is largely unknown. Here, we explore the relation between elevated groundwater table and seismic ground liquefaction based on the case of Beijing under the impact of the South-to-North Water Diversion Project. We collect groundwater table depth records and use them to drive three-dimensional geotechnical models that generate ground liquefaction hazard maps. We find a remarkable increase in coverage and severity of liquefaction due to groundwater table rise. Infrastructures built during the rapid urbanization process are often under low groundwater table and thus illy prepared for this increased seismic risk. These findings highlight the necessity to consider the seismic consequence of large-scale groundwater restoration projects.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-56525-2/MediaObjects/41467_2025_56525_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 野火介导碳转移到北极地区和温带地区</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02070-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Mathilde Bélair; Ian M. McCullough; Christopher T. Filstrup; Jennifer A. Brentrup; Jean-François Lapierre&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;野火可能会破坏从陆地到水的碳运输，但碳循环的响应方式仍不清楚。在这里，我们分析了魁北克省，加拿大和美国明尼苏达州3个地区的54个湖泊（34烧伤，20个对照）在总碳池中的主要碳形式的浓度和优势（&amp;lt;1  -  3年）。燃烧的流域中的湖泊的控制湖的溶解有机碳浓度增加了两倍，并且在考虑气候和景观驱动因素（例如，集水区与湖泊区域比率）时，火灾效应最为明显。燃烧的湖泊中溶解有机碳的数量和优势比其他碳形式的更高和命运率不同，这表明潜在的火灾介导的碳出口在大火后长达几年，但在北部森林的流域中尚未确定的命运，对此具有重要意义，并且对区域符合全球碳预算。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Wildfires can disrupt carbon transport from land to water, but how lake carbon cycling responds to fires remains unclear. Here, we analyzed the concentration and dominance of the main carbon forms in total carbon pools in 54 lakes (34 burned, 20 control) across 3 regions of Quebec, Canada and Minnesota, USA from recent wildfires ( &amp;lt; 1 – 3 years). Lakes in burned watersheds had up to double the dissolved organic carbon concentrations of control lakes, and the fire effect was most apparent when accounting for climate and landscape drivers (e.g., catchment to lake area ratio) of lake carbon cycling. The greater quantity and dominance of dissolved organic carbon in burned lakes over other carbon forms with different turnover rates and fates suggest a potential fire-mediated carbon export up to several years post fire with a yet undetermined fate in northern forested watersheds and with important implications for regional to global carbon budgets.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02070-1/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2070_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>