<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 02:16:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 干旱频率，强度和暴露因历史土地使用和土地覆盖变化而增加</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02392-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Drought frequency, intensity, and exposure have increased due to historical land use and land cover changes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Tao Tang; Jun Ge; Haiyun Shi; Lin Wang; Junji Cao; Xuhui Lee&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;干旱是地表水的明显缺乏，对环境，农业和社会经济产生了广泛的不利影响。然而，土地利用变化对干旱特征的全球影响以及对干旱的相关暴露仍然很少知道。在这项研究中，通过使用有或没有土地使用变化的模型模拟来估算干旱特征的变化。我们表明，自1850年以来的历史土地使用变化，主要是森林砍伐和农作物的扩张，增加了全球土地面积一半以上的干旱频率，持续时间和严重性。活动更大的地区往往会经历更强烈的干旱事件加剧。由于它们的频率不断增加，持续时间延长，种群，农田和森林越来越多地暴露于干旱事件，这对人类健康，农业和森林生态系统产生了严重的潜在影响。潜在的造林活动可以大大减轻干旱事件的增强事件。我们的结果为与土地管理相关的决策提供了有用的信息。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Drought, a marked deficiency of surface water, has a wide adverse impact on the environment, agriculture, and the socio-economy. The global impact of land use changes on drought features and associated exposures to droughts, however, remains largely unknown. In this study, the changes of drought features are estimated by using the model simulations with and without land use change. We show that historical land use changes since 1850, mainly deforestation and crop expansion, has increased the drought frequency, duration, and severity over half of the global land area. Regions with greater activity tend to experience stronger exacerbation of drought events. Owing to their increasing frequency and prolonged duration, populations, croplands and forests are increasingly exposed to drought events, which poses serious potential impacts on human health, agriculture, and forest ecosystems. The enhanced drought events could be substantially alleviated by potential reforestation activity. Our results provide useful information for land-management-related policy-making.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02392-0/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2392_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>