<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 02:54:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Communications | 情节洪水引起人类主导河流的突然脱氧冲击</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-62236-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Episodic flooding causes sudden deoxygenation shocks in human-dominated rivers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yongqiang Zhou; Jinling Wang; Lei Zhou; Wei Zhi; Yunlin Zhang; Boqiang Qin; Fengchang Wu; R. Iestyn Woolway; Stephen F. Jane; Erik Jeppesen; David P. Hamilton; Marguerite A. Xenopoulos; Robert G. M. Spencer; Tom J. Battin; Peter R. Leavitt&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;溶解的氧（DO）维持了河流生态系统，但水文极端的影响仍然很少。虽然高河流排放（Q）增强了通气，但洪水也带来了消氧的污染物，从而使净影响不确定。在这里，我们分析了每日饱和百分比（DO &lt;sub&gt;％SAT&lt;/sub&gt; ）和三年中1156河的Q。我们表明，随着Q的上升和55.7％的速度升高，SAT的DO和DO &lt;sub&gt;％SAT&lt;/sub&gt;降低了。洪水（Q&amp;gt;&lt;sup&gt;第95个&lt;/sup&gt;百分位数）导致两者的突然下降（19.7％）和SAT DO &lt;sub&gt;％&lt;/sub&gt; （16.2％）分别在80.1％和69.4％的河流中，农业和城市地区的下降幅度最高。这些突然的脱氧事件与铵和土地利用强度的增加相关，导致发达区域中更频繁的缺氧。与最初的预期相反，洪水通常会降低氧气水平，而城市化地区的恢复速度更快。随着气候变化加剧洪水的增强，这种突然的脱氧冲击可能会降低水生生态系统，尤其是在人类改变的景观中。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dissolved oxygen (DO) sustains river ecosystems, but the effects of hydrological extremes remain poorly understood. While high river discharge (Q) enhances aeration, floods also deliver oxygen-consuming pollutants, making net impacts uncertain. Here, we analyze daily DO and its percent saturation (DO&lt;sub&gt;%sat&lt;/sub&gt;), and Q in 1156 Chinese rivers over three years. We show that DO and DO&lt;sub&gt;%sat&lt;/sub&gt; decrease with rising Q in 69.1% and 55.7% of rivers, respectively. Floods (Q &amp;gt; 95&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile) cause abrupt declines in both DO (19.7%) and DO&lt;sub&gt;%sat&lt;/sub&gt; (16.2%) in 80.1% and 69.4% of the rivers, respectively, with the sharpest declines in agricultural and urban areas. These abrupt deoxygenation events link to increased ammonium and land-use intensity, causing more frequent hypoxia in developed regions. Contrary to initial expectations, floods often reduce oxygen levels, with faster recovery in urbanized regions. As climate change intensifies flooding, such sudden deoxygenation shocks may degrade aquatic ecosystems particularly in human-altered landscapes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-62236-5/MediaObjects/41467_2025_62236_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 在UV-VIS范围内的吸附和反射率光谱法上的废水质量监测数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05459-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Dataset on wastewater quality monitoring with adsorption and reflectance spectrometry in the UV-vis range&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Pierre Lechevallier; Günter Gruber; Vojtěch Bareš; Nicolas Neuenhofer; Laura Waldner; Abhinit Mahajan; Lena Mutzner; Jörg Rieckermann&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;废水和下水道系统监测的主要挑战是开发先进的传感技术，以改善标准污染物测量并允许对新兴污染物的实时在线检测。这项研究介绍了一个数据集，该数据集比较了25周的测量活动，将新型的高光谱成像系统与最先进的紫外线可见（UV-VIS）传感器进行了比较。该数据集包括5801个原始废水的高光谱图像，温度，铵，流量，浊度，pH和UV-VIS吸光度光谱的测量值，以及分析了常规污染物的533个抓取样品。我们还收集了四次雨季事件后收集了86个样品，并分析了20种有机化学物质，从而有见识潮湿天气对污染物水平的影响。详细介绍了数据收集和处理方法，以及可视化和分析。尽管在维护某些传感器方面遇到困难，特别是用于铵测量的离子选择电极，数据集的高时间分辨率，25周的时间跨度以及广泛的分析污染物使其成为推进城市水管理领域的宝贵资源。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A major challenge in wastewater and sewer system monitoring is the development of advanced sensing technologies to improve standard pollutant measurement and allow real-time online detection of emerging contaminants. This study presents a dataset from a 25-week measurement campaign comparing a novel hyperspectral imaging system to state-of-the-art ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) sensors. The dataset includes 5801 hyperspectral images of raw wastewater, measurements of temperature, ammonium, flow, turbidity, pH, and UV-vis absorbance spectra, as well as 533 grab samples analyzed for conventional pollutants. We also gathered 86 samples after four rain events and analyzed them for twenty organic chemicals, providing insights into the impact of wet weather on pollutant levels. The data collection and processing methodologies are detailed, along with visualizations and analysis. Despite difficulties in the maintenance of some sensors, in particular the ion-selective electrode for ammonium measurement, the dataset’s high temporal resolution, the time span of 25 weeks, and the extensive range of analyzed pollutants make it a valuable resource for advancing the field of urban water management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05459-x/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5459_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>