<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 02:21:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Climate Change | 提高用水效率并不能刺激树木生产力</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-025-02504-w</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Increased efficiency of water use does not stimulate tree productivity&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Quan Zhang; Jiawei Zhang; Mark A. Adams; Giovanna Battipaglia; Lucas A. Cernusak; Laura Fernández-de-Uña; Darren L. Ficklin; Peter Hietz; J. Julio Camarero; Högne Jungner; Mathieu Lévesque; Stefano Manzoni; Justin T. Maxwell; Charles A. Nock; Josep Peñuelas; Klaus J. Puettmann; Matthias Saurer; Rocio Urrutia-Jalabert; Peter van der Sleen; Lixin Wang; Danielle A. Way; Yang Zhou; Pieter A. Zuidema; Gabriel G. Katul&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;大气中CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (c &lt;sub&gt;a&lt;/sub&gt; ) 浓度的升高会增加植物光合作用 (A &lt;sub&gt;n&lt;/sub&gt; ) 并降低气孔导度 ( &lt;sub&gt;gs&lt;/sub&gt; )。这提高了内在水分利用效率（iWUE = A &lt;sub&gt;n&lt;/sub&gt; / g &lt;sub&gt;s&lt;/sub&gt; ），这是树木适应气候变化的主要指标。然而，iWUE 的增加是否会导致树木生长随之增加仍存在争议，这引起了人们对 iWUE 与树木生产力之间理论联系的兴趣。在这里，我们使用气孔孔径动力学的最优理论，建立了一个包络线，描述了树木生产力的最大相对增加，可以从 iWUE 的相对增加推断/预期。所得到的表达式用于解释 iWUE（可观察代理）和树木生长（目标变量）之间的关系，使用来自操纵实验和树木年轮同位素的可用实验数据。虽然 c &lt;sub&gt;a 的&lt;/sub&gt;上升会增加 iWUE，但考虑到环境（例如，大气干燥度上升）和解剖/生理（例如，树高）影响的改善，树木生长不太可能成比例增加。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Rising concentrations of atmospheric CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (c&lt;sub&gt;a&lt;/sub&gt;) increase plant photosynthesis (A&lt;sub&gt;n&lt;/sub&gt;) and reduce stomatal conductance (g&lt;sub&gt;s&lt;/sub&gt;). This increases the intrinsic water-use efficiency (iWUE = A&lt;sub&gt;n &lt;/sub&gt;/ g&lt;sub&gt;s&lt;/sub&gt;), a major proxy of tree adaptation to climate change. However, whether an increase in iWUE leads to a concomitant increase in tree growth remains in dispute, prompting interest in theoretical links between iWUE and tree productivity. Here using an optimality theory for kinetics of stomatal aperture, we establish an envelope delineating maximal relative increases in tree productivity that can be inferred/expected from relative increases in iWUE. The resulting expressions are used to interpret relations between iWUE (an observable proxy) and tree growth (the target variable), using available experimental data from manipulation experiments and tree-ring isotopes. While rising c&lt;sub&gt;a&lt;/sub&gt; increases iWUE, proportional increases in tree growth are unlikely given ameliorating environmental (for example, rising atmospheric dryness) and anatomical/physiological (for example, tree height) influences.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-25527-x/MediaObjects/41598_2025_25527_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 多元综合干旱指数（MCDI）及其组成干旱指数的全球干旱数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06320-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A global drought dataset for Multivariate Composite Drought Index (MCDI) and its constituent drought indices&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Mengjia Yuan; Guojing Gan; Jingyi Bu; Yanxin Su; Hongyu Ma; Xianghe Liu; Leyao Zhang; Yongqiang Zhang; Yanchun Gao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;高分辨率干旱指数数据集对于干旱监测和评估至关重要。尽管全球/区域干旱指数数据集众多，但综合考虑气象、农业和水文因素的综合干旱指数数据集仍然很少，从而阻碍了复杂干旱动态的捕捉和全面的风险评估。为了弥补这一差距，本研究基于新提出的多元综合干旱指数（MCDI）概念，制作了0.1°分辨率的全球干旱数据集（1980-2019），该数据集考虑了干旱的时滞和累积效应，可以有效表征综合干旱特征。该数据集包含月尺度的 MCDI 及其四个组成指数（标准化降水实际蒸散指数（SPAEI）、标准化土壤湿度指数（SSI）、标准化径流指数（SRI）、蓄水亏缺指数（WSDI））。验证结果表明，它们很好地反映了干旱演变和生态系统响应过程，特别是MCDI。总体而言，该数据集弥补了综合干旱指数的数据不足，为全球干旱监测和气候变化下干旱适应性管理提供数据支撑。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;High-resolution drought index datasets are essential for drought monitoring and assessment. Despite numerous global/regional drought index datasets, the composite drought index datasets that comprehensively consider meteorological, agricultural, and hydrological factors are still very few, thus hindering the capture of complex drought dynamics and comprehensive risk assessment. To address this gap, this study produced a 0.1° resolution global drought dataset (1980–2019) based on the newly developed concept of Multivariate Composite Drought Index (MCDI), which considered the time lag and cumulative effects of drought and could characterize comprehensive drought characteristics effectively. The dataset contains MCDI and its four constituent indices (Standardized Precipitation Actual Evapotranspiration Index (SPAEI), Standardized Soil Moisture Index (SSI), Standardized Runoff Index (SRI), Water Storage Deficit Index (WSDI)) on a monthly scale. Verification results showed that they indicated the drought evolution and ecosystem response process well, especially the MCDI. Overall, the dataset compensated for the data deficit of the comprehensive drought index and would provide data support for global drought monitoring and adaptive management of drought under climate change.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-25435-0/MediaObjects/41598_2025_25435_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>