<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 02:21:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 冰川融合水对排出藏族高原的主要河流的总径流的贡献有限</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01060-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Glacier meltwater has limited contributions to the total runoff in the major rivers draining the Tibetan Plateau&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yi Nan; Fuqiang Tian; Jeffrey McDonnell; Guangheng Ni; Lide Tian; Zongxing Li; Denghua Yan; Xinghui Xia; Ting Wang; Songjun Han; Kunbiao Li&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;藏族高原是几个主要河流盆地的源头，但在冰川熔体和地下水对径流的估计贡献中存在不确定性。我们提出了一个新的示踪剂冰川流质模型，该模型受藏族高原的五个主要河流盆地约束的限制。我们表明，冰川融化对年度径流的贡献不到5％，在销售点的五个盆地中，冰川融化的贡献比以前的估计值少。我们的次要发现是，在流域中，地面径流和地下水流之间的分配差异很大，地下水径流占了年度径流的35-75％。冰川融化的贡献具有很强的空间变异性和规模的依赖性，但是大大依赖它的人群是有限的，因此由于冰川收缩而导致的水资源的潜在显着减少并不是一个问题，这应该引起藏族高原公众的担忧。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Tibetan Plateau is the headwaters of several major river basins, but uncertainties exist in the estimated contributions of glacial melt and groundwater to runoff. We present a new tracer-aided glacio-hydrological model constrained by multiple datasets for five major river basins of the Tibetan Plateau. We show that the contribution of glacier melt to the annual runoff is less than 5% in all the five basins at the outlets—much less than previous estimates. Our secondary finding is that the partitioning between surface runoff and groundwater flow varied greatly across the watersheds, with groundwater runoff contributing 35–75% of the annual runoff. The contribution of glacier melt has a strong spatial variability and scale dependency, but the population heavily dependent on it is limited, so a potential significant decrease in water resources due to glacier shrinkage is not a problem that should raise public worries in the Tibetan Plateau.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01060-6/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1060_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>