<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 02:34:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 未来极端降水因中尺度水汽辐合加剧而加剧</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01859-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Future extreme precipitation amplified by intensified mesoscale moisture convergence&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ping Chang; Dan Fu; Xue Liu; Frederic S. Castruccio; Andreas F. Prein; Gokhan Danabasoglu; Xiaoqi Wang; Julio Bacmeister; Qiuying Zhang; Nan Rosenbloom; Teagan King; Susan C. Bates&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;极端降水事件是由复杂的多尺度大气动态相互作用驱动的，并由可用水分推动。预计它们将随着气候变化而加剧，给人类社区和生态系统带来越来越大的风险。然而，当前的低分辨率气候模型难以准确表示关键的极端降水现象，限制了我们生成稳健可靠的未来预测的能力。在这里，我们提出了一组分辨率为 10 至 25 公里的气候模拟，并改进了中尺度对流系统的表示，以评估每日极端降水及其驱动因素的未来变化。与 100 公里分辨率的模拟相比，我们的高分辨率模拟更真实地捕捉了历史时期每日极端降水的观测空间分布和强度。在未来二氧化碳排放量较高的情况下，到 2100 年，陆地上的每日极端降水量可能会增加约 41%，这主要是由于中尺度水分收敛的增加。在低分辨率模型中，这种动力学贡献对极端降水的影响被低估了三倍。这些结果凸显了高分辨率气候模型在限制未来极端事件以及为更有效的气候风险评估和适应策略提供信息方面的关键作用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Extreme precipitation events are driven by complex multiscale atmospheric dynamic interactions, fuelled by available moisture. They are expected to intensify with climate change, posing increasing risks to human communities and ecosystems. However, current low-resolution climate models struggle to accurately represent key extreme precipitation-generating phenomena, limiting our ability to generate robust and reliable future projections. Here we present an ensemble of climate simulations with a 10-to-25-km resolution and an improved representation of mesoscale convective systems to assess future changes in daily extreme precipitation and its drivers. Our high-resolution simulations more realistically capture the observed spatial distribution and intensity of daily extreme precipitation over the historical period than the 100-km resolution counterparts. In a future scenario with high carbon dioxide emissions, daily extreme precipitation over land could increase by about 41% by 2100, mainly as a result of increased mesoscale moisture convergence. The impact of this dynamical contribution to extreme precipitation is underestimated by a factor of three in the low-resolution model. These results highlight the crucial role of high-resolution climate modelling in constraining future extremes and informing more effective climate risk assessments and adaptation strategies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02854-5/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2854_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 安第斯山脉南部未来大干旱期间冰川水量减少</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02845-6</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Less water from glaciers during future megadroughts in the Southern Andes&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Álvaro Ayala; Eduardo Muñoz-Castro; Daniel Farinotti; David Farías-Barahona; Pablo A. Mendoza; Shelley MacDonell; James McPhee; Ximena Vargas; Francesca Pellicciotti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;干旱期间，冰川融化维持山区盆地的水排放，但持续的冰川退缩威胁着这一基本能力。在这里，我们评估了安第斯山脉南部冰川对南美洲有记录以来最严重、持续和广泛的干旱之一（2010 年至今）以及预计的本世纪末特大干旱的反应。通过冰川水文数值模拟，我们发现，尽管年平均降水量赤字为 36%，但 2010-2019 年的冰川径流与前十年（2000-2009 年）相比几乎没有变化，总冰量减少了 10%。然而，对未来冰川演化的模拟表明，与 2010 年之前的水平相比，在本世纪末的特大干旱期间，年度和夏季冰川径流可能分别下降 20 ± 11% 和 48 ± 6%。我们的研究结果预测，在极端干旱期间，冰川对降水不足的缓冲作用会减弱，从而加剧南美洲山区生态系统和生计的水资源短缺。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glacier melt sustains water discharge from mountain basins during droughts, but ongoing glacier retreat threatens this fundamental capacity. Here, we assess the response of glaciers in the Southern Andes to one of the most severe, persistent, and extensive droughts on record in South America (2010-present), and to projected end-of-century megadroughts. Using glacio-hydrological numerical simulations, we show that despite a mean annual precipitation deficit of 36%, glacier runoff in 2010-2019 remained almost unaltered compared to the preceding decade (2000-2009), sustained by a 10% loss of total ice volume. However, simulations of future glacier evolution indicate that annual and summer glacier runoff could decline by up to 20 ± 11% and 48 ± 6%, respectively, during end-of-century megadroughts compared to pre-2010 levels. Our results project a weakening of the glacier’s buffering role against precipitation deficits during extreme droughts, increasing water scarcity for ecosystems and livelihoods in the mountain regions of South America.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41545-025-00525-8/MediaObjects/41545_2025_525_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 基于多模型的全球大气水分源汇关系和大气盆地数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-06123-0</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A multi-model based dataset of global atmospheric moisture source-sink relationships and atmospheric basins&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yu Zhang; Deyu Zhong; Rongrong Cai; Mingxi Zhang; Yinglin Tian; Di Xie; Yuan Cao; Yuantao Mei&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;全面了解大气水文循环对于研究气候和人为变化对全球水资源的跨境影响至关重要。本研究提出了 AMSSRAB，这是蒸发和降水位置之间的大气水分源汇关系 (AMSSR) 的全球数据集，以及对全球大气水文循环进行区域化的衍生大气盆地 (AB)。通过集成三个大气水分跟踪模型（WAM2layers、UTrack 和 WaterSip），AMSSRAB 提供了大气水分流的多模型集合表示。该数据集以 1° 分辨率提供了 40 年（1979-2018）的季节性大气水分源汇关系。衍生的大气盆地确定了准独立的水分循环系统，其特征是高内部循环。 AMSSRAB 与偏差校正重建数据和之前发布的数据集表现出强烈的一致性，同时提供了补充现有蒸发-降水框架的区域视角。该数据集使研究人员能够在多个尺度上研究水分源汇关系，分析区域水分循环模式，并检查地球大气水系统内大气水分对气候变化的响应。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A comprehensive understanding of the atmospheric hydrological cycle is crucial for studying the transboundary impacts of climate and anthropogenic changes on global water resources. This study presents AMSSRAB, a global dataset of atmospheric moisture source-sink relationships (AMSSRs) between evaporation and precipitation locations, and the derived atmospheric basins (ABs) that regionalize the global atmospheric hydrological cycle. By integrating three atmospheric moisture tracking models (WAM2layers, UTrack, and WaterSip), AMSSRAB provides a multi-model ensemble representation of atmospheric moisture flows. The dataset provides seasonal atmospheric moisture source-sink relationships at 1° resolution over 40 years (1979–2018). The derived atmospheric basins identify quasi-independent moisture circulation systems characterized by high internal recycling. AMSSRAB demonstrates strong agreement with bias-corrected reconstruction data and previously published datasets while offering a regional perspective that complements existing evaporationshed-precipitationshed frameworks. This dataset enables researchers to investigate moisture source-sink relationships at multiple scales, analyze regional moisture recycling patterns, and examine atmospheric moisture responses to climate variability within the Earth’s atmospheric water system.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-24133-1/MediaObjects/41598_2025_24133_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 预计近期跨赤道北风涌流的变化及其水文影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01239-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Projected changes in cross-equatorial northerly surges and their hydrological impacts in the near future&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Sandro W. Lubis; Chuan-Chieh Chang; Samson Hagos; Ming Zhao; Ziming Chen; Karthik Balaguru; L. Ruby Leung&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;近几十年来，东南亚一些人口最稠密的地区在寒冬期间出现了前所未有的极端降水和灾难性洪水。这些极端事件经常受到跨赤道偏北气流（CENS）的影响，其特点是西海洋大陆赤道以南偏北潮湿季风的加强。然而，CENS 未来的潜在变化及其水文影响仍未得到充分探索。在这里，我们使用高分辨率气候模型模拟集合（CMIP6 HighResMIP）表明，CENS 对极端降水事件的强度和频率的区域影响预计在不久的将来（2030-2050 年）将显着增加，特别是在印度尼西亚南部和澳大利亚西北部的邻近沿海地区。更具体地说，尽管 CENS 特征在不久的将来没有明显变化，但与季节概率相比，与 CENS 相关的极端降水风险预计将增加高达 39 ± 1.2%。这种更强的影响归因于更潮湿和更温暖的环境导致润湿效率和湿静态不稳定性的增强，从而导致更强烈的CENS对流。我们的结果表明，需要有效的监测和灾害管理，以应对在不久的将来此类事件日益严重的情况。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Recent decades have witnessed unprecedented extreme precipitation and catastrophic flooding in some of the most populated regions in Southeast Asia during boreal winter. These extreme events are often influenced by the cross-equatorial northerly surge (CENS), characterized by a strengthening of northerly moist monsoon winds south of the equator in the western Maritime Continent. However, the potential future changes in CENS and its hydrological impacts remain underexplored. Here, using an ensemble of high-resolution climate model simulations (CMIP6 HighResMIP), we show that the regional impacts of CENS on the intensity and frequency of extreme precipitation events are projected to significantly increase in the near future (2030–2050), particularly over the adjacent coastal regions of southern Indonesia and northwestern Australia. More specifically, the risk of CENS-related extreme precipitation is projected to increase by up to 39 ± 1.2% relative to the seasonal probability, despite no apparent changes in the CENS characteristics in the near future. Such stronger impact is attributed to the enhanced moistening efficiency and moist static instability due to a more humid and warmer environment, which leads to more intense CENS convection. Our results suggest the need for effective monitoring and disaster managements to respond to the increasing severity of such events in the near future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-06123-0/MediaObjects/41597_2025_6123_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 阐明美国本土降水和水流对变暖的敏感性之间的松散联系</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01257-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Elucidating the loose tie between precipitation and streamflow sensitivities to warming across the contiguous United States&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Marc Prange; Ming Zhao; Elena Shevliakova; Sergey Malyshev&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;区域降水和径流对变暖的敏感性的关系变得复杂，因为径流通常是降水和蒸散之间平衡中的小残留物。此外，土地水文特性的不均匀性和人类的水文干预（如灌溉和水坝）使得水流敏感性难以用气候模型和观测来约束。在这里，我们使用 GFDL 的中等高分辨率全球气候模型，在反事实的变暖情景中阐明了驱动美国本土地区不同的平均和极端水流对变暖的敏感性的水文过程。我们表明，在美国西海岸和东部，大气河流是当前气候下高流量以及气候变暖时更频繁高流量的主要驱动力。在美国西部山区，尽管降水量和先前的土壤湿度有所增加，但径流却在减少，因为降雪的减少会加速蒸散，其速度是降水变化速度的两倍。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The relation of regional precipitation and streamflow sensitivities to warming is complicated by runoff often being the small residual in the balance between precipitation and evapotranspiration. In addition, the inhomogeneous nature of land-hydrological properties and hydrological interventions by humans, like irrigation and dams, have made streamflow sensitivities challenging to constrain with both climate models and observations. Here, we elucidate the hydrological processes driving the regionally varying mean and extreme streamflow sensitivities to warming across the contiguous United States in a counter-factual warming scenario using GFDL’s moderately high-resolution global climate model. We show that over the West Coast and eastern US, atmospheric rivers are the dominant driver of high-flows in the present climate and of more frequent high-flows in a warmer climate. Over the mountainous western US, streamflows dwindle despite increases in precipitation and antecedent soil moisture, as loss of snow fuels evapotranspiration at double the rate of precipitation changes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-24616-1/MediaObjects/41598_2025_24616_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 孟加拉国水文地貌灾害暴露程度的差异</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-64920-y</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Disparities in exposure to hydrogeomorphic hazards in Bangladesh&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Amelie Paszkowski; Timothy Tiggeloven; Edoardo Borgomeo; Jim W. Hall&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;自然灾害会损害社会经济发展。虽然人们对各种自然灾害的暴露程度已经被量化，但水文地貌灾害（包括水引起的景观变化）的暴露程度仍然未知。本研究以孟加拉国为案例研究，利用高分辨率水文地貌模型，结合人口和财富数据，对人口和财富群体的水文地貌灾害暴露程度进行了全国范围的空间评估。孟加拉国是一个地质动态极其丰富的国家，这里存在多种灾害，同时人口稠密（每&lt;sup&gt;平方公里&lt;/sup&gt;1300 人）和高贫困率（20%）。在这里，我们显示超过 2200 万人（占人口的 13%）生活在水文地貌不稳定的地区。在这 2200 万人中，86% 属于人口中最低财富群体。鉴于暴露程度如此之大，水文地貌灾害必须纳入孟加拉国及其他地区的灾害风险管理和扶贫工作中。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Natural hazards can impair socio-economic development. While population exposure to various natural hazards has been quantified, the exposure to hydrogeomorphic hazards – involving water-induced landscape changes – remains unknown. Using high-resolution hydrogeomorphic modelling, combined with population and wealth data, this study provides a national-scale spatial assessment of exposure to hydrogeomorphic hazards across population and wealth groups, taking Bangladesh as a case study. Bangladesh is an exceptionally geo-dynamic country, where multiple hazards coincide with a dense population (1300 people per km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;) and a high poverty rate (20%). Here we show that over 22 million people, making up 13% of the population, live within hydrogeomorphically unstable regions. Of the 22 million, 86% are within the lowest wealth groups of the population. Given such a high level of disparity in exposure, hydrogeomorphic hazards must be incorporated into disaster risk management and poverty alleviation efforts in Bangladesh and beyond.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-24585-5/MediaObjects/41598_2025_24585_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 最近由南极放大引发的安第斯山脉中南部水危机是过去八个世纪以来前所未有的</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02858-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Recent south-central Andes water crisis driven by Antarctic amplification is unprecedented over the last eight centuries&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Shijie Wang; Mao Hu; Feng Chen; Xiaoen Zhao; Martín A. Hadad; Fidel A. Roig; David M. Meko; Max C. A. Torbenson; Sergio Piraino; Heli Zhang; Yang Xu; Youping Chen; Weipeng Yue; Honghua Cao&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;发源于安第斯山脉的河流是满足南美洲农业和社会需求的重要水源，但日益受到气候变化的威胁。在这里，我们利用安第斯山脉中南部山麓的树木年轮记录重建了过去 827 年巴塔哥尼亚北部内格罗河 (Rió Negro) 的水流。这次重建揭示了近几十年来河流流量前所未有的下降。厄尔尼诺-南方涛动和南方环模产生的水分提供了关键的水源，但气温上升增加了大气水分需求并减少了可用性。南极的放大进一步扰乱了环流模式，加速了变暖，加剧了区域干旱。自 20 世纪以来，内格罗河的流量持续减少，每十年约 10%。各种排放情景下的预测表明排放量持续下降，凸显了迫切需要采取适应性水管理战略，以缓解该地区不断升级的水资源短缺风险。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Rivers originating from the Andes Mountains are vital water sources for agricultural and societal needs in South America, yet are increasingly threatened by climate change. Here we reconstruct streamflow of the Negro River (Rió Negro) in northern Patagonia over the past 827 years using tree-ring records from the south-central Andes foothills. This reconstruction reveals an unprecedented decline in river flow in recent decades. Moisture from the El Niño–Southern Oscillation and the Southern Annular Mode provides a key water source, but temperature rise has increased atmospheric moisture demand and reduced availability. Antarctic amplification has further disrupted circulation patterns and accelerated warming, intensifying regional aridity. Since the 20th century, the Negro River has experienced a sustained flow reduction of approximately 10% per decade. Projections under various emission scenarios indicate continued decline, highlighting the urgent need for adaptive water management strategies to mitigate escalating water scarcity risks in the region.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-24796-w/MediaObjects/41598_2025_24796_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 南加州极端洪水的多尺度驱动因素：ENSO、MJO、北太平洋急流和大气河流</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01242-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Multiscale drivers of extreme southern California flooding: ENSO, MJO, North Pacific jet, and atmospheric rivers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Edoardo Mazza; Shuyi S. Chen; Brandon W. Kerns; Andrew C. Winters&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2024 年 2 月，在 2023 年至 2024 年厄尔尼诺现象期间，由强大的大气河 (AR) 和持续的马登-朱利安振荡 (MJO) 驱动的极端降雨和洪水袭击了南加州，影响了超过 1000 万人。 AR 是造成美国西海岸极端降雨和洪水的主要原因。尽管 AR-MJO 联系已被记录，但其时空变异性仍然是预测和风险管理的主要挑战。结合降水量、流量计和人口数据，我们量化了这一极端事件的物理驱动因素和人口暴露程度。利用拉格朗日 MJO 降水跟踪算法，我们揭示了 AR 发展的多尺度相互作用。厄尔尼诺现象有利于一个大型、寿命长的 MJO，它与北太平洋急流 (NPJ) 相互作用超过三周。 MJO 对流流出通过沿对流层顶引起负位涡平流来调节 NPJ。随后的 NPJ 延伸和加速引发了爆炸性气旋，其 AR 驱动的水分输送导致了极端降雨。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Extreme rainfall and flooding, driven by a powerful atmospheric river (AR) and a persistent Madden-Julian Oscillation (MJO), hit Southern California in February 2024 during the 2023–2024 El Niño, affecting over 10 million people. ARs are key contributors to extreme rainfall and flooding along the U.S. West Coast. Although the AR-MJO link has been documented, its spatio-temporal variability remains a major forecasting and risk-management challenge. Combining precipitation, stream gauge and demographic data, we quantify the physical drivers and population exposure to this extreme event. Leveraging a Lagrangian MJO precipitation tracking algorithm, we unravel the multiscale interactions responsible for the AR’s development. El Niño favored a large, long-lived MJO that interacted with the North Pacific Jet (NPJ) over more than three weeks. The MJO convective outflow modulated the NPJ by inducing negative potential vorticity advection along the tropopause. The ensuing NPJ extension and acceleration induced explosive cyclogenesis, whose AR-driven moisture transport resulted in extreme rainfall.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01239-x/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1239_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 通过冻结雨滴碎片进行有效的冰增殖</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02953-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Efficient ice multiplication from freezing raindrop fragmentation&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Nils Pfeifer; Bernd Mom; Dmitri Moisseev; Susan Hartmann; Julian Meusel; Corinna Hoose; Maximilian Maahn&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;云是我们气候系统的重要组成部分，其生命周期受到冰形成的显着影响。测量到的云中冰浓度通常超过冰成核颗粒的数量，这是由于二次冰过程造成的差异。然而，这些过程还没有被很好地理解或量化。一种这样的过程，即冷冻时的液滴碎裂，涉及到所产生的冰粒数量的显着不确定性。在这里，我们通过结合一次再冻雨期间的实地观测和遥感观测来确定这一过程的发生。通过对现场图像进行分类，我们估计每滴会产生 1.2 到 6.1 个次级冰晶。研究发现，直径在 0.5 至 1 毫米之间的水滴特别容易破裂。这些结果突出了液滴破碎的有效性，并为改善大气模型中这一过程的表示提供了宝贵的见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Clouds are an important component of our climate system with their life cycle significantly influenced by ice formation. Measured ice concentrations in clouds often exceed the number of ice nucleating particles, a discrepancy attributed to secondary ice processes. However, these processes are not well understood or quantified. One such process, drop fragmentation upon freezing, involves significant uncertainty regarding the number of produced ice particles. Here we identify the occurrence of this process by combining in situ and remote sensing observations during a case of refreezing rain. By categorizing the in situ imagery, we estimate that between 1.2 and 6.1 secondary ice crystals are produced per drop. Drops between 0.5 and 1 mm in diameter were found to be particularly prone to breakup. These results highlight the effectiveness of droplet fragmentation and provide valuable insights for improving the representation of this process in atmospheric models.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-25277-w/MediaObjects/41598_2025_25277_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 全球粮仓地区连续发生热雨极端天气导致农作物减产的风险</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02989-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Risk of successive hot-pluvial extremes on crop yield loss over global breadbasket regions&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Abebe K. Kabtih; Cheng Qian&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;多种极端气候可能同时发生或相继发生并成为复合危害。近年来，连续热雨极端事件（SHPE）频发，但SHPE对作物产量的风险尚未得到研究。在此，我们揭示了生长季节内 SHPE 反复发生的危险及其与粮仓地区随后产量损失的关系。我们的结果显示，从 1979 年到 2024 年的生长季节内，周期性 SHPE 的演变呈增加趋势。正如负产量百分比变化和线性回归分析所示，粮仓地区存在作物同步低产的重大风险。 XGBoost 分类器模型预测，玉米、水稻、大豆和小麦产量对频繁发生 SHPE 事件的反应的负可能性分别为 49%、50%、49% 和 50%。另外，XGBoost 回归超越并解释了所研究作物全球范围内反复出现 SHPE 所造成的 36% 的产量变异性，尽管它在不同地区表现出异质性。这些见解为考虑实际风险提供了基础，最终有助于提高作物产量。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Multiple climate extremes can coincide in time or happen sequentially and become a compound hazard. Recently, frequent occurrences of successive hot-pluvial extremes (SHPEs) have been presented, yet the risk of SHPEs on crop yield has not been investigated. Here we reveal peril of recurrent occurrences of SHPEs during intra-growing season and their connection with subsequent yield loss over breadbasket regions. Our results show an increasing trend in evolution of recurrent SHPEs during intra-growing seasons from 1979 to 2024. A significant risk of synchronized low crop yields is found in breadbasket regions, as shown by negative yield percentage changes and linear regression analysis. XGBoost classifier model predicts a negative likelihood of 49%, 50%, 49%, and 50% for maize, rice, soybean, and wheat yield responses to the emergence of frequent SHPE events, respectively. Alternatively, XGBoost regression surpasses and explains 36% of yield variability caused by recurrent occurrences of SHPEs globally for the studied crops, although it exhibits heterogeneities across different regions. The insights provide a foundation for considering the actual risk, which ultimately contributes to improving crop yield.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-26817-0/MediaObjects/41598_2025_26817_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>