<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 02:35:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 森林砍伐对巴西面包板下风降水的代偿影响的观察证据</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01152-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Observational evidence of compensatory influences of deforestation on downwind precipitation in Brazilian breadbaskets&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hao Li; Damián Insua-Costa; Akash Koppa; João Lucas Geirinhas; Jessica Keune; Chiara M. Holgate; Francina Dominguez; Victoria M. H. Deman; Adriaan J. Teuling; Diego G. Miralles&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;稳定且可预测的湿季降雨对于巴西的大豆生产至关重要。然而，近几十年来，气候和土地利用变化，尤其是亚马逊森林砍伐，在该地区的降雨变化增加了。在这里，我们从大气水分传输的角度研究了巴西的两个主要大豆面包板的长期生长季节变化。利用基于观测值指导的拉格朗日模型的新型水分跟踪框架，我们确定了湿气源区域，蒸发导致这些面包板上的降雨。此外，我们量化了源蒸发与大气（Thermo）动力学的相对贡献变化对下风的变化。我们的结果表明，森林砍伐引起的蒸发量下降已经对面包板地区的下风降雨产生了负面影响。然而，加强的循环循环，通过增加的水蒸气运输和与树木覆盖降低一致的低水平风速证明，从上风区域（包括亚马逊和大西洋）到巴西大豆面包板的水分运输增强。这突出了森林砍伐对降雨的补偿性影响，通过减少的蒸发和改变大气（热）动态，以及这些影响如何影响南美的顺风大豆生产力。进一步了解这些互动对于制定土地管理策略至关重要，以减轻该地区气候变化的农业影响。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Stable and predictable wet-season rainfall is crucial for soybean production in Brazil. However, climate and land-use changes, particularly Amazon deforestation, have increased rainfall variability in the region in recent decades. Here, we investigate long-term growing-season rainfall changes over two major soybean breadbaskets in Brazil from the perspective of atmospheric moisture transport. Utilising a novel moisture tracking framework based on a Lagrangian model guided by observations, we identify moisture source regions where evaporation contributed to rainfall over these breadbaskets. Furthermore, we quantify the relative contributions of source evaporation versus atmospheric (thermo)dynamics changes to downwind rainfall variability. Our results indicate that deforestation-induced evaporation declines have negatively impacted downwind rainfall in the breadbasket regions. However, strengthened circulation, evidenced by increased water vapour transport and low-level wind speeds consistent with decreased tree cover, has enhanced moisture transport from upwind regions (including Amazonia and the Atlantic Ocean) to the Brazilian soybean breadbaskets. This highlights the compensatory effects of deforestation on rainfall through decreased evaporation and altered atmospheric (thermo)dynamics, and how these effects may influence downwind soybean productivity in South America. Further understanding these interactions is critical for developing land management strategies to mitigate the agricultural impacts of climate change in the region.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01152-3/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1152_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>