<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 08:39:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 在气候变化下对全球土壤水分投影的紧急限制</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02024-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Lei Yao; Guoyong Leng; Linfei Yu; Hongyi Li; Qiuhong Tang; Andre Python; Jim W. Hall; Xiaoyong Liao; Ji Li; Jiali Qiu; Johannes Quaas; Shengzhi Huang; Yin Jin; Jakob Zscheischler; Jian Peng&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在全球变暖下预计表面土壤水分将减少。这样的预测主要是基于气候模型，由于观察限制不足，它们显示出较大的不确定性（即，模型间扩散）。在这里，我们确定了土壤水分变化（2070-2099 Minus 1980-2014）与近期气候模型集合中的空气温度和降水趋势之间的牢固基于物理的紧急关系。我们将常用的单变量紧急限制扩展到双变量方法，并使用观察到的温度和降水趋势来限制全球土壤水分的变化。我们的结果表明，双变量紧急限制可以使土壤水分的不确定性减少7.87％，这是传统基于温度的单变量约束的效率四倍。双变量的紧急限制将土壤水分的迹象从阴性变为半干旱，干燥的亚游和潮湿区域以及整个全球土地，但加剧了干旱和高弧区域的干燥趋势。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Surface soil moisture is projected to decrease under global warming. Such projections are mostly based on climate models, which show large uncertainty (i.e., inter-model spread) partly due to inadequate observational constraint. Here we identify strong physically-based emergent relationships between soil moisture change (2070–2099 minus 1980–2014) and recent air temperature and precipitation trends across an ensemble of climate models. We extend the commonly used univariate Emergent Constraints to a bivariate method and use observed temperature and precipitation trends to constrain global soil moisture changes. Our results show that the bivariate emergent constraints can reduce soil moisture change uncertainty by 7.87%, which is four times more effective than traditional temperature-based univariate constraints. The bivariate emergent constraints change the sign of soil moisture change from negative to positive for semi-arid, dry sub-humid and humid regions and global land as a whole, but exacerbates the drying trend in arid and hyper-arid regions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02024-7/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2024_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 预计局部极端降水变化的确定性增加</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-56235-9</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Chao Li; Jieyu Liu; Fujun Du; Francis W. Zwiers; Guolin Feng&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;最新的气候模型项目广泛改变了未来极端降水的变化的幅度，从而阻碍了有效的适应计划。已经提出了许多观察性限制，以减少全球投影的不确定性，从而将次生尺度降低，但是适应通常需要详细的局部规模信息。在这里，我们提出了一种基于温度的适应性紧急约束策略，并结合了数据聚合，从而减少了在高排放场景下，预计本世纪末每日降水的年度极端变化的误差差异&amp;gt; 20％&amp;gt; 20％ 。这些改进的预测可以通过允许在地方一级的更好的影响评估和适应计划来使世界近90％的人口受益。我们的身体动机策略考虑了预测的极端降水变化的热力学和动态成分，利用了全球变暖与极端降水的热力学成分之间的联系。严格的交叉验证为限制局部极端降水预测的可靠性提供了有力的证据。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The latest climate models project widely varying magnitudes of future extreme precipitation changes, thus impeding effective adaptation planning. Many observational constraints have been proposed to reduce the uncertainty of these projections at global to sub-continental scales, but adaptation generally requires detailed, local scale information. Here, we present a temperature-based adaptative emergent constraint strategy combined with data aggregation that reduces the error variance of projected end-of-century changes in annual extremes of daily precipitation under a high emissions scenario by &amp;gt;20% across most areas of the world. These improved projections could benefit nearly 90% of the world’s population by permitting better impact assessment and adaptation planning at local levels. Our physically motivated strategy, which considers the thermodynamic and dynamic components of projected extreme precipitation change, exploits the link between global warming and the thermodynamic component of extreme precipitation. Rigorous cross-validation provides strong evidence of its reliability in constraining local extreme precipitation projections.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-56235-9/MediaObjects/41467_2025_56235_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 在高地残留物记录的Noachian火星上的二分法撤退和水的蚀变</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-024-01634-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Joseph D. McNeil; Peter Fawdon; Matthew R. Balme; Angela L. Coe; Javier Cuadros; Stuart M. R. Turner&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mawrth Vallis地区是位于火星半球二分法边界高地的高原。它具有&amp;gt; 200毫米厚的纤维硅酸盐含有含硅酸盐的地层演替，表明在Noachian时期，在4.1 GA和3.7 GA之间进行了广泛的水性改变。此外，已经确定了瓦利斯（Mawrth Vallis）北部和西部的低地的数千公里级孤立的土墩。在这里，我们使用地貌和光谱分析表明，这些土墩是通过诺阿西（Noachian）高地高原的撤退而形成的侵蚀性残留物。因此，标志着二分法的表面表达的悬崖必须在该地区向南减少数百公里。土丘中的横向和地层地球化学变化表明，在表面和地下环境中，在该区域的原位发生了广泛的多相蚀变。土墩继任是由富含辉石的单元的底线，该单元代表了区域底硅酸盐含量序列下方的未改变的材料，并且不整合地覆盖着一个薄的上限单元，标志着大型区域水性活性的末端。因此，土墩包含了该地区Noachian水性条件的发作，进化和停止的地层记录，详细介绍了火星最可居住的环境和气候。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Mawrth Vallis region is a plateau situated on the highland side of Mars’ hemispheric dichotomy boundary. It has a &amp;gt;200-m-thick phyllosilicate-bearing stratigraphic succession that indicates extensive aqueous alteration between 4.1 Ga and 3.7 Ga, during the Noachian Period. In addition, thousands of kilometre-scale isolated mounds in the lowlands north and west of Mawrth Vallis have been identified. Here we use geomorphological and spectroscopic analyses to show that the mounds are erosional remnants that formed through retreat of the highland plateau in the Noachian. Consequently, the escarpment that marks the surface expression of the dichotomy must have receded south-southeast by hundreds of kilometres in this area. Lateral and stratigraphic geochemical variation in the mounds show that widespread, multiphase aqueous alteration occurred in situ across this region in surface and subsurface environments. The mound succession is underlain by a pyroxene-rich unit that represents unaltered material below the regional phyllosilicate-bearing sequence and is unconformably overlain by a thin capping unit that marks the end of large-scale regional aqueous activity. Thus, the mounds contain a stratigraphic record of the onset, evolution and cessation of Noachian aqueous conditions in this region, detailing the environment and climate of Mars at its most habitable.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-024-01634-8/MediaObjects/41561_2024_1634_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Water | 预计的径流会因植物生理对降水的影响而下降</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-024-00361-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Corey S. Lesk; Jonathan M. Winter; Justin S. Mankin&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在高大气CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;下，植物对径流的影响是未来水资源的主要不确定性。理论和地球系统模型（ESM）表明，在高CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;下，更严格的植物气孔调节将减少蒸腾作用，可能会增强径流。然而，在隔离植物对CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;的理想化ESM模拟的12个成员合奏中，我们表明，较低的蒸腾作用可稳健地增强径流，仅在模型的全球土地面积的5％上。降水的变化是驱动径流反应中的蒸腾变化重要的五倍，并且是CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;生理强迫超过31-57％的土地面积的重要信号。至关重要的是，ESM在生理强迫降水发生变化的地方基本上不同意，但同意大多数位置的植物反应可能会减少径流而不是增加径流。这些结果表明，降水反应中的大型模型不确定性，而不是蒸腾响应，解释了为什么ESM在植物生理驱动的径流变化上不同意。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The impact of plants on runoff under high atmospheric CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; is a major uncertainty for future water resources. Theory and Earth system models (ESMs) suggest that stricter plant stomatal regulation under high CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; will reduce transpiration, potentially boosting runoff. Yet, across a 12-member ensemble of idealized ESM simulations that isolate plant responses to CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, we show that lower transpiration robustly enhances runoff over only 5% of modelled global land area. Precipitation changes are five times more important than transpiration changes in driving runoff responses and are a significant signal of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; physiological forcing over 31–57% of land areas across models. Crucially, ESMs largely disagree on where physiologically forced precipitation changes occur but agree that plant responses in most locations are as likely to reduce runoff as increase it. These results imply that large model uncertainties in precipitation responses, rather than transpiration responses, explain why ESMs disagree on plant physiologically driven runoff changes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44221-024-00361-z/MediaObjects/44221_2024_361_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 耗散海龟海滩的地下水，流体动力和沙子特征的测量</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04455-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jakob C. Christiaanse; José A. A. Antolínez; Meye J. van der Grinten; Falco Taal; Jens Figlus; Timothy M. Dellapenna; Benjamin Ritt; Christopher D. Marshall; Peter A. Tereszkiewicz; Nicholas Cohn; Edward J. Majzlik; Ad J. H. M. Reniers&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;在2023年秋天，在德克萨斯州加尔维斯顿岛的两个耗散海滩样带上收集了海滩地下水和近岸流体动力学数据。受监测的海滩是备受濒危Kemp的肯普的Ridley Sea Turtle的筑巢栖息地。从平静到暴风雨的条件不等，实验期间发生了两次风暴，将整个海滩淹没到沙丘脚趾。收集的流体动力学数据包括从淹没在前岸淹没并安装在近海地下水井中的压力登录器的读数，两个波浪浮标的数据约1.5 km，以及瞬时水线的Gopro Timestacks（Wave Runup）。其他收集的数据包括测深和地形调查，地下温度和水分含量读数以及沉积物特征。这个综合数据集可用于（1）研究相关的海滩淹没和地下水过程，包括它们对当地生态系统的影响（例如，一再泛滥海龟巢），（2）研究近岸流体动力学流程到海滩基质的传播和地下水桌，以及（3）验证现有的海滩地下水模型。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Beach groundwater and nearshore hydrodynamic data were collected during a field experiment along two dissipative beach transects on Galveston Island, Texas, in the fall of 2023. The monitored beaches serve as nesting habitat for the critically endangered Kemp’s ridley sea turtle. Conditions ranged from calm to stormy, with two storms occurring during the experiment, inundating the entire beach up to the dune toe. Collected hydrodynamic data include readings from pressure loggers submerged in the foreshore and mounted in groundwater wells in the backshore, data from two wave buoys about 1.5 km offshore, and GoPro timestacks of the instantaneous waterline (wave runup). Other collected data include bathymetry and topography surveys, subsurface temperature and moisture content readings, and sediment characteristics. This comprehensive dataset can be used to (1) study relevant beach inundation and groundwater processes, including their effect on the local ecosystem (e.g., repeated flooding of sea turtle nests), (2) study the propagation of nearshore hydrodynamic processes into the beach matrix and groundwater table, and (3) validate existing beach groundwater models.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04455-5/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4455_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | 通过校准版本的Gem-Hydro型号在大湖泊上产生的水文产量</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04409-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Étienne Gaborit; Juliane Mai; Daniel Princz; Hongren Shen; Vincent Vionnet; Bryan Tolson; Vincent Fortin&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;该数据集包含来自加拿大环境和气候变化（ECCC）开发的GEM-HYDRO模型的校准版本的输出，可在联合研究数据存储库中获得。数据集涵盖了劳伦斯大湖和渥太华河的盆地，并在2001  -  2018年期间延伸。数据由与Gem-Hydro的土地表面方案（包括降水，表面和地下表面径流，排水，排水，蒸发，雪水等效，土壤水分…）和与Gem-Hydro的水平相关的所有变量（小时通量和状态变量）组成平均每日水流位置位于212号位置。这些输出是用校准版本的GEM-HYDRO模型模拟的，该模型以开环模式（无同化）运行，并以来自ECCC的加拿大加拿大表面重新分析版本2.1的大气强迫驱动。与参考数据集相比，GEM-HYDRO可获得各种水文变量的令人满意的模拟。该数据集可用于例如驱动不同水文变量的任何路由模型，计算气候或统计数据，并研究其变异性作为本地地理形态学的函数，等等。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This dataset contains outputs from a calibrated version of the GEM-Hydro model developed at Environment and Climate Change Canada (ECCC) and is available on the Federated Research Data Repository. The dataset covers the basins of the Laurentian Great Lakes and the Ottawa River and extends over the period 2001–2018. The data consist of all variables (hourly fluxes and state variables) related to the water balance of GEM-Hydro’s land-surface scheme (including precipitation, surface and sub-surface runoff, drainage, evaporation, snow water equivalent, soil moisture…) and mean daily streamflow at 212 gauge locations. These outputs were simulated with a calibrated version of the GEM-Hydro model that was run in open-loop mode (no assimilation) and driven with atmospheric forcings coming from ECCC’s Canadian Surface Reanalysis version 2.1. GEM-Hydro achieves satisfactory simulations of various hydrologic variables when compared to reference datasets. This dataset can be used for example to drive any routing model, compute climatologies or statistics for different hydrologic variables and study their variability as a function of the local geo-morphology, etc.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04409-x/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4409_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 气候温暖的水可用性多方面变化</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00913-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Binglan Gu; Sha Zhou; Bofu Yu; Kirsten L. Findell; Benjamin R. Lintner&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;气候变暖改变了地表水利用率（PE）的空间和季节性模式，影响径流和陆地储水。但是，仍然缺乏对各种氢化物质的这些变化的全面评估。我们开发了一种多模型的合奏方法，将全球陆地氢化气候分类为四个不同的政权，基于PE的平均值和季节性。 PE预计在空间和时间之间变化越来越多。季节性低和高季节性的潮湿地区可能会在湿季径流中增加20％的浓度增加，这突出了与洪水有关的脆弱性的潜在增加。低季节性区域表现出更快的湿季增加，土壤水分的干季更快减少，增加了缺水和干旱的可能性。相反，季节性高的干燥区域对气候变化不太敏感。这些发现强调了气候变化对全球水资源的多方面影响，因此需要针对不同氢气气候制度的量身定制策略。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate warming alters spatial and seasonal patterns of surface water availability (P-E), affecting runoff and terrestrial water storage. However, a comprehensive assessment of these changes across various hydroclimates remains lacking. We develop a multi-model ensemble approach to classify global terrestrial hydroclimate into four distinct regimes based on the mean and seasonality of P-E. P-E is projected to become increasingly variable across space and time. Wet regions with low and high seasonality are likely to experience more concentrated increases in wet-season runoff by up to 20%, highlighting potential increases in flood-related vulnerability. Low-seasonality regions exhibit faster wet-season increases and more rapid dry-season decreases in soil moisture, heightening the likelihood of water scarcity and drought. Conversely, dry regions with high seasonality are less sensitive to climate change. These findings underscore the multifaceted impacts of climate change on global water resources, necessitating the need for tailored adaptation strategies for different hydroclimate regimes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00913-4/MediaObjects/41612_2025_913_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific Data | GRAICE：通过复发性神经网络重建地面储水异常</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-04403-3</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Irene Palazzoli; Serena Ceola; Pierre Gentine&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;自2002年以来，重力恢复和气候实验（GRACE）及其后续（GRACE-FO）任务提供了对陆生储存异常（TWSA）的估计，从而可以监测全球水文变化。但是，这些数据集中的时间差距以及2002年之前缺乏TWSA观察限制了我们对长期淡水变异性的理解。在这项研究中，我们使用长期短期记忆（LSTM）和&lt;i&gt;双向&lt;/i&gt;LSTM（BILSTM）神经网络开发了从1984年到2021年的四个全球每月TWSA重建。我们的模型在全球范围内准确地重现了恩典/宽限期观察，并有效地捕获了气候极端的影响。总体而言， &lt;i&gt;GRAI&lt;/i&gt; CE在预测观察到的TWSA方面优于先前的参考TWSA重建，并在河流域量表上提供可靠的水预算估计。通过产生长期连续的TWSA时间序列， &lt;i&gt;Grai&lt;/i&gt; Ce将为气候变异性和变化对淡水资源的影响提供宝贵的见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) and its follow-on (GRACE-FO) missions have provided estimates of Terrestrial Water Storage Anomalies (TWSA) since 2002, enabling the monitoring of global hydrological changes. However, temporal gaps within these datasets and the lack of TWSA observations prior to 2002 limit our understanding of long-term freshwater variability. In this study, we develop GR&lt;i&gt;Ai&lt;/i&gt;CE, a set of four global monthly TWSA reconstructions from 1984 to 2021 at 0.5° spatial resolution, using Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) and Bidirectional LSTM (BiLSTM) neural networks. Our models accurately reproduce GRACE/GRACE-FO observations at the global scale and effectively capture the impacts of climate extremes. Overall, GR&lt;i&gt;Ai&lt;/i&gt;CE outperforms a previous reference TWSA reconstruction in predicting observed TWSA and provides reliable water budget estimates at the river basin scale. By generating long-term continuous TWSA time series, GR&lt;i&gt;Ai&lt;/i&gt;CE will offer valuable insights into the impacts of climate variability and change on freshwater resources.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-04403-3/MediaObjects/41597_2025_4403_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 天山地区高山冰川集水区的占主导地位的洪水驱动因素通过可解释的深度学习揭示</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-00918-z</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Wenting Liang; Weili Duan; Yaning Chen; Gonghuan Fang; Shan Zou; Zhi Li; Zewei Qiu; Haodong Lyu&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;库马拉克河是天山地区典型的高山冰川集水区，经历了冰川融化，融雪和降雨的驱动的复杂洪水。但是，在气候变化下推动这些过程的机制尚不清楚。为了解决这个问题，使用SWAT-GLACIER水文模型和程度 - 日因子模型用于融雪，冰川融化和降雨计算。使用这些输入开发了两个长的短期记忆（LSTM）模型（LSTM-SG和LSTM-DDF），并应用了加性分解和集成梯度方法来解释洪水机制。发现冰川融水在年度最大洪水（AMF）事件中占主导地位，而融雪驱动了年度春季最大洪水（AMFSP）事件。对于AMF事件（1960- 2018年），融雪的贡献为10.01–12.21％，冰川融合的60.49–60.92％，降雨量为26.86–29.50％。对于AMFSP事件（1961- 2018年），融雪的贡献为48.49-56.08％，冰川融合的16.12–22.08％，降雨量为27.79–29.42％。这些发现为增强洪水预测和优化水资源管理提供了关键见解。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Kumalak River, a typical alpine glacierized catchment in the Tianshan region, experiences complex flooding driven by glacier meltwater, snowmelt, and rainfall. However, the mechanisms driving these processes under climate change remain unclear. To address this, a SWAT-Glacier hydrological model and a degree–day factor model were used for snowmelt, glacier meltwater, and rainfall calculations. Two Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) models (LSTM-SG and LSTM-DDF) were developed using these inputs, and additive decomposition and integrated gradient methods were applied to interpret flood mechanisms. Glacier meltwater was found to dominate annual maximum flood (AMF) events, while snowmelt drove annual spring maximum flood (AMFSp) events. For AMF events (1960–2018), contributions were 10.01–12.21% from snowmelt, 60.49–60.92% from glacier meltwater, and 26.86–29.50% from rainfall. For AMFSp events (1961–2018), contributions were 48.49–56.08% from snowmelt, 16.12–22.08% from glacier meltwater, and 27.79–29.42% from rainfall. These findings provide critical insights for enhancing flood prediction and optimizing water resource management.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-00918-z/MediaObjects/41612_2025_918_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nature Communications | 灌溉扩展对基于IRRMIP结果的湿润压力的影响</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-56356-1</link><description>&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Yi Yao; Agnès Ducharne; Benjamin I. Cook; Steven J. De Hertog; Kjetil Schanke Aas; Pedro F. Arboleda-Obando; Jonathan Buzan; Jeanne Colin; Maya Costantini; Bertrand Decharme; David M. Lawrence; Peter Lawrence; L. Ruby Leung; Min-Hui Lo; Narayanappa Devaraju; William R. Wieder; Ren-Jie Wu; Tian Zhou; Jonas Jägermeyr; Sonali McDermid; Yadu Pokhrel; Maxwell Elling; Naota Hanasaki; Paul Muñoz; Larissa S. Nazarenko; Kedar Otta; Yusuke Satoh; Tokuta Yokohata; Lei Jin; Xuhui Wang; Vimal Mishra; Subimal Ghosh; Wim Thiery&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;灌溉在20 &lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;h&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;世纪迅速扩展，通过水，能量和生物地球化学变化影响气候。对这些影响的先前评估主要依赖于单个地球系统模型，因此遭受了结构模型的不确定性。在这里，我们通过分析参与灌溉模型对比项目（IRRMIP）的六个地球系统模型的模拟结果来量化历史灌溉扩展对气候的影响。结果表明，灌溉的扩张会导致灌溉水抽水的迅速增加，这会导致在大量灌溉区域的2米空气温度极端热量（≥4倍的可能性降低）。但是，由于灌溉引起的空气湿度的增加，灌溉扩展对潮湿压力的冷却效果不太明显甚至逆转，具体取决于热应力度量。总而言之，这项研究表明，灌溉部署并不是在气候变化下升级人类热应激的有效适应措施，呼吁仔细处理当地人增加暴露于潮湿的压力。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Irrigation rapidly expanded during the 20&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;h&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; century, affecting climate via water, energy, and biogeochemical changes. Previous assessments of these effects predominantly relied on a single Earth System Model, and therefore suffered from structural model uncertainties. Here we quantify the impacts of historical irrigation expansion on climate by analysing simulation results from six Earth system models participating in the Irrigation Model Intercomparison Project (IRRMIP). Results show that irrigation expansion causes a rapid increase in irrigation water withdrawal, which leads to less frequent 2-meter air temperature heat extremes across heavily irrigated areas (≥4 times less likely). However, due to the irrigation-induced increase in air humidity, the cooling effect of irrigation expansion on moist-heat stress is less pronounced or even reversed, depending on the heat stress metric. In summary, this study indicates that irrigation deployment is not an efficient adaptation measure to escalating human heat stress under climate change, calling for carefully dealing with the increased exposure of local people to moist-heat stress.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-025-56356-1/MediaObjects/41467_2025_56356_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>