<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 02:37:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientific Data | 秘鲁各地的稳定同位素的全国性数据集</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-025-05413-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;A nationwide dataset of stable isotopes in meteoric and terrestrial water across Peru&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Carol Romero; James Apaéstegui&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;水稳定的同位素（ &lt;sup&gt;δ18o&lt;/sup&gt; ， &lt;sup&gt;δ2&lt;/sup&gt;小时）是追踪水周期中的来源和相互作用的有价值的工具，提供了专门用于理解与全球气候相关的物理机制的重要信息。尽管具有重要意义，但南美的同位素研究主题受到有限数据的阻碍。为了解决这一差距，我们启动了一个国家水平的水稳定同位素数据集，其中涵盖了秘鲁（WSI-Perudb）的不同水源。 The dataset contains curated in-house data and incorporates previously published records from various locations collected between 2000 and 2021. The WSIPeruDB dataset is composed of 489 water collection sites and allows a comprehensive use of the dataset by implementing standardized metadata templates containing essential geographical information such as latitude, longitude, and altitude (from sea level to 5000 m asl), and sampling information such as sample type （例如地下水，降水，河流，春季等）和采样频率（例如每两周，每月，每月）。 WSIPERUDB数据集可在Zenodo上公开可用，可促进科学界的访问和使用。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Water Stable Isotopes (δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O, δ&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;H) are valuable tools for tracing sources and interactions in the water cycle, providing important information dedicated to understanding physical mechanisms related to global climate. Despite their significance, the topic of isotopic research in South America has been hindered by limited data. To address this gap, we launched a national-level water stable isotope dataset covering different water sources in Peru (WSI-PeruDB). The dataset contains curated in-house data and incorporates previously published records from various locations collected between 2000 and 2021. The WSIPeruDB dataset is composed of 489 water collection sites and allows a comprehensive use of the dataset by implementing standardized metadata templates containing essential geographical information such as latitude, longitude, and altitude (from sea level to 5000 m a.s.l), and sampling information such as sample type (e.g. groundwater, precipitation, river, spring, and others) and sampling frequency (e.g. biweekly, daily, monthly). The WSIPeruDB dataset is publicly available on Zenodo, facilitating access and use for the scientific community.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41597-025-05413-x/MediaObjects/41597_2025_5413_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>