<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 02:12:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nature Geoscience | 洪水对热带爆炸性火山喷发的全球反应</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01782-5</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Global response of floods to tropical explosive volcanic eruptions&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Hanbeen Kim; Gabriele Villarini; Wenchang Yang; Gabriel Vecchi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;高火山爆炸指数（≥5）的热带火山喷发影响全球气候系统，但对它们如何影响洪水知之甚少。在这里，利用全球气候模型模拟，使用火山刺激和季节性气候驾驶员与峰值排放之间的统计关系，我们调查了全球7,886个季节性峰值排放的响应平流层气溶胶羽流主要分布在南半球，主要分别在北半球，并在两个半球上对称地分布。对于跨膜间不对称气溶胶分布的爆发，热带区域比非热带区域显示出对喷发的直接和广泛反应，并且在发生喷发发生的半球峰值下降的明显降低（增加）峰值排放的明显降低（增加）。对于对称气溶胶分布的情况，热带（干旱）区域的趋势最强烈，通过减小（增加）两个半球的峰值排放来应对喷发。这些区域洪水反应主要归因于整个气候地区的季节性降水变化。除了直接的火山危害外，我们的研究还提供了全球视野，即由于大型爆炸性喷发引起的氢化气候变化引起的次要洪水危害。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tropical volcanic eruptions with a high volcanic explosivity index (≥5) impact the global climate system, but little is known about how they affect floods. Here, leveraging global climate model simulations with volcanic forcings and statistical relationships between seasonal climate drivers and peak discharge, we investigate the response of seasonal peak discharges at 7,886 streamgauges worldwide to three tropical explosive volcanic eruptions in the twentieth century: Agung 1963 (Indonesia), Santa Maria 1902 (Guatemala) and Pinatubo 1991 (Philippines), whose stratospheric aerosol plumes were distributed primarily in the Southern Hemisphere, primarily in the Northern Hemisphere and symmetrically across both hemispheres, respectively. For the eruptions with interhemispherically asymmetric aerosol distributions, tropical regions show more immediate and widespread responses to the eruptions than non-tropical regions, with a distinct interhemispheric contrast of decreasing (increasing) peak discharges in the hemisphere in which the eruption happened (did not happen). For the case of symmetric aerosol distribution, tropical (arid) regions have the strongest tendency to respond to the eruption by decreasing (increasing) peak discharges in both hemispheres. These regional flood responses are attributed mainly to seasonal precipitation changes across the climate regions. Beyond direct volcanic hazards, our study provides a global view of the secondary flood hazards resulting from hydroclimatic changes induced by large explosive eruptions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41561-025-01782-5/MediaObjects/41561_2025_1782_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 观察到的流量数据显示，厄尔尼诺 - 南方振荡增加了南美极端事件的可能性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02714-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Observed streamflow data shows El Niño–Southern Oscillation increases likelihood of extreme events in South America&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Ingrid Petry; Fernando M. Fan; Andrew W. Wood&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;了解厄尔尼诺 - 南方振荡如何影响极端流量事件对于预测南美与水有关的风险至关重要。在这里，我们分析了这种气候现象与使用多年河流排放的多年观察数据集的洪水和干旱的可能性之间的关系。我们量化了极端事件的概率如何在厄尔尼诺 - 南南振荡的不同阶段转移。结果表明，在拉普拉塔盆地的厄尔尼诺尼诺期间，洪水的可能性增加了120％以上，在亚马逊北部的LaNiña期间，洪水的可能性增加了120％以上。通常对最大降水和水流信号进行排列，但是洪水流比高降水表现出更强的扩增，这表明对极端事件的累积气候影响。相反，增加的干旱概率超过120％与亚马逊的厄尔尼诺相关，而拉尼娜（LaNiña）在南美内陆增加了80％以上的干旱风险。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Understanding how the El Niño–Southern Oscillation influences extreme streamflow events is essential for anticipating water-related risks in South America. Here, we analyse the relationship between this climate phenomenon and the likelihood of floods and droughts using a multi-decadal observational dataset of river discharge. We quantify how the probabilities of extreme events shift under different phases of the El Niño–Southern Oscillation. The results show that flood likelihood increases by over 120% during El Niño in the La Plata Basin and by over 120% during La Niña in the northern Amazon. Maximum precipitation and streamflow signals are generally aligned, but flood flows exhibit stronger amplification than high precipitation, suggesting a cumulative climate effect on extreme events. In contrast, increased drought probabilities of more than 120% is linked to El Niño in the Amazon, while La Niña raises drought risk in inland South America of more than 80%.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02714-2/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2714_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 海底喀斯特弹簧的磁滞揭示了流动逆转和盐水入侵现象中的倾斜点</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02522-8</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Hysteresis of submarine karst springs reveals tipping points in flow reversal and saline intrusion phenomena&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Jean-Christophe Maréchal; Bernard Ladouche; Claudine Lamotte; Benoit Dewandel; Vivien Hakoun; Pierre Perrochet&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;排出内陆喀斯特含水层的海底弹簧可能会遭受突然的流动逆转，其中淡水会流出海洋或盐水流入含水层。在这里，我们在Vise Spring（法国南部的Thau Lagoon下方）提供了全流逆转长期数据时间序列，在此期间，盐水流入含水层。我们证明，水系统状态移动的驱动参数是含水层和泻湖之间的液压梯度，由水密度变化控制。我们揭示了两个临界点的存在：（i）在液压梯度阈值下方，水系统突然从正常状态降解为盐水侵入，（ii）液压梯度对于恢复水系统是必不可少的。由于盐水填充了垂直的喀斯特导管，水系统的高滞后是造成了较长降解和盐水侵入的持续时间。在不断变化的气候环境中，由于海平面上升和充值，威胁内陆或海上淡水资源的减少，海底喀斯特弹簧的流动逆转可能会更加频繁，将来更长。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Submarine springs that drain inland karst aquifers may be subject to abrupt flow reversals in which alternatively freshwater outflows to the sea or saltwater inflows into the aquifer. Here we provide a full flow reversal long-duration data time series at the Vise spring (below Thau lagoon, south of France) during which saltwater inflows into the aquifer. We demonstrate that the driving parameter of the hydrosystem regime shifts is the hydraulic gradient between the aquifer and the lagoon, controlled by water density changes. We reveal the existence of two tipping points: (i) below a hydraulic gradient threshold, the hydrosystem suddenly degrades from a normal regime to saltwater intrusion, and (ii) a much larger hydraulic gradient is necessary for the recovery of the hydrosystem. The high hysteresis of the hydrosystem, due to the vertical karst conduit filling by saltwater, is responsible for the long duration of the degradation and saltwater intrusion. In a changing climate context, flow reversal at submarine karst springs could be more frequent and longer in the future due to sea level rise and a decrease in recharge, threatening inland or offshore freshwater resources.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02522-8/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2522_Figa_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>