<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 02:26:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 影响美国西部海狸池塘复合物中地表水积累的因素</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02573-x</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Factors influencing surface water accumulation in beaver pond complexes across the Western United States&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Luwen Wan; Emily Fairfax; Kate Maher&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;北美海狸（Castor Canadensis）建造大坝和池塘，以改变水流，增强洪泛区储水，并在干旱和野火期间提供避难所。但是，池塘区域可变性的驱动因素仍然很少理解。在这里，我们量化了使用解释性建模方法在绘制海狸池塘的地表水面积并创建海狸池塘配合物之后，使用解释性建模方法量化了驱动池塘面积和大坝长度变化的影响因子。映射面积与手动描述（r &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; = 0.89）以及87个复合物之间的添加剂池塘面积和大坝长度良好相关。大坝长度是池塘地区最强的协变量，而木质植被高度和溪流功率指数也具有影响力。这些协变量一起解释了74％的变化。我们的结果为海狸恢复的现场选择和优先级提供了一个经验基础，支持具有可比的数据可用性和景观特征的地区的流域管理，气候弹性和生态保护策略。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;North American beavers (Castor canadensis) build dams and ponds that alter streamflow, enhance floodplain water storage, and provide refugia during droughts and wildfires. However, drivers of pond area variability remain poorly understood. Here, we quantified the influencing factors that drive pond area and dam length variations using an explanatory modeling approach, after mapping surface water area of beaver ponds and creating beaver pond complexes. Mapped area correlated well with manual delineations (r&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; = 0.89), and additive pond area and dam length across 87 complexes followed a significant log-log scaling relationship. Dam length was the strongest covariate of pond area, while woody vegetation height and stream power index were also influential; together, these covariates explained 74% of the variation. Our results provide an empirical foundation to inform site selection and prioritization for beaver restoration, supporting watershed management, climate resilience and ecological conservation strategies in regions with comparable data availability and landscape characteristics.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02573-x/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2573_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>