<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 02:14:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>npj Climate and Atmospheric Science | 天气系统影响极端降水高分辨率模拟中光谱微移的有效性</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-025-01224-4</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Synoptic systems influence the effectiveness of spectral nudging in high-resolution simulations of extreme precipitation&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Daeun Kwon; Ga-Yeong Seo; Seung-Ki Min; Seok-Woo Son; Young-Hee Ryu; Eun-Soon Im; Dong-Hyun Cha; Jin-Uk Kim; Young-Hwa Byun; Kyung-On Boo&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;光谱微移（SN）是一种有效的数值技术，可以防止区域气候模拟中背景场过度偏离边界条件。本研究调查了 SN 在韩国暖季极端降水的三个典型事件的对流允许模型模拟中的有效性。案例研究表明，SN 通过使天气环流与观测结果更加一致，改善了极端降水模拟。轨迹分析还表明，SN 会影响引发极端降水的水汽输送和局部上升。然而，改善的程度取决于天气条件和域大小。 SN 的影响通常随着域大小的增加而增加，特别是对于与受地表过程影响的事件相比，由具有强烈斜压不稳定性的上层海槽驱动的事件。还发现，在主波尺度落在域大小和 SN 所用截止波长之间的事件中，SN 更有效。基于一系列敏感性实验，提出模拟极端降水事件最有效的配置是将SN应用于大约3000 km宽的域。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Spectral nudging (SN) is an effective numerical technique that prevents the background field from deviating excessively from the boundary conditions in regional climate modeling. This study investigates the effectiveness of SN in convection-permitting model simulations of three typical events of warm-season extreme precipitation in South Korea. The case studies show that SN improves extreme precipitation simulations by keeping synoptic circulations more consistent with observations. Trajectory analysis also shows that SN influences the moisture transport and local ascent that trigger extreme precipitation. However, the extent of the improvement depends on the synoptic condition and the domain size. The influence of SN generally increases with increasing domain size, especially for events driven by the developing upper-level trough with strong baroclinic instability compared to those influenced by surface processes. SN is also found to be more effective in events whose dominant wave scales fall between the domain size and the cut-off wavelength used for SN. Based on a series of sensitivity experiments, it is proposed that the most effective configuration for simulating extreme precipitation events is to apply SN to a domain approximately 3000 km wide.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41612-025-01224-4/MediaObjects/41612_2025_1224_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>