<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 02:15:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 湖泊干旱的全球评估和热点</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02285-2</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;Global assessment and hotspots of lake drought&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Xing Cheng; Shuo Wang; Jianli Chen; Amir AghaKouchak&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;近年来，许多湖泊表现出很大的可变性，使“湖泊干旱”成为人们日益关注的问题。但是，没有既定的框架来识别和研究湖泊的干旱。在这里，我们提出了一个可靠的定义，并使用1985年至2018年的月度数据进行全球评估，对超过160,000个湖泊（≥1km &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ）。我们的发现表明，15.7％的湖泊在干旱频率上经历了统计学上显着的趋势（p &amp;lt;0.05），在美国南部的52.7％和澳大利亚南部的Hotspots中，澳大利亚南部的Hotspots在澳大利亚南部的52.7％和澳大利亚南部的Hotspots中都有70.4％。此外，我们在美国南部（2012- 2014年）和澳大利亚东南部（2007- 2010年）中确定了两次严重的湖泊干旱事件，对供水，生物多样性和生态健康构成了巨大威胁。湖泊干旱的趋势上升是由温度升高，蒸气压力不足以及与湖水周期相关的因素驱动的，例如降水量不足，蒸发增加和过度抽水。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Many lakes have exhibited substantial variability in recent years, making “lake drought” a growing concern. However, there is no established framework for identifying and studying lake droughts. Here, we propose a reliable definition for it and provide a global assessment of over 160,000 lakes (≥1 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;) using monthly area data from 1985 to 2018. Our findings show that 15.7% of lakes have experienced statistically significant increasing trends in drought frequency (p &amp;lt; 0.05), with hotspots in the Southern United States at 52.7% and Southeast Australia at 70.4%. Furthermore, we identify two severe lake drought events in the Southern United States (2012–2014) and Southeast Australia (2007–2010), posing dramatic threats to water supplies, biodiversity, and ecological health. Rising trends in lake drought are driven by increasing temperature, vapor pressure deficit, and factors associated with the lake water cycle, such as precipitation deficit, increased evaporation, and excessive water withdrawal.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02285-2/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2285_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>