<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</title><link>https://www.nature.com</link><description>Nature Hydrology RSS Feed</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 02:13:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Communications Earth &amp; Environment | 通过大豆和牛肉供应链对巴西水的国际依赖</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-025-02658-7</link><description>&lt;b&gt;标题: &lt;/b&gt;International reliance on Brazil’s water through soy and beef supply chains&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;作者:&lt;/b&gt; Michael J. Lathuillière; Rafaela Flach; Lan Wang-Erlandsson; Vivian Ribeiro; Erasmus K. H. J. zu Ermgassen; Carlos M. Souza Jr&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;摘要（谷歌翻译）&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;随着商品进入供应链，消费者依靠遥远的淡水来源来确保继续供应。这些信息通常缺乏评估供应链对特定河流盆地及其缺水水平的依赖所需的可追溯性和粒度。在这里，我们量化了巴西大豆的生产和出口淡水的数量和来源，以及向中国和欧盟的牛肉，以及2015  -  2017年期间的森林砍伐和温室气体排放。这两个部门主要依靠雨养系统，还依靠大豆灌溉，以及牛饮酒和蒸发的组合，这些水库用作饮酒来源。大约20％和50％的淡水出口到中国和欧盟所需的淡水依赖于稀有水的河流盆地。我们的研究进一步展示了多种调节器评估是指导商品领域的决策至关重要的关键。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;英文摘要&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As commodities enter supply chains, consumers rely on distant freshwater sources to ensure continued supply. This information often lacks the traceability and granularity required to assess the reliance of supply chains on specific river basins and their level of water scarcity. Here, we quantify the volume and source of freshwater for the production and export of Brazilian soy and beef to China and the EU, together with deforestation and greenhouse gas emissions for the 2015–2017 period. Both sectors mainly rely on rainfed systems, but also soy irrigation and a combination of cattle drinking and evaporation from reservoirs serving as the drinking source. About 20% and 50% of the freshwater required for exports to China and the EU, respectively, rely on river basins with high or critical water scarcity. Our study further shows how a multi-indicator assessment is key to guiding decisions in commodity sectors towards sustainable production and supply chains.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs43247-025-02658-7/MediaObjects/43247_2025_2658_Fig1_HTML.png" /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>